<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Deuteronomy" book-id="5" n="30">
<verse>Here's what will happen. While you're out among the nations where GOD has dispersed you and the blessings and curses come in just the way I have set them before you, and you and your children take them seriously</verse>
<verse>and come back to GOD, your God, and obey him with your whole heart and soul according to everything that I command you today,</verse>
<verse>GOD, your God, will restore everything you lost; he'll have compassion on you; he'll come back and pick up the pieces from all the places where you were scattered.</verse>
<verse>No matter how far away you end up, GOD, your God, will get you out of there</verse>
<verse>and bring you back to the land your ancestors once possessed. It will be yours again. He will give you a good life and make you more numerous than your ancestors.</verse>
<verse>GOD, your God, will cut away the thick calluses on your heart and your children's hearts, freeing you to love GOD, your God, with your whole heart and soul and live, really live.</verse>
<verse>GOD, your God, will put all these curses on your enemies who hated you and were out to get you.</verse>
<verse>And you will make a new start, listening obediently to GOD, keeping all his commandments that I'm commanding you today.</verse>
<verse>GOD, your God, will outdo himself in making things go well for you: you'll have babies, get calves, grow crops, and enjoy an all-around good life. Yes, GOD will start enjoying you again, making things go well for you just as he enjoyed doing it for your ancestors.</verse>
<verse>But only if you listen obediently to GOD, your God, and keep the commandments and regulations written in this Book of Revelation. Nothing halfhearted here; you must return to GOD, your God, totally, heart and soul, holding nothing back.</verse>
<verse>This commandment that I'm commanding you today isn't too much for you, it's not out of your reach.</verse>
<verse>It's not on a high mountain--you don't have to get mountaineers to climb the peak and bring it down to your level and explain it before you can live it.</verse>
<verse>And it's not across the ocean--you don't have to send sailors out to get it, bring it back, and then explain it before you can live it.</verse>
<verse>No. The word is right here and now--as near as the tongue in your mouth, as near as the heart in your chest. Just do it!</verse>
<verse>Look at what I've done for you today: I've placed in front of you Life and Good Death and Evil.</verse>
<verse>And I command you today: Love GOD, your God. Walk in his ways. Keep his commandments, regulations, and rules so that you will live, really live, live exuberantly, blessed by GOD, your God, in the land you are about to enter and possess.</verse>
<verse>But I warn you: If you have a change of heart, refuse to listen obediently, and willfully go off to serve and worship other gods,</verse>
<verse>you will most certainly die. You won't last long in the land that you are crossing the Jordan to enter and possess.</verse>
<verse>I call Heaven and Earth to witness against you today: I place before you Life and Death, Blessing and Curse. Choose life so that you and your children will live.</verse>
<verse>And love GOD, your God, listening obediently to him, firmly embracing him. Oh yes, he is life itself, a long life settled on the soil that GOD, your God, promised to give your ancestors, Abraham, Isaac, and Jacob.</verse>
</chapter>