<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Deuteronomy" book_id="5" n="6">
<verse>This is the commandment, the rules and regulations, that GOD, your God, commanded me to teach you to live out in the land you're about to cross into to possess.</verse>
<verse>This is so that you'll live in deep reverence before GOD lifelong, observing all his rules and regulations that I'm commanding you, you and your children and your grandchildren, living good long lives.</verse>
<verse>Listen obediently, Israel. Do what you're told so that you'll have a good life, a life of abundance and bounty, just as GOD promised, in a land abounding in milk and honey.</verse>
<verse>Attention, Israel! GOD, our God! GOD the one and only!</verse>
<verse>Love GOD, your God, with your whole heart: love him with all that's in you, love him with all you've got!</verse>
<verse>Write these commandments that I've given you today on your hearts. Get them inside of you</verse>
<verse>and then get them inside your children. Talk about them wherever you are, sitting at home or walking in the street; talk about them from the time you get up in the morning to when you fall into bed at night.</verse>
<verse>Tie them on your hands and foreheads as a reminder;</verse>
<verse>inscribe them on the doorposts of your homes and on your city gates.</verse>
<verse>When GOD, your God, ushers you into the land he promised through your ancestors Abraham, Isaac, and Jacob to give you, you're going to walk into large, bustling cities you didn't build,</verse>
<verse>well-furnished houses you didn't buy, come upon wells you didn't dig, vineyards and olive orchards you didn't plant. When you take it all in and settle down, pleased and content,</verse>
<verse>make sure you don't forget how you got there--GOD brought you out of slavery in Egypt.</verse>
<verse>Deeply respect GOD, your God. Serve and worship him exclusively. Back up your promises with his name only.</verse>
<verse>Don't fool around with other gods, the gods of your neighbors,</verse>
<verse>because GOD, your God, who is alive among you is a jealous God. Don't provoke him, igniting his hot anger that would burn you right off the face of the Earth.</verse>
<verse>Don't push GOD, your God, to the wall as you did that day at Massah, the Testing-Place.</verse>
<verse>Carefully keep the commands of GOD, your God, all the requirements and regulations he gave you.</verse>
<verse>Do what is right; do what is good in GOD's sight so you'll live a good life and be able to march in and take this pleasant land that GOD so solemnly promised through your ancestors,</verse>
<verse>throwing out your enemies left and right--exactly as GOD said.</verse>
<verse>The next time your child asks you, "What do these requirements and regulations and rules that GOD, our God, has commanded mean?"</verse>
<verse>tell your child, "We were slaves to Pharaoh in Egypt and GOD powerfully intervened and got us out of that country.</verse>
<verse>We stood there and watched as GOD delivered miracle-signs, great wonders, and evil-visitations on Egypt, on Pharaoh and his household.</verse>
<verse>He pulled us out of there so he could bring us here and give us the land he so solemnly promised to our ancestors.</verse>
<verse>That's why GOD commanded us to follow all these rules, so that we would live reverently before GOD, our God, as he gives us this good life, keeping us alive for a long time to come.</verse>
<verse>"It will be a set-right and put-together life for us if we make sure that we do this entire commandment in the Presence of GOD, our God, just as he commanded us to do." [JC]</verse>
</chapter>