<?xml version="1.0"?>
<chapter translation="KJV" testament="New" book="Matthew" n="10" book-id="40">
      <verse>And when he had called unto <supplied>him</supplied> his twelve disciples, he gave them power <supplied>against</supplied> unclean spirits, to cast them out, and to heal all manner of sickness and all manner of disease.
</verse><verse>Now the names of the twelve apostles are these; The first, Simon, who is called Peter, and Andrew his brother; James <supplied>the son</supplied> of Zebedee, and John his brother;
</verse><verse>Philip, and Bartholomew; Thomas, and Matthew the publican; James <supplied>the son</supplied> of Alphaeus, and Lebbaeus, whose surname was Thaddaeus;
</verse><verse>Simon the Canaanite, and Judas Iscariot, who also betrayed him.
</verse><verse>These twelve Jesus sent forth, and commanded them, saying, <jesus>Go not into the way of the Gentiles, and into <supplied>any</supplied> city of the Samaritans enter ye not: </jesus></verse><verse><jesus>But go rather to the lost sheep of the house of Israel. </jesus></verse><verse><jesus>And
as ye go, preach, saying, The kingdom of heaven is at hand. </jesus></verse><verse><jesus>Heal the sick, cleanse the lepers, raise the dead, cast out devils: freely ye have received, freely give. </jesus></verse><verse><jesus>Provide neither gold, nor silver, nor brass in your
purses, </jesus></verse><verse><jesus>Nor scrip for <supplied>your</supplied> journey, neither two coats, neither shoes, nor yet staves: for the workman is worthy of his meat. </jesus></verse><verse><jesus>And into whatsoever city or town ye shall enter, enquire who in it is worthy; and there
abide till ye go thence. </jesus></verse><verse><jesus>And when ye come into an house, salute it. </jesus></verse><verse><jesus>And if the house be worthy, let your peace come upon it: but if it be not worthy, let your peace return to you. </jesus></verse><verse><jesus>And whosoever shall not
receive you, nor hear your words, when ye depart out of that house or city, shake off the dust of your feet. </jesus></verse><verse><jesus>Verily I say unto you, It shall be more tolerable for the land of Sodom and Gomorrha in the day of judgment, than for that
city.
     
      </jesus>
      </verse>
      <verse>
      <jesus>Behold, I send you forth as sheep in the midst of wolves: be ye therefore wise as serpents, and harmless as doves. </jesus></verse><verse><jesus>But beware of men: for they will deliver you up to the councils, and they will scourge you in their
synagogues; </jesus></verse><verse><jesus>And ye shall be brought before governors and kings for my sake, for a testimony against them and the Gentiles. </jesus></verse><verse><jesus>But when they deliver you up, take no thought how or what ye shall speak: for it shall be given
you in that same hour what ye shall speak. </jesus></verse><verse><jesus>For it is not ye that speak, but the Spirit of your Father which speaketh in you. </jesus></verse><verse><jesus>And the brother shall deliver up the brother to death, and the father the child: and the
children shall rise up against <supplied>their</supplied> parents, and cause them to be put to death. </jesus></verse><verse><jesus>And ye shall be hated of all <supplied>men</supplied> for my name&#x2019;s sake: but he that endureth to the end shall be saved. </jesus></verse><verse><jesus>But when they persecute
you in this city, flee ye into another: for verily I say unto you, Ye shall not have gone over the cities of Israel, till the Son of man be come. </jesus></verse><verse><jesus>The disciple is not above <supplied>his</supplied> master, nor the servant above his lord.
</jesus></verse><verse><jesus>It is enough for the disciple that he be as his master, and the servant as his lord. If they have called the master of the house Beelzebub, how much more <supplied>shall they call</supplied> them of his household? </jesus></verse><verse><jesus>Fear them not
therefore: for there is nothing covered, that shall not be revealed; and hid, that shall not be known. </jesus></verse><verse><jesus>What I tell you in darkness, <supplied>that</supplied> speak ye in light: and what ye hear in the ear, <supplied>that</supplied> preach ye upon the housetops.
</jesus></verse><verse><jesus>And fear not them which kill the body, but are not able to kill the soul: but rather fear him which is able to destroy both soul and body in hell. </jesus></verse><verse><jesus>Are not two sparrows sold for a farthing? and one of them shall not fall
on the ground without your Father. </jesus></verse><verse><jesus>But the very hairs of your head are all numbered. </jesus></verse><verse><jesus>Fear ye not therefore, ye are of more value than many sparrows. </jesus></verse><verse><jesus>Whosoever therefore shall confess me before men, him will
I confess also before my Father which is in heaven. </jesus></verse><verse><jesus>But whosoever shall deny me before men, him will I also deny before my Father which is in heaven. </jesus></verse><verse><jesus>Think not that I am come to send peace on earth: I came not to send
peace, but a sword. </jesus></verse><verse><jesus>For I am come to set a man at variance against his father, and the daughter against her mother, and the daughter in law against her mother in law. </jesus></verse><verse><jesus>And a man&#x2019;s foes <supplied>shall be</supplied> they of his own
household. </jesus></verse><verse><jesus>He that loveth father or mother more than me is not worthy of me: and he that loveth son or daughter more than me is not worthy of me. </jesus></verse><verse><jesus>And he that taketh not his cross, and followeth after me, is not worthy of
me. </jesus></verse><verse><jesus>He that findeth his life shall lose it: and he that loseth his life for my sake shall find it.
     
      </jesus>
      </verse>
      <verse>
      <jesus>He that receiveth you receiveth me, and he that receiveth me receiveth him that sent me. </jesus></verse><verse><jesus>He that receiveth a prophet in the name of a prophet shall receive a prophet&#x2019;s reward; and he that receiveth a righteous man in the
name of a righteous man shall receive a righteous man&#x2019;s reward. </jesus></verse><verse><jesus>And whosoever shall give to drink unto one of these little ones a cup of cold <supplied>water</supplied> only in the name of a disciple, verily I say unto you, he shall in no wise lose
his reward.
     
      </jesus>
      </verse>
      </chapter>
