<chapter translation="NIV" testament="New" book="Matthew" book-id="40" n="1">
<verse>A record of the genealogy of Jesus Christ the son of David, the son of Abraham:</verse>
<verse>Abraham was the father of Isaac, Isaac the father of Jacob, Jacob the father of Judah and his brothers,</verse>
<verse>Judah the father of Perez and Zerah, whose mother was Tamar, Perez the father of Hezron, Hezron the father of Ram,</verse>
<verse>Ram the father of Amminadab, Amminadab the father of Nahshon, Nahshon the father of Salmon,</verse>
<verse>Salmon the father of Boaz, whose mother was Rahab, Boaz the father of Obed, whose mother was Ruth, Obed the father of Jesse,</verse>
<verse>and Jesse the father of King David. David was the father of Solomon, whose mother had been Uriah's wife,</verse>
<verse>Solomon the father of Rehoboam, Rehoboam the father of Abijah, Abijah the father of Asa,</verse>
<verse>Asa the father of Jehoshaphat, Jehoshaphat the father of Jehoram, Jehoram the father of Uzziah,</verse>
<verse>Uzziah the father of Jotham, Jotham the father of Ahaz, Ahaz the father of Hezekiah,</verse>
<verse>Hezekiah the father of Manasseh, Manasseh the father of Amon, Amon the father of Josiah,</verse>
<verse>and Josiah the father of Jeconiah and his brothers at the time of the exile to Babylon.</verse>
<verse>After the exile to Babylon: Jeconiah was the father of Shealtiel, Shealtiel the father of Zerubbabel,</verse>
<verse>Zerubbabel the father of Abiud, Abiud the father of Eliakim, Eliakim the father of Azor,</verse>
<verse>Azor the father of Zadok, Zadok the father of Akim, Akim the father of Eliud,</verse>
<verse>Eliud the father of Eleazar, Eleazar the father of Matthan, Matthan the father of Jacob,</verse>
<verse>and Jacob the father of Joseph, the husband of Mary, of whom was born Jesus, who is called Christ.</verse>
<verse>Thus there were fourteen generations in all from Abraham to David, fourteen from David to the exile to Babylon, and fourteen from the exile to the Christ.</verse>
<verse>This is how the birth of Jesus Christ came about: His mother Mary was pledged to be married to Joseph, but before they came together, she was found to be with child through the Holy Spirit.</verse>
<verse>Because Joseph her husband was a righteous man and did not want to expose her to public disgrace, he had in mind to divorce her quietly.</verse>
<verse>But after he had considered this, an angel of the Lord appeared to him in a dream and said, "Joseph son of David, do not be afraid to take Mary home as your wife, because what is conceived in her is from the Holy Spirit.</verse>
<verse>She will give birth to a son, and you are to give him the name Jesus, because he will save his people from their sins."</verse>
<verse>All this took place to fulfill what the Lord had said through the prophet:</verse>
<verse>"The virgin will be with child and will give birth to a son, and they will call him Immanuel"--which means, "God with us."</verse>
<verse>When Joseph woke up, he did what the angel of the Lord had commanded him and took Mary home as his wife.</verse>
<verse>But he had no union with her until she gave birth to a son. And he gave him the name Jesus.</verse>
</chapter>