<chapter translation="NIV" testament="New" book="Matthew" book-id="40" n="22">
<verse>Jesus spoke to them again in parables, saying:</verse>
<verse>"The kingdom of heaven is like a king who prepared a wedding banquet for his son.</verse>
<verse>He sent his servants to those who had been invited to the banquet to tell them to come, but they refused to come.</verse>
<verse>"Then he sent some more servants and said, 'Tell those who have been invited that I have prepared my dinner: My oxen and fattened cattle have been butchered, and everything is ready. Come to the wedding banquet.'</verse>
<verse>"But they paid no attention and went off--one to his field, another to his business.</verse>
<verse>The rest seized his servants, mistreated them and killed them.</verse>
<verse>The king was enraged. He sent his army and destroyed those murderers and burned their city.</verse>
<verse>"Then he said to his servants, 'The wedding banquet is ready, but those I invited did not deserve to come.</verse>
<verse>Go to the street corners and invite to the banquet anyone you find.'</verse>
<verse>So the servants went out into the streets and gathered all the people they could find, both good and bad, and the wedding hall was filled with guests.</verse>
<verse>"But when the king came in to see the guests, he noticed a man there who was not wearing wedding clothes.</verse>
<verse>'Friend,' he asked, 'how did you get in here without wedding clothes?' The man was speechless.</verse>
<verse>"Then the king told the attendants, 'Tie him hand and foot, and throw him outside, into the darkness, where there will be weeping and gnashing of teeth.'</verse>
<verse>"For many are invited, but few are chosen."</verse>
<verse>Then the Pharisees went out and laid plans to trap him in his words.</verse>
<verse>They sent their disciples to him along with the Herodians. "Teacher," they said, "we know you are a man of integrity and that you teach the way of God in accordance with the truth. You aren't swayed by men, because you pay no attention to who they are.</verse>
<verse>Tell us then, what is your opinion? Is it right to pay taxes to Caesar or not?"</verse>
<verse>But Jesus, knowing their evil intent, said, "You hypocrites, why are you trying to trap me?</verse>
<verse>Show me the coin used for paying the tax." They brought him a denarius,</verse>
<verse>and he asked them, "Whose portrait is this? And whose inscription?"</verse>
<verse>"Caesar's," they replied. Then he said to them, "Give to Caesar what is Caesar's, and to God what is God's."</verse>
<verse>When they heard this, they were amazed. So they left him and went away.</verse>
<verse>That same day the Sadducees, who say there is no resurrection, came to him with a question.</verse>
<verse>"Teacher," they said, "Moses told us that if a man dies without having children, his brother must marry the widow and have children for him.</verse>
<verse>Now there were seven brothers among us. The first one married and died, and since he had no children, he left his wife to his brother.</verse>
<verse>The same thing happened to the second and third brother, right on down to the seventh.</verse>
<verse>Finally, the woman died.</verse>
<verse>Now then, at the resurrection, whose wife will she be of the seven, since all of them were married to her?"</verse>
<verse>Jesus replied, "You are in error because you do not know the Scriptures or the power of God.</verse>
<verse>At the resurrection people will neither marry nor be given in marriage; they will be like the angels in heaven.</verse>
<verse>But about the resurrection of the dead--have you not read what God said to you,</verse>
<verse>'I am the God of Abraham, the God of Isaac, and the God of Jacob'? He is not the God of the dead but of the living."</verse>
<verse>When the crowds heard this, they were astonished at his teaching.</verse>
<verse>Hearing that Jesus had silenced the Sadducees, the Pharisees got together.</verse>
<verse>One of them, an expert in the law, tested him with this question:</verse>
<verse>"Teacher, which is the greatest commandment in the Law?"</verse>
<verse>Jesus replied: "'Love the Lord your God with all your heart and with all your soul and with all your mind.'</verse>
<verse>This is the first and greatest commandment.</verse>
<verse>And the second is like it: 'Love your neighbor as yourself.'</verse>
<verse>All the Law and the Prophets hang on these two commandments."</verse>
<verse>While the Pharisees were gathered together, Jesus asked them,</verse>
<verse>"What do you think about the Christ? Whose son is he?The son of David," they replied.</verse>
<verse>He said to them, "How is it then that David, speaking by the Spirit, calls him 'Lord'? For he says,</verse>
<verse>"'The Lord said to my Lord: "Sit at my right hand until I put your enemies under your feet."'</verse>
<verse>If then David calls him 'Lord,' how can he be his son?"</verse>
<verse>No one could say a word in reply, and from that day on no one dared to ask him any more questions.</verse>
</chapter>