<chapter translation="NIV" testament="New" book="Matthew" book-id="40" n="28">
<verse>After the Sabbath, at dawn on the first day of the week, Mary Magdalene and the other Mary went to look at the tomb.</verse>
<verse>There was a violent earthquake, for an angel of the Lord came down from heaven and, going to the tomb, rolled back the stone and sat on it.</verse>
<verse>His appearance was like lightning, and his clothes were white as snow.</verse>
<verse>The guards were so afraid of him that they shook and became like dead men.</verse>
<verse>The angel said to the women, "Do not be afraid, for I know that you are looking for Jesus, who was crucified.</verse>
<verse>He is not here; he has risen, just as he said. Come and see the place where he lay.</verse>
<verse>Then go quickly and tell his disciples: 'He has risen from the dead and is going ahead of you into Galilee. There you will see him.' Now I have told you."</verse>
<verse>So the women hurried away from the tomb, afraid yet filled with joy, and ran to tell his disciples.</verse>
<verse>Suddenly Jesus met them. "Greetings," he said. They came to him, clasped his feet and worshiped him.</verse>
<verse>Then Jesus said to them, "Do not be afraid. Go and tell my brothers to go to Galilee; there they will see me."</verse>
<verse>While the women were on their way, some of the guards went into the city and reported to the chief priests everything that had happened.</verse>
<verse>When the chief priests had met with the elders and devised a plan, they gave the soldiers a large sum of money,</verse>
<verse>telling them, "You are to say, 'His disciples came during the night and stole him away while we were asleep.'</verse>
<verse>If this report gets to the governor, we will satisfy him and keep you out of trouble."</verse>
<verse>So the soldiers took the money and did as they were instructed. And this story has been widely circulated among the Jews to this very day.</verse>
<verse>Then the eleven disciples went to Galilee, to the mountain where Jesus had told them to go.</verse>
<verse>When they saw him, they worshiped him; but some doubted.</verse>
<verse>Then Jesus came to them and said, "All authority in heaven and on earth has been given to me.</verse>
<verse>Therefore go and make disciples of all nations, baptizing them in the name of the Father and of the Son and of the Holy Spirit,</verse>
<verse>and teaching them to obey everything I have commanded you. And surely I am with you always, to the very end of the age."</verse>
</chapter>