<chapter translation="NIV" testament="New" book="Matthew" book-id="40" n="3">
<verse>In those days John the Baptist came, preaching in the Desert of Judea</verse>
<verse>and saying, "Repent, for the kingdom of heaven is near."</verse>
<verse>This is he who was spoken of through the prophet Isaiah: "A voice of one calling in the desert, 'Prepare the way for the Lord, make straight paths for him.'"</verse>
<verse>John's clothes were made of camel's hair, and he had a leather belt around his waist. His food was locusts and wild honey.</verse>
<verse>People went out to him from Jerusalem and all Judea and the whole region of the Jordan.</verse>
<verse>Confessing their sins, they were baptized by him in the Jordan River.</verse>
<verse>But when he saw many of the Pharisees and Sadducees coming to where he was baptizing, he said to them: "You brood of vipers! Who warned you to flee from the coming wrath?</verse>
<verse>Produce fruit in keeping with repentance.</verse>
<verse>And do not think you can say to yourselves, 'We have Abraham as our father.' I tell you that out of these stones God can raise up children for Abraham.</verse>
<verse>The ax is already at the root of the trees, and every tree that does not produce good fruit will be cut down and thrown into the fire.</verse>
<verse>"I baptize you with water for repentance. But after me will come one who is more powerful than I, whose sandals I am not fit to carry. He will baptize you with the Holy Spirit and with fire.</verse>
<verse>His winnowing fork is in his hand, and he will clear his threshing floor, gathering his wheat into the barn and burning up the chaff with unquenchable fire."</verse>
<verse>Then Jesus came from Galilee to the Jordan to be baptized by John.</verse>
<verse>But John tried to deter him, saying, "I need to be baptized by you, and do you come to me?"</verse>
<verse>Jesus replied, "Let it be so now; it is proper for us to do this to fulfill all righteousness." Then John consented.</verse>
<verse>As soon as Jesus was baptized, he went up out of the water. At that moment heaven was opened, and he saw the Spirit of God descending like a dove and lighting on him.</verse>
<verse>And a voice from heaven said, "This is my Son, whom I love; with him I am well pleased."</verse>
</chapter>