<chapter translation="NIV" testament="New" book="Matthew" book_id="40" n="4">
<verse>Then Jesus was led by the Spirit into the desert to be tempted by the devil.</verse>
<verse>After fasting forty days and forty nights, he was hungry.</verse>
<verse>The tempter came to him and said, "If you are the Son of God, tell these stones to become bread."</verse>
<verse>Jesus answered, "It is written: 'Man does not live on bread alone, but on every word that comes from the mouth of God.'"</verse>
<verse>Then the devil took him to the holy city and had him stand on the highest point of the temple.</verse>
<verse>"If you are the Son of God," he said, "throw yourself down. For it is written: "'He will command his angels concerning you, and they will lift you up in their hands, so that you will not strike your foot against a stone.'"</verse>
<verse>Jesus answered him, "It is also written: 'Do not put the Lord your God to the test.'"</verse>
<verse>Again, the devil took him to a very high mountain and showed him all the kingdoms of the world and their splendor.</verse>
<verse>"All this I will give you," he said, "if you will bow down and worship me."</verse>
<verse>Jesus said to him, "Away from me, Satan! For it is written: 'Worship the Lord your God, and serve him only.'"</verse>
<verse>Then the devil left him, and angels came and attended him.</verse>
<verse>When Jesus heard that John had been put in prison, he returned to Galilee.</verse>
<verse>Leaving Nazareth, he went and lived in Capernaum, which was by the lake in the area of Zebulun and Naphtali--</verse>
<verse>to fulfill what was said through the prophet Isaiah:</verse>
<verse>"Land of Zebulun and land of Naphtali, the way to the sea, along the Jordan, Galilee of the Gentiles--</verse>
<verse>the people living in darkness have seen a great light; on those living in the land of the shadow of death a light has dawned."</verse>
<verse>From that time on Jesus began to preach, "Repent, for the kingdom of heaven is near."</verse>
<verse>As Jesus was walking beside the Sea of Galilee, he saw two brothers, Simon called Peter and his brother Andrew. They were casting a net into the lake, for they were fishermen.</verse>
<verse>"Come, follow me," Jesus said, "and I will make you fishers of men."</verse>
<verse>At once they left their nets and followed him.</verse>
<verse>Going on from there, he saw two other brothers, James son of Zebedee and his brother John. They were in a boat with their father Zebedee, preparing their nets. Jesus called them,</verse>
<verse>and immediately they left the boat and their father and followed him.</verse>
<verse>Jesus went throughout Galilee, teaching in their synagogues, preaching the good news of the kingdom, and healing every disease and sickness among the people.</verse>
<verse>News about him spread all over Syria, and people brought to him all who were ill with various diseases, those suffering severe pain, the demon-possessed, those having seizures, and the paralyzed, and he healed them.</verse>
<verse>Large crowds from Galilee, the Decapolis, Jerusalem, Judea and the region across the Jordan followed him.</verse>
</chapter>