<chapter translation="NIV" testament="New" book="Matthew" book_id="40" n="7">
<verse>"Do not judge, or you too will be judged.</verse>
<verse>For in the same way you judge others, you will be judged, and with the measure you use, it will be measured to you.</verse>
<verse>"Why do you look at the speck of sawdust in your brother's eye and pay no attention to the plank in your own eye?</verse>
<verse>How can you say to your brother, 'Let me take the speck out of your eye,' when all the time there is a plank in your own eye?</verse>
<verse>You hypocrite, first take the plank out of your own eye, and then you will see clearly to remove the speck from your brother's eye.</verse>
<verse>"Do not give dogs what is sacred; do not throw your pearls to pigs. If you do, they may trample them under their feet, and then turn and tear you to pieces.</verse>
<verse>"Ask and it will be given to you; seek and you will find; knock and the door will be opened to you.</verse>
<verse>For everyone who asks receives; he who seeks finds; and to him who knocks, the door will be opened.</verse>
<verse>"Which of you, if his son asks for bread, will give him a stone?</verse>
<verse>Or if he asks for a fish, will give him a snake?</verse>
<verse>If you, then, though you are evil, know how to give good gifts to your children, how much more will your Father in heaven give good gifts to those who ask him!</verse>
<verse>So in everything, do to others what you would have them do to you, for this sums up the Law and the Prophets.</verse>
<verse>"Enter through the narrow gate. For wide is the gate and broad is the road that leads to destruction, and many enter through it.</verse>
<verse>But small is the gate and narrow the road that leads to life, and only a few find it.</verse>
<verse>"Watch out for false prophets. They come to you in sheep's clothing, but inwardly they are ferocious wolves.</verse>
<verse>By their fruit you will recognize them. Do people pick grapes from thornbushes, or figs from thistles?</verse>
<verse>Likewise every good tree bears good fruit, but a bad tree bears bad fruit.</verse>
<verse>A good tree cannot bear bad fruit, and a bad tree cannot bear good fruit.</verse>
<verse>Every tree that does not bear good fruit is cut down and thrown into the fire.</verse>
<verse>Thus, by their fruit you will recognize them.</verse>
<verse>"Not everyone who says to me, 'Lord, Lord,' will enter the kingdom of heaven, but only he who does the will of my Father who is in heaven.</verse>
<verse>Many will say to me on that day, 'Lord, Lord, did we not prophesy in your name, and in your name drive out demons and perform many miracles?'</verse>
<verse>Then I will tell them plainly, 'I never knew you. Away from me, you evildoers!'</verse>
<verse>"Therefore everyone who hears these words of mine and puts them into practice is like a wise man who built his house on the rock.</verse>
<verse>The rain came down, the streams rose, and the winds blew and beat against that house; yet it did not fall, because it had its foundation on the rock.</verse>
<verse>But everyone who hears these words of mine and does not put them into practice is like a foolish man who built his house on sand.</verse>
<verse>The rain came down, the streams rose, and the winds blew and beat against that house, and it fell with a great crash."</verse>
<verse>When Jesus had finished saying these things, the crowds were amazed at his teaching,</verse>
<verse>because he taught as one who had authority, and not as their teachers of the law.</verse>
</chapter>