<chapter translation="ESV" testament="Old" book="Psalms" book-id="19" n="103">
<verse>Bless the LORD, O my soul, and all that is within me, bless his holy name!</verse>
<verse>Bless the LORD, O my soul, and forget not all his benefits,</verse>
<verse>who forgives all your iniquity, who heals all your diseases,</verse>
<verse>who redeems your life from the pit, who crowns you with steadfast love and mercy,</verse>
<verse>who satisfies you with good so that your youth is renewed like the eagle's.</verse>
<verse>The LORD works righteousness and justice for all who are oppressed.</verse>
<verse>He made known his ways to Moses, his acts to the people of Israel.</verse>
<verse>The LORD is merciful and gracious, slow to anger and abounding in steadfast love.</verse>
<verse>He will not always chide, nor will he keep his anger forever.</verse>
<verse>He does not deal with us according to our sins, nor repay us according to our iniquities.</verse>
<verse>For as high as the heavens are above the earth, so great is his steadfast love toward those who fear him;</verse>
<verse>as far as the east is from the west, so far does he remove our transgressions from us.</verse>
<verse>As a father shows compassion to his children, so the LORD shows compassion to those who fear him.</verse>
<verse>For he knows our frame; he remembers that we are dust.</verse>
<verse>As for man, his days are like grass; he flourishes like a flower of the field;</verse>
<verse>for the wind passes over it, and it is gone, and its place knows it no more.</verse>
<verse>But the steadfast love of the LORD is from everlasting to everlasting on those who fear him, and his righteousness to children's children,</verse>
<verse>to those who keep his covenant and remember to do his commandments.</verse>
<verse>The LORD has established his throne in the heavens, and his kingdom rules over all.</verse>
<verse>Bless the LORD, O you his angels, you mighty ones who do his word, obeying the voice of his word!</verse>
<verse>Bless the LORD, all his hosts, his ministers, who do his will!</verse>
<verse>Bless the LORD, all his works, in all places of his dominion. Bless the LORD, O my soul!</verse>
</chapter>