<chapter translation="ESV" testament="Old" book="Psalms" book-id="19" n="106">
<verse>Praise the LORD! Oh give thanks to the LORD, for he is good, for his steadfast love endures forever!</verse>
<verse>Who can utter the mighty deeds of the LORD, or declare all his praise?</verse>
<verse>Blessed are they who observe justice, who do righteousness at all times!</verse>
<verse>Remember me, O LORD, when you show favor to your people; help me when you save them,</verse>
<verse>that I may look upon the prosperity of your chosen ones, that I may rejoice in the gladness of your nation, that I may glory with your inheritance.</verse>
<verse>Both we and our fathers have sinned; we have committed iniquity; we have done wickedness.</verse>
<verse>Our fathers, when they were in Egypt, did not consider your wondrous works; they did not remember the abundance of your steadfast love, but rebelled by the Sea, at the Red Sea.</verse>
<verse>Yet he saved them for his name's sake, that he might make known his mighty power.</verse>
<verse>He rebuked the Red Sea, and it became dry, and he led them through the deep as through a desert.</verse>
<verse>So he saved them from the hand of the foe and redeemed them from the power of the enemy.</verse>
<verse>And the waters covered their adversaries; not one of them was left.</verse>
<verse>Then they believed his words; they sang his praise.</verse>
<verse>But they soon forgot his works; they did not wait for his counsel.</verse>
<verse>But they had a wanton craving in the wilderness, and put God to the test in the desert;</verse>
<verse>he gave them what they asked, but sent a wasting disease among them.</verse>
<verse>When men in the camp were jealous of Moses and Aaron, the holy one of the LORD,</verse>
<verse>the earth opened and swallowed up Dathan, and covered the company of Abiram.</verse>
<verse>Fire also broke out in their company; the flame burned up the wicked.</verse>
<verse>They made a calf in Horeb and worshiped a metal image.</verse>
<verse>They exchanged the glory of God for the image of an ox that eats grass.</verse>
<verse>They forgot God, their Savior, who had done great things in Egypt,</verse>
<verse>wondrous works in the land of Ham, and awesome deeds by the Red Sea.</verse>
<verse>Therefore he said he would destroy them--had not Moses, his chosen one, stood in the breach before him, to turn away his wrath from destroying them.</verse>
<verse>Then they despised the pleasant land, having no faith in his promise.</verse>
<verse>They murmured in their tents, and did not obey the voice of the LORD.</verse>
<verse>Therefore he raised his hand and swore to them that he would make them fall in the wilderness,</verse>
<verse>and would make their offspring fall among the nations, scattering them among the lands.</verse>
<verse>Then they yoked themselves to the Baal of Peor, and ate sacrifices offered to the dead;</verse>
<verse>they provoked the LORD to anger with their deeds, and a plague broke out among them.</verse>
<verse>Then Phinehas stood up and intervened, and the plague was stayed.</verse>
<verse>And that was counted to him as righteousness from generation to generation forever.</verse>
<verse>They angered him at the waters of Meribah, and it went ill with Moses on their account,</verse>
<verse>for they made his spirit bitter, and he spoke rashly with his lips.</verse>
<verse>They did not destroy the peoples, as the LORD commanded them,</verse>
<verse>but they mixed with the nations and learned to do as they did.</verse>
<verse>They served their idols, which became a snare to them.</verse>
<verse>They sacrificed their sons and their daughters to the demons;</verse>
<verse>they poured out innocent blood, the blood of their sons and daughters, whom they sacrificed to the idols of Canaan, and the land was polluted with blood.</verse>
<verse>Thus they became unclean by their acts, and played the whore in their deeds.</verse>
<verse>Then the anger of the LORD was kindled against his people, and he abhorred his heritage;</verse>
<verse>he gave them into the hand of the nations, so that those who hated them ruled over them.</verse>
<verse>Their enemies oppressed them, and they were brought into subjection under their power.</verse>
<verse>Many times he delivered them, but they were rebellious in their purposes and were brought low through their iniquity.</verse>
<verse>Nevertheless, he looked upon their distress, when he heard their cry.</verse>
<verse>For their sake he remembered his covenant, and relented according to the abundance of his steadfast love.</verse>
<verse>He caused them to be pitied by all those who held them captive.</verse>
<verse>Save us, O LORD our God, and gather us from among the nations, that we may give thanks to your holy name and glory in your praise.</verse>
<verse>Blessed be the LORD, the God of Israel, from everlasting to everlasting! And let all the people say, "Amen!" Praise the LORD!</verse>
</chapter>