<chapter translation="ESV" testament="Old" book="Psalms" book_id="19" n="118">
<verse>Oh give thanks to the LORD, for he is good; for his steadfast love endures forever!</verse>
<verse>Let Israel say, "His steadfast love endures forever."</verse>
<verse>Let the house of Aaron say, "His steadfast love endures forever."</verse>
<verse>Let those who fear the LORD say, "His steadfast love endures forever."</verse>
<verse>Out of my distress I called on the LORD; the LORD answered me and set me free.</verse>
<verse>The LORD is on my side; I will not fear. What can man do to me?</verse>
<verse>The LORD is on my side as my helper; I shall look in triumph on those who hate me.</verse>
<verse>It is better to take refuge in the LORD than to trust in man.</verse>
<verse>It is better to take refuge in the LORD than to trust in princes.</verse>
<verse>All nations surrounded me; in the name of the LORD I cut them off!</verse>
<verse>They surrounded me, surrounded me on every side; in the name of the LORD I cut them off!</verse>
<verse>They surrounded me like bees; they went out like a fire among thorns; in the name of the LORD I cut them off!</verse>
<verse>I was pushed hard, so that I was falling, but the LORD helped me.</verse>
<verse>The LORD is my strength and my song; he has become my salvation.</verse>
<verse>Glad songs of salvation are in the tents of the righteous: "The right hand of the LORD does valiantly,</verse>
<verse>the right hand of the LORD exalts, the right hand of the LORD does valiantly!"</verse>
<verse>I shall not die, but I shall live, and recount the deeds of the LORD.</verse>
<verse>The LORD has disciplined me severely, but he has not given me over to death.</verse>
<verse>Open to me the gates of righteousness, that I may enter through them and give thanks to the LORD.</verse>
<verse>This is the gate of the LORD; the righteous shall enter through it.</verse>
<verse>I thank you that you have answered me and have become my salvation.</verse>
<verse>The stone that the builders rejected has become the cornerstone.</verse>
<verse>This is the LORD's doing; it is marvelous in our eyes.</verse>
<verse>This is the day that the LORD has made; let us rejoice and be glad in it.</verse>
<verse>Save us, we pray, O LORD! O LORD, we pray, give us success!</verse>
<verse>Blessed is he who comes in the name of the LORD! We bless you from the house of the LORD.</verse>
<verse>The LORD is God, and he has made his light to shine upon us. Bind the festal sacrifice with cords, up to the horns of the altar!</verse>
<verse>You are my God, and I will give thanks to you; you are my God; I will extol you.</verse>
<verse>Oh give thanks to the LORD, for he is good; for his steadfast love endures forever!</verse>
</chapter>