<chapter translation="ESV" testament="Old" book="Psalms" book_id="19" n="136">
<verse>Give thanks to the LORD, for he is good, for his steadfast love endures forever.</verse>
<verse>Give thanks to the God of gods, for his steadfast love endures forever.</verse>
<verse>Give thanks to the Lord of lords, for his steadfast love endures forever;</verse>
<verse>to him who alone does great wonders, for his steadfast love endures forever;</verse>
<verse>to him who by understanding made the heavens, for his steadfast love endures forever;</verse>
<verse>to him who spread out the earth above the waters, for his steadfast love endures forever;</verse>
<verse>to him who made the great lights, for his steadfast love endures forever;</verse>
<verse>the sun to rule over the day, for his steadfast love endures forever;</verse>
<verse>the moon and stars to rule over the night, for his steadfast love endures forever;</verse>
<verse>to him who struck down the firstborn of Egypt, for his steadfast love endures forever;</verse>
<verse>and brought Israel out from among them, for his steadfast love endures forever;</verse>
<verse>with a strong hand and an outstretched arm, for his steadfast love endures forever;</verse>
<verse>to him who divided the Red Sea in two, for his steadfast love endures forever;</verse>
<verse>and made Israel pass through the midst of it, for his steadfast love endures forever;</verse>
<verse>but overthrew Pharaoh and his host in the Red Sea, for his steadfast love endures forever;</verse>
<verse>to him who led his people through the wilderness, for his steadfast love endures forever;</verse>
<verse>to him who struck down great kings, for his steadfast love endures forever;</verse>
<verse>and killed mighty kings, for his steadfast love endures forever;</verse>
<verse>Sihon, king of the Amorites, for his steadfast love endures forever;</verse>
<verse>and Og, king of Bashan, for his steadfast love endures forever;</verse>
<verse>and gave their land as a heritage, for his steadfast love endures forever;</verse>
<verse>a heritage to Israel his servant, for his steadfast love endures forever.</verse>
<verse>It is he who remembered us in our low estate, for his steadfast love endures forever;</verse>
<verse>and rescued us from our foes, for his steadfast love endures forever;</verse>
<verse>he who gives food to all flesh, for his steadfast love endures forever.</verse>
<verse>Give thanks to the God of heaven, for his steadfast love endures forever.</verse>
</chapter>