<chapter translation="ESV" testament="Old" book="Psalms" book-id="19" n="40">
<verse>I waited patiently for the LORD; he inclined to me and heard my cry.</verse>
<verse>He drew me up from the pit of destruction, out of the miry bog, and set my feet upon a rock, making my steps secure.</verse>
<verse>He put a new song in my mouth, a song of praise to our God. Many will see and fear, and put their trust in the LORD.</verse>
<verse>Blessed is the man who makes the LORD his trust, who does not turn to the proud, to those who go astray after a lie!</verse>
<verse>You have multiplied, O LORD my God, your wondrous deeds and your thoughts toward us; none can compare with you! I will proclaim and tell of them, yet they are more than can be told.</verse>
<verse>Sacrifice and offering you have not desired, but you have given me an open ear. Burnt offering and sin offering you have not required.</verse>
<verse>Then I said, "Behold, I have come; in the scroll of the book it is written of me:</verse>
<verse>I desire to do your will, O my God; your law is within my heart."</verse>
<verse>I have told the glad news of deliverance in the great congregation; behold, I have not restrained my lips, as you know, O LORD.</verse>
<verse>I have not hidden your deliverance within my heart; I have spoken of your faithfulness and your salvation; I have not concealed your steadfast love and your faithfulness from the great congregation.</verse>
<verse>As for you, O LORD, you will not restrain your mercy from me; your steadfast love and your faithfulness will ever preserve me!</verse>
<verse>For evils have encompassed me beyond number; my iniquities have overtaken me, and I cannot see; they are more than the hairs of my head; my heart fails me.</verse>
<verse>Be pleased, O LORD, to deliver me! O LORD, make haste to help me!</verse>
<verse>Let those be put to shame and disappointed altogether who seek to snatch away my life; let those be turned back and brought to dishonor who desire my hurt!</verse>
<verse>Let those be appalled because of their shame who say to me, "Aha, Aha!"</verse>
<verse>But may all who seek you rejoice and be glad in you; may those who love your salvation say continually, "Great is the LORD!"</verse>
<verse>As for me, I am poor and needy, but the Lord takes thought for me. You are my help and my deliverer; do not delay, O my God!</verse>
</chapter>