<chapter translation="ESV" testament="Old" book="Psalms" book-id="19" n="49">
<verse>Hear this, all peoples! Give ear, all inhabitants of the world,</verse>
<verse>both low and high, rich and poor together!</verse>
<verse>My mouth shall speak wisdom; the meditation of my heart shall be understanding.</verse>
<verse>I will incline my ear to a proverb; I will solve my riddle to the music of the lyre.</verse>
<verse>Why should I fear in times of trouble, when the iniquity of those who cheat me surrounds me,</verse>
<verse>those who trust in their wealth and boast of the abundance of their riches?</verse>
<verse>Truly no man can ransom another, or give to God the price of his life,</verse>
<verse>for the ransom of their life is costly and can never suffice,</verse>
<verse>that he should live on forever and never see the pit.</verse>
<verse>For he sees that even the wise die; the fool and the stupid alike must perish and leave their wealth to others.</verse>
<verse>Their graves are their homes forever, their dwelling places to all generations, though they called lands by their own names.</verse>
<verse>Man in his pomp will not remain; he is like the beasts that perish.</verse>
<verse>This is the path of those who have foolish confidence; yet after them people approve of their boasts. Selah</verse>
<verse>Like sheep they are appointed for Sheol; Death shall be their shepherd, and the upright shall rule over them in the morning. Their form shall be consumed in Sheol, with no place to dwell.</verse>
<verse>But God will ransom my soul from the power of Sheol, for he will receive me. Selah</verse>
<verse>Be not afraid when a man becomes rich, when the glory of his house increases.</verse>
<verse>For when he dies he will carry nothing away; his glory will not go down after him.</verse>
<verse>For though, while he lives, he counts himself blessed,--and though you get praise when you do well for yourself--</verse>
<verse>his soul will go to the generation of his fathers, who will never again see light.</verse>
<verse>Man in his pomp yet without understanding is like the beasts that perish.</verse>
</chapter>