<chapter translation="ESV" testament="Old" book="Psalms" book-id="19" n="55">
<verse>Give ear to my prayer, O God, and hide not yourself from my plea for mercy!</verse>
<verse>Attend to me, and answer me; I am restless in my complaint and I moan,</verse>
<verse>because of the noise of the enemy, because of the oppression of the wicked. For they drop trouble upon me, and in anger they bear a grudge against me.</verse>
<verse>My heart is in anguish within me; the terrors of death have fallen upon me.</verse>
<verse>Fear and trembling come upon me, and horror overwhelms me.</verse>
<verse>And I say, "Oh, that I had wings like a dove! I would fly away and be at rest;</verse>
<verse>yes, I would wander far away; I would lodge in the wilderness; Selah</verse>
<verse>I would hurry to find a shelter from the raging wind and tempest."</verse>
<verse>Destroy, O Lord, divide their tongues; for I see violence and strife in the city.</verse>
<verse>Day and night they go around it on its walls, and iniquity and trouble are within it;</verse>
<verse>ruin is in its midst; oppression and fraud do not depart from its marketplace.</verse>
<verse>For it is not an enemy who taunts me--then I could bear it; it is not an adversary who deals insolently with me--then I could hide from him.</verse>
<verse>But it is you, a man, my equal, my companion, my familiar friend.</verse>
<verse>We used to take sweet counsel together; within God's house we walked in the throng.</verse>
<verse>Let death steal over them; let them go down to Sheol alive; for evil is in their dwelling place and in their heart.</verse>
<verse>But I call to God, and the LORD will save me.</verse>
<verse>Evening and morning and at noon I utter my complaint and moan, and he hears my voice.</verse>
<verse>He redeems my soul in safety from the battle that I wage, for many are arrayed against me.</verse>
<verse>God will give ear and humble them, he who is enthroned from of old, Selah because they do not change and do not fear God.</verse>
<verse>My companion stretched out his hand against his friends; he violated his covenant.</verse>
<verse>His speech was smooth as butter, yet war was in his heart; his words were softer than oil, yet they were drawn swords.</verse>
<verse>Cast your burden on the LORD, and he will sustain you; he will never permit the righteous to be moved.</verse>
<verse>But you, O God, will cast them down into the pit of destruction; men of blood and treachery shall not live out half their days. But I will trust in you.</verse>
</chapter>