<chapter translation="ESV" testament="Old" book="Psalms" book-id="19" n="9">
<verse>I will give thanks to the LORD with my whole heart; I will recount all of your wonderful deeds.</verse>
<verse>I will be glad and exult in you; I will sing praise to your name, O Most High.</verse>
<verse>When my enemies turn back, they stumble and perish before your presence.</verse>
<verse>For you have maintained my just cause; you have sat on the throne, giving righteous judgment.</verse>
<verse>You have rebuked the nations; you have made the wicked perish; you have blotted out their name forever and ever.</verse>
<verse>The enemy came to an end in everlasting ruins; their cities you rooted out; the very memory of them has perished.</verse>
<verse>But the LORD sits enthroned forever; he has established his throne for justice,</verse>
<verse>and he judges the world with righteousness; he judges the peoples with uprightness.</verse>
<verse>The LORD is a stronghold for the oppressed, a stronghold in times of trouble.</verse>
<verse>And those who know your name put their trust in you, for you, O LORD, have not forsaken those who seek you.</verse>
<verse>Sing praises to the LORD, who sits enthroned in Zion! Tell among the peoples his deeds!</verse>
<verse>For he who avenges blood is mindful of them; he does not forget the cry of the afflicted.</verse>
<verse>Be gracious to me, O LORD! See my affliction from those who hate me, O you who lift me up from the gates of death,</verse>
<verse>that I may recount all your praises, that in the gates of the daughter of Zion I may rejoice in your salvation.</verse>
<verse>The nations have sunk in the pit that they made; in the net that they hid their own foot has been caught.</verse>
<verse>The LORD has made himself known; he has executed judgment; the wicked are snared in the work of their own hands. Higgaion. Selah</verse>
<verse>The wicked shall return to Sheol, all the nations that forget God.</verse>
<verse>For the needy shall not always be forgotten, and the hope of the poor shall not perish forever.</verse>
<verse>Arise, O LORD! Let not man prevail; let the nations be judged before you!</verse>
<verse>Put them in fear, O LORD! Let the nations know that they are but men! Selah</verse>
</chapter>