<chapter translation="ESV" testament="Old" book="Psalms" book_id="19" n="94">
<verse>O LORD, God of vengeance, O God of vengeance, shine forth!</verse>
<verse>Rise up, O judge of the earth; repay to the proud what they deserve!</verse>
<verse>O LORD, how long shall the wicked, how long shall the wicked exult?</verse>
<verse>They pour out their arrogant words; all the evildoers boast.</verse>
<verse>They crush your people, O LORD, and afflict your heritage.</verse>
<verse>They kill the widow and the sojourner, and murder the fatherless;</verse>
<verse>and they say, "The LORD does not see; the God of Jacob does not perceive."</verse>
<verse>Understand, O dullest of the people! Fools, when will you be wise?</verse>
<verse>He who planted the ear, does he not hear? He who formed the eye, does he not see?</verse>
<verse>He who disciplines the nations, does he not rebuke? He who teaches man knowledge--</verse>
<verse>the LORD--knows the thoughts of man, that they are but a breath.</verse>
<verse>Blessed is the man whom you discipline, O LORD, and whom you teach out of your law,</verse>
<verse>to give him rest from days of trouble, until a pit is dug for the wicked.</verse>
<verse>For the LORD will not forsake his people; he will not abandon his heritage;</verse>
<verse>for justice will return to the righteous, and all the upright in heart will follow it.</verse>
<verse>Who rises up for me against the wicked? Who stands up for me against evildoers?</verse>
<verse>If the LORD had not been my help, my soul would soon have lived in the land of silence.</verse>
<verse>When I thought, "My foot slips," your steadfast love, O LORD, held me up.</verse>
<verse>When the cares of my heart are many, your consolations cheer my soul.</verse>
<verse>Can wicked rulers be allied with you, those who frame injustice by statute?</verse>
<verse>They band together against the life of the righteous and condemn the innocent to death.</verse>
<verse>But the LORD has become my stronghold, and my God the rock of my refuge.</verse>
<verse>He will bring back on them their iniquity and wipe them out for their wickedness; the LORD our God will wipe them out.</verse>
</chapter>