<chapter translation="NASB" testament="New" book="1 Thessalonians" book_id="52" n="5">
<verse>Now as to the times and the epochs, brethren, you have no need of anything to be written to you.</verse>
<verse>For you yourselves know full well that the day of the Lord will come just like a thief in the night.</verse>
<verse>While they are saying, "Peace and safety!" then destruction will come upon them suddenly like labor pains upon a woman with child, and they will not escape.</verse>
<verse>But you, brethren, are not in darkness, that the day would overtake you like a thief;</verse>
<verse>for you are all sons of light and sons of day. We are not of night nor of darkness;</verse>
<verse>so then let us not sleep as others do, but let us be alert and sober.</verse>
<verse>For those who sleep do their sleeping at night, and those who get drunk get drunk at night.</verse>
<verse>But since we are of the day, let us be sober, having put on the breastplate of faith and love, and as a helmet, the hope of salvation.</verse>
<verse>For God has not destined us for wrath, but for obtaining salvation through our Lord Jesus Christ,</verse>
<verse>who died for us, so that whether we are awake or asleep, we will live together with Him.</verse>
<verse>Therefore encourage one another and build up one another, just as you also are doing.</verse>
<verse>But we request of you, brethren, that you appreciate those who diligently labor among you, and have charge over you in the Lord and give you instruction,</verse>
<verse>and that you esteem them very highly in love because of their work. Live in peace with one another.</verse>
<verse>We urge you, brethren, admonish the unruly, encourage the fainthearted, help the weak, be patient with everyone.</verse>
<verse>See that no one repays another with evil for evil, but always seek after that which is good for one another and for all people.</verse>
<verse>Rejoice always;</verse>
<verse>pray without ceasing;</verse>
<verse>in everything give thanks; for this is God's will for you in Christ Jesus.</verse>
<verse>Do not quench the Spirit;</verse>
<verse>do not despise prophetic utterances.</verse>
<verse>But examine everything carefully; hold fast to that which is good;</verse>
<verse>abstain from every form of evil.</verse>
<verse>Now may the God of peace Himself sanctify you entirely; and may your spirit and soul and body be preserved complete, without blame at the coming of our Lord Jesus Christ.</verse>
<verse>Faithful is He who calls you, and He also will bring it to pass.</verse>
<verse>Brethren, pray for us.</verse>
<verse>Greet all the brethren with a holy kiss.</verse>
<verse>I adjure you by the Lord to have this letter read to all the brethren.</verse>
<verse>The grace of our Lord Jesus Christ be with you.</verse>
</chapter>