<chapter translation="NIV" testament="New" book="1 Timothy" book-id="54" n="3">
<verse>Here is a trustworthy saying: If anyone sets his heart on being an overseer, he desires a noble task.</verse>
<verse>Now the overseer must be above reproach, the husband of but one wife, temperate, self-controlled, respectable, hospitable, able to teach,</verse>
<verse>not given to drunkenness, not violent but gentle, not quarrelsome, not a lover of money.</verse>
<verse>He must manage his own family well and see that his children obey him with proper respect.</verse>
<verse>(If anyone does not know how to manage his own family, how can he take care of God's church?)</verse>
<verse>He must not be a recent convert, or he may become conceited and fall under the same judgment as the devil.</verse>
<verse>He must also have a good reputation with outsiders, so that he will not fall into disgrace and into the devil's trap.</verse>
<verse>Deacons, likewise, are to be men worthy of respect, sincere, not indulging in much wine, and not pursuing dishonest gain.</verse>
<verse>They must keep hold of the deep truths of the faith with a clear conscience.</verse>
<verse>They must first be tested; and then if there is nothing against them, let them serve as deacons.</verse>
<verse>In the same way, their wives are to be women worthy of respect, not malicious talkers but temperate and trustworthy in everything.</verse>
<verse>A deacon must be the husband of but one wife and must manage his children and his household well.</verse>
<verse>Those who have served well gain an excellent standing and great assurance in their faith in Christ Jesus.</verse>
<verse>Although I hope to come to you soon, I am writing you these instructions so that,</verse>
<verse>if I am delayed, you will know how people ought to conduct themselves in God's household, which is the church of the living God, the pillar and foundation of the truth.</verse>
<verse>Beyond all question, the mystery of godliness is great: He appeared in a body, was vindicated by the Spirit, was seen by angels, was preached among the nations, was believed on in the world, was taken up in glory.</verse>
</chapter>