<chapter translation="NIV" testament="New" book="1 Timothy" book_id="54" n="4">
<verse>The Spirit clearly says that in later times some will abandon the faith and follow deceiving spirits and things taught by demons.</verse>
<verse>Such teachings come through hypocritical liars, whose consciences have been seared as with a hot iron.</verse>
<verse>They forbid people to marry and order them to abstain from certain foods, which God created to be received with thanksgiving by those who believe and who know the truth.</verse>
<verse>For everything God created is good, and nothing is to be rejected if it is received with thanksgiving,</verse>
<verse>because it is consecrated by the word of God and prayer.</verse>
<verse>If you point these things out to the brothers, you will be a good minister of Christ Jesus, brought up in the truths of the faith and of the good teaching that you have followed.</verse>
<verse>Have nothing to do with godless myths and old wives' tales; rather, train yourself to be godly.</verse>
<verse>For physical training is of some value, but godliness has value for all things, holding promise for both the present life and the life to come.</verse>
<verse>This is a trustworthy saying that deserves full acceptance</verse>
<verse>(and for this we labor and strive), that we have put our hope in the living God, who is the Savior of all men, and especially of those who believe.</verse>
<verse>Command and teach these things.</verse>
<verse>Don't let anyone look down on you because you are young, but set an example for the believers in speech, in life, in love, in faith and in purity.</verse>
<verse>Until I come, devote yourself to the public reading of Scripture, to preaching and to teaching.</verse>
<verse>Do not neglect your gift, which was given you through a prophetic message when the body of elders laid their hands on you.</verse>
<verse>Be diligent in these matters; give yourself wholly to them, so that everyone may see your progress.</verse>
<verse>Watch your life and doctrine closely. Persevere in them, because if you do, you will save both yourself and your hearers.</verse>
</chapter>