<chapter translation="NIV" testament="New" book="Hebrews" book_id="58" n="3">
<verse>Therefore, holy brothers, who share in the heavenly calling, fix your thoughts on Jesus, the apostle and high priest whom we confess.</verse>
<verse>He was faithful to the one who appointed him, just as Moses was faithful in all God's house.</verse>
<verse>Jesus has been found worthy of greater honor than Moses, just as the builder of a house has greater honor than the house itself.</verse>
<verse>For every house is built by someone, but God is the builder of everything.</verse>
<verse>Moses was faithful as a servant in all God's house, testifying to what would be said in the future.</verse>
<verse>But Christ is faithful as a son over God's house. And we are his house, if we hold on to our courage and the hope of which we boast.</verse>
<verse>So, as the Holy Spirit says: "Today, if you hear his voice,</verse>
<verse>do not harden your hearts as you did in the rebellion, during the time of testing in the desert,</verse>
<verse>where your fathers tested and tried me and for forty years saw what I did.</verse>
<verse>That is why I was angry with that generation, and I said, 'Their hearts are always going astray, and they have not known my ways.'</verse>
<verse>So I declared on oath in my anger, 'They shall never enter my rest.'"</verse>
<verse>See to it, brothers, that none of you has a sinful, unbelieving heart that turns away from the living God.</verse>
<verse>But encourage one another daily, as long as it is called Today, so that none of you may be hardened by sin's deceitfulness.</verse>
<verse>We have come to share in Christ if we hold firmly till the end the confidence we had at first.</verse>
<verse>As has just been said: "Today, if you hear his voice, do not harden your hearts as you did in the rebellion."</verse>
<verse>Who were they who heard and rebelled? Were they not all those Moses led out of Egypt?</verse>
<verse>And with whom was he angry for forty years? Was it not with those who sinned, whose bodies fell in the desert?</verse>
<verse>And to whom did God swear that they would never enter his rest if not to those who disobeyed?</verse>
<verse>So we see that they were not able to enter, because of their unbelief.</verse>
</chapter>