<chapter translation="NIV" testament="New" book="Hebrews" book-id="58" n="4">
<verse>Therefore, since the promise of entering his rest still stands, let us be careful that none of you be found to have fallen short of it.</verse>
<verse>For we also have had the gospel preached to us, just as they did; but the message they heard was of no value to them, because those who heard did not combine it with faith.</verse>
<verse>Now we who have believed enter that rest, just as God has said, "So I declared on oath in my anger, 'They shall never enter my rest.'"</verse>
<verse>And yet his work has been finished since the creation of the world. For somewhere he has spoken about the seventh day in these words: "And on the seventh day God rested from all his work."</verse>
<verse>And again in the passage above he says, "They shall never enter my rest."</verse>
<verse>It still remains that some will enter that rest, and those who formerly had the gospel preached to them did not go in, because of their disobedience.</verse>
<verse>Therefore God again set a certain day, calling it Today, when a long time later he spoke through David, as was said before: "Today, if you hear his voice, do not harden your hearts."</verse>
<verse>For if Joshua had given them rest, God would not have spoken later about another day.</verse>
<verse>There remains, then, a Sabbath-rest for the people of God;</verse>
<verse>for anyone who enters God's rest also rests from his own work, just as God did from his.</verse>
<verse>Let us, therefore, make every effort to enter that rest, so that no one will fall by following their example of disobedience.</verse>
<verse>For the word of God is living and active. Sharper than any double--edged sword, it penetrates even to dividing soul and spirit, joints and marrow; it judges the thoughts and attitudes of the heart.</verse>
<verse>Nothing in all creation is hidden from God's sight. Everything is uncovered and laid bare before the eyes of him to whom we must give account.</verse>
<verse>Therefore, since we have a great high priest who has gone through the heavens, Jesus the Son of God, let us hold firmly to the faith we profess.</verse>
<verse>For we do not have a high priest who is unable to sympathize with our weaknesses, but we have one who has been tempted in every way, just as we are--yet was without sin.</verse>
<verse>Let us then approach the throne of grace with confidence, so that we may receive mercy and find grace to help us in our time of need.</verse>
</chapter>