<chapter translation="NASB" testament="New" book="2 Timothy" book-id="55" n="2">
<verse>You therefore, my son, be strong in the grace that is in Christ Jesus.</verse>
<verse>The things which you have heard from me in the presence of many witnesses, entrust these to faithful men who will be able to teach others also.</verse>
<verse>Suffer hardship with me, as a good soldier of Christ Jesus.</verse>
<verse>No soldier in active service entangles himself in the affairs of everyday life, so that he may please the one who enlisted him as a soldier.</verse>
<verse>Also if anyone competes as an athlete, he does not win the prize unless he competes according to the rules.</verse>
<verse>The hard-working farmer ought to be the first to receive his share of the crops.</verse>
<verse>Consider what I say, for the Lord will give you understanding in everything.</verse>
<verse>Remember Jesus Christ, risen from the dead, descendant of David, according to my gospel,</verse>
<verse>for which I suffer hardship even to imprisonment as a criminal; but the word of God is not imprisoned.</verse>
<verse>For this reason I endure all things for the sake of those who are chosen, so that they also may obtain the salvation which is in Christ Jesus and with it eternal glory.</verse>
<verse>It is a trustworthy statement: For if we died with Him, we will also live with Him;</verse>
<verse>If we endure, we will also reign with Him; If we deny Him, He also will deny us;</verse>
<verse>If we are faithless, He remains faithful, for He cannot deny Himself.</verse>
<verse>Remind them of these things, and solemnly charge them in the presence of God not to wrangle about words, which is useless and leads to the ruin of the hearers.</verse>
<verse>Be diligent to present yourself approved to God as a workman who does not need to be ashamed, accurately handling the word of truth.</verse>
<verse>But avoid worldly and empty chatter, for it will lead to further ungodliness,</verse>
<verse>and their talk will spread like gangrene. Among them are Hymenaeus and Philetus,</verse>
<verse>men who have gone astray from the truth saying that the resurrection has already taken place, and they upset the faith of some.</verse>
<verse>Nevertheless, the firm foundation of God stands, having this seal, "The Lord knows those who are His," and, "Everyone who names the name of the Lord is to abstain from wickedness."</verse>
<verse>Now in a large house there are not only gold and silver vessels, but also vessels of wood and of earthenware, and some to honor and some to dishonor.</verse>
<verse>Therefore, if anyone cleanses himself from these things, he will be a vessel for honor, sanctified, useful to the Master, prepared for every good work.</verse>
<verse>Now flee from youthful lusts and pursue righteousness, faith, love and peace, with those who call on the Lord from a pure heart.</verse>
<verse>But refuse foolish and ignorant speculations, knowing that they produce quarrels.</verse>
<verse>The Lord's bond-servant must not be quarrelsome, but be kind to all, able to teach, patient when wronged,</verse>
<verse>with gentleness correcting those who are in opposition, if perhaps God may grant them repentance leading to the knowledge of the truth,</verse>
<verse>and they may come to their senses and escape from the snare of the devil, having been held captive by him to do his will.</verse>
</chapter>