<chapter translation="NASB" testament="New" book="2 Timothy" book-id="55" n="3">
<verse>But realize this, that in the last days difficult times will come.</verse>
<verse>For men will be lovers of self, lovers of money, boastful, arrogant, revilers, disobedient to parents, ungrateful, unholy,</verse>
<verse>unloving, irreconcilable, malicious gossips, without self-control, brutal, haters of good,</verse>
<verse>treacherous, reckless, conceited, lovers of pleasure rather than lovers of God,</verse>
<verse>holding to a form of godliness, although they have denied its power; Avoid such men as these.</verse>
<verse>For among them are those who enter into households and captivate weak women weighed down with sins, led on by various impulses,</verse>
<verse>always learning and never able to come to the knowledge of the truth.</verse>
<verse>Just as Jannes and Jambres opposed Moses, so these men also oppose the truth, men of depraved mind, rejected in regard to the faith.</verse>
<verse>But they will not make further progress; for their folly will be obvious to all, just as Jannes's and Jambres's folly was also.</verse>
<verse>Now you followed my teaching, conduct, purpose, faith, patience, love, perseverance,</verse>
<verse>persecutions, and sufferings, such as happened to me at Antioch, at Iconium and at Lystra; what persecutions I endured, and out of them all the Lord rescued me!</verse>
<verse>Indeed, all who desire to live godly in Christ Jesus will be persecuted.</verse>
<verse>But evil men and impostors will proceed from bad to worse, deceiving and being deceived.</verse>
<verse>You, however, continue in the things you have learned and become convinced of, knowing from whom you have learned them,</verse>
<verse>and that from childhood you have known the sacred writings which are able to give you the wisdom that leads to salvation through faith which is in Christ Jesus.</verse>
<verse>All Scripture is inspired by God and profitable for teaching, for reproof, for correction, for training in righteousness;</verse>
<verse>so that the man of God may be adequate, equipped for every good work.</verse>
</chapter>