<chapter translation="NASB" testament="New" book="2 Timothy" book_id="55" n="4">
<verse>I solemnly charge you in the presence of God and of Christ Jesus, who is to judge the living and the dead, and by His appearing and His kingdom:</verse>
<verse>preach the word; be ready in season and out of season; reprove, rebuke, exhort, with great patience and instruction.</verse>
<verse>For the time will come when they will not endure sound doctrine; but wanting to have their ears tickled, they will accumulate for themselves teachers in accordance to their own desires,</verse>
<verse>and will turn away their ears from the truth and will turn aside to myths.</verse>
<verse>But you, be sober in all things, endure hardship, do the work of an evangelist, fulfill your ministry.</verse>
<verse>For I am already being poured out as a drink offering, and the time of my departure has come.</verse>
<verse>I have fought the good fight, I have finished the course, I have kept the faith;</verse>
<verse>in the future there is laid up for me the crown of righteousness, which the Lord, the righteous Judge, will award to me on that day; and not only to me, but also to all who have loved His appearing.</verse>
<verse>Make every effort to come to me soon;</verse>
<verse>for Demas, having loved this present world, has deserted me and gone to Thessalonica; Crescens has gone to Galatia, Titus to Dalmatia.</verse>
<verse>Only Luke is with me. Pick up Mark and bring him with you, for he is useful to me for service.</verse>
<verse>But Tychicus I have sent to Ephesus.</verse>
<verse>When you come bring the cloak which I left at Troas with Carpus, and the books, especially the parchments.</verse>
<verse>Alexander the coppersmith did me much harm; the Lord will repay him according to his deeds.</verse>
<verse>Be on guard against him yourself, for he vigorously opposed our teaching.</verse>
<verse>At my first defense no one supported me, but all deserted me; may it not be counted against them.</verse>
<verse>But the Lord stood with me and strengthened me, so that through me the proclamation might be fully accomplished, and that all the Gentiles might hear; and I was rescued out of the lion's mouth.</verse>
<verse>The Lord will rescue me from every evil deed, and will bring me safely to His heavenly kingdom; to Him be the glory forever and ever. Amen.</verse>
<verse>Greet Prisca and Aquila, and the household of Onesiphorus.</verse>
<verse>Erastus remained at Corinth, but Trophimus I left sick at Miletus.</verse>
<verse>Make every effort to come before winter. Eubulus greets you, also Pudens and Linus and Claudia and all the brethren.</verse>
<verse>The Lord be with your spirit. Grace be with you.</verse>
</chapter>