<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Exodus" book_id="2" n="1">
<verse>These are the names of the sons of Israel who went to Egypt with Jacob, each with his family:</verse>
<verse>Reuben, Simeon, Levi and Judah;</verse>
<verse>Issachar, Zebulun and Benjamin;</verse>
<verse>Dan and Naphtali; Gad and Asher.</verse>
<verse>The descendants of Jacob numbered seventy in all; Joseph was already in Egypt.</verse>
<verse>Now Joseph and all his brothers and all that generation died,</verse>
<verse>but the Israelites were fruitful and multiplied greatly and became exceedingly numerous, so that the land was filled with them.</verse>
<verse>Then a new king, who did not know about Joseph, came to power in Egypt.</verse>
<verse>"Look," he said to his people, "the Israelites have become much too numerous for us.</verse>
<verse>Come, we must deal shrewdly with them or they will become even more numerous and, if war breaks out, will join our enemies, fight against us and leave the country."</verse>
<verse>So they put slave masters over them to oppress them with forced labor, and they built Pithom and Rameses as store cities for Pharaoh.</verse>
<verse>But the more they were oppressed, the more they multiplied and spread; so the Egyptians came to dread the Israelites</verse>
<verse>and worked them ruthlessly.</verse>
<verse>They made their lives bitter with hard labor in brick and mortar and with all kinds of work in the fields; in all their hard labor the Egyptians used them ruthlessly.</verse>
<verse>The king of Egypt said to the Hebrew midwives, whose names were Shiphrah and Puah,</verse>
<verse>"When you help the Hebrew women in childbirth and observe them on the delivery stool, if it is a boy, kill him; but if it is a girl, let her live."</verse>
<verse>The midwives, however, feared God and did not do what the king of Egypt had told them to do; they let the boys live.</verse>
<verse>Then the king of Egypt summoned the midwives and asked them, "Why have you done this? Why have you let the boys live?"</verse>
<verse>The midwives answered Pharaoh, "Hebrew women are not like Egyptian women; they are vigorous and give birth before the midwives arrive."</verse>
<verse>So God was kind to the midwives and the people increased and became even more numerous.</verse>
<verse>And because the midwives feared God, he gave them families of their own.</verse>
<verse>Then Pharaoh gave this order to all his people: "Every boy that is born you must throw into the Nile, but let every girl live."</verse>
</chapter>