<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Exodus" book-id="2" n="26">
<verse>"Make the tabernacle with ten curtains of finely twisted linen and blue, purple and scarlet yarn, with cherubim worked into them by a skilled craftsman.</verse>
<verse>All the curtains are to be the same size-twenty-eight cubits long and four cubits wide.</verse>
<verse>Join five of the curtains together, and do the same with the other five.</verse>
<verse>Make loops of blue material along the edge of the end curtain in one set, and do the same with the end curtain in the other set.</verse>
<verse>Make fifty loops on one curtain and fifty loops on the end curtain of the other set, with the loops opposite each other.</verse>
<verse>Then make fifty gold clasps and use them to fasten the curtains together so that the tabernacle is a unit.</verse>
<verse>"Make curtains of goat hair for the tent over the tabernacle-eleven altogether.</verse>
<verse>All eleven curtains are to be the same size-thirty cubits long and four cubits wide.</verse>
<verse>Join five of the curtains together into one set and the other six into another set. Fold the sixth curtain double at the front of the tent.</verse>
<verse>Make fifty loops along the edge of the end curtain in one set and also along the edge of the end curtain in the other set.</verse>
<verse>Then make fifty bronze clasps and put them in the loops to fasten the tent together as a unit.</verse>
<verse>As for the additional length of the tent curtains, the half curtain that is left over is to hang down at the rear of the tabernacle.</verse>
<verse>The tent curtains will be a cubit longer on both sides; what is left will hang over the sides of the tabernacle so as to cover it.</verse>
<verse>Make for the tent a covering of ram skins dyed red, and over that a covering of hides of sea cows.</verse>
<verse>"Make upright frames of acacia wood for the tabernacle.</verse>
<verse>Each frame is to be ten cubits long and a cubit and a half wide,</verse>
<verse>with two projections set parallel to each other. Make all the frames of the tabernacle in this way.</verse>
<verse>Make twenty frames for the south side of the tabernacle</verse>
<verse>and make forty silver bases to go under them-two bases for each frame, one under each projection.</verse>
<verse>For the other side, the north side of the tabernacle, make twenty frames</verse>
<verse>and forty silver bases-two under each frame.</verse>
<verse>Make six frames for the far end, that is, the west end of the tabernacle,</verse>
<verse>and make two frames for the corners at the far end.</verse>
<verse>At these two corners they must be double from the bottom all the way to the top, and fitted into a single ring; both shall be like that.</verse>
<verse>So there will be eight frames and sixteen silver bases-two under each frame.</verse>
<verse>"Also make crossbars of acacia wood: five for the frames on one side of the tabernacle,</verse>
<verse>five for those on the other side, and five for the frames on the west, at the far end of the tabernacle.</verse>
<verse>The center crossbar is to extend from end to end at the middle of the frames.</verse>
<verse>Overlay the frames with gold and make gold rings to hold the crossbars. Also overlay the crossbars with gold.</verse>
<verse>"Set up the tabernacle according to the plan shown you on the mountain.</verse>
<verse>"Make a curtain of blue, purple and scarlet yarn and finely twisted linen, with cherubim worked into it by a skilled craftsman.</verse>
<verse>Hang it with gold hooks on four posts of acacia wood overlaid with gold and standing on four silver bases.</verse>
<verse>Hang the curtain from the clasps and place the ark of the Testimony behind the curtain. The curtain will separate the Holy Place from the Most Holy Place.</verse>
<verse>Put the atonement cover on the ark of the Testimony in the Most Holy Place.</verse>
<verse>Place the table outside the curtain on the north side of the tabernacle and put the lampstand opposite it on the south side.</verse>
<verse>"For the entrance to the tent make a curtain of blue, purple and scarlet yarn and finely twisted linen-the work of an embroiderer.</verse>
<verse>Make gold hooks for this curtain and five posts of acacia wood overlaid with gold. And cast five bronze bases for them.</verse>
</chapter>