<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Exodus" book_id="2" n="31">
<verse>Then the LORD said to Moses,</verse>
<verse>"See, I have chosen Bezalel son of Uri, the son of Hur, of the tribe of Judah,</verse>
<verse>and I have filled him with the Spirit of God, with skill, ability and knowledge in all kinds of crafts-</verse>
<verse>to make artistic designs for work in gold, silver and bronze,</verse>
<verse>to cut and set stones, to work in wood, and to engage in all kinds of craftsmanship.</verse>
<verse>Moreover, I have appointed Oholiab son of Ahisamach, of the tribe of Dan, to help him. Also I have given skill to all the craftsmen to make everything I have commanded you:</verse>
<verse>the Tent of Meeting, the ark of the Testimony with the atonement cover on it, and all the other furnishings of the tent-</verse>
<verse>the table and its articles, the pure gold lampstand and all its accessories, the altar of incense,</verse>
<verse>the altar of burnt offering and all its utensils, the basin with its stand-</verse>
<verse>and also the woven garments, both the sacred garments for Aaron the priest and the garments for his sons when they serve as priests,</verse>
<verse>and the anointing oil and fragrant incense for the Holy Place. They are to make them just as I commanded you."</verse>
<verse>Then the LORD said to Moses,</verse>
<verse>"Say to the Israelites, 'You must observe my Sabbaths. This will be a sign between me and you for the generations to come, so you may know that I am the LORD, who makes you holy.</verse>
<verse>"'Observe the Sabbath, because it is holy to you. Anyone who desecrates it must be put to death; whoever does any work on that day must be cut off from his people.</verse>
<verse>For six days, work is to be done, but the seventh day is a Sabbath of rest, holy to the LORD. Whoever does any work on the Sabbath day must be put to death.</verse>
<verse>The Israelites are to observe the Sabbath, celebrating it for the generations to come as a lasting covenant.</verse>
<verse>It will be a sign between me and the Israelites forever, for in six days the LORD made the heavens and the earth, and on the seventh day he abstained from work and rested.'"</verse>
<verse>When the LORD finished speaking to Moses on Mount Sinai, he gave him the two tablets of the Testimony, the tablets of stone inscribed by the finger of God.</verse>
</chapter>