<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Exodus" book-id="2" n="37">
<verse>Bezalel made the ark of acacia wood-two and a half cubits long, a cubit and a half wide, and a cubit and a half high.</verse>
<verse>He overlaid it with pure gold, both inside and out, and made a gold molding around it.</verse>
<verse>He cast four gold rings for it and fastened them to its four feet, with two rings on one side and two rings on the other.</verse>
<verse>Then he made poles of acacia wood and overlaid them with gold.</verse>
<verse>And he inserted the poles into the rings on the sides of the ark to carry it.</verse>
<verse>He made the atonement cover of pure gold-two and a half cubits long and a cubit and a half wide.</verse>
<verse>Then he made two cherubim out of hammered gold at the ends of the cover.</verse>
<verse>He made one cherub on one end and the second cherub on the other; at the two ends he made them of one piece with the cover.</verse>
<verse>The cherubim had their wings spread upward, overshadowing the cover with them. The cherubim faced each other, looking toward the cover.</verse>
<verse>They made the table of acacia wood-two cubits long, a cubit wide, and a cubit and a half high.</verse>
<verse>Then they overlaid it with pure gold and made a gold molding around it.</verse>
<verse>They also made around it a rim a handbreadth wide and put a gold molding on the rim.</verse>
<verse>They cast four gold rings for the table and fastened them to the four corners, where the four legs were.</verse>
<verse>The rings were put close to the rim to hold the poles used in carrying the table.</verse>
<verse>The poles for carrying the table were made of acacia wood and were overlaid with gold.</verse>
<verse>And they made from pure gold the articles for the table-its plates and dishes and bowls and its pitchers for the pouring out of drink offerings.</verse>
<verse>They made the lampstand of pure gold and hammered it out, base and shaft; its flowerlike cups, buds and blossoms were of one piece with it.</verse>
<verse>Six branches extended from the sides of the lampstand-three on one side and three on the other.</verse>
<verse>Three cups shaped like almond flowers with buds and blossoms were on one branch, three on the next branch and the same for all six branches extending from the lampstand.</verse>
<verse>And on the lampstand were four cups shaped like almond flowers with buds and blossoms.</verse>
<verse>One bud was under the first pair of branches extending from the lampstand, a second bud under the second pair, and a third bud under the third pair-six branches in all.</verse>
<verse>The buds and the branches were all of one piece with the lampstand, hammered out of pure gold.</verse>
<verse>They made its seven lamps, as well as its wick trimmers and trays, of pure gold.</verse>
<verse>They made the lampstand and all its accessories from one talent of pure gold.</verse>
<verse>They made the altar of incense out of acacia wood. It was square, a cubit long and a cubit wide, and two cubits high -its horns of one piece with it.</verse>
<verse>They overlaid the top and all the sides and the horns with pure gold, and made a gold molding around it.</verse>
<verse>They made two gold rings below the molding-two on opposite sides-to hold the poles used to carry it.</verse>
<verse>They made the poles of acacia wood and overlaid them with gold.</verse>
<verse>They also made the sacred anointing oil and the pure, fragrant incense-the work of a perfumer.</verse>
</chapter>