<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Exodus" book-id="2" n="6">
<verse>Then the LORD said to Moses, "Now you will see what I will do to Pharaoh: Because of my mighty hand he will let them go; because of my mighty hand he will drive them out of his country."</verse>
<verse>God also said to Moses, "I am the LORD.</verse>
<verse>I appeared to Abraham, to Isaac and to Jacob as God Almighty, but by my name the LORD I did not make myself known to them.</verse>
<verse>I also established my covenant with them to give them the land of Canaan, where they lived as aliens.</verse>
<verse>Moreover, I have heard the groaning of the Israelites, whom the Egyptians are enslaving, and I have remembered my covenant.</verse>
<verse>"Therefore, say to the Israelites: 'I am the LORD, and I will bring you out from under the yoke of the Egyptians. I will free you from being slaves to them, and I will redeem you with an outstretched arm and with mighty acts of judgment.</verse>
<verse>I will take you as my own people, and I will be your God. Then you will know that I am the LORD your God, who brought you out from under the yoke of the Egyptians.</verse>
<verse>And I will bring you to the land I swore with uplifted hand to give to Abraham, to Isaac and to Jacob. I will give it to you as a possession. I am the LORD.'"</verse>
<verse>Moses reported this to the Israelites, but they did not listen to him because of their discouragement and cruel bondage.</verse>
<verse>Then the LORD said to Moses,</verse>
<verse>"Go, tell Pharaoh king of Egypt to let the Israelites go out of his country."</verse>
<verse>But Moses said to the LORD, "If the Israelites will not listen to me, why would Pharaoh listen to me, since I speak with faltering lips?"</verse>
<verse>Now the LORD spoke to Moses and Aaron about the Israelites and Pharaoh king of Egypt, and he commanded them to bring the Israelites out of Egypt.</verse>
<verse>These were the heads of their families: The sons of Reuben the firstborn son of Israel were Hanoch and Pallu, Hezron and Carmi. These were the clans of Reuben.</verse>
<verse>The sons of Simeon were Jemuel, Jamin, Ohad, Jakin, Zohar and Shaul the son of a Canaanite woman. These were the clans of Simeon.</verse>
<verse>These were the names of the sons of Levi according to their records: Gershon, Kohath and Merari. Levi lived 137 years.</verse>
<verse>The sons of Gershon, by clans, were Libni and Shimei.</verse>
<verse>The sons of Kohath were Amram, Izhar, Hebron and Uzziel. Kohath lived 133 years.</verse>
<verse>The sons of Merari were Mahli and Mushi. These were the clans of Levi according to their records.</verse>
<verse>Amram married his father's sister Jochebed, who bore him Aaron and Moses. Amram lived 137 years.</verse>
<verse>The sons of Izhar were Korah, Nepheg and Zicri.</verse>
<verse>The sons of Uzziel were Mishael, Elzaphan and Sithri.</verse>
<verse>Aaron married Elisheba, daughter of Amminadab and sister of Nahshon, and she bore him Nadab and Abihu, Eleazar and Ithamar.</verse>
<verse>The sons of Korah were Assir, Elkanah and Abiasaph. These were the Korahite clans.</verse>
<verse>Eleazar son of Aaron married one of the daughters of Putiel, and she bore him Phinehas. These were the heads of the Levite families, clan by clan.</verse>
<verse>It was this same Aaron and Moses to whom the LORD said, "Bring the Israelites out of Egypt by their divisions."</verse>
<verse>They were the ones who spoke to Pharaoh king of Egypt about bringing the Israelites out of Egypt. It was the same Moses and Aaron.</verse>
<verse>Now when the LORD spoke to Moses in Egypt,</verse>
<verse>he said to him, "I am the LORD. Tell Pharaoh king of Egypt everything I tell you."</verse>
<verse>But Moses said to the LORD, "Since I speak with faltering lips, why would Pharaoh listen to me?"</verse>
</chapter>