<chapter translation="MSG" testament="New" book="Revelation" book_id="66" n="16">
<verse>I heard a shout of command from the Temple to the Seven Angels: "Begin! Pour out the seven bowls of God's wrath on earth!"</verse>
<verse>The first Angel stepped up and poured his bowl out on earth: Loathsome, stinking sores erupted on all who had taken the mark of the Beast and worshiped its image.</verse>
<verse>The second Angel poured his bowl on the sea: The sea coagulated into blood, and everything in it died.</verse>
<verse>The third Angel poured his bowl on rivers and springs: The waters turned to blood.</verse>
<verse>I heard the Angel of Waters say, Righteous you are, and your judgments are righteous, THE IS, THE WAS, THE HOLY.</verse>
<verse>They poured out the blood of saints and prophets so you've given them blood to drink--they've gotten what they deserve!</verse>
<verse>Just then I heard the Altar chime in, Yes, O God, the Sovereign-Strong! Your judgments are true and just!</verse>
<verse>The fourth Angel poured his bowl on the sun: Fire blazed from the sun and scorched men and women.</verse>
<verse>Burned and blistered, they cursed God's Name, the God behind these disasters. They refused to repent, refused to honor God.</verse>
<verse>The fifth Angel poured his bowl on the throne of the Beast: Its kingdom fell into sudden eclipse. Mad with pain, men and women bit and chewed their tongues,</verse>
<verse>cursed the God of Heaven for their torment and sores, and refused to repent and change their ways.</verse>
<verse>The sixth Angel poured his bowl on the great Euphrates River: It dried up to nothing. The dry riverbed became a fine roadbed for the kings from the East.</verse>
<verse>From the mouths of the Dragon, the Beast, and the False Prophet I saw three foul demons crawl out--they looked like frogs.</verse>
<verse>These are demon spirits performing signs. They're after the kings of the whole world to get them gathered for battle on the Great Day of God, the Sovereign-Strong.</verse>
<verse>"Keep watch! I come unannounced, like a thief. You're blessed if, awake and dressed, you're ready for me. Too bad if you're found running through the streets, naked and ashamed."</verse>
<verse>The frog-demons gathered the kings together at the place called in Hebrew Armageddon.</verse>
<verse>The seventh Angel poured his bowl into the air: From the Throne in the Temple came a shout, "Done!"</verse>
<verse>followed by lightning flashes and shouts, thunder crashes and a colossal earthquake--a huge and devastating earthquake, never an earthquake like it since time began.</verse>
<verse>The Great City split three ways, the cities of the nations toppled to ruin. Great Babylon had to drink the wine of God's raging anger--God remembered to give her the cup!</verse>
<verse>Every island fled and not a mountain was to be found.</verse>
<verse>Hailstones weighing a ton plummeted, crushing and smashing men and women as they cursed God for the hail, the epic disaster of hail.</verse>
</chapter>