<chapter translation="MSG" testament="New" book="Revelation" book-id="66" n="19">
<verse>I heard a sound like massed choirs in Heaven singing, Hallelujah! The salvation and glory and power are God's--</verse>
<verse>his judgments true, his judgments just. He judged the great Whore who corrupted the earth with her lust. He avenged on her the blood of his servants.</verse>
<verse>Then, more singing: Hallelujah! The smoke from her burning billows up to high Heaven forever and ever and ever.</verse>
<verse>The Twenty-four Elders and the Four Animals fell to their knees and worshiped God on his Throne, praising, Amen! Yes! Hallelujah!</verse>
<verse>From the Throne came a shout, a command: Praise our God, all you his servants, All you who fear him, small and great!</verse>
<verse>Then I heard the sound of massed choirs, the sound of a mighty cataract, the sound of strong thunder: Hallelujah! The Master reigns, our God, the Sovereign-Strong!</verse>
<verse>Let us celebrate, let us rejoice, let us give him the glory! The Marriage of the Lamb has come; his Wife has made herself ready.</verse>
<verse>She was given a bridal gown of bright and shining linen. The linen is the righteousness of the saints.</verse>
<verse>The Angel said to me, "Write this: "Blessed are those invited to the Wedding Supper of the Lamb.'" He added, "These are the true words of God!"</verse>
<verse>I fell at his feet to worship him, but he wouldn't let me. "Don't do that," he said. "I'm a servant just like you, and like your brothers and sisters who hold to the witness of Jesus. The witness of Jesus is the spirit of prophecy."</verse>
<verse>Then I saw Heaven open wide--and oh! a white horse and its Rider. The Rider, named Faithful and True, judges and makes war in pure righteousness.</verse>
<verse>His eyes are a blaze of fire, on his head many crowns. He has a Name inscribed that's known only to himself.</verse>
<verse>He is dressed in a robe soaked with blood, and he is addressed as "Word of God."</verse>
<verse>The armies of Heaven, mounted on white horses and dressed in dazzling white linen, follow him.</verse>
<verse>A sharp sword comes out of his mouth so he can subdue the nations, then rule them with a rod of iron. He treads the winepress of the raging wrath of God, the Sovereign-Strong.</verse>
<verse>On his robe and thigh is written, KING OF KINGS, LORD OF LORDS.</verse>
<verse>I saw an Angel standing in the sun, shouting to all flying birds in Middle-Heaven, "Come to the Great Supper of God!</verse>
<verse>Feast on the flesh of kings and captains and champions, horses and their riders. Eat your fill of them all--free and slave, small and great!"</verse>
<verse>I saw the Beast and, assembled with him, earth's kings and their armies, ready to make war against the One on the horse and his army.</verse>
<verse>The Beast was taken, and with him, his puppet, the False Prophet, who used signs to dazzle and deceive those who had taken the mark of the Beast and worshiped his image. They were thrown alive, those two, into Lake Fire and Brimstone.</verse>
<verse>The rest were killed by the sword of the One on the horse, the sword that comes from his mouth. All the birds held a feast on their flesh.</verse>
</chapter>