<chapter translation="MSG" testament="New" book="Revelation" book-id="66" n="22">
<verse>Then the Angel showed me Water-of-Life River, crystal bright. It flowed from the Throne of God and the Lamb,</verse>
<verse>right down the middle of the street. The Tree of Life was planted on each side of the River, producing twelve kinds of fruit, a ripe fruit each month. The leaves of the Tree are for healing the nations.</verse>
<verse>Never again will anything be cursed. The Throne of God and of the Lamb is at the center. His servants will offer God service--worshiping,</verse>
<verse>they'll look on his face, their foreheads mirroring God.</verse>
<verse>Never again will there be any night. No one will need lamplight or sunlight. The shining of God, the Master, is all the light anyone needs. And they will rule with him age after age after age.</verse>
<verse>The Angel said to me, "These are dependable and accurate words, every one. The God and Master of the spirits of the prophets sent his Angel to show his servants what must take place, and soon.</verse>
<verse>And tell them, "Yes, I'm on my way!' Blessed be the one who keeps the words of the prophecy of this book."</verse>
<verse>I, John, saw all these things with my own eyes, heard them with my ears. Immediately when I heard and saw, I fell on my face to worship at the feet of the Angel who laid it all out before me.</verse>
<verse>He objected, "No you don't! I'm a servant just like you and your companions, the prophets, and all who keep the words of this book. Worship God!"</verse>
<verse>The Angel continued, "Don't seal the words of the prophecy of this book; don't put it away on the shelf. Time is just about up.</verse>
<verse>Let evildoers do their worst and the dirty-minded go all out in pollution, but let the righteous maintain a straight course and the holy continue on in holiness." [JC]</verse>
<verse>"Yes, I'm on my way! I'll be there soon! I'm bringing my payroll with me. I'll pay all people in full for their life's work.</verse>
<verse>I'm A to Z, the First and the Final, Beginning and Conclusion.</verse>
<verse>"How blessed are those who wash their robes! The Tree of Life is theirs for good, and they'll walk through the gates to the City.</verse>
<verse>But outside for good are the filthy curs: sorcerers, fornicators, murderers, idolaters--all who love and live lies.</verse>
<verse>"I, Jesus, sent my Angel to testify to these things for the churches. I'm the Root and Branch of David, the Bright Morning Star."</verse>
<verse>"Come!" say the Spirit and the Bride. Whoever hears, echo, "Come!" Is anyone thirsty? Come! All who will, come and drink, Drink freely of the Water of Life!</verse>
<verse>I give fair warning to all who hear the words of the prophecy of this book: If you add to the words of this prophecy, God will add to your life the disasters written in this book;</verse>
<verse>if you subtract from the words of the book of this prophecy, God will subtract your part from the Tree of Life and the Holy City that are written in this book.</verse>
<verse>He who testifies to all these things says it again: "I'm on my way! I'll be there soon!" Yes! Come, Master Jesus!</verse>
<verse>The grace of the Master Jesus be with all of you. Oh, Yes!</verse>
</chapter>