<chapter translation="MSG" testament="New" book="Revelation" book-id="66" n="5">
<verse>I saw a scroll in the right hand of the One Seated on the Throne. It was written on both sides, fastened with seven seals.</verse>
<verse>I also saw a powerful Angel, calling out in a voice like thunder, "Is there anyone who can open the scroll, who can break its seals?"</verse>
<verse>There was no one--no one in Heaven, no one on earth, no one from the underworld--able to break open the scroll and read it.</verse>
<verse>I wept and wept and wept that no one was found able to open the scroll, able to read it.</verse>
<verse>One of the Elders said, "Don't weep. Look--the Lion from Tribe Judah, the Root of David's Tree, has conquered. He can open the scroll, can rip through the seven seals."</verse>
<verse>So I looked, and there, surrounded by Throne, Animals, and Elders, was a Lamb, slaughtered but standing tall. Seven horns he had, and seven eyes, the Seven Spirits of God sent into all the earth.</verse>
<verse>He came to the One Seated on the Throne and took the scroll from his right hand.</verse>
<verse>The moment he took the scroll, the Four Animals and Twenty-four Elders fell down and worshiped the Lamb. Each had a harp and each had a bowl, a gold bowl filled with incense, the prayers of God's holy people.</verse>
<verse>And they sang a new song: Worthy! Take the scroll, open its seals. Slain! Paying in blood, you bought men and women, Bought them back from all over the earth, Bought them back for God.</verse>
<verse>Then you made them a Kingdom, Priests for our God, Priest-kings to rule over the earth.</verse>
<verse>I looked again. I heard a company of Angels around the Throne, the Animals, and the Elders--ten thousand times ten thousand their number, thousand after thousand after thousand</verse>
<verse>in full song: The slain Lamb is worthy! Take the power, the wealth, the wisdom, the strength! Take the honor, the glory, the blessing!</verse>
<verse>Then I heard every creature in Heaven and earth, in underworld and sea, join in, all voices in all places, singing: To the One on the Throne! To the Lamb! The blessing, the honor, the glory, the strength, For age after age after age.</verse>
<verse>The Four Animals called out, "Oh, Yes! "The Elders fell to their knees and worshiped.</verse>
</chapter>