<chapter translation="MSG" testament="New" book="Revelation" book_id="66" n="8">
<verse>When the Lamb ripped off the seventh seal, Heaven fell quiet--complete silence for about half an hour.</verse>
<verse>I saw the Seven Angels who are always in readiness before God handed seven trumpets.</verse>
<verse>Then another Angel, carrying a gold censer, came and stood at the Altar. He was given a great quantity of incense so that he could offer up the prayers of all the holy people of God on the Golden Altar before the Throne.</verse>
<verse>Smoke billowed up from the incense-laced prayers of the holy ones, rose before God from the hand of the Angel.</verse>
<verse>Then the Angel filled the censer with fire from the Altar and heaved it to earth. It set off thunders, voices, lightnings, and an earthquake.</verse>
<verse>The Seven Angels with the trumpets got ready to blow them.</verse>
<verse>At the first trumpet blast, hail and fire mixed with blood were dumped on earth. A third of the earth was scorched, a third of the trees, and every blade of green grass--burned to a crisp.</verse>
<verse>The second Angel trumpeted. Something like a huge mountain blazing with fire was flung into the sea. A third of the sea turned to blood,</verse>
<verse>a third of the living sea creatures died, and a third of the ships sank.</verse>
<verse>The third Angel trumpeted. A huge Star, blazing like a torch, fell from Heaven, wiping out a third of the rivers and a third of the springs.</verse>
<verse>The Star's name was Wormwood. A third of the water turned bitter, and many people died from the poisoned water.</verse>
<verse>The fourth Angel trumpeted. A third of the sun, a third of the moon, and a third of the stars were hit, blacked out by a third, both day and night in one-third blackout.</verse>
<verse>I looked hard; I heard a lone eagle, flying through Middle-Heaven, crying out ominously, "Doom! Doom! Doom to everyone left on earth! There are three more Angels about to blow their trumpets. Doom is on its way!" [JC]</verse>
</chapter>