<chapter translation="ESV" testament="New" book="2 Timothy" book-id="55" n="3">
<verse>But understand this, that in the last days there will come times of difficulty.</verse>
<verse>For people will be lovers of self, lovers of money, proud, arrogant, abusive, disobedient to their parents, ungrateful, unholy,</verse>
<verse>heartless, unappeasable, slanderous, without self-control, brutal, not loving good,</verse>
<verse>treacherous, reckless, swollen with conceit, lovers of pleasure rather than lovers of God,</verse>
<verse>having the appearance of godliness, but denying its power. Avoid such people.</verse>
<verse>For among them are those who creep into households and capture weak women, burdened with sins and led astray by various passions,</verse>
<verse>always learning and never able to arrive at a knowledge of the truth.</verse>
<verse>Just as Jannes and Jambres opposed Moses, so these men also oppose the truth, men corrupted in mind and disqualified regarding the faith.</verse>
<verse>But they will not get very far, for their folly will be plain to all, as was that of those two men.</verse>
<verse>You, however, have followed my teaching, my conduct, my aim in life, my faith, my patience, my love, my steadfastness,</verse>
<verse>my persecutions and sufferings that happened to me at Antioch, at Iconium, and at Lystra--which persecutions I endured; yet from them all the Lord rescued me.</verse>
<verse>Indeed, all who desire to live a godly life in Christ Jesus will be persecuted,</verse>
<verse>while evil people and impostors will go on from bad to worse, deceiving and being deceived.</verse>
<verse>But as for you, continue in what you have learned and have firmly believed, knowing from whom you learned it</verse>
<verse>and how from childhood you have been acquainted with the sacred writings, which are able to make you wise for salvation through faith in Christ Jesus.</verse>
<verse>All Scripture is breathed out by God and profitable for teaching, for reproof, for correction, and for training in righteousness,</verse>
<verse>that the man of God may be competent, equipped for every good work.</verse>
</chapter>