<chapter translation="NASB" testament="New" book="2 Thessalonians" book_id="53" n="2">
<verse>Now we request you, brethren, with regard to the coming of our Lord Jesus Christ and our gathering together to Him,</verse>
<verse>that you not be quickly shaken from your composure or be disturbed either by a spirit or a message or a letter as if from us, to the effect that the day of the Lord has come.</verse>
<verse>Let no one in any way deceive you, for it will not come unless the apostasy comes first, and the man of lawlessness is revealed, the son of destruction,</verse>
<verse>who opposes and exalts himself above every so-called god or object of worship, so that he takes his seat in the temple of God, displaying himself as being God.</verse>
<verse>Do you not remember that while I was still with you, I was telling you these things?</verse>
<verse>And you know what restrains him now, so that in his time he will be revealed.</verse>
<verse>For the mystery of lawlessness is already at work; only he who now restrains will do so until he is taken out of the way.</verse>
<verse>Then that lawless one will be revealed whom the Lord will slay with the breath of His mouth and bring to an end by the appearance of His coming;</verse>
<verse>that is, the one whose coming is in accord with the activity of Satan, with all power and signs and false wonders,</verse>
<verse>and with all the deception of wickedness for those who perish, because they did not receive the love of the truth so as to be saved.</verse>
<verse>For this reason God will send upon them a deluding influence so that they will believe what is false,</verse>
<verse>in order that they all may be judged who did not believe the truth, but took pleasure in wickedness.</verse>
<verse>But we should always give thanks to God for you, brethren beloved by the Lord, because God has chosen you from the beginning for salvation through sanctification by the Spirit and faith in the truth.</verse>
<verse>It was for this He called you through our gospel, that you may gain the glory of our Lord Jesus Christ.</verse>
<verse>So then, brethren, stand firm and hold to the traditions which you were taught, whether by word of mouth or by letter from us.</verse>
<verse>Now may our Lord Jesus Christ Himself and God our Father, who has loved us and given us eternal comfort and good hope by grace,</verse>
<verse>comfort and strengthen your hearts in every good work and word.</verse>
</chapter>