<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Isaiah" book_id="23" n="11">
<verse>Then a shoot will spring from the stem of Jesse, And a branch from his roots will bear fruit.</verse>
<verse>The Spirit of the LORD will rest on Him, The spirit of wisdom and understanding, The spirit of counsel and strength, The spirit of knowledge and the fear of the LORD.</verse>
<verse>And He will delight in the fear of the LORD, And He will not judge by what His eyes see, Nor make a decision by what His ears hear;</verse>
<verse>But with righteousness He will judge the poor, And decide with fairness for the afflicted of the earth; And He will strike the earth with the rod of His mouth, And with the breath of His lips He will slay the wicked.</verse>
<verse>Also righteousness will be the belt about His loins, And faithfulness the belt about His waist.</verse>
<verse>And the wolf will dwell with the lamb, And the leopard will lie down with the young goat, And the calf and the young lion and the fatling together; And a little boy will lead them.</verse>
<verse>Also the cow and the bear will graze, Their young will lie down together, And the lion will eat straw like the ox.</verse>
<verse>The nursing child will play by the hole of the cobra, And the weaned child will put his hand on the viper's den.</verse>
<verse>They will not hurt or destroy in all My holy mountain, For the earth will be full of the knowledge of the LORD As the waters cover the sea.</verse>
<verse>Then in that day The nations will resort to the root of Jesse, Who will stand as a signal for the peoples; And His resting place will be glorious.</verse>
<verse>Then it will happen on that day that the Lord Will again recover the second time with His hand The remnant of His people, who will remain, From Assyria, Egypt, Pathros, Cush, Elam, Shinar, Hamath, And from the islands of the sea.</verse>
<verse>And He will lift up a standard for the nations And assemble the banished ones of Israel, And will gather the dispersed of Judah From the four corners of the earth.</verse>
<verse>Then the jealousy of Ephraim will depart, And those who harass Judah will be cut off; Ephraim will not be jealous of Judah, And Judah will not harass Ephraim.</verse>
<verse>They will swoop down on the slopes of the Philistines on the west; Together they will plunder the sons of the east; They will possess Edom and Moab, And the sons of Ammon will be subject to them.</verse>
<verse>And the LORD will utterly destroy The tongue of the Sea of Egypt; And He will wave His hand over the River With His scorching wind; And He will strike it into seven streams And make men walk over dry-shod.</verse>
<verse>And there will be a highway from Assyria For the remnant of His people who will be left, Just as there was for Israel In the day that they came up out of the land of Egypt.</verse>
</chapter>