<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Isaiah" book-id="23" n="13">
<verse>The oracle concerning Babylon which Isaiah the son of Amoz saw.</verse>
<verse>Lift up a standard on the bare hill, Raise your voice to them, Wave the hand that they may enter the doors of the nobles.</verse>
<verse>I have commanded My consecrated ones, I have even called My mighty warriors, My proudly exulting ones, To execute My anger.</verse>
<verse>A sound of tumult on the mountains, Like that of many people! A sound of the uproar of kingdoms, Of nations gathered together! The LORD of hosts is mustering the army for battle.</verse>
<verse>They are coming from a far country, From the farthest horizons, The LORD and His instruments of indignation, To destroy the whole land.</verse>
<verse>Wail, for the day of the LORD is near! It will come as destruction from the Almighty.</verse>
<verse>Therefore all hands will fall limp, And every man's heart will melt.</verse>
<verse>They will be terrified, Pains and anguish will take hold of them; They will writhe like a woman in labor, They will look at one another in astonishment, Their faces aflame.</verse>
<verse>Behold, the day of the LORD is coming, Cruel, with fury and burning anger, To make the land a desolation; And He will exterminate its sinners from it.</verse>
<verse>For the stars of heaven and their constellations Will not flash forth their light; The sun will be dark when it rises And the moon will not shed its light.</verse>
<verse>Thus I will punish the world for its evil And the wicked for their iniquity; I will also put an end to the arrogance of the proud And abase the haughtiness of the ruthless.</verse>
<verse>I will make mortal man scarcer than pure gold And mankind than the gold of Ophir.</verse>
<verse>Therefore I will make the heavens tremble, And the earth will be shaken from its place At the fury of the LORD of hosts In the day of His burning anger.</verse>
<verse>And it will be that like a hunted gazelle, Or like sheep with none to gather them, They will each turn to his own people, And each one flee to his own land.</verse>
<verse>Anyone who is found will be thrust through, And anyone who is captured will fall by the sword.</verse>
<verse>Their little ones also will be dashed to pieces Before their eyes; Their houses will be plundered And their wives ravished.</verse>
<verse>Behold, I am going to stir up the Medes against them, Who will not value silver or take pleasure in gold.</verse>
<verse>And their bows will mow down the young men, They will not even have compassion on the fruit of the womb, Nor will their eye pity children.</verse>
<verse>And Babylon, the beauty of kingdoms, the glory of the Chaldeans' pride, Will be as when God overthrew Sodom and Gomorrah.</verse>
<verse>It will never be inhabited or lived in from generation to generation; Nor will the Arab pitch his tent there, Nor will shepherds make their flocks lie down there.</verse>
<verse>But desert creatures will lie down there, And their houses will be full of owls; Ostriches also will live there, and shaggy goats will frolic there.</verse>
<verse>Hyenas will howl in their fortified towers And jackals in their luxurious palaces. Her fateful time also will soon come And her days will not be prolonged.</verse>
</chapter>