<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Isaiah" book_id="23" n="32">
<verse>Behold, a king will reign righteously And princes will rule justly.</verse>
<verse>Each will be like a refuge from the wind And a shelter from the storm, Like streams of water in a dry country, Like the shade of a huge rock in a parched land.</verse>
<verse>Then the eyes of those who see will not be blinded, And the ears of those who hear will listen.</verse>
<verse>The mind of the hasty will discern the truth, And the tongue of the stammerers will hasten to speak clearly.</verse>
<verse>No longer will the fool be called noble, Or the rogue be spoken of as generous.</verse>
<verse>For a fool speaks nonsense, And his heart inclines toward wickedness: To practice ungodliness and to speak error against the LORD, To keep the hungry person unsatisfied And to withhold drink from the thirsty.</verse>
<verse>As for a rogue, his weapons are evil; He devises wicked schemes To destroy the afflicted with slander, Even though the needy one speaks what is right.</verse>
<verse>But the noble man devises noble plans; And by noble plans he stands.</verse>
<verse>Rise up, you women who are at ease, And hear my voice; Give ear to my word, You complacent daughters.</verse>
<verse>Within a year and a few days You will be troubled, O complacent daughters; For the vintage is ended, And the fruit gathering will not come.</verse>
<verse>Tremble, you women who are at ease; Be troubled, you complacent daughters; Strip, undress and put sackcloth on your waist,</verse>
<verse>Beat your breasts for the pleasant fields, for the fruitful vine,</verse>
<verse>For the land of my people in which thorns and briars shall come up; Yea, for all the joyful houses and for the jubilant city.</verse>
<verse>Because the palace has been abandoned, the populated city forsaken. Hill and watch-tower have become caves forever, A delight for wild donkeys, a pasture for flocks;</verse>
<verse>Until the Spirit is poured out upon us from on high, And the wilderness becomes a fertile field, And the fertile field is considered as a forest.</verse>
<verse>Then justice will dwell in the wilderness And righteousness will abide in the fertile field.</verse>
<verse>And the work of righteousness will be peace, And the service of righteousness, quietness and confidence forever.</verse>
<verse>Then my people will live in a peaceful habitation, And in secure dwellings and in undisturbed resting places;</verse>
<verse>And it will hail when the forest comes down, And the city will be utterly laid low.</verse>
<verse>How blessed will you be, you who sow beside all waters, Who let out freely the ox and the donkey.</verse>
</chapter>