<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Isaiah" book-id="23" n="33">
<verse>Woe to you, O destroyer, While you were not destroyed; And he who is treacherous, while others did not deal treacherously with him. As soon as you finish destroying, you will be destroyed; As soon as you cease to deal treacherously, others will deal treacherously with you.</verse>
<verse>O LORD, be gracious to us; we have waited for You. Be their strength every morning, Our salvation also in the time of distress.</verse>
<verse>At the sound of the tumult peoples flee; At the lifting up of Yourself nations disperse.</verse>
<verse>Your spoil is gathered as the caterpillar gathers; As locusts rushing about men rush about on it.</verse>
<verse>The LORD is exalted, for He dwells on high; He has filled Zion with justice and righteousness.</verse>
<verse>And He will be the stability of your times, A wealth of salvation, wisdom and knowledge; The fear of the LORD is his treasure.</verse>
<verse>Behold, their brave men cry in the streets, The ambassadors of peace weep bitterly.</verse>
<verse>The highways are desolate, the traveler has ceased, He has broken the covenant, he has despised the cities, He has no regard for man.</verse>
<verse>The land mourns and pines away, Lebanon is shamed and withers; Sharon is like a desert plain, And Bashan and Carmel lose their foliage.</verse>
<verse>"Now I will arise," says the LORD, "Now I will be exalted, now I will be lifted up.</verse>
<verse>"You have conceived chaff, you will give birth to stubble; My breath will consume you like a fire.</verse>
<verse>"The peoples will be burned to lime, Like cut thorns which are burned in the fire.</verse>
<verse>"You who are far away, hear what I have done; And you who are near, acknowledge My might."</verse>
<verse>Sinners in Zion are terrified; Trembling has seized the godless. "Who among us can live with the consuming fire? Who among us can live with continual burning?"</verse>
<verse>He who walks righteously and speaks with sincerity, He who rejects unjust gain And shakes his hands so that they hold no bribe; He who stops his ears from hearing about bloodshed And shuts his eyes from looking upon evil;</verse>
<verse>He will dwell on the heights, His refuge will be the impregnable rock; His bread will be given him, His water will be sure.</verse>
<verse>Your eyes will see the King in His beauty; They will behold a far-distant land.</verse>
<verse>Your heart will meditate on terror: "Where is he who counts? Where is he who weighs? Where is he who counts the towers?"</verse>
<verse>You will no longer see a fierce people, A people of unintelligible speech which no one comprehends, Of a stammering tongue which no one understands.</verse>
<verse>Look upon Zion, the city of our appointed feasts; Your eyes will see Jerusalem, an undisturbed habitation, A tent which will not be folded; Its stakes will never be pulled up, Nor any of its cords be torn apart.</verse>
<verse>But there the majestic One, the LORD, will be for us A place of rivers and wide canals On which no boat with oars will go, And on which no mighty ship will pass--</verse>
<verse>For the LORD is our judge, The LORD is our lawgiver, The LORD is our king; He will save us--</verse>
<verse>Your tackle hangs slack; It cannot hold the base of its mast firmly, Nor spread out the sail. Then the prey of an abundant spoil will be divided; The lame will take the plunder.</verse>
<verse>And no resident will say, "I am sick"; The people who dwell there will be forgiven their iniquity.</verse>
</chapter>