<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Isaiah" book-id="23" n="46">
<verse>Bel has bowed down, Nebo stoops over; Their images are consigned to the beasts and the cattle. The things that you carry are burdensome, A load for the weary beast.</verse>
<verse>They stooped over, they have bowed down together; They could not rescue the burden, But have themselves gone into captivity.</verse>
<verse>"Listen to Me, O house of Jacob, And all the remnant of the house of Israel, You who have been borne by Me from birth And have been carried from the womb;</verse>
<verse>Even to your old age I will be the same, And even to your graying years I will bear you! I have done it, and I will carry you; And I will bear you and I will deliver you.</verse>
<verse>"To whom would you liken Me And make Me equal and compare Me, That we would be alike?</verse>
<verse>"Those who lavish gold from the purse And weigh silver on the scale Hire a goldsmith, and he makes it into a god; They bow down, indeed they worship it.</verse>
<verse>"They lift it upon the shoulder and carry it; They set it in its place and it stands there. It does not move from its place. Though one may cry to it, it cannot answer; It cannot deliver him from his distress.</verse>
<verse>"Remember this, and be assured; Recall it to mind, you transgressors.</verse>
<verse>"Remember the former things long past, For I am God, and there is no other; I am God, and there is no one like Me,</verse>
<verse>Declaring the end from the beginning, And from ancient times things which have not been done, Saying, 'My purpose will be established, And I will accomplish all My good pleasure';</verse>
<verse>Calling a bird of prey from the east, The man of My purpose from a far country. Truly I have spoken; truly I will bring it to pass. I have planned it, surely I will do it.</verse>
<verse>"Listen to Me, you stubborn-minded, Who are far from righteousness.</verse>
<verse>"I bring near My righteousness, it is not far off; And My salvation will not delay. And I will grant salvation in Zion, And My glory for Israel.</verse>
</chapter>