<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Isaiah" book_id="23" n="47">
<verse>"Come down and sit in the dust, O virgin daughter of Babylon; Sit on the ground without a throne, O daughter of the Chaldeans! For you shall no longer be called tender and delicate.</verse>
<verse>"Take the millstones and grind meal. Remove your veil, strip off the skirt, Uncover the leg, cross the rivers.</verse>
<verse>"Your nakedness will be uncovered, Your shame also will be exposed; I will take vengeance and will not spare a man."</verse>
<verse>Our Redeemer, the LORD of hosts is His name, The Holy One of Israel.</verse>
<verse>"Sit silently, and go into darkness, O daughter of the Chaldeans, For you will no longer be called The queen of kingdoms.</verse>
<verse>"I was angry with My people, I profaned My heritage And gave them into your hand. You did not show mercy to them, On the aged you made your yoke very heavy.</verse>
<verse>"Yet you said, 'I will be a queen forever.' These things you did not consider Nor remember the outcome of them.</verse>
<verse>"Now, then, hear this, you sensual one, Who dwells securely, Who says in your heart, 'I am, and there is no one besides me. I will not sit as a widow, Nor know loss of children.'</verse>
<verse>"But these two things will come on you suddenly in one day: Loss of children and widowhood. They will come on you in full measure In spite of your many sorceries, In spite of the great power of your spells.</verse>
<verse>"You felt secure in your wickedness and said, 'No one sees me,' Your wisdom and your knowledge, they have deluded you; For you have said in your heart, 'I am, and there is no one besides me.'</verse>
<verse>"But evil will come on you Which you will not know how to charm away; And disaster will fall on you For which you cannot atone; And destruction about which you do not know Will come on you suddenly.</verse>
<verse>"Stand fast now in your spells And in your many sorceries With which you have labored from your youth; Perhaps you will be able to profit, Perhaps you may cause trembling.</verse>
<verse>"You are wearied with your many counsels; Let now the astrologers, Those who prophesy by the stars, Those who predict by the new moons, Stand up and save you from what will come upon you.</verse>
<verse>"Behold, they have become like stubble, Fire burns them; They cannot deliver themselves from the power of the flame; There will be no coal to warm by Nor a fire to sit before!</verse>
<verse>"So have those become to you with whom you have labored, Who have trafficked with you from your youth; Each has wandered in his own way; There is none to save you.</verse>
</chapter>