<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Isaiah" book_id="23" n="6">
<verse>Let me sing now for my well-beloved A song of my beloved concerning His vineyard. My well-beloved had a vineyard on a fertile hill.</verse>
<verse>He dug it all around, removed its stones, And planted it with the choicest vine. And He built a tower in the middle of it And also hewed out a wine vat in it; Then He expected it to produce good grapes, But it produced only worthless ones.</verse>
<verse>"And now, O inhabitants of Jerusalem and men of Judah, Judge between Me and My vineyard.</verse>
<verse>"What more was there to do for My vineyard that I have not done in it? Why, when I expected it to produce good grapes did it produce worthless ones?</verse>
<verse>"So now let Me tell you what I am going to do to My vineyard: I will remove its hedge and it will be consumed; I will break down its wall and it will become trampled ground.</verse>
<verse>"I will lay it waste; It will not be pruned or hoed, But briars and thorns will come up. I will also charge the clouds to rain no rain on it."</verse>
<verse>For the vineyard of the LORD of hosts is the house of Israel And the men of Judah His delightful plant. Thus He looked for justice, but behold, bloodshed; For righteousness, but behold, a cry of distress.</verse>
<verse>Woe to those who add house to house and join field to field, Until there is no more room, So that you have to live alone in the midst of the land!</verse>
<verse>In my ears the LORD of hosts has sworn, "Surely, many houses shall become desolate, Even great and fine ones, without occupants.</verse>
<verse>"For ten acres of vineyard will yield only one bath of wine, And a homer of seed will yield but an ephah of grain."</verse>
<verse>Woe to those who rise early in the morning that they may pursue strong drink, Who stay up late in the evening that wine may inflame them!</verse>
<verse>Their banquets are accompanied by lyre and harp, by tambourine and flute, and by wine; But they do not pay attention to the deeds of the LORD, Nor do they consider the work of His hands.</verse>
<verse>Therefore My people go into exile for their lack of knowledge; And their honorable men are famished, And their multitude is parched with thirst.</verse>
</chapter>