<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Isaiah" book_id="23" n="62">
<verse>For Zion's sake I will not keep silent, And for Jerusalem's sake I will not keep quiet, Until her righteousness goes forth like brightness, And her salvation like a torch that is burning.</verse>
<verse>The nations will see your righteousness, And all kings your glory; And you will be called by a new name Which the mouth of the LORD will designate.</verse>
<verse>You will also be a crown of beauty in the hand of the LORD, And a royal diadem in the hand of your God.</verse>
<verse>It will no longer be said to you, "Forsaken," Nor to your land will it any longer be said, "Desolate"; But you will be called, "My delight is in her," And your land, "Married"; For the LORD delights in you, And to Him your land will be married.</verse>
<verse>For as a young man marries a virgin, So your sons will marry you; And as the bridegroom rejoices over the bride, So your God will rejoice over you.</verse>
<verse>On your walls, O Jerusalem, I have appointed watchmen; All day and all night they will never keep silent. You who remind the LORD, take no rest for yourselves;</verse>
<verse>And give Him no rest until He establishes And makes Jerusalem a praise in the earth.</verse>
<verse>The LORD has sworn by His right hand and by His strong arm, "I will never again give your grain as food for your enemies; Nor will foreigners drink your new wine for which you have labored."</verse>
<verse>But those who garner it will eat it and praise the LORD; And those who gather it will drink it in the courts of My sanctuary.</verse>
<verse>Go through, go through the gates, Clear the way for the people; Build up, build up the highway, Remove the stones, lift up a standard over the peoples.</verse>
<verse>Behold, the LORD has proclaimed to the end of the earth, Say to the daughter of Zion, "Lo, your salvation comes; Behold His reward is with Him, and His recompense before Him."</verse>
<verse>And they will call them, "The holy people, The redeemed of the LORD"; And you will be called, "Sought out, a city not forsaken."</verse>
</chapter>