<?xml version="1.0"?>
<chapter translation="KJV" testament="Old" book="Zechariah" n="13" book_id="38">
      <verse>In that day there shall be a fountain opened to the house of David and to the inhabitants of Jerusalem for sin and for uncleanness.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>And it shall come to pass in that day, saith the LORD of hosts, <supplied>that</supplied> I will cut off the names of the idols out of the land, and they shall no more be remembered: and also I will cause the prophets and the unclean spirit to pass out of
the land.
</verse><verse>And it shall come to pass, <supplied>that</supplied> when any shall yet prophesy, then his father and his mother that begat him shall say unto him, Thou shalt not live; for thou speakest lies in the name of the LORD: and his father and his mother that begat
him shall thrust him through when he prophesieth.
</verse><verse>And it shall come to pass in that day, <supplied>that</supplied> the prophets shall be ashamed every one of his vision, when he hath prophesied; neither shall they wear a rough garment to deceive:
</verse><verse>But he shall say, I <supplied>am</supplied> no prophet, I <supplied>am</supplied> an husbandman; for man taught me to keep cattle from my youth.
</verse><verse>And <supplied>one</supplied> shall say unto him, What <supplied>are</supplied> these wounds in thine hands? Then he shall answer, <supplied>Those</supplied> with which I was wounded <supplied>in</supplied> the house of my friends.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>Awake, O sword, against my shepherd, and against the man <supplied>that is</supplied> my fellow, saith the LORD of hosts: smite the shepherd, and the sheep shall be scattered: and I will turn mine hand upon the little ones.
</verse><verse>And it shall come to pass, <supplied>that</supplied> in all the land, saith the LORD, two parts therein shall be cut off <supplied>and</supplied> die; but the third shall be left therein.
</verse><verse>And I will bring the third part through the fire, and will refine them as silver is refined, and will try them as gold is tried: they shall call on my name, and I will hear them: I will say, It <supplied>is</supplied> my people: and they shall say, The LORD
<supplied>is</supplied> my God.
     
      </verse>
      </chapter>
