<?xml version="1.0"?>
<chapter translation="KJV" testament="Old" book="Zechariah" n="5" book_id="38">
      <verse>Then I turned, and lifted up mine eyes, and looked, and behold a flying roll.
</verse><verse>And he said unto me, What seest thou? And I answered, I see a flying roll; the length thereof <supplied>is</supplied> twenty cubits, and the breadth thereof ten cubits.
</verse><verse>Then said he unto me, This <supplied>is</supplied> the curse that goeth forth over the face of the whole earth: for every one that stealeth shall be cut off <supplied>as</supplied> on this side according to it; and every one that sweareth shall be cut off <supplied>as</supplied> on
that side according to it.
</verse><verse>I will bring it forth, saith the LORD of hosts, and it shall enter into the house of the thief, and into the house of him that sweareth falsely by my name: and it shall remain in the midst of his house, and shall consume it with the timber
thereof and the stones thereof.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>Then the angel that talked with me went forth, and said unto me, Lift up now thine eyes, and see what <supplied>is</supplied> this that goeth forth.
</verse><verse>And I said, What <supplied>is</supplied> it? And he said, This <supplied>is</supplied> an ephah that goeth forth. He said moreover, This <supplied>is</supplied> their resemblance through all the earth.
</verse><verse>And, behold, there was lifted up a talent of lead: and this <supplied>is</supplied> a woman that sitteth in the midst of the ephah.
</verse><verse>And he said, This <supplied>is</supplied> wickedness. And he cast it into the midst of the ephah; and he cast the weight of lead upon the mouth thereof.
</verse><verse>Then lifted I up mine eyes, and looked, and, behold, there came out two women, and the wind <supplied>was</supplied> in their wings; for they had wings like the wings of a stork: and they lifted up the ephah between the earth and the heaven.
</verse><verse>Then said I to the angel that talked with me, Whither do these bear the ephah?
</verse><verse>And he said unto me, To build it an house in the land of Shinar: and it shall be established, and set there upon her own base.
     
      </verse>
      </chapter>
