<chapter translation="ESV" testament="New" book="1 Thessalonians" book_id="52" n="5">
<verse>Now concerning the times and the seasons, brothers, you have no need to have anything written to you.</verse>
<verse>For you yourselves are fully aware that the day of the Lord will come like a thief in the night.</verse>
<verse>While people are saying, "There is peace and security," then sudden destruction will come upon them as labor pains come upon a pregnant woman, and they will not escape.</verse>
<verse>But you are not in darkness, brothers, for that day to surprise you like a thief.</verse>
<verse>For you are all children of light, children of the day. We are not of the night or of the darkness.</verse>
<verse>So then let us not sleep, as others do, but let us keep awake and be sober.</verse>
<verse>For those who sleep, sleep at night, and those who get drunk, are drunk at night.</verse>
<verse>But since we belong to the day, let us be sober, having put on the breastplate of faith and love, and for a helmet the hope of salvation.</verse>
<verse>For God has not destined us for wrath, but to obtain salvation through our Lord Jesus Christ,</verse>
<verse>who died for us so that whether we are awake or asleep we might live with him.</verse>
<verse>Therefore encourage one another and build one another up, just as you are doing.</verse>
<verse>We ask you, brothers, to respect those who labor among you and are over you in the Lord and admonish you,</verse>
<verse>and to esteem them very highly in love because of their work. Be at peace among yourselves.</verse>
<verse>And we urge you, brothers, admonish the idle, encourage the fainthearted, help the weak, be patient with them all.</verse>
<verse>See that no one repays anyone evil for evil, but always seek to do good to one another and to everyone.</verse>
<verse>Rejoice always,</verse>
<verse>pray without ceasing,</verse>
<verse>give thanks in all circumstances; for this is the will of God in Christ Jesus for you.</verse>
<verse>Do not quench the Spirit.</verse>
<verse>Do not despise prophecies,</verse>
<verse>but test everything; hold fast what is good.</verse>
<verse>Abstain from every form of evil.</verse>
<verse>Now may the God of peace himself sanctify you completely, and may your whole spirit and soul and body be kept blameless at the coming of our Lord Jesus Christ.</verse>
<verse>He who calls you is faithful; he will surely do it.</verse>
<verse>Brothers, pray for us.</verse>
<verse>Greet all the brothers with a holy kiss.</verse>
<verse>I put you under oath before the Lord to have this letter read to all the brothers.</verse>
<verse>The grace of our Lord Jesus Christ be with you.</verse>
</chapter>