<chapter translation="MSG" testament="New" book="1 John" book_id="62" n="3">
<verse>What marvelous love the Father has extended to us! Just look at it--we're called children of God! That's who we really are. But that's also why the world doesn't recognize us or take us seriously, because it has no idea who he is or what he's up to.</verse>
<verse>But friends, that's exactly who we are: children of God. And that's only the beginning. Who knows how we'll end up! What we know is that when Christ is openly revealed, we'll see him--and in seeing him, become like him.</verse>
<verse>All of us who look forward to his Coming stay ready, with the glistening purity of Jesus' life as a model for our own.</verse>
<verse>All who indulge in a sinful life are dangerously lawless, for sin is a major disruption of God's order.</verse>
<verse>Surely you know that Christ showed up in order to get rid of sin. There is no sin in him, and sin is not part of his program.</verse>
<verse>No one who lives deeply in Christ makes a practice of sin. None of those who do practice sin have taken a good look at Christ. They've got him all backwards.</verse>
<verse>So, my dear children, don't let anyone divert you from the truth. It's the person who acts right who is right, just as we see it lived out in our righteous Messiah.</verse>
<verse>Those who make a practice of sin are straight from the Devil, the pioneer in the practice of sin. The Son of God entered the scene to abolish the Devil's ways.</verse>
<verse>People conceived and brought into life by God don't make a practice of sin. How could they? God's seed is deep within them, making them who they are. It's not in the nature of the God-begotten to practice and parade sin.</verse>
<verse>Here's how you tell the difference between God's children and the Devil's children: The one who won't practice righteous ways isn't from God, nor is the one who won't love brother or sister. A simple test. [JC]</verse>
<verse>For this is the original message we heard: We should love each other.</verse>
<verse>We must not be like Cain, who joined the Evil One and then killed his brother. And why did he kill him? Because he was deep in the practice of evil, while the acts of his brother were righteous.</verse>
<verse>So don't be surprised, friends, when the world hates you. This has been going on a long time.</verse>
<verse>The way we know we've been transferred from death to life is that we love our brothers and sisters. Anyone who doesn't love is as good as dead.</verse>
<verse>Anyone who hates a brother or sister is a murderer, and you know very well that eternal life and murder don't go together.</verse>
<verse>This is how we've come to understand and experience love: Christ sacrificed his life for us. This is why we ought to live sacrificially for our fellow believers, and not just be out for ourselves.</verse>
<verse>If you see some brother or sister in need and have the means to do something about it but turn a cold shoulder and do nothing, what happens to God's love? It disappears. And you made it disappear.</verse>
<verse>My dear children, let's not just talk about love; let's practice real love.</verse>
<verse>This is the only way we'll know we're living truly, living in God's reality.</verse>
<verse>It's also the way to shut down debilitating self-criticism, even when there is something to it. For God is greater than our worried hearts and knows more about us than we do ourselves.</verse>
<verse>And friends, once that's taken care of and we're no longer accusing or condemning ourselves, we're bold and free before God!</verse>
<verse>We're able to stretch our hands out and receive what we asked for because we're doing what he said, doing what pleases him.</verse>
<verse>Again, this is God's command: to believe in his personally named Son, Jesus Christ. He told us to love each other, in line with the original command.</verse>
<verse>As we keep his commands, we live deeply and surely in him, and he lives in us. And this is how we experience his deep and abiding presence in us: by the Spirit he gave us.</verse>
</chapter>