<?xml version="1.0"?>
<chapter translation="KJV" testament="New" book="Romans" n="11" chapters="16">
      <verse>I say then, Hath God cast away his people? God forbid. For I also am an Israelite, of the seed of Abraham, <supplied>of</supplied> the tribe of Benjamin.
</verse><verse>God hath not cast away his people which he foreknew. Wot ye not what the scripture saith of Elias? how he maketh intercession to God against Israel, saying,
</verse><verse>Lord, they have killed thy prophets, and digged down thine altars; and I am left alone, and they seek my life.
</verse><verse>But what saith the answer of God unto him? I have reserved to myself seven thousand men, who have not bowed the knee to <supplied>the image of</supplied> Baal.
</verse><verse>Even so then at this present time also there is a remnant according to the election of grace.
</verse><verse>And if by grace, then <supplied>is it</supplied> no more of works: otherwise grace is no more grace. But if <supplied>it be</supplied> of works, then is it no more grace: otherwise work is no more work.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>What then? Israel hath not obtained that which he seeketh for; but the election hath obtained it, and the rest were blinded
</verse><verse>(According as it is written, God hath given them the spirit of slumber, eyes that they should not see, and ears that they should not hear;) unto this day.
</verse><verse>And David saith, Let their table be made a snare, and a trap, and a stumblingblock, and a recompence unto them:
</verse><verse>Let their eyes be darkened, that they may not see, and bow down their back alway.
</verse><verse>I say then, Have they stumbled that they should fall? God forbid: but <supplied>rather</supplied> through their fall salvation <supplied>is come</supplied> unto the Gentiles, for to provoke them to jealousy.
</verse><verse>Now if the fall of them <supplied>be</supplied> the riches of the world, and the diminishing of them the riches of the Gentiles; how much more their fulness?
     
      </verse>
      <verse>For I speak to you Gentiles, inasmuch as I am the apostle of the Gentiles, I magnify mine office:
</verse><verse>If by any means I may provoke to emulation <supplied>them which are</supplied> my flesh, and might save some of them.
</verse><verse>For if the casting away of them <supplied>be</supplied> the reconciling of the world, what <supplied>shall</supplied> the receiving <supplied>of them be,</supplied> but life from the dead?
</verse><verse>For if the firstfruit <supplied>be</supplied> holy, the lump <supplied>is</supplied> also <supplied>holy:</supplied> and if the root <supplied>be</supplied> holy, so <supplied>are</supplied> the branches.
</verse><verse>And if some of the branches be broken off, and thou, being a wild olive tree, wert graffed in among them, and with them partakest of the root and fatness of the olive tree;
</verse><verse>Boast not against the branches. But if thou boast, thou bearest not the root, but the root thee.
</verse><verse>Thou wilt say then, The branches were broken off, that I might be graffed in.
</verse><verse>Well; because of unbelief they were broken off, and thou standest by faith. Be not highminded, but fear:
</verse><verse>For if God spared not the natural branches, <supplied>take heed</supplied> lest he also spare not thee.
</verse><verse>Behold therefore the goodness and severity of God: on them which fell, severity; but toward thee, goodness, if thou continue in <supplied>his</supplied> goodness: otherwise thou also shalt be cut off.
</verse><verse>And they also, if they abide not still in unbelief, shall be graffed in: for God is able to graff them in again.
</verse><verse>For if thou wert cut out of the olive tree which is wild by nature, and wert graffed contrary to nature into a good olive tree: how much more shall these, which be the natural <supplied>branches,</supplied> be graffed into their own olive tree?
     
      </verse>
      <verse>For I would not, brethren, that ye should be ignorant of this mystery, lest ye should be wise in your own conceits; that blindness in part is happened to Israel, until the fulness of the Gentiles be come in.
</verse><verse>And so all Israel shall be saved: as it is written, There shall come out of Sion the Deliverer, and shall turn away ungodliness from Jacob:
</verse><verse>For this <supplied>is</supplied> my covenant unto them, when I shall take away their sins.
</verse><verse>As concerning the gospel, <supplied>they are</supplied> enemies for your sakes: but as touching the election, <supplied>they are</supplied> beloved for the fathers&#x2019; sakes.
</verse><verse>For the gifts and calling of God <supplied>are</supplied> without repentance.
</verse><verse>For as ye in times past have not believed God, yet have now obtained mercy through their unbelief:
</verse><verse>Even so have these also now not believed, that through your mercy they also may obtain mercy.
</verse><verse>For God hath concluded them all in unbelief, that he might have mercy upon all.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>O the depth of the riches both of the wisdom and knowledge of God! how unsearchable <supplied>are</supplied> his judgments, and his ways past finding out!
</verse><verse>For who hath known the mind of the Lord? or who hath been his counsellor?
</verse><verse>Or who hath first given to him, and it shall be recompensed unto him again?
</verse><verse>For of him, and through him, and to him, <supplied>are</supplied> all things: to whom <supplied>be</supplied> glory for ever. Amen.
     
      </verse>
      </chapter>
