<chapter translation="NASB" testament="New" book="James" book_id="59" n="3">
<verse>Let not many of you become teachers, my brethren, knowing that as such we will incur a stricter judgment.</verse>
<verse>For we all stumble in many ways. If anyone does not stumble in what he says, he is a perfect man, able to bridle the whole body as well.</verse>
<verse>Now if we put the bits into the horses' mouths so that they will obey us, we direct their entire body as well.</verse>
<verse>Look at the ships also, though they are so great and are driven by strong winds, are still directed by a very small rudder wherever the inclination of the pilot desires.</verse>
<verse>So also the tongue is a small part of the body, and yet it boasts of great things. See how great a forest is set aflame by such a small fire!</verse>
<verse>And the tongue is a fire, the very world of iniquity; the tongue is set among our members as that which defiles the entire body, and sets on fire the course of our life, and is set on fire by hell.</verse>
<verse>For every species of beasts and birds, of reptiles and creatures of the sea, is tamed and has been tamed by the human race.</verse>
<verse>But no one can tame the tongue; it is a restless evil and full of deadly poison.</verse>
<verse>With it we bless our Lord and Father, and with it we curse men, who have been made in the likeness of God;</verse>
<verse>from the same mouth come both blessing and cursing. My brethren, these things ought not to be this way.</verse>
<verse>Does a fountain send out from the same opening both fresh and bitter water?</verse>
<verse>Can a fig tree, my brethren, produce olives, or a vine produce figs? Nor can salt water produce fresh.</verse>
<verse>Who among you is wise and understanding? Let him show by his good behavior his deeds in the gentleness of wisdom.</verse>
<verse>But if you have bitter jealousy and selfish ambition in your heart, do not be arrogant and so lie against the truth.</verse>
<verse>This wisdom is not that which comes down from above, but is earthly, natural, demonic.</verse>
<verse>For where jealousy and selfish ambition exist, there is disorder and every evil thing.</verse>
<verse>But the wisdom from above is first pure, then peaceable, gentle, reasonable, full of mercy and good fruits, unwavering, without hypocrisy.</verse>
<verse>And the seed whose fruit is righteousness is sown in peace by those who make peace.</verse>
</chapter>