<chapter translation="NASB" testament="New" book="James" book-id="59" n="4">
<verse>What is the source of quarrels and conflicts among you? Is not the source your pleasures that wage war in your members?</verse>
<verse>You lust and do not have; so you commit murder. You are envious and cannot obtain; so you fight and quarrel. You do not have because you do not ask.</verse>
<verse>You ask and do not receive, because you ask with wrong motives, so that you may spend it on your pleasures.</verse>
<verse>You adulteresses, do you not know that friendship with the world is hostility toward God? Therefore whoever wishes to be a friend of the world makes himself an enemy of God.</verse>
<verse>Or do you think that the Scripture speaks to no purpose: "He jealously desires the Spirit which He has made to dwell in us"?</verse>
<verse>But He gives a greater grace. Therefore it says, "GOD IS OPPOSED TO THE PROUD, BUT GIVES GRACE TO THE HUMBLE."</verse>
<verse>Submit therefore to God. Resist the devil and he will flee from you.</verse>
<verse>Draw near to God and He will draw near to you. Cleanse your hands, you sinners; and purify your hearts, you double-minded.</verse>
<verse>Be miserable and mourn and weep; let your laughter be turned into mourning and your joy to gloom.</verse>
<verse>Humble yourselves in the presence of the Lord, and He will exalt you.</verse>
<verse>Do not speak against one another, brethren. He who speaks against a brother or judges his brother, speaks against the law and judges the law; but if you judge the law, you are not a doer of the law but a judge of it.</verse>
<verse>There is only one Lawgiver and Judge, the One who is able to save and to destroy; but who are you who judge your neighbor?</verse>
<verse>Come now, you who say, "Today or tomorrow we will go to such and such a city, and spend a year there and engage in business and make a profit."</verse>
<verse>Yet you do not know what your life will be like tomorrow. You are just a vapor that appears for a little while and then vanishes away.</verse>
<verse>Instead, you ought to say, "If the Lord wills, we will live and also do this or that."</verse>
<verse>But as it is, you boast in your arrogance; all such boasting is evil.</verse>
<verse>Therefore, to one who knows the right thing to do and does not do it, to him it is sin.</verse>
</chapter>