<chapter translation="KJV" testament="New" book="MAT" n="26">
      <verse>And it came to pass, when Jesus had finished all these sayings, he said unto his disciples,
</verse><verse><jesus>Ye know that after two days is <supplied>the feast of</supplied> the passover, and the Son of man is betrayed to be crucified. </jesus></verse><verse>Then assembled together the chief priests, and the scribes, and the elders of the people, unto the palace of the high
priest, who was called Caiaphas,
</verse><verse>And consulted that they might take Jesus by subtilty, and kill <supplied>him. </supplied></verse><verse>But they said, Not on the feast <supplied>day,</supplied> lest there be an uproar among the people.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>Now when Jesus was in Bethany, in the house of Simon the leper,
</verse><verse>There came unto him a woman having an alabaster box of very precious ointment, and poured it on his head, as he sat <supplied>at meat. </supplied></verse><verse>But when his disciples saw <supplied>it,</supplied> they had indignation, saying, To what purpose <supplied>is</supplied> this
waste?
</verse><verse>For this ointment might have been sold for much, and given to the poor.
</verse><verse>When Jesus understood <supplied>it,</supplied> he said unto them, <jesus>Why trouble ye the woman? for she hath wrought a good work upon me. </jesus></verse><verse><jesus>For ye have the poor always with you; but me ye have not always. </jesus></verse><verse><jesus>For in that she hath
poured this ointment on my body, she did <supplied>it</supplied> for my burial. </jesus></verse><verse><jesus>Verily I say unto you, Wheresoever this gospel shall be preached in the whole world, <supplied>there</supplied> shall also this, that this woman hath done, be told for a memorial of
her.
     
      </jesus>
      </verse>
      <verse>Then one of the twelve, called Judas Iscariot, went unto the chief priests,
</verse><verse>And said <supplied>unto them,</supplied> What will ye give me, and I will deliver him unto you? And they covenanted with him for thirty pieces of silver.
</verse><verse>And from that time he sought opportunity to betray him.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>Now the first <supplied>day</supplied> of the <supplied>feast of</supplied> unleavened bread the disciples came to Jesus, saying unto him, Where wilt thou that we prepare for thee to eat the passover?
</verse><verse>And he said, <jesus>Go into the city to such a man, and say unto him, The Master saith, My time is at hand; I will keep the passover at thy house with my disciples. </jesus></verse><verse>And the disciples did as Jesus had appointed them; and they made ready
the passover.
</verse><verse>Now when the even was come, he sat down with the twelve.
</verse><verse>And as they did eat, he said, <jesus>Verily I say unto you, that one of you shall betray me. </jesus></verse><verse>And they were exceeding sorrowful, and began every one of them to say unto him, Lord, is it I?
</verse><verse>And he answered and said, <jesus>He that dippeth <supplied>his</supplied> hand with me in the dish, the same shall betray me. </jesus></verse><verse><jesus>The Son of man goeth as it is written of him: but woe unto that man by whom the Son of man is betrayed! it had been
good for that man if he had not been born. </jesus></verse><verse>Then Judas, which betrayed him, answered and said, Master, is it I? He said unto him, <jesus>Thou hast said.
     
      </jesus>
      </verse>
      <verse>And as they were eating, Jesus took bread, and blessed <supplied>it,</supplied> and brake <supplied>it,</supplied> and gave <supplied>it</supplied> to the disciples, and said, <jesus>Take, eat; this is my body. </jesus></verse><verse>And he took the cup, and gave thanks, and gave <supplied>it</supplied> to
them, saying, <jesus>Drink ye all of it; </jesus></verse><verse><jesus>For this is my blood of the new testament, which is shed for many for the remission of sins. </jesus></verse><verse><jesus>But I say unto you, I will not drink henceforth of this fruit of the vine, until that day
when I drink it new with you in my Father’s kingdom. </jesus></verse><verse>And when they had sung an hymn, they went out into the mount of Olives.
</verse><verse>Then saith Jesus unto them, <jesus>All ye shall be offended because of me this night: for it is written, I will smite the shepherd, and the sheep of the flock shall be scattered abroad. </jesus></verse><verse><jesus>But after I am risen again, I will go before
you into Galilee. </jesus></verse><verse>Peter answered and said unto him, Though all <supplied>men</supplied> shall be offended because of thee, <supplied>yet</supplied> will I never be offended.
</verse><verse>Jesus said unto him, <jesus>Verily I say unto thee, That this night, before the cock crow, thou shalt deny me thrice. </jesus></verse><verse>Peter said unto him, Though I should die with thee, yet will I not deny thee. Likewise also said all the disciples.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>Then cometh Jesus with them unto a place called Gethsemane, and saith unto the disciples, <jesus>Sit ye here, while I go and pray yonder. </jesus></verse><verse>And he took with him Peter and the two sons of Zebedee, and began to be sorrowful and very heavy.
</verse><verse>Then saith he unto them, <jesus>My soul is exceeding sorrowful, even unto death: tarry ye here, and watch with me. </jesus></verse><verse>And he went a little farther, and fell on his face, and prayed, saying, <jesus>O my Father, if it be possible, let this cup
pass from me: nevertheless not as I will, but as thou <supplied>wilt. </supplied></jesus></verse><verse>And he cometh unto the disciples, and findeth them asleep, and saith unto Peter, <jesus>What, could ye not watch with me one hour? </jesus></verse><verse><jesus>Watch and pray, that ye enter
not into temptation: the spirit indeed <supplied>is</supplied> willing, but the flesh <supplied>is</supplied> weak. </jesus></verse><verse>He went away again the second time, and prayed, saying, <jesus>O my Father, if this cup may not pass away from me, except I drink it, thy will be done.
</jesus></verse><verse>And he came and found them asleep again: for their eyes were heavy.
</verse><verse>And he left them, and went away again, and prayed the third time, saying the same words.
</verse><verse>Then cometh he to his disciples, and saith unto them, <jesus>Sleep on now, and take <supplied>your</supplied> rest: behold, the hour is at hand, and the Son of man is betrayed into the hands of sinners. </jesus></verse><verse><jesus>Rise, let us be going: behold, he is at
hand that doth betray me.
     
      </jesus>
      </verse>
      <verse>And while he yet spake, lo, Judas, one of the twelve, came, and with him a great multitude with swords and staves, from the chief priests and elders of the people.
</verse><verse>Now he that betrayed him gave them a sign, saying, Whomsoever I shall kiss, that same is he: hold him fast.
</verse><verse>And forthwith he came to Jesus, and said, Hail, master; and kissed him.
</verse><verse>And Jesus said unto him, <jesus>Friend, wherefore art thou come?</jesus> Then came they, and laid hands on Jesus, and took him.
</verse><verse>And, behold, one of them which were with Jesus stretched out <supplied>his</supplied> hand, and drew his sword, and struck a servant of the high priest’s, and smote off his ear.
</verse><verse>Then said Jesus unto him, <jesus>Put up again thy sword into his place: for all they that take the sword shall perish with the sword. </jesus></verse><verse><jesus>Thinkest thou that I cannot now pray to my Father, and he shall presently give me more than twelve
legions of angels? </jesus></verse><verse><jesus>But how then shall the scriptures be fulfilled, that thus it must be? </jesus></verse><verse>In that same hour said Jesus to the multitudes, <jesus>Are ye come out as against a thief with swords and staves for to take me? I sat
daily with you teaching in the temple, and ye laid no hold on me. </jesus></verse><verse><jesus>But all this was done, that the scriptures of the prophets might be fulfilled. </jesus>Then all the disciples forsook him, and fled.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>And they that had laid hold on Jesus led <supplied>him</supplied> away to Caiaphas the high priest, where the scribes and the elders were assembled.
</verse><verse>But Peter followed him afar off unto the high priest’s palace, and went in, and sat with the servants, to see the end.
</verse><verse>Now the chief priests, and elders, and all the council, sought false witness against Jesus, to put him to death;
</verse><verse>But found none: yea, though many false witnesses came, <supplied>yet</supplied> found they none. At the last came two false witnesses,
</verse><verse>And said, This <supplied>fellow</supplied> said, I am able to destroy the temple of God, and to build it in three days.
</verse><verse>And the high priest arose, and said unto him, Answerest thou nothing? what <supplied>is it which</supplied> these witness against thee?
</verse><verse>But Jesus held his peace. And the high priest answered and said unto him, I adjure thee by the living God, that thou tell us whether thou be the Christ, the Son of God.
</verse><verse>Jesus saith unto him, <jesus>Thou hast said: nevertheless I say unto you, Hereafter shall ye see the Son of man sitting on the right hand of power, and coming in the clouds of heaven. </jesus></verse><verse>Then the high priest rent his clothes, saying, He
hath spoken blasphemy; what further need have we of witnesses? behold, now ye have heard his blasphemy.
</verse><verse>What think ye? They answered and said, He is guilty of death.
</verse><verse>Then did they spit in his face, and buffeted him; and others smote <supplied>him</supplied> with the palms of their hands,
</verse><verse>Saying, Prophesy unto us, thou Christ, Who is he that smote thee?
     
      </verse>
      <verse>Now Peter sat without in the palace: and a damsel came unto him, saying, Thou also wast with Jesus of Galilee.
</verse><verse>But he denied before <supplied>them</supplied> all, saying, I know not what thou sayest.
</verse><verse>And when he was gone out into the porch, another <supplied>maid</supplied> saw him, and said unto them that were there, This <supplied>fellow</supplied> was also with Jesus of Nazareth.
</verse><verse>And again he denied with an oath, I do not know the man.
</verse><verse>And after a while came unto <supplied>him</supplied> they that stood by, and said to Peter, Surely thou also art <supplied>one</supplied> of them; for thy speech bewrayeth thee.
</verse><verse>Then began he to curse and to swear, <supplied>saying,</supplied> I know not the man. And immediately the cock crew.
</verse><verse>And Peter remembered the word of Jesus, which said unto him, <jesus>Before the cock crow, thou shalt deny me thrice.</jesus> And he went out, and wept bitterly.
     
      </verse>
      </chapter>