<?xml version="1.0"?>
<chapter translation="KJV" testament="New" book="John" n="12" book_id="43">
      <verse>Then Jesus six days before the passover came to Bethany, where Lazarus was which had been dead, whom he raised from the dead.
</verse><verse>There they made him a supper; and Martha served: but Lazarus was one of them that sat at the table with him.
</verse><verse>Then took Mary a pound of ointment of spikenard, very costly, and anointed the feet of Jesus, and wiped his feet with her hair: and the house was filled with the odour of the ointment.
</verse><verse>Then saith one of his disciples, Judas Iscariot, Simon&#x2019;s <supplied>son,</supplied> which should betray him,
</verse><verse>Why was not this ointment sold for three hundred pence, and given to the poor?
</verse><verse>This he said, not that he cared for the poor; but because he was a thief, and had the bag, and bare what was put therein.
</verse><verse>Then said Jesus, <jesus>Let her alone: against the day of my burying hath she kept this. </jesus></verse><verse><jesus>For the poor always ye have with you; but me ye have not always. </jesus></verse><verse>Much people of the Jews therefore knew that he was there: and they came
not for Jesus&#x2019; sake only, but that they might see Lazarus also, whom he had raised from the dead.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>But the chief priests consulted that they might put Lazarus also to death;
</verse><verse>Because that by reason of him many of the Jews went away, and believed on Jesus.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>On the next day much people that were come to the feast, when they heard that Jesus was coming to Jerusalem,
</verse><verse>Took branches of palm trees, and went forth to meet him, and cried, Hosanna: Blessed <supplied>is</supplied> the King of Israel that cometh in the name of the Lord.
</verse><verse>And Jesus, when he had found a young ass, sat thereon; as it is written,
</verse><verse>Fear not, daughter of Sion: behold, thy King cometh, sitting on an ass&#x2019;s colt.
</verse><verse>These things understood not his disciples at the first: but when Jesus was glorified, then remembered they that these things were written of him, and <supplied>that</supplied> they had done these things unto him.
</verse><verse>The people therefore that was with him when he called Lazarus out of his grave, and raised him from the dead, bare record.
</verse><verse>For this cause the people also met him, for that they heard that he had done this miracle.
</verse><verse>The Pharisees therefore said among themselves, Perceive ye how ye prevail nothing? behold, the world is gone after him.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>And there were certain Greeks among them that came up to worship at the feast:
</verse><verse>The same came therefore to Philip, which was of Bethsaida of Galilee, and desired him, saying, Sir, we would see Jesus.
</verse><verse>Philip cometh and telleth Andrew: and again Andrew and Philip tell Jesus.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>And Jesus answered them, saying, <jesus>The hour is come, that the Son of man should be glorified. </jesus></verse><verse><jesus>Verily, verily, I say unto you, Except a corn of wheat fall into the ground and die, it abideth alone: but if it die, it bringeth
forth much fruit. </jesus></verse><verse><jesus>He that loveth his life shall lose it; and he that hateth his life in this world shall keep it unto life eternal. </jesus></verse><verse><jesus>If any man serve me, let him follow me; and where I am, there shall also my servant be:
if any man serve me, him will <supplied>my</supplied> Father honour. </jesus></verse><verse><jesus>Now is my soul troubled; and what shall I say? Father, save me from this hour: but for this cause came I unto this hour. </jesus></verse><verse><jesus>Father, glorify thy name.</jesus> Then came
there a voice from heaven, <supplied>saying,</supplied> I have both glorified <supplied>it,</supplied> and will glorify <supplied>it</supplied> again.
</verse><verse>The people therefore, that stood by, and heard <supplied>it,</supplied> said that it thundered: others said, An angel spake to him.
</verse><verse>Jesus answered and said, <jesus>This voice came not because of me, but for your sakes. </jesus></verse><verse><jesus>Now is the judgment of this world: now shall the prince of this world be cast out. </jesus></verse><verse><jesus>And I, if I be lifted up from the earth, will
draw all <supplied>men</supplied> unto me. </jesus></verse><verse>This he said, signifying what death he should die.
</verse><verse>The people answered him, We have heard out of the law that Christ abideth for ever: and how sayest thou, <jesus>The Son of man must be lifted up?</jesus> who is this Son of man?
</verse><verse>Then Jesus said unto them, <jesus>Yet a little while is the light with you. Walk while ye have the light, lest darkness come upon you: for he that walketh in darkness knoweth not whither he goeth. </jesus></verse><verse><jesus>While ye have light, believe in the
light, that ye may be the children of light.</jesus> These things spake Jesus, and departed, and did hide himself from them.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>But though he had done so many miracles before them, yet they believed not on him:
</verse><verse>That the saying of Esaias the prophet might be fulfilled, which he spake, Lord, who hath believed our report? and to whom hath the arm of the Lord been revealed?
</verse><verse>Therefore they could not believe, because that Esaias said again,
</verse><verse>He hath blinded their eyes, and hardened their heart; that they should not see with <supplied>their</supplied> eyes, nor understand with <supplied>their</supplied> heart, and be converted, and I should heal them.
</verse><verse>These things said Esaias, when he saw his glory, and spake of him.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>Nevertheless among the chief rulers also many believed on him; but because of the Pharisees they did not confess <supplied>him,</supplied> lest they should be put out of the synagogue:
</verse><verse>For they loved the praise of men more than the praise of God.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>Jesus cried and said, <jesus>He that believeth on me, believeth not on me, but on him that sent me. </jesus></verse><verse><jesus>And he that seeth me seeth him that sent me. </jesus></verse><verse><jesus>I am come a light into the world, that whosoever believeth on me should
not abide in darkness. </jesus></verse><verse><jesus>And if any man hear my words, and believe not, I judge him not: for I came not to judge the world, but to save the world. </jesus></verse><verse><jesus>He that rejecteth me, and receiveth not my words, hath one that judgeth him:
the word that I have spoken, the same shall judge him in the last day. </jesus></verse><verse><jesus>For I have not spoken of myself; but the Father which sent me, he gave me a commandment, what I should say, and what I should speak. </jesus></verse><verse><jesus>And I know that
his commandment is life everlasting: whatsoever I speak therefore, even as the Father said unto me, so I speak.
     
      </jesus>
      </verse>
      </chapter>
