<chapter translation="NIV" testament="New" book="Titus" book_id="56" n="1">
<verse>Paul, a servant of God and an apostle of Jesus Christ for the faith of God's elect and the knowledge of the truth that leads to godliness--</verse>
<verse>a faith and knowledge resting on the hope of eternal life, which God, who does not lie, promised before the beginning of time,</verse>
<verse>and at his appointed season he brought his word to light through the preaching entrusted to me by the command of God our Savior,</verse>
<verse>To Titus, my true son in our common faith: Grace and peace from God the Father and Christ Jesus our Savior.</verse>
<verse>The reason I left you in Crete was that you might straighten out what was left unfinished and appoint elders in every town, as I directed you.</verse>
<verse>An elder must be blameless, the husband of but one wife, a man whose children believe and are not open to the charge of being wild and disobedient.</verse>
<verse>Since an overseer is entrusted with God's work, he must be blameless--not overbearing, not quick-tempered, not given to drunkenness, not violent, not pursuing dishonest gain.</verse>
<verse>Rather he must be hospitable, one who loves what is good, who is self-controlled, upright, holy and disciplined.</verse>
<verse>He must hold firmly to the trustworthy message as it has been taught, so that he can encourage others by sound doctrine and refute those who oppose it.</verse>
<verse>For there are many rebellious people, mere talkers and deceivers, especially those of the circumcision group.</verse>
<verse>They must be silenced, because they are ruining whole households by teaching things they ought not to teach--and that for the sake of dishonest gain.</verse>
<verse>Even one of their own prophets has said, "Cretans are always liars, evil brutes, lazy gluttons."</verse>
<verse>This testimony is true. Therefore, rebuke them sharply, so that they will be sound in the faith</verse>
<verse>and will pay no attention to Jewish myths or to the commands of those who reject the truth.</verse>
<verse>To the pure, all things are pure, but to those who are corrupted and do not believe, nothing is pure. In fact, both their minds and consciences are corrupted.</verse>
<verse>They claim to know God, but by their actions they deny him. They are detestable, disobedient and unfit for doing anything good.</verse>
</chapter>