<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Ezekiel" book_id="26" n="30">
<verse>The word of the LORD came again to me saying,</verse>
<verse>"Son of man, prophesy and say, 'Thus says the Lord GOD, "Wail, 'Alas for the day!'</verse>
<verse>"For the day is near, Even the day of the LORD is near; It will be a day of clouds, A time of doom for the nations.</verse>
<verse>"A sword will come upon Egypt, And anguish will be in Ethiopia; When the slain fall in Egypt, They take away her wealth, And her foundations are torn down.</verse>
<verse>"Ethiopia, Put, Lud, all Arabia, Libya and the people of the land that is in league will fall with them by the sword."</verse>
<verse>'Thus says the LORD, "Indeed, those who support Egypt will fall And the pride of her power will come down; From Migdol to Syene They will fall within her by the sword," Declares the Lord GOD.</verse>
<verse>"They will be desolate In the midst of the desolated lands; And her cities will be In the midst of the devastated cities.</verse>
<verse>"And they will know that I am the LORD, When I set a fire in Egypt And all her helpers are broken.</verse>
<verse>"On that day messengers will go forth from Me in ships to frighten secure Ethiopia; and anguish will be on them as on the day of Egypt; for behold, it comes!"</verse>
<verse>'Thus says the Lord GOD, "I will also make the hordes of Egypt cease By the hand of Nebuchadnezzar king of Babylon.</verse>
<verse>"He and his people with him, The most ruthless of the nations, Will be brought in to destroy the land; And they will draw their swords against Egypt And fill the land with the slain.</verse>
<verse>"Moreover, I will make the Nile canals dry And sell the land into the hands of evil men. And I will make the land desolate And all that is in it, By the hand of strangers; I the LORD have spoken."</verse>
<verse>'Thus says the Lord GOD, "I will also destroy the idols And make the images cease from Memphis. And there will no longer be a prince in the land of Egypt; And I will put fear in the land of Egypt.</verse>
<verse>"I will make Pathros desolate, Set a fire in Zoan And execute judgments on Thebes.</verse>
<verse>"I will pour out My wrath on Sin, The stronghold of Egypt; I will also cut off the hordes of Thebes.</verse>
<verse>"I will set a fire in Egypt; Sin will writhe in anguish, Thebes will be breached And Memphis will have distresses daily.</verse>
<verse>"The young men of On and of Pi-beseth Will fall by the sword, And the women will go into captivity.</verse>
<verse>"In Tehaphnehes the day will be dark When I break there the yoke bars of Egypt. Then the pride of her power will cease in her; A cloud will cover her, And her daughters will go into captivity.</verse>
<verse>"Thus I will execute judgments on Egypt, And they will know that I am the LORD."'"</verse>
<verse>In the eleventh year, in the first month, on the seventh of the month, the word of the LORD came to me saying,</verse>
<verse>"Son of man, I have broken the arm of Pharaoh king of Egypt; and, behold, it has not been bound up for healing or wrapped with a bandage, that it may be strong to hold the sword.</verse>
<verse>"Therefore thus says the Lord GOD, 'Behold, I am against Pharaoh king of Egypt and will break his arms, both the strong and the broken; and I will make the sword fall from his hand.</verse>
<verse>'I will scatter the Egyptians among the nations and disperse them among the lands.</verse>
<verse>'For I will strengthen the arms of the king of Babylon and put My sword in his hand; and I will break the arms of Pharaoh, so that he will groan before him with the groanings of a wounded man.</verse>
<verse>'Thus I will strengthen the arms of the king of Babylon, but the arms of Pharaoh will fall. Then they will know that I am the LORD, when I put My sword into the hand of the king of Babylon and he stretches it out against the land of Egypt.</verse>
<verse>'When I scatter the Egyptians among the nations and disperse them among the lands, then they will know that I am the LORD.'"</verse>
</chapter>