<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Ezekiel" book-id="26" n="37">
<verse>The hand of the LORD was upon me, and He brought me out by the Spirit of the LORD and set me down in the middle of the valley; and it was full of bones.</verse>
<verse>He caused me to pass among them round about, and behold, there were very many on the surface of the valley; and lo, they were very dry.</verse>
<verse>He said to me, "Son of man, can these bones live?" And I answered, "O Lord GOD, You know."</verse>
<verse>Again He said to me, "Prophesy over these bones and say to them, 'O dry bones, hear the word of the LORD.'</verse>
<verse>"Thus says the Lord GOD to these bones, 'Behold, I will cause breath to enter you that you may come to life.</verse>
<verse>'I will put sinews on you, make flesh grow back on you, cover you with skin and put breath in you that you may come alive; and you will know that I am the LORD.'"</verse>
<verse>So I prophesied as I was commanded; and as I prophesied, there was a noise, and behold, a rattling; and the bones came together, bone to its bone.</verse>
<verse>And I looked, and behold, sinews were on them, and flesh grew and skin covered them; but there was no breath in them.</verse>
<verse>Then He said to me, "Prophesy to the breath, prophesy, son of man, and say to the breath, 'Thus says the Lord GOD, "Come from the four winds, O breath, and breathe on these slain, that they come to life."'"</verse>
<verse>So I prophesied as He commanded me, and the breath came into them, and they came to life and stood on their feet, an exceedingly great army.</verse>
<verse>Then He said to me, "Son of man, these bones are the whole house of Israel; behold, they say, 'Our bones are dried up and our hope has perished. We are completely cut off.'</verse>
<verse>"Therefore prophesy and say to them, 'Thus says the Lord GOD, "Behold, I will open your graves and cause you to come up out of your graves, My people; and I will bring you into the land of Israel.</verse>
<verse>"Then you will know that I am the LORD, when I have opened your graves and caused you to come up out of your graves, My people.</verse>
<verse>"I will put My Spirit within you and you will come to life, and I will place you on your own land. Then you will know that I, the LORD, have spoken and done it," declares the LORD.'"</verse>
<verse>The word of the LORD came again to me saying,</verse>
<verse>"And you, son of man, take for yourself one stick and write on it, 'For Judah and for the sons of Israel, his companions'; then take another stick and write on it, 'For Joseph, the stick of Ephraim and all the house of Israel, his companions.'</verse>
<verse>"Then join them for yourself one to another into one stick, that they may become one in your hand.</verse>
<verse>"When the sons of your people speak to you saying, 'Will you not declare to us what you mean by these?'</verse>
<verse>say to them, 'Thus says the Lord GOD, "Behold, I will take the stick of Joseph, which is in the hand of Ephraim, and the tribes of Israel, his companions; and I will put them with it, with the stick of Judah, and make them one stick, and they will be one in My hand."'</verse>
<verse>"The sticks on which you write will be in your hand before their eyes.</verse>
<verse>"Say to them, 'Thus says the Lord GOD, "Behold, I will take the sons of Israel from among the nations where they have gone, and I will gather them from every side and bring them into their own land;</verse>
<verse>and I will make them one nation in the land, on the mountains of Israel; and one king will be king for all of them; and they will no longer be two nations and no longer be divided into two kingdoms.</verse>
<verse>"They will no longer defile themselves with their idols, or with their detestable things, or with any of their transgressions; but I will deliver them from all their dwelling places in which they have sinned, and will cleanse them. And they will be My people, and I will be their God.</verse>
<verse>"My servant David will be king over them, and they will all have one shepherd; and they will walk in My ordinances and keep My statutes and observe them.</verse>
<verse>"They will live on the land that I gave to Jacob My servant, in which your fathers lived; and they will live on it, they, and their sons and their sons' sons, forever; and David My servant will be their prince forever.</verse>
<verse>"I will make a covenant of peace with them; it will be an everlasting covenant with them. And I will place them and multiply them, and will set My sanctuary in their midst forever.</verse>
<verse>"My dwelling place also will be with them; and I will be their God, and they will be My people.</verse>
<verse>"And the nations will know that I am the LORD who sanctifies Israel, when My sanctuary is in their midst forever."'"</verse>
</chapter>