<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="2 Samuel" book_id="10" n="1">
<verse>Shortly after Saul died, David returned to Ziklag from his rout of the Amalekites.</verse>
<verse>Three days later a man showed up unannounced from Saul's army camp. Disheveled and obviously in mourning, he fell to his knees in respect before David.</verse>
<verse>David asked, "What brings you here?" He answered, "I've just escaped from the camp of Israel."</verse>
<verse>"So what happened?" said David. "What's the news?" He said, "The Israelites have fled the battlefield, leaving a lot of their dead comrades behind. And Saul and his son Jonathan are dead."</verse>
<verse>David pressed the young soldier for details: "How do you know for sure that Saul and Jonathan are dead?"</verse>
<verse>"I just happened by Mount Gilboa and came on Saul, badly wounded and leaning on his spear, with enemy chariots and horsemen bearing down hard on him.</verse>
<verse>He looked behind him, saw me, and called me to him. "Yes sir,' I said, "at your service.'</verse>
<verse>He asked me who I was, and I told him, "I'm an Amalekite.'"</verse>
<verse>"Come here," he said, "and put me out of my misery. I'm nearly dead already, but my life hangs on."</verse>
<verse>"So I did what he asked--I killed him. I knew he wouldn't last much longer anyway. I removed his royal headband and bracelet, and have brought them to my master. Here they are."</verse>
<verse>In lament, David ripped his clothes to ribbons. All the men with him did the same.</verse>
<verse>They wept and fasted the rest of the day, grieving the death of Saul and his son Jonathan, and also the army of GOD and the nation Israel, victims in a failed battle.</verse>
<verse>Then David spoke to the young soldier who had brought the report: "Who are you, anyway?I'm from an immigrant family--an Amalekite."</verse>
<verse>"Do you mean to say," said David, "that you weren't afraid to up and kill GOD's anointed king?"</verse>
<verse>Right then he ordered one of his soldiers, "Strike him dead!" The soldier struck him, and he died.</verse>
<verse>"You asked for it," David told him. "You sealed your death sentence when you said you killed GOD's anointed king."</verse>
<verse>Then David sang this lament over Saul and his son Jonathan,</verse>
<verse>and gave orders that everyone in Judah learn it by heart. Yes, it's even inscribed in The Book of Jashar.</verse>
<verse>Oh, oh, Gazelles of Israel, struck down on your hills, the mighty warriors--fallen, fallen!</verse>
<verse>Don't announce it in the city of Gath, don't post the news in the streets of Ashkelon. Don't give those coarse Philistine girls one more excuse for a drunken party!</verse>
<verse>No more dew or rain for you, hills of Gilboa, and not a drop from springs and wells, For there the warriors' shields were dragged through the mud, Saul's shield left there to rot.</verse>
<verse>Jonathan's bow was bold--the bigger they were the harder they fell. Saul's sword was fearless--once out of the scabbard, nothing could stop it.</verse>
<verse>Saul and Jonathan--beloved, beautiful! Together in life, together in death. Swifter than plummeting eagles, stronger than proud lions.</verse>
<verse>Women of Israel, weep for Saul. He dressed you in finest cottons and silks, spared no expense in making you elegant.</verse>
<verse>The mighty warriors--fallen, fallen in the middle of the fight! Jonathan--struck down on your hills!</verse>
<verse>O my dear brother Jonathan, I'm crushed by your death. Your friendship was a miracle-wonder, love far exceeding anything I've known--or ever hope to know.</verse>
<verse>The mighty warriors--fallen, fallen. And the arms of war broken to bits.</verse>
</chapter>