<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="2 Samuel" book_id="10" n="22">
<verse>David prayed to GOD the words of this song after GOD saved him from all his enemies and from Saul.</verse>
<verse>GOD is bedrock under my feet, the castle in which I live, my rescuing knight.</verse>
<verse>My God--the high crag where I run for dear life, hiding behind the boulders, safe in the granite hideout; My mountaintop refuge, he saves me from ruthless men.</verse>
<verse>I sing to GOD the Praise-Lofty, and find myself safe and saved.</verse>
<verse>The waves of death crashed over me, devil waters rushed over me.</verse>
<verse>Hell's ropes cinched me tight; death traps barred every exit.</verse>
<verse>A hostile world! I called to GOD, to my God I cried out. From his palace he heard me call; my cry brought me right into his presence--a private audience!</verse>
<verse>Earth wobbled and lurched; the very heavens shook like leaves, Quaked like aspen leaves because of his rage.</verse>
<verse>His nostrils flared, billowing smoke; his mouth spit fire. Tongues of fire darted in and out;</verse>
<verse>he lowered the sky. He stepped down; under his feet an abyss opened up.</verse>
<verse>He rode a winged creature, swift on wind-wings.</verse>
<verse>He wrapped himself in a trenchcoat of black rain-cloud darkness.</verse>
<verse>But his cloud-brightness burst through, a grand comet of fireworks.</verse>
<verse>Then GOD thundered out of heaven; the High God gave a great shout.</verse>
<verse>God shot his arrows--pandemonium! He hurled his lightnings--a rout!</verse>
<verse>The secret sources of ocean were exposed, the hidden depths of earth lay uncovered The moment GOD roared in protest, let loose his hurricane anger.</verse>
<verse>But me he caught--reached all the way from sky to sea; he pulled me out</verse>
<verse>Of that ocean of hate, that enemy chaos, the void in which I was drowning.</verse>
<verse>They hit me when I was down, but GOD stuck by me.</verse>
<verse>He stood me up on a wide-open field; I stood there saved--surprised to be loved!</verse>
<verse>GOD made my life complete when I placed all the pieces before him. When I cleaned up my act, he gave me a fresh start.</verse>
<verse>Indeed, I've kept alert to GOD's ways; I haven't taken God for granted.</verse>
<verse>Every day I review the ways he works, I try not to miss a trick.</verse>
<verse>I feel put back together, and I'm watching my step.</verse>
<verse>GOD rewrote the text of my life when I opened the book of my heart to his eyes.</verse>
<verse>You stick by people who stick with you, you're straight with people who're straight with you,</verse>
<verse>You're good to good people, you shrewdly work around the bad ones.</verse>
<verse>You take the side of the down-and-out, but the stuck-up you take down a peg.</verse>
<verse>Suddenly, GOD, your light floods my path, GOD drives out the darkness.</verse>
<verse>I smash the bands of marauders, I vault the high fences.</verse>
<verse>What a God! His road stretches straight and smooth. Every GOD-direction is road-tested. Everyone who runs toward him Makes it.</verse>
<verse>Is there any god like GOD? Are we not at bedrock?</verse>
<verse>Is not this the God who armed me well, then aimed me in the right direction?</verse>
<verse>Now I run like a deer; I'm king of the mountain.</verse>
<verse>He shows me how to fight; I can bend a bronze bow!</verse>
<verse>You protect me with salvation-armor; you touch me and I feel ten feet tall.</verse>
<verse>You cleared the ground under me so my footing was firm.</verse>
<verse>When I chased my enemies I caught them; I didn't let go till they were dead men.</verse>
<verse>I nailed them; they were down for good; then I walked all over them.</verse>
<verse>You armed me well for this fight; you smashed the upstarts.</verse>
<verse>You made my enemies turn tail, and I wiped out the haters.</verse>
<verse>They cried "uncle" but Uncle didn't come; They yelled for GOD and got no for an answer.</verse>
<verse>I ground them to dust; they gusted in the wind. I threw them out, like garbage in the gutter.</verse>
<verse>You rescued me from a squabbling people; you made me a leader of nations. People I'd never heard of served me;</verse>
<verse>the moment they got wind of me they submitted.</verse>
<verse>They gave up; they came trembling from their hideouts.</verse>
<verse>Live, GOD! Blessing to my Rock, my towering Salvation-God!</verse>
<verse>This God set things right for me and shut up the people who talked back.</verse>
<verse>He rescued me from enemy anger. You pulled me from the grip of upstarts, You saved me from the bullies.</verse>
<verse>That's why I'm thanking you, GOD, all over the world. That's why I'm singing songs that rhyme your name.</verse>
<verse>God's king takes the trophy; God's chosen is beloved. I mean David and all his children--always.</verse>
</chapter>