<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="2 Samuel" book-id="10" n="4">
<verse>Saul's son, Ish-Bosheth, heard that Abner had died in Hebron. His heart sank. The whole country was shaken.</verse>
<verse>Ish-Bosheth had two men who were captains of raiding bands--one was named Baanah, the other Recab. They were sons of Rimmon the Beerothite, a Benjaminite. (The people of Beeroth had been assigned to Benjamin</verse>
<verse>ever since they escaped to Gittaim. They still live there as resident aliens.)</verse>
<verse>It so happened that Saul's son, Jonathan, had a son who was maimed in both feet. When he was five years old, the report on Saul and Jonathan came from Jezreel. His nurse picked him up and ran, but in her hurry to get away she fell, and the boy was maimed. His name was Mephibosheth.</verse>
<verse>One day Baanah and Recab, the two sons of Rimmon, headed out for the house of Ish-Bosheth. They arrived at the hottest time of the day, just as he was taking his afternoon nap.</verse>
<verse>They entered the house on a ruse, pretending official business. The maid guarding the bedroom had fallen asleep, so Recab and Baanah slipped by her</verse>
<verse>and entered the room where Ish-Bosheth was asleep on his bed. They killed him and then cut off his head, carrying it off as a trophy. They traveled all night long, taking the route through the Arabah Valley.</verse>
<verse>They presented the head of Ish-Bosheth to David at Hebron, telling the king, "Here's the head of Ish-Bosheth, Saul's son, your enemy. He was out to kill you, but GOD has given vengeance to my master, the king--vengeance this very day on Saul and his children!"</verse>
<verse>David answered the brothers Recab and Baanah, sons of Rimmon the Beerothite, "As surely as GOD lives--the One who got me out of every trouble I've ever been in</verse>
<verse>-when the messenger told me, "Good news! Saul is dead!' supposing I'd be delighted, I arrested him and killed him on the spot in Ziklag. That's what he got for his so-called good news!</verse>
<verse>And now you show up--evil men who killed an innocent man in cold blood, a man asleep in his own house! Don't think I won't find you guilty of murder and rid the country of you!"</verse>
<verse>David then issued orders to his soldiers. They killed the two--chopped off their hands and feet, and hung the corpses at the pool in Hebron. But Ish-Bosheth's head they took and buried in Abner's tomb in Hebron.</verse>
</chapter>