<chapter translation="NASB" testament="New" book="Ephesians" book-id="49" n="3">
<verse>For this reason I, Paul, the prisoner of Christ Jesus for the sake of you Gentiles--</verse>
<verse>if indeed you have heard of the stewardship of God's grace which was given to me for you;</verse>
<verse>that by revelation there was made known to me the mystery, as I wrote before in brief.</verse>
<verse>By referring to this, when you read you can understand my insight into the mystery of Christ,</verse>
<verse>which in other generations was not made known to the sons of men, as it has now been revealed to His holy apostles and prophets in the Spirit;</verse>
<verse>to be specific, that the Gentiles are fellow heirs and fellow members of the body, and fellow partakers of the promise in Christ Jesus through the gospel,</verse>
<verse>of which I was made a minister, according to the gift of God's grace which was given to me according to the working of His power.</verse>
<verse>To me, the very least of all saints, this grace was given, to preach to the Gentiles the unfathomable riches of Christ,</verse>
<verse>and to bring to light what is the administration of the mystery which for ages has been hidden in God who created all things;</verse>
<verse>so that the manifold wisdom of God might now be made known through the church to the rulers and the authorities in the heavenly places.</verse>
<verse>This was in accordance with the eternal purpose which He carried out in Christ Jesus our Lord,</verse>
<verse>in whom we have boldness and confident access through faith in Him.</verse>
<verse>Therefore I ask you not to lose heart at my tribulations on your behalf, for they are your glory.</verse>
<verse>For this reason I bow my knees before the Father,</verse>
<verse>from whom every family in heaven and on earth derives its name,</verse>
<verse>that He would grant you, according to the riches of His glory, to be strengthened with power through His Spirit in the inner man,</verse>
<verse>so that Christ may dwell in your hearts through faith; and that you, being rooted and grounded in love,</verse>
<verse>may be able to comprehend with all the saints what is the breadth and length and height and depth,</verse>
<verse>and to know the love of Christ which surpasses knowledge, that you may be filled up to all the fullness of God.</verse>
<verse>Now to Him who is able to do far more abundantly beyond all that we ask or think, according to the power that works within us,</verse>
<verse>to Him be the glory in the church and in Christ Jesus to all generations forever and ever. Amen.</verse>
</chapter>