<chapter translation="NASB" testament="New" book="Ephesians" book_id="49" n="5">
<verse>Therefore be imitators of God, as beloved children;</verse>
<verse>and walk in love, just as Christ also loved you and gave Himself up for us, an offering and a sacrifice to God as a fragrant aroma.</verse>
<verse>But immorality or any impurity or greed must not even be named among you, as is proper among saints;</verse>
<verse>and there must be no filthiness and silly talk, or coarse jesting, which are not fitting, but rather giving of thanks.</verse>
<verse>For this you know with certainty, that no immoral or impure person or covetous man, who is an idolater, has an inheritance in the kingdom of Christ and God.</verse>
<verse>Let no one deceive you with empty words, for because of these things the wrath of God comes upon the sons of disobedience.</verse>
<verse>Therefore do not be partakers with them;</verse>
<verse>for you were formerly darkness, but now you are Light in the Lord; walk as children of Light</verse>
<verse>(for the fruit of the Light consists in all goodness and righteousness and truth),</verse>
<verse>trying to learn what is pleasing to the Lord.</verse>
<verse>Do not participate in the unfruitful deeds of darkness, but instead even expose them;</verse>
<verse>for it is disgraceful even to speak of the things which are done by them in secret.</verse>
<verse>But all things become visible when they are exposed by the light, for everything that becomes visible is light.</verse>
<verse>For this reason it says, "Awake, sleeper, And arise from the dead, And Christ will shine on you."</verse>
<verse>Therefore be careful how you walk, not as unwise men but as wise,</verse>
<verse>making the most of your time, because the days are evil.</verse>
<verse>So then do not be foolish, but understand what the will of the Lord is.</verse>
<verse>And do not get drunk with wine, for that is dissipation, but be filled with the Spirit,</verse>
<verse>speaking to one another in psalms and hymns and spiritual songs, singing and making melody with your heart to the Lord;</verse>
<verse>always giving thanks for all things in the name of our Lord Jesus Christ to God, even the Father;</verse>
<verse>and be subject to one another in the fear of Christ.</verse>
<verse>Wives, be subject to your own husbands, as to the Lord.</verse>
<verse>For the husband is the head of the wife, as Christ also is the head of the church, He Himself being the Savior of the body.</verse>
<verse>But as the church is subject to Christ, so also the wives ought to be to their husbands in everything.</verse>
<verse>Husbands, love your wives, just as Christ also loved the church and gave Himself up for her,</verse>
<verse>so that He might sanctify her, having cleansed her by the washing of water with the word,</verse>
<verse>that He might present to Himself the church in all her glory, having no spot or wrinkle or any such thing; but that she would be holy and blameless.</verse>
<verse>So husbands ought also to love their own wives as their own bodies. He who loves his own wife loves himself;</verse>
<verse>for no one ever hated his own flesh, but nourishes and cherishes it, just as Christ also does the church,</verse>
<verse>because we are members of His body.</verse>
<verse>FOR THIS REASON A MAN SHALL LEAVE HIS FATHER AND MOTHER AND SHALL BE JOINED TO HIS WIFE, AND THE TWO SHALL BECOME ONE FLESH.</verse>
<verse>This mystery is great; but I am speaking with reference to Christ and the church.</verse>
<verse>Nevertheless, each individual among you also is to love his own wife even as himself, and the wife must see to it that she respects her husband.</verse>
</chapter>