<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Amos" book_id="30" n="2">
<verse>Thus says the LORD, "For three transgressions of Moab and for four I will not revoke its punishment, Because he burned the bones of the king of Edom to lime.</verse>
<verse>"So I will send fire upon Moab And it will consume the citadels of Kerioth; And Moab will die amid tumult, With war cries and the sound of a trumpet.</verse>
<verse>"I will also cut off the judge from her midst And slay all her princes with him," says the LORD.</verse>
<verse>Thus says the LORD, "For three transgressions of Judah and for four I will not revoke its punishment, Because they rejected the law of the LORD And have not kept His statutes; Their lies also have led them astray, Those after which their fathers walked.</verse>
<verse>"So I will send fire upon Judah And it will consume the citadels of Jerusalem."</verse>
<verse>Thus says the LORD, "For three transgressions of Israel and for four I will not revoke its punishment, Because they sell the righteous for money And the needy for a pair of sandals.</verse>
<verse>"These who pant after the very dust of the earth on the head of the helpless Also turn aside the way of the humble; And a man and his father resort to the same girl In order to profane My holy name.</verse>
<verse>"On garments taken as pledges they stretch out beside every altar, And in the house of their God they drink the wine of those who have been fined.</verse>
<verse>"Yet it was I who destroyed the Amorite before them, Though his height was like the height of cedars And he was strong as the oaks; I even destroyed his fruit above and his root below.</verse>
<verse>"It was I who brought you up from the land of Egypt, And I led you in the wilderness forty years That you might take possession of the land of the Amorite.</verse>
<verse>"Then I raised up some of your sons to be prophets And some of your young men to be Nazirites. Is this not so, O sons of Israel?" declares the LORD.</verse>
<verse>"But you made the Nazirites drink wine, And you commanded the prophets saying, 'You shall not prophesy!'</verse>
<verse>"Behold, I am weighted down beneath you As a wagon is weighted down when filled with sheaves.</verse>
<verse>"Flight will perish from the swift, And the stalwart will not strengthen his power, Nor the mighty man save his life.</verse>
<verse>"He who grasps the bow will not stand his ground, The swift of foot will not escape, Nor will he who rides the horse save his life.</verse>
<verse>"Even the bravest among the warriors will flee naked in that day," declares the LORD.</verse>
</chapter>