<chapter translation="NIV" testament="New" book="Acts" book-id="44" n="24">
<verse>Five days later the high priest Ananias went down to Caesarea with some of the elders and a lawyer named Tertullus, and they brought their charges against Paul before the governor.</verse>
<verse>When Paul was called in, Tertullus presented his case before Felix: "We have enjoyed a long period of peace under you, and your foresight has brought about reforms in this nation.</verse>
<verse>Everywhere and in every way, most excellent Felix, we acknowledge this with profound gratitude.</verse>
<verse>But in order not to weary you further, I would request that you be kind enough to hear us briefly.</verse>
<verse>"We have found this man to be a troublemaker, stirring up riots among the Jews all over the world. He is a ringleader of the Nazarene sect</verse>
<verse>and even tried to desecrate the temple; so we seized him.</verse>
<verse>See Footnote</verse>
<verse>By examining him yourself you will be able to learn the truth about all these charges we are bringing against him."</verse>
<verse>The Jews joined in the accusation, asserting that these things were true.</verse>
<verse>When the governor motioned for him to speak, Paul replied: "I know that for a number of years you have been a judge over this nation; so I gladly make my defense.</verse>
<verse>You can easily verify that no more than twelve days ago I went up to Jerusalem to worship.</verse>
<verse>My accusers did not find me arguing with anyone at the temple, or stirring up a crowd in the synagogues or anywhere else in the city.</verse>
<verse>And they cannot prove to you the charges they are now making against me.</verse>
<verse>However, I admit that I worship the God of our fathers as a follower of the Way, which they call a sect. I believe everything that agrees with the Law and that is written in the Prophets,</verse>
<verse>and I have the same hope in God as these men, that there will be a resurrection of both the righteous and the wicked.</verse>
<verse>So I strive always to keep my conscience clear before God and man.</verse>
<verse>"After an absence of several years, I came to Jerusalem to bring my people gifts for the poor and to present offerings.</verse>
<verse>I was ceremonially clean when they found me in the temple courts doing this. There was no crowd with me, nor was I involved in any disturbance.</verse>
<verse>But there are some Jews from the province of Asia, who ought to be here before you and bring charges if they have anything against me.</verse>
<verse>Or these who are here should state what crime they found in me when I stood before the Sanhedrin--</verse>
<verse>unless it was this one thing I shouted as I stood in their presence: 'It is concerning the resurrection of the dead that I am on trial before you today.'"</verse>
<verse>Then Felix, who was well acquainted with the Way, adjourned the proceedings. "When Lysias the commander comes," he said, "I will decide your case."</verse>
<verse>He ordered the centurion to keep Paul under guard but to give him some freedom and permit his friends to take care of his needs.</verse>
<verse>Several days later Felix came with his wife Drusilla, who was a Jewess. He sent for Paul and listened to him as he spoke about faith in Christ Jesus.</verse>
<verse>As Paul discoursed on righteousness, self-control and the judgment to come, Felix was afraid and said, "That's enough for now! You may leave. When I find it convenient, I will send for you."</verse>
<verse>At the same time he was hoping that Paul would offer him a bribe, so he sent for him frequently and talked with him.</verse>
<verse>When two years had passed, Felix was succeeded by Porcius Festus, but because Felix wanted to grant a favor to the Jews, he left Paul in prison.</verse>
</chapter>