<chapter translation="NIV" testament="New" book="Acts" book_id="44" n="26">
<verse>Then Agrippa said to Paul, "You have permission to speak for yourself." So Paul motioned with his hand and began his defense:</verse>
<verse>"King Agrippa, I consider myself fortunate to stand before you today as I make my defense against all the accusations of the Jews,</verse>
<verse>and especially so because you are well acquainted with all the Jewish customs and controversies. Therefore, I beg you to listen to me patiently.</verse>
<verse>"The Jews all know the way I have lived ever since I was a child, from the beginning of my life in my own country, and also in Jerusalem.</verse>
<verse>They have known me for a long time and can testify, if they are willing, that according to the strictest sect of our religion, I lived as a Pharisee.</verse>
<verse>And now it is because of my hope in what God has promised our fathers that I am on trial today.</verse>
<verse>This is the promise our twelve tribes are hoping to see fulfilled as they earnestly serve God day and night. O king, it is because of this hope that the Jews are accusing me.</verse>
<verse>Why should any of you consider it incredible that God raises the dead?</verse>
<verse>"I too was convinced that I ought to do all that was possible to oppose the name of Jesus of Nazareth.</verse>
<verse>And that is just what I did in Jerusalem. On the authority of the chief priests I put many of the saints in prison, and when they were put to death, I cast my vote against them.</verse>
<verse>Many a time I went from one synagogue to another to have them punished, and I tried to force them to blaspheme. In my obsession against them, I even went to foreign cities to persecute them.</verse>
<verse>"On one of these journeys I was going to Damascus with the authority and commission of the chief priests.</verse>
<verse>About noon, O king, as I was on the road, I saw a light from heaven, brighter than the sun, blazing around me and my companions.</verse>
<verse>We all fell to the ground, and I heard a voice saying to me in Aramaic, 'Saul, Saul, why do you persecute me? It is hard for you to kick against the goads.'</verse>
<verse>"Then I asked, 'Who are you, Lord?'</verse>
<verse>"'I am Jesus, whom you are persecuting,' the Lord replied. 'Now get up and stand on your feet. I have appeared to you to appoint you as a servant and as a witness of what you have seen of me and what I will show you.</verse>
<verse>I will rescue you from your own people and from the Gentiles. I am sending you to them</verse>
<verse>to open their eyes and turn them from darkness to light, and from the power of Satan to God, so that they may receive forgiveness of sins and a place among those who are sanctified by faith in me.'</verse>
<verse>"So then, King Agrippa, I was not disobedient to the vision from heaven.</verse>
<verse>First to those in Damascus, then to those in Jerusalem and in all Judea, and to the Gentiles also, I preached that they should repent and turn to God and prove their repentance by their deeds.</verse>
<verse>That is why the Jews seized me in the temple courts and tried to kill me.</verse>
<verse>But I have had God's help to this very day, and so I stand here and testify to small and great alike. I am saying nothing beyond what the prophets and Moses said would happen--</verse>
<verse>that the Christ would suffer and, as the first to rise from the dead, would proclaim light to his own people and to the Gentiles."</verse>
<verse>At this point Festus interrupted Paul's defense. "You are out of your mind, Paul!" he shouted. "Your great learning is driving you insane."</verse>
<verse>"I am not insane, most excellent Festus," Paul replied. "What I am saying is true and reasonable.</verse>
<verse>The king is familiar with these things, and I can speak freely to him. I am convinced that none of this has escaped his notice, because it was not done in a corner.</verse>
<verse>King Agrippa, do you believe the prophets? I know you do."</verse>
<verse>Then Agrippa said to Paul, "Do you think that in such a short time you can persuade me to be a Christian?"</verse>
<verse>Paul replied, "Short time or long--I pray God that not only you but all who are listening to me today may become what I am, except for these chains."</verse>
<verse>The king rose, and with him the governor and Bernice and those sitting with them.</verse>
<verse>They left the room, and while talking with one another, they said, "This man is not doing anything that deserves death or imprisonment."</verse>
<verse>Agrippa said to Festus, "This man could have been set free if he had not appealed to Caesar."</verse>
</chapter>