<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Proverbs" book_id="20" n="1">
<verse>The proverbs of Solomon son of David, king of Israel:</verse>
<verse>for attaining wisdom and discipline; for understanding words of insight;</verse>
<verse>for acquiring a disciplined and prudent life, doing what is right and just and fair;</verse>
<verse>for giving prudence to the simple, knowledge and discretion to the young-</verse>
<verse>let the wise listen and add to their learning, and let the discerning get guidance-</verse>
<verse>for understanding proverbs and parables, the sayings and riddles of the wise.</verse>
<verse>The fear of the Lord is the beginning of knowledge, but fools despise wisdom and discipline.</verse>
<verse>Listen, my son, to your father's instruction and do not forsake your mother's teaching.</verse>
<verse>They will be a garland to grace your head and a chain to adorn your neck.</verse>
<verse>My son, if sinners entice you, do not give in to them.</verse>
<verse>If they say, "Come along with us; let's lie in wait for someone's blood, let's waylay some harmless soul;</verse>
<verse>let's swallow them alive, like the grave, and whole, like those who go down to the pit;</verse>
<verse>we will get all sorts of valuable things and fill our houses with plunder;</verse>
<verse>throw in your lot with us, and we will share a common purse"-</verse>
<verse>my son, do not go along with them, do not set foot on their paths;</verse>
<verse>for their feet rush into sin, they are swift to shed blood.</verse>
<verse>How useless to spread a net in full view of all the birds!</verse>
<verse>These men lie in wait for their own blood; they waylay only themselves!</verse>
<verse>Such is the end of all who go after ill-gotten gain; it takes away the lives of those who get it.</verse>
<verse>Wisdom calls aloud in the street, she raises her voice in the public squares;</verse>
<verse>at the head of the noisy streets she cries out, in the gateways of the city she makes her speech:</verse>
<verse>"How long will you simple ones love your simple ways? How long will mockers delight in mockery and fools hate knowledge?</verse>
<verse>If you had responded to my rebuke, I would have poured out my heart to you and made my thoughts known to you.</verse>
<verse>But since you rejected me when I called and no one gave heed when I stretched out my hand,</verse>
<verse>since you ignored all my advice and would not accept my rebuke,</verse>
<verse>I in turn will laugh at your disaster; I will mock when calamity overtakes you-</verse>
<verse>when calamity overtakes you like a storm, when disaster sweeps over you like a whirlwind, when distress and trouble overwhelm you.</verse>
<verse>"Then they will call to me but I will not answer; they will look for me but will not find me.</verse>
<verse>Since they hated knowledge and did not choose to fear the LORD,</verse>
<verse>since they would not accept my advice and spurned my rebuke,</verse>
<verse>they will eat the fruit of their ways and be filled with the fruit of their schemes.</verse>
<verse>For the waywardness of the simple will kill them, and the complacency of fools will destroy them;</verse>
<verse>but whoever listens to me will live in safety and be at ease, without fear of harm."</verse>
</chapter>