<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Proverbs" book_id="20" n="10">
<verse>The proverbs of Solomon: A wise son brings joy to his father, but a foolish son grief to his mother.</verse>
<verse>Ill-gotten treasures are of no value, but righteousness delivers from death.</verse>
<verse>The LORD does not let the righteous go hungry but he thwarts the craving of the wicked.</verse>
<verse>Lazy hands make a man poor, but diligent hands bring wealth.</verse>
<verse>He who gathers crops in summer is a wise son, but he who sleeps during harvest is a disgraceful son.</verse>
<verse>Blessings crown the head of the righteous, but violence overwhelms the mouth of the wicked.</verse>
<verse>The memory of the righteous will be a blessing, but the name of the wicked will rot.</verse>
<verse>The wise in heart accept commands, but a chattering fool comes to ruin.</verse>
<verse>The man of integrity walks securely, but he who takes crooked paths will be found out.</verse>
<verse>He who winks maliciously causes grief, and a chattering fool comes to ruin.</verse>
<verse>The mouth of the righteous is a fountain of life, but violence overwhelms the mouth of the wicked.</verse>
<verse>Hatred stirs up dissension, but love covers over all wrongs.</verse>
<verse>Wisdom is found on the lips of the discerning, but a rod is for the back of him who lacks judgment.</verse>
<verse>Wise men store up knowledge, but the mouth of a fool invites ruin.</verse>
<verse>The wealth of the rich is their fortified city, but poverty is the ruin of the poor.</verse>
<verse>The wages of the righteous bring them life, but the income of the wicked brings them punishment.</verse>
<verse>He who heeds discipline shows the way to life, but whoever ignores correction leads others astray.</verse>
<verse>He who conceals his hatred has lying lips, and whoever spreads slander is a fool.</verse>
<verse>When words are many, sin is not absent, but he who holds his tongue is wise.</verse>
<verse>The tongue of the righteous is choice silver, but the heart of the wicked is of little value.</verse>
<verse>The lips of the righteous nourish many, but fools die for lack of judgment.</verse>
<verse>The blessing of the LORD brings wealth, and he adds no trouble to it.</verse>
<verse>A fool finds pleasure in evil conduct, but a man of understanding delights in wisdom.</verse>
<verse>What the wicked dreads will overtake him; what the righteous desire will be granted.</verse>
<verse>When the storm has swept by, the wicked are gone, but the righteous stand firm forever.</verse>
<verse>As vinegar to the teeth and smoke to the eyes, so is a sluggard to those who send him.</verse>
<verse>The fear of the LORD adds length to life, but the years of the wicked are cut short.</verse>
<verse>The prospect of the righteous is joy, but the hopes of the wicked come to nothing.</verse>
<verse>The way of the LORD is a refuge for the righteous, but it is the ruin of those who do evil.</verse>
<verse>The righteous will never be uprooted, but the wicked will not remain in the land.</verse>
<verse>The mouth of the righteous brings forth wisdom, but a perverse tongue will be cut out.</verse>
<verse>The lips of the righteous know what is fitting, but the mouth of the wicked only what is perverse.</verse>
</chapter>