<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Proverbs" book-id="20" n="11">
<verse>The LORD abhors dishonest scales, but accurate weights are his delight.</verse>
<verse>When pride comes, then comes disgrace, but with humility comes wisdom.</verse>
<verse>The integrity of the upright guides them, but the unfaithful are destroyed by their duplicity.</verse>
<verse>Wealth is worthless in the day of wrath, but righteousness delivers from death.</verse>
<verse>The righteousness of the blameless makes a straight way for them, but the wicked are brought down by their own wickedness.</verse>
<verse>The righteousness of the upright delivers them, but the unfaithful are trapped by evil desires.</verse>
<verse>When a wicked man dies, his hope perishes; all he expected from his power comes to nothing.</verse>
<verse>The righteous man is rescued from trouble, and it comes on the wicked instead.</verse>
<verse>With his mouth the godless destroys his neighbor, but through knowledge the righteous escape.</verse>
<verse>When the righteous prosper, the city rejoices; when the wicked perish, there are shouts of joy.</verse>
<verse>Through the blessing of the upright a city is exalted, but by the mouth of the wicked it is destroyed.</verse>
<verse>A man who lacks judgment derides his neighbor, but a man of understanding holds his tongue.</verse>
<verse>A gossip betrays a confidence, but a trustworthy man keeps a secret.</verse>
<verse>For lack of guidance a nation falls, but many advisers make victory sure.</verse>
<verse>He who puts up security for another will surely suffer, but whoever refuses to strike hands in pledge is safe.</verse>
<verse>A kindhearted woman gains respect, but ruthless men gain only wealth.</verse>
<verse>A kind man benefits himself, but a cruel man brings trouble on himself.</verse>
<verse>The wicked man earns deceptive wages, but he who sows righteousness reaps a sure reward.</verse>
<verse>The truly righteous man attains life, but he who pursues evil goes to his death.</verse>
<verse>The LORD detests men of perverse heart but he delights in those whose ways are blameless.</verse>
<verse>Be sure of this: The wicked will not go unpunished, but those who are righteous will go free.</verse>
<verse>Like a gold ring in a pig's snout is a beautiful woman who shows no discretion.</verse>
<verse>The desire of the righteous ends only in good, but the hope of the wicked only in wrath.</verse>
<verse>One man gives freely, yet gains even more; another withholds unduly, but comes to poverty.</verse>
<verse>A generous man will prosper; he who refreshes others will himself be refreshed.</verse>
<verse>People curse the man who hoards grain, but blessing crowns him who is willing to sell.</verse>
<verse>He who seeks good finds goodwill, but evil comes to him who searches for it.</verse>
<verse>Whoever trusts in his riches will fall, but the righteous will thrive like a green leaf.</verse>
<verse>He who brings trouble on his family will inherit only wind, and the fool will be servant to the wise.</verse>
<verse>The fruit of the righteous is a tree of life, and he who wins souls is wise.</verse>
<verse>If the righteous receive their due on earth, how much more the ungodly and the sinner!</verse>
</chapter>