<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Proverbs" book-id="20" n="12">
<verse>Whoever loves discipline loves knowledge, but he who hates correction is stupid.</verse>
<verse>A good man obtains favor from the LORD, but the LORD condemns a crafty man.</verse>
<verse>A man cannot be established through wickedness, but the righteous cannot be uprooted.</verse>
<verse>A wife of noble character is her husband's crown, but a disgraceful wife is like decay in his bones.</verse>
<verse>The plans of the righteous are just, but the advice of the wicked is deceitful.</verse>
<verse>The words of the wicked lie in wait for blood, but the speech of the upright rescues them.</verse>
<verse>Wicked men are overthrown and are no more, but the house of the righteous stands firm.</verse>
<verse>A man is praised according to his wisdom, but men with warped minds are despised.</verse>
<verse>Better to be a nobody and yet have a servant than pretend to be somebody and have no food.</verse>
<verse>A righteous man cares for the needs of his animal, but the kindest acts of the wicked are cruel.</verse>
<verse>He who works his land will have abundant food, but he who chases fantasies lacks judgment.</verse>
<verse>The wicked desire the plunder of evil men, but the root of the righteous flourishes.</verse>
<verse>An evil man is trapped by his sinful talk, but a righteous man escapes trouble.</verse>
<verse>From the fruit of his lips a man is filled with good things as surely as the work of his hands rewards him.</verse>
<verse>The way of a fool seems right to him, but a wise man listens to advice.</verse>
<verse>A fool shows his annoyance at once, but a prudent man overlooks an insult.</verse>
<verse>A truthful witness gives honest testimony, but a false witness tells lies.</verse>
<verse>Reckless words pierce like a sword, but the tongue of the wise brings healing.</verse>
<verse>Truthful lips endure forever, but a lying tongue lasts only a moment.</verse>
<verse>There is deceit in the hearts of those who plot evil, but joy for those who promote peace.</verse>
<verse>No harm befalls the righteous, but the wicked have their fill of trouble.</verse>
<verse>The LORD detests lying lips, but he delights in men who are truthful.</verse>
<verse>A prudent man keeps his knowledge to himself, but the heart of fools blurts out folly.</verse>
<verse>Diligent hands will rule, but laziness ends in slave labor.</verse>
<verse>An anxious heart weighs a man down, but a kind word cheers him up.</verse>
<verse>A righteous man is cautious in friendship, but the way of the wicked leads them astray.</verse>
<verse>The lazy man does not roast his game, but the diligent man prizes his possessions.</verse>
<verse>In the way of righteousness there is life; along that path is immortality.</verse>
</chapter>