<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Proverbs" book-id="20" n="13">
<verse>A wise son heeds his father's instruction, but a mocker does not listen to rebuke.</verse>
<verse>From the fruit of his lips a man enjoys good things, but the unfaithful have a craving for violence.</verse>
<verse>He who guards his lips guards his life, but he who speaks rashly will come to ruin.</verse>
<verse>The sluggard craves and gets nothing, but the desires of the diligent are fully satisfied.</verse>
<verse>The righteous hate what is false, but the wicked bring shame and disgrace.</verse>
<verse>Righteousness guards the man of integrity, but wickedness overthrows the sinner.</verse>
<verse>One man pretends to be rich, yet has nothing; another pretends to be poor, yet has great wealth.</verse>
<verse>A man's riches may ransom his life, but a poor man hears no threat.</verse>
<verse>The light of the righteous shines brightly, but the lamp of the wicked is snuffed out.</verse>
<verse>Pride only breeds quarrels, but wisdom is found in those who take advice.</verse>
<verse>Dishonest money dwindles away, but he who gathers money little by little makes it grow.</verse>
<verse>Hope deferred makes the heart sick, but a longing fulfilled is a tree of life.</verse>
<verse>He who scorns instruction will pay for it, but he who respects a command is rewarded.</verse>
<verse>The teaching of the wise is a fountain of life, turning a man from the snares of death.</verse>
<verse>Good understanding wins favor, but the way of the unfaithful is hard.</verse>
<verse>Every prudent man acts out of knowledge, but a fool exposes his folly.</verse>
<verse>A wicked messenger falls into trouble, but a trustworthy envoy brings healing.</verse>
<verse>He who ignores discipline comes to poverty and shame, but whoever heeds correction is honored.</verse>
<verse>A longing fulfilled is sweet to the soul, but fools detest turning from evil.</verse>
<verse>He who walks with the wise grows wise, but a companion of fools suffers harm.</verse>
<verse>Misfortune pursues the sinner, but prosperity is the reward of the righteous.</verse>
<verse>A good man leaves an inheritance for his children's children, but a sinner's wealth is stored up for the righteous.</verse>
<verse>A poor man's field may produce abundant food, but injustice sweeps it away.</verse>
<verse>He who spares the rod hates his son, but he who loves him is careful to discipline him.</verse>
<verse>The righteous eat to their hearts' content, but the stomach of the wicked goes hungry.</verse>
</chapter>