<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Proverbs" book_id="20" n="15">
<verse>A gentle answer turns away wrath, but a harsh word stirs up anger.</verse>
<verse>The tongue of the wise commends knowledge, but the mouth of the fool gushes folly.</verse>
<verse>The eyes of the LORD are everywhere, keeping watch on the wicked and the good.</verse>
<verse>The tongue that brings healing is a tree of life, but a deceitful tongue crushes the spirit.</verse>
<verse>A fool spurns his father's discipline, but whoever heeds correction shows prudence.</verse>
<verse>The house of the righteous contains great treasure, but the income of the wicked brings them trouble.</verse>
<verse>The lips of the wise spread knowledge; not so the hearts of fools.</verse>
<verse>The LORD detests the sacrifice of the wicked, but the prayer of the upright pleases him.</verse>
<verse>The LORD detests the way of the wicked but he loves those who pursue righteousness.</verse>
<verse>Stern discipline awaits him who leaves the path; he who hates correction will die.</verse>
<verse>Death and Destruction lie open before the LORD - how much more the hearts of men!</verse>
<verse>A mocker resents correction; he will not consult the wise.</verse>
<verse>A happy heart makes the face cheerful, but heartache crushes the spirit.</verse>
<verse>The discerning heart seeks knowledge, but the mouth of a fool feeds on folly.</verse>
<verse>All the days of the oppressed are wretched, but the cheerful heart has a continual feast.</verse>
<verse>Better a little with the fear of the LORD than great wealth with turmoil.</verse>
<verse>Better a meal of vegetables where there is love than a fattened calf with hatred.</verse>
<verse>A hot-tempered man stirs up dissension, but a patient man calms a quarrel.</verse>
<verse>The way of the sluggard is blocked with thorns, but the path of the upright is a highway.</verse>
<verse>A wise son brings joy to his father, but a foolish man despises his mother.</verse>
<verse>Folly delights a man who lacks judgment, but a man of understanding keeps a straight course.</verse>
<verse>Plans fail for lack of counsel, but with many advisers they succeed.</verse>
<verse>A man finds joy in giving an apt reply- and how good is a timely word!</verse>
<verse>The path of life leads upward for the wise to keep him from going down to the grave.</verse>
<verse>The LORD tears down the proud man's house but he keeps the widow's boundaries intact.</verse>
<verse>The LORD detests the thoughts of the wicked, but those of the pure are pleasing to him.</verse>
<verse>A greedy man brings trouble to his family, but he who hates bribes will live.</verse>
<verse>The heart of the righteous weighs its answers, but the mouth of the wicked gushes evil.</verse>
<verse>The LORD is far from the wicked but he hears the prayer of the righteous.</verse>
<verse>A cheerful look brings joy to the heart, and good news gives health to the bones.</verse>
<verse>He who listens to a life-giving rebuke will be at home among the wise.</verse>
<verse>He who ignores discipline despises himself, but whoever heeds correction gains understanding.</verse>
<verse>The fear of the LORD teaches a man wisdom, and humility comes before honor.</verse>
</chapter>