<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Proverbs" book-id="20" n="16">
<verse>To man belong the plans of the heart, but from the LORD comes the reply of the tongue.</verse>
<verse>All a man's ways seem innocent to him, but motives are weighed by the LORD.</verse>
<verse>Commit to the LORD whatever you do, and your plans will succeed.</verse>
<verse>The LORD works out everything for his own ends- even the wicked for a day of disaster.</verse>
<verse>The LORD detests all the proud of heart. Be sure of this: They will not go unpunished.</verse>
<verse>Through love and faithfulness sin is atoned for; through the fear of the LORD a man avoids evil.</verse>
<verse>When a man's ways are pleasing to the LORD, he makes even his enemies live at peace with him.</verse>
<verse>Better a little with righteousness than much gain with injustice.</verse>
<verse>In his heart a man plans his course, but the LORD determines his steps.</verse>
<verse>The lips of a king speak as an oracle, and his mouth should not betray justice.</verse>
<verse>Honest scales and balances are from the LORD; all the weights in the bag are of his making.</verse>
<verse>Kings detest wrongdoing, for a throne is established through righteousness.</verse>
<verse>Kings take pleasure in honest lips; they value a man who speaks the truth.</verse>
<verse>A king's wrath is a messenger of death, but a wise man will appease it.</verse>
<verse>When a king's face brightens, it means life; his favor is like a rain cloud in spring.</verse>
<verse>How much better to get wisdom than gold, to choose understanding rather than silver!</verse>
<verse>The highway of the upright avoids evil; he who guards his way guards his life.</verse>
<verse>Pride goes before destruction, a haughty spirit before a fall.</verse>
<verse>Better to be lowly in spirit and among the oppressed than to share plunder with the proud.</verse>
<verse>Whoever gives heed to instruction prospers, and blessed is he who trusts in the LORD.</verse>
<verse>The wise in heart are called discerning, and pleasant words promote instruction.</verse>
<verse>Understanding is a fountain of life to those who have it, but folly brings punishment to fools.</verse>
<verse>A wise man's heart guides his mouth, and his lips promote instruction.</verse>
<verse>Pleasant words are a honeycomb, sweet to the soul and healing to the bones.</verse>
<verse>There is a way that seems right to a man, but in the end it leads to death.</verse>
<verse>The laborer's appetite works for him; his hunger drives him on.</verse>
<verse>A scoundrel plots evil, and his speech is like a scorching fire.</verse>
<verse>A perverse man stirs up dissension, and a gossip separates close friends.</verse>
<verse>A violent man entices his neighbor and leads him down a path that is not good.</verse>
<verse>He who winks with his eye is plotting perversity; he who purses his lips is bent on evil.</verse>
<verse>Gray hair is a crown of splendor; it is attained by a righteous life.</verse>
<verse>Better a patient man than a warrior, a man who controls his temper than one who takes a city.</verse>
<verse>The lot is cast into the lap, but its every decision is from the LORD.</verse>
</chapter>