<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Proverbs" book-id="20" n="17">
<verse>Better a dry crust with peace and quiet than a house full of feasting, with strife.</verse>
<verse>A wise servant will rule over a disgraceful son, and will share the inheritance as one of the brothers.</verse>
<verse>The crucible for silver and the furnace for gold, but the LORD tests the heart.</verse>
<verse>A wicked man listens to evil lips; a liar pays attention to a malicious tongue.</verse>
<verse>He who mocks the poor shows contempt for their Maker; whoever gloats over disaster will not go unpunished.</verse>
<verse>Children's children are a crown to the aged, and parents are the pride of their children.</verse>
<verse>Arrogant lips are unsuited to a fool- how much worse lying lips to a ruler!</verse>
<verse>A bribe is a charm to the one who gives it; wherever he turns, he succeeds.</verse>
<verse>He who covers over an offense promotes love, but whoever repeats the matter separates close friends.</verse>
<verse>A rebuke impresses a man of discernment more than a hundred lashes a fool.</verse>
<verse>An evil man is bent only on rebellion; a merciless official will be sent against him.</verse>
<verse>Better to meet a bear robbed of her cubs than a fool in his folly.</verse>
<verse>If a man pays back evil for good, evil will never leave his house.</verse>
<verse>Starting a quarrel is like breaching a dam; so drop the matter before a dispute breaks out.</verse>
<verse>Acquitting the guilty and condemning the innocent- the LORD detests them both.</verse>
<verse>Of what use is money in the hand of a fool, since he has no desire to get wisdom?</verse>
<verse>A friend loves at all times, and a brother is born for adversity.</verse>
<verse>A man lacking in judgment strikes hands in pledge and puts up security for his neighbor.</verse>
<verse>He who loves a quarrel loves sin; he who builds a high gate invites destruction.</verse>
<verse>A man of perverse heart does not prosper; he whose tongue is deceitful falls into trouble.</verse>
<verse>To have a fool for a son brings grief; there is no joy for the father of a fool.</verse>
<verse>A cheerful heart is good medicine, but a crushed spirit dries up the bones.</verse>
<verse>A wicked man accepts a bribe in secret to pervert the course of justice.</verse>
<verse>A discerning man keeps wisdom in view, but a fool's eyes wander to the ends of the earth.</verse>
<verse>A foolish son brings grief to his father and bitterness to the one who bore him.</verse>
<verse>It is not good to punish an innocent man, or to flog officials for their integrity.</verse>
<verse>A man of knowledge uses words with restraint, and a man of understanding is even-tempered.</verse>
<verse>Even a fool is thought wise if he keeps silent, and discerning if he holds his tongue.</verse>
</chapter>