<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Proverbs" book_id="20" n="19">
<verse>Better a poor man whose walk is blameless than a fool whose lips are perverse.</verse>
<verse>It is not good to have zeal without knowledge, nor to be hasty and miss the way.</verse>
<verse>A man's own folly ruins his life, yet his heart rages against the LORD.</verse>
<verse>Wealth brings many friends, but a poor man's friend deserts him.</verse>
<verse>A false witness will not go unpunished, and he who pours out lies will not go free.</verse>
<verse>Many curry favor with a ruler, and everyone is the friend of a man who gives gifts.</verse>
<verse>A poor man is shunned by all his relatives- how much more do his friends avoid him! Though he pursues them with pleading, they are nowhere to be found.</verse>
<verse>He who gets wisdom loves his own soul; he who cherishes understanding prospers.</verse>
<verse>A false witness will not go unpunished, and he who pours out lies will perish.</verse>
<verse>It is not fitting for a fool to live in luxury- how much worse for a slave to rule over princes!</verse>
<verse>A man's wisdom gives him patience; it is to his glory to overlook an offense.</verse>
<verse>A king's rage is like the roar of a lion, but his favor is like dew on the grass.</verse>
<verse>A foolish son is his father's ruin, and a quarrelsome wife is like a constant dripping.</verse>
<verse>Houses and wealth are inherited from parents, but a prudent wife is from the LORD.</verse>
<verse>Laziness brings on deep sleep, and the shiftless man goes hungry.</verse>
<verse>He who obeys instructions guards his life, but he who is contemptuous of his ways will die.</verse>
<verse>He who is kind to the poor lends to the LORD, and he will reward him for what he has done.</verse>
<verse>Discipline your son, for in that there is hope; do not be a willing party to his death.</verse>
<verse>A hot-tempered man must pay the penalty; if you rescue him, you will have to do it again.</verse>
<verse>Listen to advice and accept instruction, and in the end you will be wise.</verse>
<verse>Many are the plans in a man's heart, but it is the LORD's purpose that prevails.</verse>
<verse>What a man desires is unfailing love; better to be poor than a liar.</verse>
<verse>The fear of the LORD leads to life: Then one rests content, untouched by trouble.</verse>
<verse>The sluggard buries his hand in the dish; he will not even bring it back to his mouth!</verse>
<verse>Flog a mocker, and the simple will learn prudence; rebuke a discerning man, and he will gain knowledge.</verse>
<verse>He who robs his father and drives out his mother is a son who brings shame and disgrace.</verse>
<verse>Stop listening to instruction, my son, and you will stray from the words of knowledge.</verse>
<verse>A corrupt witness mocks at justice, and the mouth of the wicked gulps down evil.</verse>
<verse>Penalties are prepared for mockers, and beatings for the backs of fools.</verse>
</chapter>