<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Proverbs" book_id="20" n="2">
<verse>My son, if you accept my words and store up my commands within you,</verse>
<verse>turning your ear to wisdom and applying your heart to understanding,</verse>
<verse>and if you call out for insight and cry aloud for understanding,</verse>
<verse>and if you look for it as for silver and search for it as for hidden treasure,</verse>
<verse>then you will understand the fear of the LORD and find the knowledge of God.</verse>
<verse>For the LORD gives wisdom, and from his mouth come knowledge and understanding.</verse>
<verse>He holds victory in store for the upright, he is a shield to those whose walk is blameless,</verse>
<verse>for he guards the course of the just and protects the way of his faithful ones.</verse>
<verse>Then you will understand what is right and just and fair-every good path.</verse>
<verse>For wisdom will enter your heart, and knowledge will be pleasant to your soul.</verse>
<verse>Discretion will protect you, and understanding will guard you.</verse>
<verse>Wisdom will save you from the ways of wicked men, from men whose words are perverse,</verse>
<verse>who leave the straight paths to walk in dark ways,</verse>
<verse>who delight in doing wrong and rejoice in the perverseness of evil,</verse>
<verse>whose paths are crooked and who are devious in their ways.</verse>
<verse>It will save you also from the adulteress, from the wayward wife with her seductive words,</verse>
<verse>who has left the partner of her youth and ignored the covenant she made before God.</verse>
<verse>For her house leads down to death and her paths to the spirits of the dead.</verse>
<verse>None who go to her return or attain the paths of life.</verse>
<verse>Thus you will walk in the ways of good men and keep to the paths of the righteous.</verse>
<verse>For the upright will live in the land, and the blameless will remain in it;</verse>
<verse>but the wicked will be cut off from the land, and the unfaithful will be torn from it.</verse>
</chapter>