<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Proverbs" book_id="20" n="20">
<verse>Wine is a mocker and beer a brawler; whoever is led astray by them is not wise.</verse>
<verse>A king's wrath is like the roar of a lion; he who angers him forfeits his life.</verse>
<verse>It is to a man's honor to avoid strife, but every fool is quick to quarrel.</verse>
<verse>A sluggard does not plow in season; so at harvest time he looks but finds nothing.</verse>
<verse>The purposes of a man's heart are deep waters, but a man of understanding draws them out.</verse>
<verse>Many a man claims to have unfailing love, but a faithful man who can find?</verse>
<verse>The righteous man leads a blameless life; blessed are his children after him.</verse>
<verse>When a king sits on his throne to judge, he winnows out all evil with his eyes.</verse>
<verse>Who can say, "I have kept my heart pure; I am clean and without sin"?</verse>
<verse>Differing weights and differing measures- the LORD detests them both.</verse>
<verse>Even a child is known by his actions, by whether his conduct is pure and right.</verse>
<verse>Ears that hear and eyes that see- the LORD has made them both.</verse>
<verse>Do not love sleep or you will grow poor; stay awake and you will have food to spare.</verse>
<verse>"It's no good, it's no good!" says the buyer; then off he goes and boasts about his purchase.</verse>
<verse>Gold there is, and rubies in abundance, but lips that speak knowledge are a rare jewel.</verse>
<verse>Take the garment of one who puts up security for a stranger; hold it in pledge if he does it for a wayward woman.</verse>
<verse>Food gained by fraud tastes sweet to a man, but he ends up with a mouth full of gravel.</verse>
<verse>Make plans by seeking advice; if you wage war, obtain guidance.</verse>
<verse>A gossip betrays a confidence; so avoid a man who talks too much.</verse>
<verse>If a man curses his father or mother, his lamp will be snuffed out in pitch darkness.</verse>
<verse>An inheritance quickly gained at the beginning will not be blessed at the end.</verse>
<verse>Do not say, "I'll pay you back for this wrong!" Wait for the LORD, and he will deliver you.</verse>
<verse>The LORD detests differing weights, and dishonest scales do not please him.</verse>
<verse>A man's steps are directed by the LORD. How then can anyone understand his own way?</verse>
<verse>It is a trap for a man to dedicate something rashly and only later to consider his vows.</verse>
<verse>A wise king winnows out the wicked; he drives the threshing wheel over them.</verse>
<verse>The lamp of the LORD searches the spirit of a man; it searches out his inmost being.</verse>
<verse>Love and faithfulness keep a king safe; through love his throne is made secure.</verse>
<verse>The glory of young men is their strength, gray hair the splendor of the old.</verse>
<verse>Blows and wounds cleanse away evil, and beatings purge the inmost being.</verse>
</chapter>