<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Proverbs" book-id="20" n="22">
<verse>A good name is more desirable than great riches; to be esteemed is better than silver or gold.</verse>
<verse>Rich and poor have this in common: The LORD is the Maker of them all.</verse>
<verse>A prudent man sees danger and takes refuge, but the simple keep going and suffer for it.</verse>
<verse>Humility and the fear of the LORD bring wealth and honor and life.</verse>
<verse>In the paths of the wicked lie thorns and snares, but he who guards his soul stays far from them.</verse>
<verse>Train a child in the way he should go, and when he is old he will not turn from it.</verse>
<verse>The rich rule over the poor, and the borrower is servant to the lender.</verse>
<verse>He who sows wickedness reaps trouble, and the rod of his fury will be destroyed.</verse>
<verse>A generous man will himself be blessed, for he shares his food with the poor.</verse>
<verse>Drive out the mocker, and out goes strife; quarrels and insults are ended.</verse>
<verse>He who loves a pure heart and whose speech is gracious will have the king for his friend.</verse>
<verse>The eyes of the LORD keep watch over knowledge, but he frustrates the words of the unfaithful.</verse>
<verse>The sluggard says, "There is a lion outside!" or, "I will be murdered in the streets!"</verse>
<verse>The mouth of an adulteress is a deep pit; he who is under the LORD's wrath will fall into it.</verse>
<verse>Folly is bound up in the heart of a child, but the rod of discipline will drive it far from him.</verse>
<verse>He who oppresses the poor to increase his wealth and he who gives gifts to the rich-both come to poverty.</verse>
<verse>Pay attention and listen to the sayings of the wise; apply your heart to what I teach,</verse>
<verse>for it is pleasing when you keep them in your heart and have all of them ready on your lips.</verse>
<verse>So that your trust may be in the LORD, I teach you today, even you.</verse>
<verse>Have I not written thirty sayings for you, sayings of counsel and knowledge,</verse>
<verse>teaching you true and reliable words, so that you can give sound answers to him who sent you?</verse>
<verse>Do not exploit the poor because they are poor and do not crush the needy in court,</verse>
<verse>for the LORD will take up their case and will plunder those who plunder them.</verse>
<verse>Do not make friends with a hot-tempered man, do not associate with one easily angered,</verse>
<verse>or you may learn his ways and get yourself ensnared.</verse>
<verse>Do not be a man who strikes hands in pledge or puts up security for debts;</verse>
<verse>if you lack the means to pay, your very bed will be snatched from under you.</verse>
<verse>Do not move an ancient boundary stone set up by your forefathers.</verse>
<verse>Do you see a man skilled in his work? He will serve before kings; he will not serve before obscure men.</verse>
</chapter>