<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Proverbs" book_id="20" n="25">
<verse>These are more proverbs of Solomon, copied by the men of Hezekiah king of Judah:</verse>
<verse>It is the glory of God to conceal a matter; to search out a matter is the glory of kings.</verse>
<verse>As the heavens are high and the earth is deep, so the hearts of kings are unsearchable.</verse>
<verse>Remove the dross from the silver, and out comes material for the silversmith;</verse>
<verse>remove the wicked from the king's presence, and his throne will be established through righteousness.</verse>
<verse>Do not exalt yourself in the king's presence, and do not claim a place among great men;</verse>
<verse>it is better for him to say to you, "Come up here," than for him to humiliate you before a nobleman. What you have seen with your eyes</verse>
<verse>do not bring hastily to court, for what will you do in the end if your neighbor puts you to shame?</verse>
<verse>If you argue your case with a neighbor, do not betray another man's confidence,</verse>
<verse>or he who hears it may shame you and you will never lose your bad reputation.</verse>
<verse>A word aptly spoken is like apples of gold in settings of silver.</verse>
<verse>Like an earring of gold or an ornament of fine gold is a wise man's rebuke to a listening ear.</verse>
<verse>Like the coolness of snow at harvest time is a trustworthy messenger to those who send him; he refreshes the spirit of his masters.</verse>
<verse>Like clouds and wind without rain is a man who boasts of gifts he does not give.</verse>
<verse>Through patience a ruler can be persuaded, and a gentle tongue can break a bone.</verse>
<verse>If you find honey, eat just enough- too much of it, and you will vomit.</verse>
<verse>Seldom set foot in your neighbor's house- too much of you, and he will hate you.</verse>
<verse>Like a club or a sword or a sharp arrow is the man who gives false testimony against his neighbor.</verse>
<verse>Like a bad tooth or a lame foot is reliance on the unfaithful in times of trouble.</verse>
<verse>Like one who takes away a garment on a cold day, or like vinegar poured on soda, is one who sings songs to a heavy heart.</verse>
<verse>If your enemy is hungry, give him food to eat; if he is thirsty, give him water to drink.</verse>
<verse>In doing this, you will heap burning coals on his head, and the LORD will reward you.</verse>
<verse>As a north wind brings rain, so a sly tongue brings angry looks.</verse>
<verse>Better to live on a corner of the roof than share a house with a quarrelsome wife.</verse>
<verse>Like cold water to a weary soul is good news from a distant land.</verse>
<verse>Like a muddied spring or a polluted well is a righteous man who gives way to the wicked.</verse>
<verse>It is not good to eat too much honey, nor is it honorable to seek one's own honor.</verse>
<verse>Like a city whose walls are broken down is a man who lacks self-control.</verse>
</chapter>