<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Proverbs" book_id="20" n="26">
<verse>Like snow in summer or rain in harvest, honor is not fitting for a fool.</verse>
<verse>Like a fluttering sparrow or a darting swallow, an undeserved curse does not come to rest.</verse>
<verse>A whip for the horse, a halter for the donkey, and a rod for the backs of fools!</verse>
<verse>Do not answer a fool according to his folly, or you will be like him yourself.</verse>
<verse>Answer a fool according to his folly, or he will be wise in his own eyes.</verse>
<verse>Like cutting off one's feet or drinking violence is the sending of a message by the hand of a fool.</verse>
<verse>Like a lame man's legs that hang limp is a proverb in the mouth of a fool.</verse>
<verse>Like tying a stone in a sling is the giving of honor to a fool.</verse>
<verse>Like a thornbush in a drunkard's hand is a proverb in the mouth of a fool.</verse>
<verse>Like an archer who wounds at random is he who hires a fool or any passer-by.</verse>
<verse>As a dog returns to its vomit, so a fool repeats his folly.</verse>
<verse>Do you see a man wise in his own eyes? There is more hope for a fool than for him.</verse>
<verse>The sluggard says, "There is a lion in the road, a fierce lion roaming the streets!"</verse>
<verse>As a door turns on its hinges, so a sluggard turns on his bed.</verse>
<verse>The sluggard buries his hand in the dish; he is too lazy to bring it back to his mouth.</verse>
<verse>The sluggard is wiser in his own eyes than seven men who answer discreetly.</verse>
<verse>Like one who seizes a dog by the ears is a passer-by who meddles in a quarrel not his own.</verse>
<verse>Like a madman shooting firebrands or deadly arrows</verse>
<verse>is a man who deceives his neighbor and says, "I was only joking!"</verse>
<verse>Without wood a fire goes out; without gossip a quarrel dies down.</verse>
<verse>As charcoal to embers and as wood to fire, so is a quarrelsome man for kindling strife.</verse>
<verse>The words of a gossip are like choice morsels; they go down to a man's inmost parts.</verse>
<verse>Like a coating of glaze over earthenware are fervent lips with an evil heart.</verse>
<verse>A malicious man disguises himself with his lips, but in his heart he harbors deceit.</verse>
<verse>Though his speech is charming, do not believe him, for seven abominations fill his heart.</verse>
<verse>His malice may be concealed by deception, but his wickedness will be exposed in the assembly.</verse>
<verse>If a man digs a pit, he will fall into it; if a man rolls a stone, it will roll back on him.</verse>
<verse>A lying tongue hates those it hurts, and a flattering mouth works ruin.</verse>
</chapter>