<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Proverbs" book_id="20" n="27">
<verse>Do not boast about tomorrow, for you do not know what a day may bring forth.</verse>
<verse>Let another praise you, and not your own mouth; someone else, and not your own lips.</verse>
<verse>Stone is heavy and sand a burden, but provocation by a fool is heavier than both.</verse>
<verse>Anger is cruel and fury overwhelming, but who can stand before jealousy?</verse>
<verse>Better is open rebuke than hidden love.</verse>
<verse>Wounds from a friend can be trusted, but an enemy multiplies kisses.</verse>
<verse>He who is full loathes honey, but to the hungry even what is bitter tastes sweet.</verse>
<verse>Like a bird that strays from its nest is a man who strays from his home.</verse>
<verse>Perfume and incense bring joy to the heart, and the pleasantness of one's friend springs from his earnest counsel.</verse>
<verse>Do not forsake your friend and the friend of your father, and do not go to your brother's house when disaster strikes you- better a neighbor nearby than a brother far away.</verse>
<verse>Be wise, my son, and bring joy to my heart; then I can answer anyone who treats me with contempt.</verse>
<verse>The prudent see danger and take refuge, but the simple keep going and suffer for it.</verse>
<verse>Take the garment of one who puts up security for a stranger; hold it in pledge if he does it for a wayward woman.</verse>
<verse>If a man loudly blesses his neighbor early in the morning, it will be taken as a curse.</verse>
<verse>A quarrelsome wife is like a constant dripping on a rainy day;</verse>
<verse>restraining her is like restraining the wind or grasping oil with the hand.</verse>
<verse>As iron sharpens iron, so one man sharpens another.</verse>
<verse>He who tends a fig tree will eat its fruit, and he who looks after his master will be honored.</verse>
<verse>As water reflects a face, so a man's heart reflects the man.</verse>
<verse>Death and Destruction are never satisfied, and neither are the eyes of man.</verse>
<verse>The crucible for silver and the furnace for gold, but man is tested by the praise he receives.</verse>
<verse>Though you grind a fool in a mortar, grinding him like grain with a pestle, you will not remove his folly from him.</verse>
<verse>Be sure you know the condition of your flocks, give careful attention to your herds;</verse>
<verse>for riches do not endure forever, and a crown is not secure for all generations.</verse>
<verse>When the hay is removed and new growth appears and the grass from the hills is gathered in,</verse>
<verse>the lambs will provide you with clothing, and the goats with the price of a field.</verse>
<verse>You will have plenty of goats' milk to feed you and your family and to nourish your servant girls.</verse>
</chapter>