<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Proverbs" book_id="20" n="28">
<verse>The wicked man flees though no one pursues, but the righteous are as bold as a lion.</verse>
<verse>When a country is rebellious, it has many rulers, but a man of understanding and knowledge maintains order.</verse>
<verse>A ruler who oppresses the poor is like a driving rain that leaves no crops.</verse>
<verse>Those who forsake the law praise the wicked, but those who keep the law resist them.</verse>
<verse>Evil men do not understand justice, but those who seek the LORD understand it fully.</verse>
<verse>Better a poor man whose walk is blameless than a rich man whose ways are perverse.</verse>
<verse>He who keeps the law is a discerning son, but a companion of gluttons disgraces his father.</verse>
<verse>He who increases his wealth by exorbitant interest amasses it for another, who will be kind to the poor.</verse>
<verse>If anyone turns a deaf ear to the law, even his prayers are detestable.</verse>
<verse>He who leads the upright along an evil path will fall into his own trap, but the blameless will receive a good inheritance.</verse>
<verse>A rich man may be wise in his own eyes, but a poor man who has discernment sees through him.</verse>
<verse>When the righteous triumph, there is great elation; but when the wicked rise to power, men go into hiding.</verse>
<verse>He who conceals his sins does not prosper, but whoever confesses and renounces them finds mercy.</verse>
<verse>Blessed is the man who always fears the LORD, but he who hardens his heart falls into trouble.</verse>
<verse>Like a roaring lion or a charging bear is a wicked man ruling over a helpless people.</verse>
<verse>A tyrannical ruler lacks judgment, but he who hates ill-gotten gain will enjoy a long life.</verse>
<verse>A man tormented by the guilt of murder will be a fugitive till death; let no one support him.</verse>
<verse>He whose walk is blameless is kept safe, but he whose ways are perverse will suddenly fall.</verse>
<verse>He who works his land will have abundant food, but the one who chases fantasies will have his fill of poverty.</verse>
<verse>A faithful man will be richly blessed, but one eager to get rich will not go unpunished.</verse>
<verse>To show partiality is not good- yet a man will do wrong for a piece of bread.</verse>
<verse>A stingy man is eager to get rich and is unaware that poverty awaits him.</verse>
<verse>He who rebukes a man will in the end gain more favor than he who has a flattering tongue.</verse>
<verse>He who robs his father or mother and says, "It's not wrong"- he is partner to him who destroys.</verse>
<verse>A greedy man stirs up dissension, but he who trusts in the LORD will prosper.</verse>
<verse>He who trusts in himself is a fool, but he who walks in wisdom is kept safe.</verse>
<verse>He who gives to the poor will lack nothing, but he who closes his eyes to them receives many curses.</verse>
<verse>When the wicked rise to power, people go into hiding; but when the wicked perish, the righteous thrive.</verse>
</chapter>