<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Proverbs" book_id="20" n="29">
<verse>A man who remains stiff-necked after many rebukes will suddenly be destroyed-without remedy.</verse>
<verse>When the righteous thrive, the people rejoice; when the wicked rule, the people groan.</verse>
<verse>A man who loves wisdom brings joy to his father, but a companion of prostitutes squanders his wealth.</verse>
<verse>By justice a king gives a country stability, but one who is greedy for bribes tears it down.</verse>
<verse>Whoever flatters his neighbor is spreading a net for his feet.</verse>
<verse>An evil man is snared by his own sin, but a righteous one can sing and be glad.</verse>
<verse>The righteous care about justice for the poor, but the wicked have no such concern.</verse>
<verse>Mockers stir up a city, but wise men turn away anger.</verse>
<verse>If a wise man goes to court with a fool, the fool rages and scoffs, and there is no peace.</verse>
<verse>Bloodthirsty men hate a man of integrity and seek to kill the upright.</verse>
<verse>A fool gives full vent to his anger, but a wise man keeps himself under control.</verse>
<verse>If a ruler listens to lies, all his officials become wicked.</verse>
<verse>The poor man and the oppressor have this in common: The LORD gives sight to the eyes of both.</verse>
<verse>If a king judges the poor with fairness, his throne will always be secure.</verse>
<verse>The rod of correction imparts wisdom, but a child left to himself disgraces his mother.</verse>
<verse>When the wicked thrive, so does sin, but the righteous will see their downfall.</verse>
<verse>Discipline your son, and he will give you peace; he will bring delight to your soul.</verse>
<verse>Where there is no revelation, the people cast off restraint; but blessed is he who keeps the law.</verse>
<verse>A servant cannot be corrected by mere words; though he understands, he will not respond.</verse>
<verse>Do you see a man who speaks in haste? There is more hope for a fool than for him.</verse>
<verse>If a man pampers his servant from youth, he will bring grief in the end.</verse>
<verse>An angry man stirs up dissension, and a hot-tempered one commits many sins.</verse>
<verse>A man's pride brings him low, but a man of lowly spirit gains honor.</verse>
<verse>The accomplice of a thief is his own enemy; he is put under oath and dare not testify.</verse>
<verse>Fear of man will prove to be a snare, but whoever trusts in the LORD is kept safe.</verse>
<verse>Many seek an audience with a ruler, but it is from the LORD that man gets justice.</verse>
<verse>The righteous detest the dishonest; the wicked detest the upright.</verse>
</chapter>