<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Proverbs" book-id="20" n="3">
<verse>My son, do not forget my teaching, but keep my commands in your heart,</verse>
<verse>for they will prolong your life many years and bring you prosperity.</verse>
<verse>Let love and faithfulness never leave you; bind them around your neck, write them on the tablet of your heart.</verse>
<verse>Then you will win favor and a good name in the sight of God and man.</verse>
<verse>Trust in the LORD with all your heart and lean not on your own understanding;</verse>
<verse>in all your ways acknowledge him, and he will make your paths straight.</verse>
<verse>Do not be wise in your own eyes; fear the LORD and shun evil.</verse>
<verse>This will bring health to your body and nourishment to your bones.</verse>
<verse>Honor the LORD with your wealth, with the firstfruits of all your crops;</verse>
<verse>then your barns will be filled to overflowing, and your vats will brim over with new wine.</verse>
<verse>My son, do not despise the LORD's discipline and do not resent his rebuke,</verse>
<verse>because the LORD disciplines those he loves, as a father the son he delights in.</verse>
<verse>Blessed is the man who finds wisdom, the man who gains understanding,</verse>
<verse>for she is more profitable than silver and yields better returns than gold.</verse>
<verse>She is more precious than rubies; nothing you desire can compare with her.</verse>
<verse>Long life is in her right hand; in her left hand are riches and honor.</verse>
<verse>Her ways are pleasant ways, and all her paths are peace.</verse>
<verse>She is a tree of life to those who embrace her; those who lay hold of her will be blessed.</verse>
<verse>By wisdom the LORD laid the earth's foundations, by understanding he set the heavens in place;</verse>
<verse>by his knowledge the deeps were divided, and the clouds let drop the dew.</verse>
<verse>My son, preserve sound judgment and discernment, do not let them out of your sight;</verse>
<verse>they will be life for you, an ornament to grace your neck.</verse>
<verse>Then you will go on your way in safety, and your foot will not stumble;</verse>
<verse>when you lie down, you will not be afraid; when you lie down, your sleep will be sweet.</verse>
<verse>Have no fear of sudden disaster or of the ruin that overtakes the wicked,</verse>
<verse>for the LORD will be your confidence and will keep your foot from being snared.</verse>
<verse>Do not withhold good from those who deserve it, when it is in your power to act.</verse>
<verse>Do not say to your neighbor, "Come back later; I'll give it tomorrow"- when you now have it with you.</verse>
<verse>Do not plot harm against your neighbor, who lives trustfully near you.</verse>
<verse>Do not accuse a man for no reason- when he has done you no harm.</verse>
<verse>Do not envy a violent man or choose any of his ways,</verse>
<verse>for the LORD detests a perverse man but takes the upright into his confidence.</verse>
<verse>The LORD's curse is on the house of the wicked, but he blesses the home of the righteous.</verse>
<verse>He mocks proud mockers but gives grace to the humble.</verse>
<verse>The wise inherit honor, but fools he holds up to shame.</verse>
</chapter>