<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Proverbs" book-id="20" n="31">
<verse>The sayings of King Lemuel-an oracle his mother taught him:</verse>
<verse>"O my son, O son of my womb, O son of my vows,</verse>
<verse>do not spend your strength on women, your vigor on those who ruin kings.</verse>
<verse>"It is not for kings, O Lemuel- not for kings to drink wine, not for rulers to crave beer,</verse>
<verse>lest they drink and forget what the law decrees, and deprive all the oppressed of their rights.</verse>
<verse>Give beer to those who are perishing, wine to those who are in anguish;</verse>
<verse>let them drink and forget their poverty and remember their misery no more.</verse>
<verse>"Speak up for those who cannot speak for themselves, for the rights of all who are destitute.</verse>
<verse>Speak up and judge fairly; defend the rights of the poor and needy." Epilogue: The Wife of Noble Character</verse>
<verse>A wife of noble character who can find? She is worth far more than rubies.</verse>
<verse>Her husband has full confidence in her and lacks nothing of value.</verse>
<verse>She brings him good, not harm, all the days of her life.</verse>
<verse>She selects wool and flax and works with eager hands.</verse>
<verse>She is like the merchant ships, bringing her food from afar.</verse>
<verse>She gets up while it is still dark; she provides food for her family and portions for her servant girls.</verse>
<verse>She considers a field and buys it; out of her earnings she plants a vineyard.</verse>
<verse>She sets about her work vigorously; her arms are strong for her tasks.</verse>
<verse>She sees that her trading is profitable, and her lamp does not go out at night.</verse>
<verse>In her hand she holds the distaff and grasps the spindle with her fingers.</verse>
<verse>She opens her arms to the poor and extends her hands to the needy.</verse>
<verse>When it snows, she has no fear for her household; for all of them are clothed in scarlet.</verse>
<verse>She makes coverings for her bed; she is clothed in fine linen and purple.</verse>
<verse>Her husband is respected at the city gate, where he takes his seat among the elders of the land.</verse>
<verse>She makes linen garments and sells them, and supplies the merchants with sashes.</verse>
<verse>She is clothed with strength and dignity; she can laugh at the days to come.</verse>
<verse>She speaks with wisdom, and faithful instruction is on her tongue.</verse>
<verse>She watches over the affairs of her household and does not eat the bread of idleness.</verse>
<verse>Her children arise and call her blessed; her husband also, and he praises her:</verse>
<verse>"Many women do noble things, but you surpass them all."</verse>
<verse>Charm is deceptive, and beauty is fleeting; but a woman who fears the LORD is to be praised.</verse>
<verse>Give her the reward she has earned, and let her works bring her praise at the city gate.</verse>
</chapter>