<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Proverbs" book-id="20" n="4">
<verse>Listen, my sons, to a father's instruction; pay attention and gain understanding.</verse>
<verse>I give you sound learning, so do not forsake my teaching.</verse>
<verse>When I was a boy in my father's house, still tender, and an only child of my mother,</verse>
<verse>he taught me and said, "Lay hold of my words with all your heart; keep my commands and you will live.</verse>
<verse>Get wisdom, get understanding; do not forget my words or swerve from them.</verse>
<verse>Do not forsake wisdom, and she will protect you; love her, and she will watch over you.</verse>
<verse>Wisdom is supreme; therefore get wisdom. Though it cost all you have, get understanding.</verse>
<verse>Esteem her, and she will exalt you; embrace her, and she will honor you.</verse>
<verse>She will set a garland of grace on your head and present you with a crown of splendor."</verse>
<verse>Listen, my son, accept what I say, and the years of your life will be many.</verse>
<verse>I guide you in the way of wisdom and lead you along straight paths.</verse>
<verse>When you walk, your steps will not be hampered; when you run, you will not stumble.</verse>
<verse>Hold on to instruction, do not let it go; guard it well, for it is your life.</verse>
<verse>Do not set foot on the path of the wicked or walk in the way of evil men.</verse>
<verse>Avoid it, do not travel on it; turn from it and go on your way.</verse>
<verse>For they cannot sleep till they do evil; they are robbed of slumber till they make someone fall.</verse>
<verse>They eat the bread of wickedness and drink the wine of violence.</verse>
<verse>The path of the righteous is like the first gleam of dawn, shining ever brighter till the full light of day.</verse>
<verse>But the way of the wicked is like deep darkness; they do not know what makes them stumble.</verse>
<verse>My son, pay attention to what I say; listen closely to my words.</verse>
<verse>Do not let them out of your sight, keep them within your heart;</verse>
<verse>for they are life to those who find them and health to a man's whole body.</verse>
<verse>Above all else, guard your heart, for it is the wellspring of life.</verse>
<verse>Put away perversity from your mouth; keep corrupt talk far from your lips.</verse>
<verse>Let your eyes look straight ahead, fix your gaze directly before you.</verse>
<verse>Make level paths for your feet and take only ways that are firm.</verse>
<verse>Do not swerve to the right or the left; keep your foot from evil.</verse>
</chapter>