<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Proverbs" book_id="20" n="5">
<verse>My son, pay attention to my wisdom, listen well to my words of insight,</verse>
<verse>that you may maintain discretion and your lips may preserve knowledge.</verse>
<verse>For the lips of an adulteress drip honey, and her speech is smoother than oil;</verse>
<verse>but in the end she is bitter as gall, sharp as a double-edged sword.</verse>
<verse>Her feet go down to death; her steps lead straight to the grave.</verse>
<verse>She gives no thought to the way of life; her paths are crooked, but she knows it not.</verse>
<verse>Now then, my sons, listen to me; do not turn aside from what I say.</verse>
<verse>Keep to a path far from her, do not go near the door of her house,</verse>
<verse>lest you give your best strength to others and your years to one who is cruel,</verse>
<verse>lest strangers feast on your wealth and your toil enrich another man's house.</verse>
<verse>At the end of your life you will groan, when your flesh and body are spent.</verse>
<verse>You will say, "How I hated discipline! How my heart spurned correction!</verse>
<verse>I would not obey my teachers or listen to my instructors.</verse>
<verse>I have come to the brink of utter ruin in the midst of the whole assembly."</verse>
<verse>Drink water from your own cistern, running water from your own well.</verse>
<verse>Should your springs overflow in the streets, your streams of water in the public squares?</verse>
<verse>Let them be yours alone, never to be shared with strangers.</verse>
<verse>May your fountain be blessed, and may you rejoice in the wife of your youth.</verse>
<verse>A loving doe, a graceful deer- may her breasts satisfy you always, may you ever be captivated by her love.</verse>
<verse>Why be captivated, my son, by an adulteress? Why embrace the bosom of another man's wife?</verse>
<verse>For a man's ways are in full view of the LORD, and he examines all his paths.</verse>
<verse>The evil deeds of a wicked man ensnare him; the cords of his sin hold him fast.</verse>
<verse>He will die for lack of discipline, led astray by his own great folly.</verse>
</chapter>