<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Proverbs" book-id="20" n="6">
<verse>My son, if you have put up security for your neighbor, if you have struck hands in pledge for another,</verse>
<verse>if you have been trapped by what you said, ensnared by the words of your mouth,</verse>
<verse>then do this, my son, to free yourself, since you have fallen into your neighbor's hands: Go and humble yourself; press your plea with your neighbor!</verse>
<verse>Allow no sleep to your eyes, no slumber to your eyelids.</verse>
<verse>Free yourself, like a gazelle from the hand of the hunter, like a bird from the snare of the fowler.</verse>
<verse>Go to the ant, you sluggard; consider its ways and be wise!</verse>
<verse>It has no commander, no overseer or ruler,</verse>
<verse>yet it stores its provisions in summer and gathers its food at harvest.</verse>
<verse>How long will you lie there, you sluggard? When will you get up from your sleep?</verse>
<verse>A little sleep, a little slumber, a little folding of the hands to rest-</verse>
<verse>and poverty will come on you like a bandit and scarcity like an armed man.</verse>
<verse>A scoundrel and villain, who goes about with a corrupt mouth,</verse>
<verse>who winks with his eye, signals with his feet and motions with his fingers,</verse>
<verse>who plots evil with deceit in his heart- he always stirs up dissension.</verse>
<verse>Therefore disaster will overtake him in an instant; he will suddenly be destroyed-without remedy.</verse>
<verse>There are six things the LORD hates, seven that are detestable to him:</verse>
<verse>haughty eyes, a lying tongue, hands that shed innocent blood,</verse>
<verse>a heart that devises wicked schemes, feet that are quick to rush into evil,</verse>
<verse>a false witness who pours out lies and a man who stirs up dissension among brothers.</verse>
<verse>My son, keep your father's commands and do not forsake your mother's teaching.</verse>
<verse>Bind them upon your heart forever; fasten them around your neck.</verse>
<verse>When you walk, they will guide you; when you sleep, they will watch over you; when you awake, they will speak to you.</verse>
<verse>For these commands are a lamp, this teaching is a light, and the corrections of discipline are the way to life,</verse>
<verse>keeping you from the immoral woman, from the smooth tongue of the wayward wife.</verse>
<verse>Do not lust in your heart after her beauty or let her captivate you with her eyes,</verse>
<verse>for the prostitute reduces you to a loaf of bread, and the adulteress preys upon your very life.</verse>
<verse>Can a man scoop fire into his lap without his clothes being burned?</verse>
<verse>Can a man walk on hot coals without his feet being scorched?</verse>
<verse>So is he who sleeps with another man's wife; no one who touches her will go unpunished.</verse>
<verse>Men do not despise a thief if he steals to satisfy his hunger when he is starving.</verse>
<verse>Yet if he is caught, he must pay sevenfold, though it costs him all the wealth of his house.</verse>
<verse>But a man who commits adultery lacks judgment; whoever does so destroys himself.</verse>
<verse>Blows and disgrace are his lot, and his shame will never be wiped away;</verse>
<verse>for jealousy arouses a husband's fury, and he will show no mercy when he takes revenge.</verse>
<verse>He will not accept any compensation; he will refuse the bribe, however great it is.</verse>
</chapter>