<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Proverbs" book_id="20" n="7">
<verse>My son, keep my words and store up my commands within you.</verse>
<verse>Keep my commands and you will live; guard my teachings as the apple of your eye.</verse>
<verse>Bind them on your fingers; write them on the tablet of your heart.</verse>
<verse>Say to wisdom, "You are my sister," and call understanding your kinsman;</verse>
<verse>they will keep you from the adulteress, from the wayward wife with her seductive words.</verse>
<verse>At the window of my house I looked out through the lattice.</verse>
<verse>I saw among the simple, I noticed among the young men, a youth who lacked judgment.</verse>
<verse>He was going down the street near her corner, walking along in the direction of her house</verse>
<verse>at twilight, as the day was fading, as the dark of night set in.</verse>
<verse>Then out came a woman to meet him, dressed like a prostitute and with crafty intent.</verse>
<verse>(She is loud and defiant, her feet never stay at home;</verse>
<verse>now in the street, now in the squares, at every corner she lurks.)</verse>
<verse>She took hold of him and kissed him and with a brazen face she said:</verse>
<verse>"I have fellowship offerings at home; today I fulfilled my vows.</verse>
<verse>So I came out to meet you; I looked for you and have found you!</verse>
<verse>I have covered my bed with colored linens from Egypt.</verse>
<verse>I have perfumed my bed with myrrh, aloes and cinnamon.</verse>
<verse>Come, let's drink deep of love till morning; let's enjoy ourselves with love!</verse>
<verse>My husband is not at home; he has gone on a long journey.</verse>
<verse>He took his purse filled with money and will not be home till full moon."</verse>
<verse>With persuasive words she led him astray; she seduced him with her smooth talk.</verse>
<verse>All at once he followed her like an ox going to the slaughter, like a deer stepping into a noose</verse>
<verse>till an arrow pierces his liver, like a bird darting into a snare, little knowing it will cost him his life.</verse>
<verse>Now then, my sons, listen to me; pay attention to what I say.</verse>
<verse>Do not let your heart turn to her ways or stray into her paths.</verse>
<verse>Many are the victims she has brought down; her slain are a mighty throng.</verse>
<verse>Her house is a highway to the grave, leading down to the chambers of death.</verse>
</chapter>