<chapter translation="MSG" testament="New" book="1 Thessalonians" book-id="52" n="3">
<verse>So when we couldn't stand being separated from you any longer and could find no way to visit you ourselves, we stayed in Athens</verse>
<verse>and sent Timothy to get you up and about, cheering you on so you wouldn't be discouraged by these hard times. He's a brother and companion in the faith, God's man in spreading the Message, preaching Christ.</verse>
<verse>Not that the troubles should come as any surprise to you. You've always known that we're in for this kind of thing. It's part of our calling.</verse>
<verse>When we were with you, we made it quite clear that there was trouble ahead. And now that it's happened, you know what it's like.</verse>
<verse>That's why I couldn't quit worrying; I had to know for myself how you were doing in the faith. I didn't want the Tempter getting to you and tearing down everything we had built up together.</verse>
<verse>But now that Timothy is back, bringing this terrific report on your faith and love, we feel a lot better. It's especially gratifying to know that you continue to think well of us, and that you want to see us as much as we want to see you!</verse>
<verse>In the middle of our trouble and hard times here, just knowing how you're doing keeps us going.</verse>
<verse>Knowing that your faith is alive keeps us alive.</verse>
<verse>What would be an adequate thanksgiving to offer God for all the joy we experience before him because of you?</verse>
<verse>We do what we can, praying away, night and day, asking for the bonus of seeing your faces again and doing what we can to help when your faith falters.</verse>
<verse>May God our Father himself and our Master Jesus clear the road to you!</verse>
<verse>And may the Master pour on the love so it fills your lives and splashes over on everyone around you, just as it does from us to you.</verse>
<verse>May you be infused with strength and purity, filled with confidence in the presence of God our Father when our Master Jesus arrives with all his followers.</verse>
</chapter>