<chapter translation="NASB" testament="New" book="Titus" book_id="56" n="1">
<verse>Paul, a bond-servant of God and an apostle of Jesus Christ, for the faith of those chosen of God and the knowledge of the truth which is according to godliness,</verse>
<verse>in the hope of eternal life, which God, who cannot lie, promised long ages ago,</verse>
<verse>but at the proper time manifested, even His word, in the proclamation with which I was entrusted according to the commandment of God our Savior,</verse>
<verse>To Titus, my true child in a common faith: Grace and peace from God the Father and Christ Jesus our Savior.</verse>
<verse>For this reason I left you in Crete, that you would set in order what remains and appoint elders in every city as I directed you,</verse>
<verse>namely, if any man is above reproach, the husband of one wife, having children who believe, not accused of dissipation or rebellion.</verse>
<verse>For the overseer must be above reproach as God's steward, not self-willed, not quick-tempered, not addicted to wine, not pugnacious, not fond of sordid gain,</verse>
<verse>but hospitable, loving what is good, sensible, just, devout, self-controlled,</verse>
<verse>holding fast the faithful word which is in accordance with the teaching, so that he will be able both to exhort in sound doctrine and to refute those who contradict.</verse>
<verse>For there are many rebellious men, empty talkers and deceivers, especially those of the circumcision,</verse>
<verse>who must be silenced because they are upsetting whole families, teaching things they should not teach for the sake of sordid gain.</verse>
<verse>One of themselves, a prophet of their own, said, "Cretans are always liars, evil beasts, lazy gluttons."</verse>
<verse>This testimony is true. For this reason reprove them severely so that they may be sound in the faith,</verse>
<verse>not paying attention to Jewish myths and commandments of men who turn away from the truth.</verse>
<verse>To the pure, all things are pure; but to those who are defiled and unbelieving, nothing is pure, but both their mind and their conscience are defiled.</verse>
<verse>They profess to know God, but by their deeds they deny Him, being detestable and disobedient and worthless for any good deed.</verse>
</chapter>