<chapter translation="MSG" testament="New" book="Luke" book_id="42" n="1">
<verse>Forsooth for many men endeavoured to ordain the telling of things, which be filled in us. So many others have tried their hand at putting together a story of the wonderful harvest of Scripture and history that took place among us,</verse>
<verse>using reports handed down by the original eyewitnesses who served this Word with their very lives.</verse>
<verse>Since I have investigated all the reports in close detail, starting from the story's beginning, I decided to write it all out for you, most honorable Theophilus,</verse>
<verse>so you can know beyond the shadow of a doubt the reliability of what you were taught.</verse>
<verse>During the rule of Herod, King of Judea, there was a priest assigned service in the regiment of Abijah. His name was Zachariah. His wife was descended from the daughters of Aaron. Her name was Elizabeth.</verse>
<verse>Together they lived honorably before God, careful in keeping to the ways of the commandments and enjoying a clear conscience before God.</verse>
<verse>But they were childless because Elizabeth could never conceive, and now they were quite old.</verse>
<verse>It so happened that as Zachariah was carrying out his priestly duties before God, working the shift assigned to his regiment,</verse>
<verse>it came his one turn in life to enter the sanctuary of God and burn incense.</verse>
<verse>The congregation was gathered and praying outside the Temple at the hour of the incense offering.</verse>
<verse>Unannounced, an angel of God appeared just to the right of the altar of incense.</verse>
<verse>Zachariah was paralyzed in fear.</verse>
<verse>But the angel reassured him, "Don't fear, Zachariah. Your prayer has been heard. Elizabeth, your wife, will bear a son by you. You are to name him John.</verse>
<verse>You're going to leap like a gazelle for joy, and not only you--many will delight in his birth.</verse>
<verse>He'll achieve great stature with God. "He'll drink neither wine nor beer. He'll be filled with the Holy Spirit from the moment he leaves his mother's womb.</verse>
<verse>He will turn many sons and daughters of Israel back to their God.</verse>
<verse>He will herald God's arrival in the style and strength of Elijah, soften the hearts of parents to children, and kindle devout understanding among hardened skeptics--he'll get the people ready for God."</verse>
<verse>Zachariah said to the angel, "Do you expect me to believe this? I'm an old man and my wife is an old woman."</verse>
<verse>But the angel said, "I am Gabriel, the sentinel of God, sent especially to bring you this glad news.</verse>
<verse>But because you won't believe me, you'll be unable to say a word until the day of your son's birth. Every word I've spoken to you will come true on time--God's time."</verse>
<verse>Meanwhile, the congregation waiting for Zachariah was getting restless, wondering what was keeping him so long in the sanctuary.</verse>
<verse>When he came out and couldn't speak, they knew he had seen a vision. He continued speechless and had to use sign language with the people.</verse>
<verse>When the course of his priestly assignment was completed, he went back home.[</verse>
<verse>It wasn't long before his wife, Elizabeth, conceived. She went off by herself for five months, relishing her pregnancy.</verse>
<verse>"So, this is how God acts to remedy my unfortunate condition!" she said.</verse>
<verse>In the sixth month of Elizabeth's pregnancy, God sent the angel Gabriel to the Galilean village of Nazareth</verse>
<verse>to a virgin engaged to be married to a man descended from David. His name was Joseph, and the virgin's name, Mary.</verse>
<verse>Upon entering, Gabriel greeted her: Good morning! You're beautiful with God's beauty, Beautiful inside and out! God be with you.</verse>
<verse>She was thoroughly shaken, wondering what was behind a greeting like that.</verse>
<verse>But the angel assured her, "Mary, you have nothing to fear. God has a surprise for you:</verse>
<verse>You will become pregnant and give birth to a son and call his name Jesus.</verse>
<verse>He will be great, be called "Son of the Highest.' The Lord God will give him the throne of his father David;</verse>
<verse>He will rule Jacob's house forever--no end, ever, to his kingdom."</verse>
<verse>Mary said to the angel, "But how? I've never slept with a man."</verse>
<verse>The angel answered, The Holy Spirit will come upon you, the power of the Highest hover over you; Therefore, the child you bring to birth will be called Holy, Son of God.</verse>
<verse>"And did you know that your cousin Elizabeth conceived a son, old as she is? Everyone called her barren, and here she is six months' pregnant!</verse>
<verse>Nothing, you see, is impossible with God."</verse>
<verse>And Mary said, Yes, I see it all now: I'm the Lord's maid, ready to serve. Let it be with me just as you say. Then the angel left her.</verse>
<verse>Mary didn't waste a minute. She got up and traveled to a town in Judah in the hill country,</verse>
<verse>straight to Zachariah's house, and greeted Elizabeth.</verse>
<verse>When Elizabeth heard Mary's greeting, the baby in her womb leaped. She was filled with the Holy Spirit,</verse>
<verse>and sang out exuberantly, You're so blessed among women, and the babe in your womb, also blessed!</verse>
<verse>And why am I so blessed that the mother of my Lord visits me?</verse>
<verse>The moment the sound of your greeting entered my ears, The babe in my womb skipped like a lamb for sheer joy.</verse>
<verse>Blessed woman, who believed what God said, believed every word would come true!</verse>
<verse>And Mary said, I'm bursting with God-news;</verse>
<verse>I'm dancing the song of my Savior God.</verse>
<verse>God took one good look at me, and look what happened--I'm the most fortunate woman on earth! What God has done for me will never be forgotten,</verse>
<verse>the God whose very name is holy, set apart from all others.</verse>
<verse>His mercy flows in wave after wave on those who are in awe before him.</verse>
<verse>He bared his arm and showed his strength, scattered the bluffing braggarts.</verse>
<verse>He knocked tyrants off their high horses, pulled victims out of the mud.</verse>
<verse>The starving poor sat down to a banquet; the callous rich were left out in the cold.</verse>
<verse>He embraced his chosen child, Israel; he remembered and piled on the mercies, piled them high.</verse>
<verse>It's exactly what he promised, beginning with Abraham and right up to now.</verse>
<verse>Mary stayed with Elizabeth for three months and then went back to her own home.</verse>
<verse>When Elizabeth was full-term in her pregnancy, she bore a son.</verse>
<verse>Her neighbors and relatives, seeing that God had overwhelmed her with mercy, celebrated with her.</verse>
<verse>On the eighth day, they came to circumcise the child and were calling him Zachariah after his father.</verse>
<verse>But his mother intervened: "No. He is to be called John."</verse>
<verse>"But," they said, "no one in your family is named that."</verse>
<verse>They used sign language to ask Zachariah what he wanted him named.</verse>
<verse>Asking for a tablet, Zachariah wrote, "His name is to be John." That took everyone by surprise.</verse>
<verse>Surprise followed surprise--Zachariah's mouth was now open, his tongue loose, and he was talking, praising God!</verse>
<verse>A deep, reverential fear settled over the neighborhood, and in all that Judean hill country people talked about nothing else.</verse>
<verse>Everyone who heard about it took it to heart, wondering, "What will become of this child? Clearly, God has his hand in this."</verse>
<verse>Then Zachariah was filled with the Holy Spirit and prophesied,</verse>
<verse>Blessed be the Lord, the God of Israel; he came and set his people free.</verse>
<verse>He set the power of salvation in the center of our lives, and in the very house of David his servant,</verse>
<verse>Just as he promised long ago through the preaching of his holy prophets:</verse>
<verse>Deliverance from our enemies and every hateful hand;</verse>
<verse>Mercy to our fathers, as he remembers to do what he said he'd do,</verse>
<verse>What he swore to our father Abraham--</verse>
<verse>a clean rescue from the enemy camp, So we can worship him without a care in the world,</verse>
<verse>made holy before him as long as we live.</verse>
<verse>And you, my child, "Prophet of the Highest," will go ahead of the Master to prepare his ways,</verse>
<verse>Present the offer of salvation to his people, the forgiveness of their sins.</verse>
<verse>Through the heartfelt mercies of our God, God's Sunrise will break in upon us,</verse>
<verse>Shining on those in the darkness, those sitting in the shadow of death, Then showing us the way, one foot at a time, down the path of peace.</verse>
<verse>The child grew up, healthy and spirited. He lived out in the desert until the day he made his prophetic debut in Israel.</verse>
</chapter>