<chapter translation="MSG" testament="New" book="Luke" book_id="42" n="24">
<verse>At the crack of dawn on Sunday, the women came to the tomb carrying the burial spices they had prepared.</verse>
<verse>They found the entrance stone rolled back from the tomb,</verse>
<verse>so they walked in. But once inside, they couldn't find the body of the Master Jesus.</verse>
<verse>They were puzzled, wondering what to make of this. Then, out of nowhere it seemed, two men, light cascading over them, stood there.</verse>
<verse>The women were awestruck and bowed down in worship. The men said, "Why are you looking for the Living One in a cemetery?</verse>
<verse>He is not here, but raised up. Remember how he told you when you were still back in Galilee</verse>
<verse>that he had to be handed over to sinners, be killed on a cross, and in three days rise up?"</verse>
<verse>Then they remembered Jesus' words.</verse>
<verse>They left the tomb and broke the news of all this to the Eleven and the rest.</verse>
<verse>Mary Magdalene, Joanna, Mary the mother of James, and the other women with them kept telling these things to the apostles,</verse>
<verse>but the apostles didn't believe a word of it, thought they were making it all up.</verse>
<verse>But Peter jumped to his feet and ran to the tomb. He stooped to look in and saw a few grave clothes, that's all. He walked away puzzled, shaking his head.</verse>
<verse>That same day two of them were walking to the village Emmaus, about seven miles out of Jerusalem.</verse>
<verse>They were deep in conversation, going over all these things that had happened.</verse>
<verse>In the middle of their talk and questions, Jesus came up and walked along with them.</verse>
<verse>But they were not able to recognize who he was.</verse>
<verse>He asked, "What's this you're discussing so intently as you walk along?" They just stood there, long-faced, like they had lost their best friend.</verse>
<verse>Then one of them, his name was Cleopas, said, "Are you the only one in Jerusalem who hasn't heard what's happened during the last few days?"</verse>
<verse>He said, "What has happened?" They said, "The things that happened to Jesus the Nazarene. He was a man of God, a prophet, dynamic in work and word, blessed by both God and all the people.</verse>
<verse>Then our high priests and leaders betrayed him, got him sentenced to death, and crucified him.</verse>
<verse>And we had our hopes up that he was the One, the One about to deliver Israel. And it is now the third day since it happened.</verse>
<verse>But now some of our women have completely confused us. Early this morning they were at the tomb</verse>
<verse>and couldn't find his body. They came back with the story that they had seen a vision of angels who said he was alive.</verse>
<verse>Some of our friends went off to the tomb to check and found it empty just as the women said, but they didn't see Jesus."</verse>
<verse>Then he said to them, "So thick-headed! So slow-hearted! Why can't you simply believe all that the prophets said?</verse>
<verse>Don't you see that these things had to happen, that the Messiah had to suffer and only then enter into his glory?"</verse>
<verse>Then he started at the beginning, with the Books of Moses, and went on through all the Prophets, pointing out everything in the Scriptures that referred to him.</verse>
<verse>They came to the edge of the village where they were headed. He acted as if he were going on</verse>
<verse>but they pressed him: "Stay and have supper with us. It's nearly evening; the day is done." So he went in with them.</verse>
<verse>And here is what happened: He sat down at the table with them. Taking the bread, he blessed and broke and gave it to them.</verse>
<verse>At that moment, open-eyed, wide-eyed, they recognized him. And then he disappeared.</verse>
<verse>Back and forth they talked. "Didn't we feel on fire as he conversed with us on the road, as he opened up the Scriptures for us?"</verse>
<verse>They didn't waste a minute. They were up and on their way back to Jerusalem. They found the Eleven and their friends gathered together,</verse>
<verse>talking away: "It's really happened! The Master has been raised up--Simon saw him!"</verse>
<verse>Then the two went over everything that happened on the road and how they recognized him when he broke the bread.</verse>
<verse>While they were saying all this, Jesus appeared to them and said, "Peace be with you."</verse>
<verse>They thought they were seeing a ghost and were scared half to death.</verse>
<verse>He continued with them, "Don't be upset, and don't let all these doubting questions take over.</verse>
<verse>Look at my hands; look at my feet--it's really me. Touch me. Look me over from head to toe. A ghost doesn't have muscle and bone like this."</verse>
<verse>As he said this, he showed them his hands and feet.</verse>
<verse>They still couldn't believe what they were seeing. It was too much; it seemed too good to be true. He asked, "Do you have any food here?"</verse>
<verse>They gave him a piece of leftover fish they had cooked.</verse>
<verse>He took it and ate it right before their eyes.</verse>
<verse>Then he said, "Everything I told you while I was with you comes to this: All the things written about me in the Law of Moses, in the Prophets, and in the Psalms have to be fulfilled."</verse>
<verse>He went on to open their understanding of the Word of God, showing them how to read their Bibles this way.</verse>
<verse>He said, "You can see now how it is written that the Messiah suffers, rises from the dead on the third day,</verse>
<verse>and then a total life-change through the forgiveness of sins is proclaimed in his name to all nations--starting from here, from Jerusalem!</verse>
<verse>You're the first to hear and see it. You're the witnesses.</verse>
<verse>What comes next is very important: I am sending what my Father promised to you, so stay here in the city until he arrives, until you're equipped with power from on high."</verse>
<verse>He then led them out of the city over to Bethany. Raising his hands he blessed them,</verse>
<verse>and while blessing them, took his leave, being carried up to heaven.</verse>
<verse>And they were on their knees, worshiping him. They returned to Jerusalem bursting with joy.</verse>
<verse>They spent all their time in the Temple praising God. Yes.</verse>
</chapter>