<chapter translation="MSG" testament="New" book="2 Thessalonians" book-id="53" n="2">
<verse>Now, friends, read these next words carefully. Slow down and don't go jumping to conclusions regarding the day when our Master, Jesus Christ, will come back and we assemble to welcome him.</verse>
<verse>Don't let anyone shake you up or get you excited over some breathless report or rumored letter from me that the day of the Master's arrival has come and gone.</verse>
<verse>Don't fall for any line like that. Before that day comes, a couple of things have to happen. First, the Apostasy. Second, the debut of the Anarchist, a real dog of Satan.</verse>
<verse>He'll defy and then take over every so-called god or altar. Having cleared away the opposition, he'll then set himself up in God's Temple as "God Almighty."</verse>
<verse>Don't you remember me going over all this in detail when I was with you? Are your memories that short?</verse>
<verse>You'll also remember that I told you the Anarchist is being held back until just the right time.</verse>
<verse>That doesn't mean that the spirit of anarchy is not now at work. It is, secretly and underground.</verse>
<verse>But the time will come when the Anarchist will no longer be held back, but will be let loose. But don't worry. The Master Jesus will be right on his heels and blow him away. The Master appears and--puff!-the Anarchist is out of there.</verse>
<verse>The Anarchist's coming is all Satan's work. All his power and signs and miracles are fake,</verse>
<verse>evil sleight of hand that plays to the gallery of those who hate the truth that could save them.</verse>
<verse>And since they're so obsessed with evil, God rubs their noses in it--gives them what they want.</verse>
<verse>Since they refuse to trust truth, they're banished to their chosen world of lies and illusions.</verse>
<verse>Meanwhile, we've got our hands full continually thanking God for you, our good friends--so loved by God! God picked you out as his from the very start. Think of it: included in God's original plan of salvation by the bond of faith in the living truth.</verse>
<verse>This is the life of the Spirit he invited you to through the Message we delivered, in which you get in on the glory of our Master, Jesus Christ.</verse>
<verse>So, friends, take a firm stand, feet on the ground and head high. Keep a tight grip on what you were taught, whether in personal conversation or by our letter.</verse>
<verse>May Jesus himself and God our Father, who reached out in love and surprised you with gifts of unending help and confidence,</verse>
<verse>put a fresh heart in you, invigorate your work, enliven your speech.</verse>
</chapter>