<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Numbers" book-id="4" n="28">
<verse>Then the LORD spoke to Moses, saying,</verse>
<verse>"Command the sons of Israel and say to them, 'You shall be careful to present My offering, My food for My offerings by fire, of a soothing aroma to Me, at their appointed time.'</verse>
<verse>"You shall say to them, 'This is the offering by fire which you shall offer to the LORD: two male lambs one year old without defect as a continual burnt offering every day.</verse>
<verse>'You shall offer the one lamb in the morning and the other lamb you shall offer at twilight;</verse>
<verse>also a tenth of an ephah of fine flour for a grain offering, mixed with a fourth of a hin of beaten oil.</verse>
<verse>'It is a continual burnt offering which was ordained in Mount Sinai as a soothing aroma, an offering by fire to the LORD.</verse>
<verse>'Then the drink offering with it shall be a fourth of a hin for each lamb, in the holy place you shall pour out a drink offering of strong drink to the LORD.</verse>
<verse>'The other lamb you shall offer at twilight; as the grain offering of the morning and as its drink offering, you shall offer it, an offering by fire, a soothing aroma to the LORD.</verse>
<verse>'Then on the sabbath day two male lambs one year old without defect, and two-tenths of an ephah of fine flour mixed with oil as a grain offering, and its drink offering:</verse>
<verse>'This is the burnt offering of every sabbath in addition to the continual burnt offering and its drink offering.</verse>
<verse>'Then at the beginning of each of your months you shall present a burnt offering to the LORD: two bulls and one ram, seven male lambs one year old without defect;</verse>
<verse>and three-tenths of an ephah of fine flour mixed with oil for a grain offering, for each bull; and two-tenths of fine flour mixed with oil for a grain offering, for the one ram;</verse>
<verse>and a tenth of an ephah of fine flour mixed with oil for a grain offering for each lamb, for a burnt offering of a soothing aroma, an offering by fire to the LORD.</verse>
<verse>'Their drink offerings shall be half a hin of wine for a bull and a third of a hin for the ram and a fourth of a hin for a lamb; this is the burnt offering of each month throughout the months of the year.</verse>
<verse>'And one male goat for a sin offering to the LORD; it shall be offered with its drink offering in addition to the continual burnt offering.</verse>
<verse>'Then on the fourteenth day of the first month shall be the LORD'S Passover.</verse>
<verse>'On the fifteenth day of this month shall be a feast, unleavened bread shall be eaten for seven days.</verse>
<verse>'On the first day shall be a holy convocation; you shall do no laborious work.</verse>
<verse>'You shall present an offering by fire, a burnt offering to the LORD: two bulls and one ram and seven male lambs one year old, having them without defect.</verse>
<verse>'For their grain offering, you shall offer fine flour mixed with oil: three-tenths of an ephah for a bull and two-tenths for the ram.</verse>
<verse>'A tenth of an ephah you shall offer for each of the seven lambs;</verse>
<verse>and one male goat for a sin offering to make atonement for you.</verse>
<verse>'You shall present these besides the burnt offering of the morning, which is for a continual burnt offering.</verse>
<verse>'After this manner you shall present daily, for seven days, the food of the offering by fire, of a soothing aroma to the LORD; it shall be presented with its drink offering in addition to the continual burnt offering.</verse>
<verse>'On the seventh day you shall have a holy convocation; you shall do no laborious work.</verse>
<verse>'Also on the day of the first fruits, when you present a new grain offering to the LORD in your Feast of Weeks, you shall have a holy convocation; you shall do no laborious work.</verse>
<verse>'You shall offer a burnt offering for a soothing aroma to the LORD: two young bulls, one ram, seven male lambs one year old;</verse>
<verse>and their grain offering, fine flour mixed with oil: three-tenths of an ephah for each bull, two-tenths for the one ram,</verse>
<verse>a tenth for each of the seven lambs;</verse>
<verse>also one male goat to make atonement for you.</verse>
<verse>'Besides the continual burnt offering and its grain offering, you shall present them with their drink offerings. They shall be without defect.</verse>
</chapter>