<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Amos" book_id="30" n="3">
<verse>Hear this word the LORD has spoken against you, O people of Israel-against the whole family I brought up out of Egypt:</verse>
<verse>"You only have I chosen of all the families of the earth; therefore I will punish you for all your sins."</verse>
<verse>Do two walk together unless they have agreed to do so?</verse>
<verse>Does a lion roar in the thicket when he has no prey? Does he growl in his den when he has caught nothing?</verse>
<verse>Does a bird fall into a trap on the ground where no snare has been set? Does a trap spring up from the earth when there is nothing to catch?</verse>
<verse>When a trumpet sounds in a city, do not the people tremble? When disaster comes to a city, has not the LORD caused it?</verse>
<verse>Surely the Sovereign LORD does nothing without revealing his plan to his servants the prophets.</verse>
<verse>The lion has roared- who will not fear? The Sovereign LORD has spoken- who can but prophesy?</verse>
<verse>Proclaim to the fortresses of Ashdod and to the fortresses of Egypt: "Assemble yourselves on the mountains of Samaria; see the great unrest within her and the oppression among her people."</verse>
<verse>"They do not know how to do right," declares the LORD, "who hoard plunder and loot in their fortresses."</verse>
<verse>Therefore this is what the Sovereign LORD says: "An enemy will overrun the land; he will pull down your strongholds and plunder your fortresses."</verse>
<verse>This is what the LORD says: "As a shepherd saves from the lion's mouth only two leg bones or a piece of an ear, so will the Israelites be saved, those who sit in Samaria on the edge of their beds and in Damascus on their couches. "</verse>
<verse>"Hear this and testify against the house of Jacob," declares the Lord, the LORD God Almighty.</verse>
<verse>"On the day I punish Israel for her sins, I will destroy the altars of Bethel; the horns of the altar will be cut off and fall to the ground.</verse>
<verse>I will tear down the winter house along with the summer house; the houses adorned with ivory will be destroyed and the mansions will be demolished," declares the LORD.</verse>
</chapter>