<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Amos" book-id="30" n="4">
<verse>Hear this word, you cows of Bashan on Mount Samaria, you women who oppress the poor and crush the needy and say to your husbands, "Bring us some drinks!"</verse>
<verse>The Sovereign LORD has sworn by his holiness: "The time will surely come when you will be taken away with hooks, the last of you with fishhooks.</verse>
<verse>You will each go straight out through breaks in the wall, and you will be cast out toward Harmon, "declares the LORD.</verse>
<verse>"Go to Bethel and sin; go to Gilgal and sin yet more. Bring your sacrifices every morning, your tithes every three years.</verse>
<verse>Burn leavened bread as a thank offering and brag about your freewill offerings- boast about them, you Israelites, for this is what you love to do," declares the Sovereign LORD.</verse>
<verse>"I gave you empty stomachs in every city and lack of bread in every town, yet you have not returned to me," declares the LORD.</verse>
<verse>"I also withheld rain from you when the harvest was still three months away. I sent rain on one town, but withheld it from another. One field had rain; another had none and dried up.</verse>
<verse>People staggered from town to town for water but did not get enough to drink, yet you have not returned to me," declares the LORD.</verse>
<verse>"Many times I struck your gardens and vineyards, I struck them with blight and mildew. Locusts devoured your fig and olive trees, yet you have not returned to me," declares the LORD.</verse>
<verse>"I sent plagues among you as I did to Egypt. I killed your young men with the sword, along with your captured horses. I filled your nostrils with the stench of your camps, yet you have not returned to me," declares the LORD.</verse>
<verse>"I overthrew some of you as I overthrew Sodom and Gomorrah. You were like a burning stick snatched from the fire, yet you have not returned to me," declares the LORD.</verse>
<verse>"Therefore this is what I will do to you, Israel, and because I will do this to you, prepare to meet your God, O Israel."</verse>
<verse>He who forms the mountains, creates the wind, and reveals his thoughts to man, he who turns dawn to darkness, and treads the high places of the earth- the LORD God Almighty is his name.</verse>
</chapter>