<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Amos" book-id="30" n="7">
<verse>This is what the Sovereign LORD showed me: He was preparing swarms of locusts after the king's share had been harvested and just as the second crop was coming up.</verse>
<verse>When they had stripped the land clean, I cried out, "Sovereign LORD, forgive! How can Jacob survive? He is so small!"</verse>
<verse>So the LORD relented. "This will not happen," the LORD said.</verse>
<verse>This is what the Sovereign LORD showed me: The Sovereign LORD was calling for judgment by fire; it dried up the great deep and devoured the land.</verse>
<verse>Then I cried out, "Sovereign LORD, I beg you, stop! How can Jacob survive? He is so small!"</verse>
<verse>So the LORD relented. "This will not happen either," the Sovereign LORD said.</verse>
<verse>This is what he showed me: The Lord was standing by a wall that had been built true to plumb, with a plumb line in his hand.</verse>
<verse>And the LORD asked me, "What do you see, Amos?A plumb line," I replied. Then the Lord said, "Look, I am setting a plumb line among my people Israel; I will spare them no longer.</verse>
<verse>"The high places of Isaac will be destroyed and the sanctuaries of Israel will be ruined; with my sword I will rise against the house of Jeroboam."</verse>
<verse>Then Amaziah the priest of Bethel sent a message to Jeroboam king of Israel: "Amos is raising a conspiracy against you in the very heart of Israel. The land cannot bear all his words.</verse>
<verse>For this is what Amos is saying: "'Jeroboam will die by the sword, and Israel will surely go into exile, away from their native land.'"</verse>
<verse>Then Amaziah said to Amos, "Get out, you seer! Go back to the land of Judah. Earn your bread there and do your prophesying there.</verse>
<verse>Don't prophesy anymore at Bethel, because this is the king's sanctuary and the temple of the kingdom."</verse>
<verse>Amos answered Amaziah, "I was neither a prophet nor a prophet's son, but I was a shepherd, and I also took care of sycamore-fig trees.</verse>
<verse>But the LORD took me from tending the flock and said to me, 'Go, prophesy to my people Israel.'</verse>
<verse>Now then, hear the word of the LORD. You say, "'Do not prophesy against Israel, and stop preaching against the house of Isaac.'</verse>
<verse>"Therefore this is what the LORD says: "'Your wife will become a prostitute in the city, and your sons and daughters will fall by the sword. Your land will be measured and divided up, and you yourself will die in a pagan country. And Israel will certainly go into exile, away from their native land.'"</verse>
</chapter>