<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Amos" book_id="30" n="8">
<verse>This is what the Sovereign LORD showed me: a basket of ripe fruit.</verse>
<verse>"What do you see, Amos?" he asked. "A basket of ripe fruit," I answered. Then the LORD said to me, "The time is ripe for my people Israel; I will spare them no longer.</verse>
<verse>"In that day," declares the Sovereign LORD, "the songs in the temple will turn to wailing. Many, many bodies-flung everywhere! Silence!"</verse>
<verse>Hear this, you who trample the needy and do away with the poor of the land,</verse>
<verse>saying, "When will the New Moon be over that we may sell grain, and the Sabbath be ended that we may market wheat?"- skimping the measure, boosting the price and cheating with dishonest scales,</verse>
<verse>buying the poor with silver and the needy for a pair of sandals, selling even the sweepings with the wheat.</verse>
<verse>The LORD has sworn by the Pride of Jacob: "I will never forget anything they have done.</verse>
<verse>"Will not the land tremble for this, and all who live in it mourn? The whole land will rise like the Nile; it will be stirred up and then sink like the river of Egypt.</verse>
<verse>"In that day," declares the Sovereign LORD, "I will make the sun go down at noon and darken the earth in broad daylight.</verse>
<verse>I will turn your religious feasts into mourning and all your singing into weeping. I will make all of you wear sackcloth and shave your heads. I will make that time like mourning for an only son and the end of it like a bitter day.</verse>
<verse>"The days are coming," declares the Sovereign LORD, "when I will send a famine through the land- not a famine of food or a thirst for water, but a famine of hearing the words of the LORD.</verse>
<verse>Men will stagger from sea to sea and wander from north to east, searching for the word of the LORD, but they will not find it.</verse>
<verse>"In that day "the lovely young women and strong young men will faint because of thirst.</verse>
<verse>They who swear by the shame of Samaria, or say, 'As surely as your god lives, O Dan,' or, 'As surely as the god of Beersheba lives'- they will fall, never to rise again."</verse>
</chapter>