<?xml version="1.0"?>
<chapter translation="KJV" testament="Old" book="Job" n="14" book-id="18">
      <verse>Man <supplied>that is</supplied> born of a woman <supplied>is</supplied> of few days, and full of trouble.
</verse><verse>He cometh forth like a flower, and is cut down: he fleeth also as a shadow, and continueth not.
</verse><verse>And dost thou open thine eyes upon such an one, and bringest me into judgment with thee?
</verse><verse>Who can bring a clean <supplied>thing</supplied> out of an unclean? not one.
</verse><verse>Seeing his days <supplied>are</supplied> determined, the number of his months <supplied>are</supplied> with thee, thou hast appointed his bounds that he cannot pass;
</verse><verse>Turn from him, that he may rest, till he shall accomplish, as an hireling, his day.
</verse><verse>For there is hope of a tree, if it be cut down, that it will sprout again, and that the tender branch thereof will not cease.
</verse><verse>Though the root thereof wax old in the earth, and the stock thereof die in the ground;
</verse><verse><supplied>Yet</supplied> through the scent of water it will bud, and bring forth boughs like a plant.
</verse><verse>But man dieth, and wasteth away: yea, man giveth up the ghost, and where <supplied>is</supplied> he?
</verse><verse><supplied>As</supplied> the waters fail from the sea, and the flood decayeth and drieth up:
</verse><verse>So man lieth down, and riseth not: till the heavens <supplied>be</supplied> no more, they shall not awake, nor be raised out of their sleep.
</verse><verse>Oh that thou wouldest hide me in the grave, that thou wouldest keep me secret, until thy wrath be past, that thou wouldest appoint me a set time, and remember me!
</verse><verse>If a man die, shall he live <supplied>again?</supplied> all the days of my appointed time will I wait, till my change come.
</verse><verse>Thou shalt call, and I will answer thee: thou wilt have a desire to the work of thine hands.
</verse><verse>For now thou numberest my steps: dost thou not watch over my sin?
</verse><verse>My transgression <supplied>is</supplied> sealed up in a bag, and thou sewest up mine iniquity.
</verse><verse>And surely the mountain falling cometh to nought, and the rock is removed out of his place.
</verse><verse>The waters wear the stones: thou washest away the things which grow <supplied>out</supplied> of the dust of the earth; and thou destroyest the hope of man.
</verse><verse>Thou prevailest for ever against him, and he passeth: thou changest his countenance, and sendest him away.
</verse><verse>His sons come to honour, and he knoweth <supplied>it</supplied> not; and they are brought low, but he perceiveth <supplied>it</supplied> not of them.
</verse><verse>But his flesh upon him shall have pain, and his soul within him shall mourn.
     
      </verse>
      </chapter>
