<?xml version="1.0"?>
<chapter translation="KJV" testament="Old" book="Job" n="37" book_id="18">
      <verse>At this also my heart trembleth, and is moved out of his place.
</verse><verse>Hear attentively the noise of his voice, and the sound <supplied>that</supplied> goeth out of his mouth.
</verse><verse>He directeth it under the whole heaven, and his lightning unto the ends of the earth.
</verse><verse>After it a voice roareth: he thundereth with the voice of his excellency; and he will not stay them when his voice is heard.
</verse><verse>God thundereth marvellously with his voice; great things doeth he, which we cannot comprehend.
</verse><verse>For he saith to the snow, Be thou <supplied>on</supplied> the earth; likewise to the small rain, and to the great rain of his strength.
</verse><verse>He sealeth up the hand of every man; that all men may know his work.
</verse><verse>Then the beasts go into dens, and remain in their places.
</verse><verse>Out of the south cometh the whirlwind: and cold out of the north.
</verse><verse>By the breath of God frost is given: and the breadth of the waters is straitened.
</verse><verse>Also by watering he wearieth the thick cloud: he scattereth his bright cloud:
</verse><verse>And it is turned round about by his counsels: that they may do whatsoever he commandeth them upon the face of the world in the earth.
</verse><verse>He causeth it to come, whether for correction, or for his land, or for mercy.
</verse><verse>Hearken unto this, O Job: stand still, and consider the wondrous works of God.
</verse><verse>Dost thou know when God disposed them, and caused the light of his cloud to shine?
</verse><verse>Dost thou know the balancings of the clouds, the wondrous works of him which is perfect in knowledge?
</verse><verse>How thy garments <supplied>are</supplied> warm, when he quieteth the earth by the south <supplied>wind? </supplied></verse><verse>Hast thou with him spread out the sky, <supplied>which is</supplied> strong, <supplied>and</supplied> as a molten looking glass?
</verse><verse>Teach us what we shall say unto him; <supplied>for</supplied> we cannot order <supplied>our speech</supplied> by reason of darkness.
</verse><verse>Shall it be told him that I speak? if a man speak, surely he shall be swallowed up.
</verse><verse>And now <supplied>men</supplied> see not the bright light which is in the clouds: but the wind passeth, and cleanseth them.
</verse><verse>Fair weather cometh out of the north: with God is terrible majesty.
</verse><verse><supplied>Touching</supplied> the Almighty, we cannot find him out: <supplied>he is</supplied> excellent in power, and in judgment, and in plenty of justice: he will not afflict.
</verse><verse>Men do therefore fear him: he respecteth not any <supplied>that are</supplied> wise of heart.
     
      </verse>
      </chapter>
