<chapter translation="NASB" testament="New" book="Luke" book-id="42" n="15">
<verse>Now all the tax collectors and the sinners were coming near Him to listen to Him.</verse>
<verse>Both the Pharisees and the scribes began to grumble, saying, "This man receives sinners and eats with them."</verse>
<verse>So He told them this parable, saying,</verse>
<verse>"What man among you, if he has a hundred sheep and has lost one of them, does not leave the ninety-nine in the open pasture and go after the one which is lost until he finds it?</verse>
<verse>"When he has found it, he lays it on his shoulders, rejoicing.</verse>
<verse>"And when he comes home, he calls together his friends and his neighbors, saying to them, 'Rejoice with me, for I have found my sheep which was lost!'</verse>
<verse>"I tell you that in the same way, there will be more joy in heaven over one sinner who repents than over ninety-nine righteous persons who need no repentance.</verse>
<verse>"Or what woman, if she has ten silver coins and loses one coin, does not light a lamp and sweep the house and search carefully until she finds it?</verse>
<verse>"When she has found it, she calls together her friends and neighbors, saying, 'Rejoice with me, for I have found the coin which I had lost!'</verse>
<verse>"In the same way, I tell you, there is joy in the presence of the angels of God over one sinner who repents."</verse>
<verse>And He said, "A man had two sons.</verse>
<verse>"The younger of them said to his father, 'Father, give me the share of the estate that falls to me.' So he divided his wealth between them.</verse>
<verse>"And not many days later, the younger son gathered everything together and went on a journey into a distant country, and there he squandered his estate with loose living.</verse>
<verse>"Now when he had spent everything, a severe famine occurred in that country, and he began to be impoverished.</verse>
<verse>"So he went and hired himself out to one of the citizens of that country, and he sent him into his fields to feed swine.</verse>
<verse>"And he would have gladly filled his stomach with the pods that the swine were eating, and no one was giving anything to him.</verse>
<verse>"But when he came to his senses, he said, 'How many of my father's hired men have more than enough bread, but I am dying here with hunger!</verse>
<verse>'I will get up and go to my father, and will say to him, "Father, I have sinned against heaven, and in your sight;</verse>
<verse>I am no longer worthy to be called your son; make me as one of your hired men."'</verse>
<verse>"So he got up and came to his father. But while he was still a long way off, his father saw him and felt compassion for him, and ran and embraced him and kissed him.</verse>
<verse>"And the son said to him, 'Father, I have sinned against heaven and in your sight; I am no longer worthy to be called your son.'</verse>
<verse>"But the father said to his slaves, 'Quickly bring out the best robe and put it on him, and put a ring on his hand and sandals on his feet;</verse>
<verse>and bring the fattened calf, kill it, and let us eat and celebrate;</verse>
<verse>for this son of mine was dead and has come to life again; he was lost and has been found.' And they began to celebrate.</verse>
<verse>"Now his older son was in the field, and when he came and approached the house, he heard music and dancing.</verse>
<verse>"And he summoned one of the servants and began inquiring what these things could be.</verse>
<verse>"And he said to him, 'Your brother has come, and your father has killed the fattened calf because he has received him back safe and sound.'</verse>
<verse>"But he became angry and was not willing to go in; and his father came out and began pleading with him.</verse>
<verse>"But he answered and said to his father, 'Look! For so many years I have been serving you and I have never neglected a command of yours; and yet you have never given me a young goat, so that I might celebrate with my friends;</verse>
<verse>but when this son of yours came, who has devoured your wealth with prostitutes, you killed the fattened calf for him.'</verse>
<verse>"And he said to him, 'Son, you have always been with me, and all that is mine is yours.</verse>
<verse>'But we had to celebrate and rejoice, for this brother of yours was dead and has begun to live, and was lost and has been found.'"</verse>
</chapter>