<chapter translation="NASB" testament="New" book="Luke" book_id="42" n="23">
<verse>Then the whole body of them got up and brought Him before Pilate.</verse>
<verse>And they began to accuse Him, saying, "We found this man misleading our nation and forbidding to pay taxes to Caesar, and saying that He Himself is Christ, a King."</verse>
<verse>So Pilate asked Him, saying, "Are You the King of the Jews?" And He answered him and said, "It is as you say."</verse>
<verse>Then Pilate said to the chief priests and the crowds, "I find no guilt in this man."</verse>
<verse>But they kept on insisting, saying, "He stirs up the people, teaching all over Judea, starting from Galilee even as far as this place."</verse>
<verse>When Pilate heard it, he asked whether the man was a Galilean.</verse>
<verse>And when he learned that He belonged to Herod's jurisdiction, he sent Him to Herod, who himself also was in Jerusalem at that time.</verse>
<verse>Now Herod was very glad when he saw Jesus; for he had wanted to see Him for a long time, because he had been hearing about Him and was hoping to see some sign performed by Him.</verse>
<verse>And he questioned Him at some length; but He answered him nothing.</verse>
<verse>And the chief priests and the scribes were standing there, accusing Him vehemently.</verse>
<verse>And Herod with his soldiers, after treating Him with contempt and mocking Him, dressed Him in a gorgeous robe and sent Him back to Pilate.</verse>
<verse>Now Herod and Pilate became friends with one another that very day; for before they had been enemies with each other.</verse>
<verse>Pilate summoned the chief priests and the rulers and the people,</verse>
<verse>and said to them, "You brought this man to me as one who incites the people to rebellion, and behold, having examined Him before you, I have found no guilt in this man regarding the charges which you make against Him.</verse>
<verse>"No, nor has Herod, for he sent Him back to us; and behold, nothing deserving death has been done by Him.</verse>
<verse>"Therefore I will punish Him and release Him."</verse>
<verse>[ Now he was obliged to release to them at the feast one prisoner.]</verse>
<verse>But they cried out all together, saying, "Away with this man, and release for us Barabbas!"</verse>
<verse>(He was one who had been thrown into prison for an insurrection made in the city, and for murder.)</verse>
<verse>Pilate, wanting to release Jesus, addressed them again,</verse>
<verse>but they kept on calling out, saying, "Crucify, crucify Him!"</verse>
<verse>And he said to them the third time, "Why, what evil has this man done? I have found in Him no guilt demanding death; therefore I will punish Him and release Him."</verse>
<verse>But they were insistent, with loud voices asking that He be crucified. And their voices began to prevail.</verse>
<verse>And Pilate pronounced sentence that their demand be granted.</verse>
<verse>And he released the man they were asking for who had been thrown into prison for insurrection and murder, but he delivered Jesus to their will.</verse>
<verse>When they led Him away, they seized a man, Simon of Cyrene, coming in from the country, and placed on him the cross to carry behind Jesus.</verse>
<verse>And following Him was a large crowd of the people, and of women who were mourning and lamenting Him.</verse>
<verse>But Jesus turning to them said, "Daughters of Jerusalem, stop weeping for Me, but weep for yourselves and for your children.</verse>
<verse>"For behold, the days are coming when they will say, 'Blessed are the barren, and the wombs that never bore, and the breasts that never nursed.'</verse>
<verse>"Then they will begin TO SAY TO THE MOUNTAINS, 'FALL ON US,' AND TO THE HILLS, 'COVER US.'</verse>
<verse>"For if they do these things when the tree is green, what will happen when it is dry?"</verse>
<verse>Two others also, who were criminals, were being led away to be put to death with Him.</verse>
<verse>When they came to the place called The Skull, there they crucified Him and the criminals, one on the right and the other on the left.</verse>
<verse>But Jesus was saying, "Father, forgive them; for they do not know what they are doing." And they cast lots, dividing up His garments among themselves.</verse>
<verse>And the people stood by, looking on. And even the rulers were sneering at Him, saying, "He saved others; let Him save Himself if this is the Christ of God, His Chosen One."</verse>
<verse>The soldiers also mocked Him, coming up to Him, offering Him sour wine,</verse>
<verse>and saying, "If You are the King of the Jews, save Yourself!"</verse>
<verse>Now there was also an inscription above Him, "THIS IS THE KING OF THE JEWS."</verse>
<verse>One of the criminals who were hanged there was hurling abuse at Him, saying, "Are You not the Christ? Save Yourself and us!"</verse>
<verse>But the other answered, and rebuking him said, "Do you not even fear God, since you are under the same sentence of condemnation?</verse>
<verse>"And we indeed are suffering justly, for we are receiving what we deserve for our deeds; but this man has done nothing wrong."</verse>
<verse>And he was saying, "Jesus, remember me when You come in Your kingdom!"</verse>
<verse>And He said to him, "Truly I say to you, today you shall be with Me in Paradise."</verse>
<verse>It was now about the sixth hour, and darkness fell over the whole land until the ninth hour,</verse>
<verse>because the sun was obscured; and the veil of the temple was torn in two.</verse>
<verse>And Jesus, crying out with a loud voice, said, "Father, INTO YOUR HANDS I COMMIT MY SPIRIT." Having said this, He breathed His last.</verse>
<verse>Now when the centurion saw what had happened, he began praising God, saying, "Certainly this man was innocent."</verse>
<verse>And all the crowds who came together for this spectacle, when they observed what had happened, began to return, beating their breasts.</verse>
<verse>And all His acquaintances and the women who accompanied Him from Galilee were standing at a distance, seeing these things.</verse>
<verse>And a man named Joseph, who was a member of the Council, a good and righteous man</verse>
<verse>(he had not consented to their plan and action), a man from Arimathea, a city of the Jews, who was waiting for the kingdom of God;</verse>
<verse>this man went to Pilate and asked for the body of Jesus.</verse>
<verse>And he took it down and wrapped it in a linen cloth, and laid Him in a tomb cut into the rock, where no one had ever lain.</verse>
<verse>It was the preparation day, and the Sabbath was about to begin.</verse>
<verse>Now the women who had come with Him out of Galilee followed, and saw the tomb and how His body was laid.</verse>
<verse>Then they returned and prepared spices and perfumes. And on the Sabbath they rested according to the commandment.</verse>
</chapter>