<chapter translation="NASB" testament="New" book="Luke" book_id="42" n="24">
<verse>But on the first day of the week, at early dawn, they came to the tomb bringing the spices which they had prepared.</verse>
<verse>And they found the stone rolled away from the tomb,</verse>
<verse>but when they entered, they did not find the body of the Lord Jesus.</verse>
<verse>While they were perplexed about this, behold, two men suddenly stood near them in dazzling clothing;</verse>
<verse>and as the women were terrified and bowed their faces to the ground, the men said to them, "Why do you seek the living One among the dead?</verse>
<verse>"He is not here, but He has risen. Remember how He spoke to you while He was still in Galilee,</verse>
<verse>saying that the Son of Man must be delivered into the hands of sinful men, and be crucified, and the third day rise again."</verse>
<verse>And they remembered His words,</verse>
<verse>and returned from the tomb and reported all these things to the eleven and to all the rest.</verse>
<verse>Now they were Mary Magdalene and Joanna and Mary the mother of James; also the other women with them were telling these things to the apostles.</verse>
<verse>But these words appeared to them as nonsense, and they would not believe them.</verse>
<verse>But Peter got up and ran to the tomb; stooping and looking in, he saw the linen wrappings only; and he went away to his home, marveling at what had happened.</verse>
<verse>And behold, two of them were going that very day to a village named Emmaus, which was about seven miles from Jerusalem.</verse>
<verse>And they were talking with each other about all these things which had taken place.</verse>
<verse>While they were talking and discussing, Jesus Himself approached and began traveling with them.</verse>
<verse>But their eyes were prevented from recognizing Him.</verse>
<verse>And He said to them, "What are these words that you are exchanging with one another as you are walking?" And they stood still, looking sad.</verse>
<verse>One of them, named Cleopas, answered and said to Him, "Are You the only one visiting Jerusalem and unaware of the things which have happened here in these days?"</verse>
<verse>And He said to them, "What things?" And they said to Him, "The things about Jesus the Nazarene, who was a prophet mighty in deed and word in the sight of God and all the people,</verse>
<verse>and how the chief priests and our rulers delivered Him to the sentence of death, and crucified Him.</verse>
<verse>"But we were hoping that it was He who was going to redeem Israel. Indeed, besides all this, it is the third day since these things happened.</verse>
<verse>"But also some women among us amazed us. When they were at the tomb early in the morning,</verse>
<verse>and did not find His body, they came, saying that they had also seen a vision of angels who said that He was alive.</verse>
<verse>"Some of those who were with us went to the tomb and found it just exactly as the women also had said; but Him they did not see."</verse>
<verse>And He said to them, "O foolish men and slow of heart to believe in all that the prophets have spoken!</verse>
<verse>"Was it not necessary for the Christ to suffer these things and to enter into His glory?"</verse>
<verse>Then beginning with Moses and with all the prophets, He explained to them the things concerning Himself in all the Scriptures.</verse>
<verse>And they approached the village where they were going, and He acted as though He were going farther.</verse>
<verse>But they urged Him, saying, "Stay with us, for it is getting toward evening, and the day is now nearly over." So He went in to stay with them.</verse>
<verse>When He had reclined at the table with them, He took the bread and blessed it, and breaking it, He began giving it to them.</verse>
<verse>Then their eyes were opened and they recognized Him; and He vanished from their sight.</verse>
<verse>They said to one another, "Were not our hearts burning within us while He was speaking to us on the road, while He was explaining the Scriptures to us?"</verse>
<verse>And they got up that very hour and returned to Jerusalem, and found gathered together the eleven and those who were with them,</verse>
<verse>saying, "The Lord has really risen and has appeared to Simon."</verse>
<verse>They began to relate their experiences on the road and how He was recognized by them in the breaking of the bread.</verse>
<verse>While they were telling these things, He Himself stood in their midst and said to them, "Peace be to you."</verse>
<verse>But they were startled and frightened and thought that they were seeing a spirit.</verse>
<verse>And He said to them, "Why are you troubled, and why do doubts arise in your hearts?</verse>
<verse>"See My hands and My feet, that it is I Myself; touch Me and see, for a spirit does not have flesh and bones as you see that I have."</verse>
<verse>And when He had said this, He showed them His hands and His feet.</verse>
<verse>While they still could not believe it because of their joy and amazement, He said to them, "Have you anything here to eat?"</verse>
<verse>They gave Him a piece of a broiled fish;</verse>
<verse>and He took it and ate it before them.</verse>
<verse>Now He said to them, "These are My words which I spoke to you while I was still with you, that all things which are written about Me in the Law of Moses and the Prophets and the Psalms must be fulfilled."</verse>
<verse>Then He opened their minds to understand the Scriptures,</verse>
<verse>and He said to them, "Thus it is written, that the Christ would suffer and rise again from the dead the third day,</verse>
<verse>and that repentance for forgiveness of sins would be proclaimed in His name to all the nations, beginning from Jerusalem.</verse>
<verse>"You are witnesses of these things.</verse>
<verse>"And behold, I am sending forth the promise of My Father upon you; but you are to stay in the city until you are clothed with power from on high."</verse>
<verse>And He led them out as far as Bethany, and He lifted up His hands and blessed them.</verse>
<verse>While He was blessing them, He parted from them and was carried up into heaven.</verse>
<verse>And they, after worshiping Him, returned to Jerusalem with great joy,</verse>
<verse>and were continually in the temple praising God.</verse>
</chapter>