<chapter translation="ESV" testament="New" book="Hebrews" book-id="58" n="3">
<verse>Therefore, holy brothers, you who share in a heavenly calling, consider Jesus, the apostle and high priest of our confession,</verse>
<verse>who was faithful to him who appointed him, just as Moses also was faithful in all God's house.</verse>
<verse>For Jesus has been counted worthy of more glory than Moses--as much more glory as the builder of a house has more honor than the house itself.</verse>
<verse>(For every house is built by someone, but the builder of all things is God.)</verse>
<verse>Now Moses was faithful in all God's house as a servant, to testify to the things that were to be spoken later,</verse>
<verse>but Christ is faithful over God's house as a son. And we are his house if indeed we hold fast our confidence and our boasting in our hope.</verse>
<verse>Therefore, as the Holy Spirit says, "Today, if you hear his voice,</verse>
<verse>do not harden your hearts as in the rebellion, on the day of testing in the wilderness,</verse>
<verse>where your fathers put me to the test and saw my works</verse>
<verse>for forty years. Therefore I was provoked with that generation, and said, 'They always go astray in their heart; they have not known my ways.'</verse>
<verse>As I swore in my wrath, 'They shall not enter my rest.'"</verse>
<verse>Take care, brothers, lest there be in any of you an evil, unbelieving heart, leading you to fall away from the living God.</verse>
<verse>But exhort one another every day, as long as it is called "today," that none of you may be hardened by the deceitfulness of sin.</verse>
<verse>For we share in Christ, if indeed we hold our original confidence firm to the end.</verse>
<verse>As it is said, "Today, if you hear his voice, do not harden your hearts as in the rebellion."</verse>
<verse>For who were those who heard and yet rebelled? Was it not all those who left Egypt led by Moses?</verse>
<verse>And with whom was he provoked for forty years? Was it not with those who sinned, whose bodies fell in the wilderness?</verse>
<verse>And to whom did he swear that they would not enter his rest, but to those who were disobedient?</verse>
<verse>So we see that they were unable to enter because of unbelief.</verse>
</chapter>