<chapter translation="ESV" testament="New" book="Hebrews" book-id="58" n="4">
<verse>Therefore, while the promise of entering his rest still stands, let us fear lest any of you should seem to have failed to reach it.</verse>
<verse>For good news came to us just as to them, but the message they heard did not benefit them, because they were not united by faith with those who listened.</verse>
<verse>For we who have believed enter that rest, as he has said, "As I swore in my wrath, 'They shall not enter my rest,'"although his works were finished from the foundation of the world.</verse>
<verse>For he has somewhere spoken of the seventh day in this way: "And God rested on the seventh day from all his works."</verse>
<verse>And again in this passage he said, "They shall not enter my rest."</verse>
<verse>Since therefore it remains for some to enter it, and those who formerly received the good news failed to enter because of disobedience,</verse>
<verse>again he appoints a certain day, "Today," saying through David so long afterward, in the words already quoted, "Today, if you hear his voice, do not harden your hearts."</verse>
<verse>For if Joshua had given them rest, God would not have spoken of another day later on.</verse>
<verse>So then, there remains a Sabbath rest for the people of God,</verse>
<verse>for whoever has entered God's rest has also rested from his works as God did from his.</verse>
<verse>Let us therefore strive to enter that rest, so that no one may fall by the same sort of disobedience.</verse>
<verse>For the word of God is living and active, sharper than any two-edged sword, piercing to the division of soul and of spirit, of joints and of marrow, and discerning the thoughts and intentions of the heart.</verse>
<verse>And no creature is hidden from his sight, but all are naked and exposed to the eyes of him to whom we must give account.</verse>
<verse>Since then we have a great high priest who has passed through the heavens, Jesus, the Son of God, let us hold fast our confession.</verse>
<verse>For we do not have a high priest who is unable to sympathize with our weaknesses, but one who in every respect has been tempted as we are, yet without sin.</verse>
<verse>Let us then with confidence draw near to the throne of grace, that we may receive mercy and find grace to help in time of need.</verse>
</chapter>