<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Joshua" book_id="6" n="8">
<verse>Now the LORD said to Joshua, "Do not fear or be dismayed. Take all the people of war with you and arise, go up to Ai; see, I have given into your hand the king of Ai, his people, his city, and his land.</verse>
<verse>"You shall do to Ai and its king just as you did to Jericho and its king; you shall take only its spoil and its cattle as plunder for yourselves. Set an ambush for the city behind it."</verse>
<verse>So Joshua rose with all the people of war to go up to Ai; and Joshua chose 30,000 men, valiant warriors, and sent them out at night.</verse>
<verse>He commanded them, saying, "See, you are going to ambush the city from behind it. Do not go very far from the city, but all of you be ready.</verse>
<verse>"Then I and all the people who are with me will approach the city. And when they come out to meet us as at the first, we will flee before them.</verse>
<verse>"They will come out after us until we have drawn them away from the city, for they will say, 'They are fleeing before us as at the first.' So we will flee before them.</verse>
<verse>"And you shall rise from your ambush and take possession of the city, for the LORD your God will deliver it into your hand.</verse>
<verse>"Then it will be when you have seized the city, that you shall set the city on fire. You shall do it according to the word of the LORD. See, I have commanded you."</verse>
<verse>So Joshua sent them away, and they went to the place of ambush and remained between Bethel and Ai, on the west side of Ai; but Joshua spent that night among the people.</verse>
<verse>Now Joshua rose early in the morning and mustered the people, and he went up with the elders of Israel before the people to Ai.</verse>
<verse>Then all the people of war who were with him went up and drew near and arrived in front of the city, and camped on the north side of Ai. Now there was a valley between him and Ai.</verse>
<verse>And he took about 5,000 men and set them in ambush between Bethel and Ai, on the west side of the city.</verse>
<verse>So they stationed the people, all the army that was on the north side of the city, and its rear guard on the west side of the city, and Joshua spent that night in the midst of the valley.</verse>
<verse>It came about when the king of Ai saw it, that the men of the city hurried and rose up early and went out to meet Israel in battle, he and all his people at the appointed place before the desert plain. But he did not know that there was an ambush against him behind the city.</verse>
<verse>Joshua and all Israel pretended to be beaten before them, and fled by the way of the wilderness.</verse>
<verse>And all the people who were in the city were called together to pursue them, and they pursued Joshua and were drawn away from the city.</verse>
<verse>So not a man was left in Ai or Bethel who had not gone out after Israel, and they left the city unguarded and pursued Israel.</verse>
<verse>Then the LORD said to Joshua, "Stretch out the javelin that is in your hand toward Ai, for I will give it into your hand." So Joshua stretched out the javelin that was in his hand toward the city.</verse>
<verse>The men in ambush rose quickly from their place, and when he had stretched out his hand, they ran and entered the city and captured it, and they quickly set the city on fire.</verse>
<verse>When the men of Ai turned back and looked, behold, the smoke of the city ascended to the sky, and they had no place to flee this way or that, for the people who had been fleeing to the wilderness turned against the pursuers.</verse>
<verse>When Joshua and all Israel saw that the men in ambush had captured the city and that the smoke of the city ascended, they turned back and slew the men of Ai.</verse>
<verse>The others came out from the city to encounter them, so that they were trapped in the midst of Israel, some on this side and some on that side; and they slew them until no one was left of those who survived or escaped.</verse>
<verse>But they took alive the king of Ai and brought him to Joshua.</verse>
<verse>Now when Israel had finished killing all the inhabitants of Ai in the field in the wilderness where they pursued them, and all of them were fallen by the edge of the sword until they were destroyed, then all Israel returned to Ai and struck it with the edge of the sword.</verse>
<verse>All who fell that day, both men and women, were 12,000--all the people of Ai.</verse>
<verse>For Joshua did not withdraw his hand with which he stretched out the javelin until he had utterly destroyed all the inhabitants of Ai.</verse>
<verse>Israel took only the cattle and the spoil of that city as plunder for themselves, according to the word of the LORD which He had commanded Joshua.</verse>
<verse>So Joshua burned Ai and made it a heap forever, a desolation until this day.</verse>
<verse>He hanged the king of Ai on a tree until evening; and at sunset Joshua gave command and they took his body down from the tree and threw it at the entrance of the city gate, and raised over it a great heap of stones that stands to this day.</verse>
<verse>Then Joshua built an altar to the LORD, the God of Israel, in Mount Ebal,</verse>
<verse>just as Moses the servant of the LORD had commanded the sons of Israel, as it is written in the book of the law of Moses, an altar of uncut stones on which no man had wielded an iron tool; and they offered burnt offerings on it to the LORD, and sacrificed peace offerings.</verse>
<verse>He wrote there on the stones a copy of the law of Moses, which he had written, in the presence of the sons of Israel.</verse>
<verse>All Israel with their elders and officers and their judges were standing on both sides of the ark before the Levitical priests who carried the ark of the covenant of the LORD, the stranger as well as the native. Half of them stood in front of Mount Gerizim and half of them in front of Mount Ebal, just as Moses the servant of the LORD had given command at first to bless the people of Israel.</verse>
<verse>Then afterward he read all the words of the law, the blessing and the curse, according to all that is written in the book of the law.</verse>
<verse>There was not a word of all that Moses had commanded which Joshua did not read before all the assembly of Israel with the women and the little ones and the strangers who were living among them.</verse>
</chapter>