<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="2 Chronicles" book-id="14" n="17">
<verse>Jehoshaphat his son then became king in his place, and made his position over Israel firm.</verse>
<verse>He placed troops in all the fortified cities of Judah, and set garrisons in the land of Judah and in the cities of Ephraim which Asa his father had captured.</verse>
<verse>The LORD was with Jehoshaphat because he followed the example of his father David's earlier days and did not seek the Baals,</verse>
<verse>but sought the God of his father, followed His commandments, and did not act as Israel did.</verse>
<verse>So the LORD established the kingdom in his control, and all Judah brought tribute to Jehoshaphat, and he had great riches and honor.</verse>
<verse>He took great pride in the ways of the LORD and again removed the high places and the Asherim from Judah.</verse>
<verse>Then in the third year of his reign he sent his officials, Ben-hail, Obadiah, Zechariah, Nethanel and Micaiah, to teach in the cities of Judah;</verse>
<verse>and with them the Levites, Shemaiah, Nethaniah, Zebadiah, Asahel, Shemiramoth, Jehonathan, Adonijah, Tobijah and Tobadonijah, the Levites; and with them Elishama and Jehoram, the priests.</verse>
<verse>They taught in Judah, having the book of the law of the LORD with them; and they went throughout all the cities of Judah and taught among the people.</verse>
<verse>Now the dread of the LORD was on all the kingdoms of the lands which were around Judah, so that they did not make war against Jehoshaphat.</verse>
<verse>Some of the Philistines brought gifts and silver as tribute to Jehoshaphat; the Arabians also brought him flocks, 7,700 rams and 7,700 male goats.</verse>
<verse>So Jehoshaphat grew greater and greater, and he built fortresses and store cities in Judah.</verse>
<verse>He had large supplies in the cities of Judah, and warriors, valiant men, in Jerusalem.</verse>
<verse>This was their muster according to their fathers' households: of Judah, commanders of thousands, Adnah was the commander, and with him 300,000 valiant warriors;</verse>
<verse>and next to him was Johanan the commander, and with him 280,000;</verse>
<verse>and next to him Amasiah the son of Zichri, who volunteered for the LORD, and with him 200,000 valiant warriors;</verse>
<verse>and of Benjamin, Eliada a valiant warrior, and with him 200,000 armed with bow and shield;</verse>
<verse>and next to him Jehozabad, and with him 180,000 equipped for war.</verse>
<verse>These are they who served the king, apart from those whom the king put in the fortified cities through all Judah.</verse>
</chapter>