<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="2 Chronicles" book-id="14" n="7">
<verse>Now when Solomon had finished praying, fire came down from heaven and consumed the burnt offering and the sacrifices, and the glory of the LORD filled the house.</verse>
<verse>The priests could not enter into the house of the LORD because the glory of the LORD filled the LORD'S house.</verse>
<verse>All the sons of Israel, seeing the fire come down and the glory of the LORD upon the house, bowed down on the pavement with their faces to the ground, and they worshiped and gave praise to the LORD, saying, "Truly He is good, truly His lovingkindness is everlasting."</verse>
<verse>Then the king and all the people offered sacrifice before the LORD.</verse>
<verse>King Solomon offered a sacrifice of 22,000 oxen and 120,000 sheep. Thus the king and all the people dedicated the house of God.</verse>
<verse>The priests stood at their posts, and the Levites also, with the instruments of music to the LORD, which King David had made for giving praise to the LORD--"for His lovingkindness is everlasting"--whenever he gave praise by their means, while the priests on the other side blew trumpets; and all Israel was standing.</verse>
<verse>Then Solomon consecrated the middle of the court that was before the house of the LORD, for there he offered the burnt offerings and the fat of the peace offerings because the bronze altar which Solomon had made was not able to contain the burnt offering, the grain offering and the fat.</verse>
<verse>So Solomon observed the feast at that time for seven days, and all Israel with him, a very great assembly who came from the entrance of Hamath to the brook of Egypt.</verse>
<verse>On the eighth day they held a solemn assembly, for the dedication of the altar they observed seven days and the feast seven days.</verse>
<verse>Then on the twenty-third day of the seventh month he sent the people to their tents, rejoicing and happy of heart because of the goodness that the LORD had shown to David and to Solomon and to His people Israel.</verse>
<verse>Thus Solomon finished the house of the LORD and the king's palace, and successfully completed all that he had planned on doing in the house of the LORD and in his palace.</verse>
<verse>Then the LORD appeared to Solomon at night and said to him, "I have heard your prayer and have chosen this place for Myself as a house of sacrifice.</verse>
<verse>"If I shut up the heavens so that there is no rain, or if I command the locust to devour the land, or if I send pestilence among My people,</verse>
<verse>and My people who are called by My name humble themselves and pray and seek My face and turn from their wicked ways, then I will hear from heaven, will forgive their sin and will heal their land.</verse>
<verse>"Now My eyes will be open and My ears attentive to the prayer offered in this place.</verse>
<verse>"For now I have chosen and consecrated this house that My name may be there forever, and My eyes and My heart will be there perpetually.</verse>
<verse>"As for you, if you walk before Me as your father David walked, even to do according to all that I have commanded you, and will keep My statutes and My ordinances,</verse>
<verse>then I will establish your royal throne as I covenanted with your father David, saying, 'You shall not lack a man to be ruler in Israel.'</verse>
<verse>"But if you turn away and forsake My statutes and My commandments which I have set before you, and go and serve other gods and worship them,</verse>
<verse>then I will uproot you from My land which I have given you, and this house which I have consecrated for My name I will cast out of My sight and I will make it a proverb and a byword among all peoples.</verse>
<verse>"As for this house, which was exalted, everyone who passes by it will be astonished and say, 'Why has the LORD done thus to this land and to this house?'</verse>
<verse>"And they will say, 'Because they forsook the LORD, the God of their fathers who brought them from the land of Egypt, and they adopted other gods and worshiped them and served them; therefore He has brought all this adversity on them.'"</verse>
</chapter>