<chapter translation="NIV" testament="New" book="2 Timothy" book_id="55" n="2">
<verse>You then, my son, be strong in the grace that is in Christ Jesus.</verse>
<verse>And the things you have heard me say in the presence of many witnesses entrust to reliable men who will also be qualified to teach others.</verse>
<verse>Endure hardship with us like a good soldier of Christ Jesus.</verse>
<verse>No one serving as a soldier gets involved in civilian affairs--he wants to please his commanding officer.</verse>
<verse>Similarly, if anyone competes as an athlete, he does not receive the victor's crown unless he competes according to the rules.</verse>
<verse>The hardworking farmer should be the first to receive a share of the crops.</verse>
<verse>Reflect on what I am saying, for the Lord will give you insight into all this.</verse>
<verse>Remember Jesus Christ, raised from the dead, descended from David. This is my gospel,</verse>
<verse>for which I am suffering even to the point of being chained like a criminal. But God's word is not chained.</verse>
<verse>Therefore I endure everything for the sake of the elect, that they too may obtain the salvation that is in Christ Jesus, with eternal glory.</verse>
<verse>Here is a trustworthy saying: If we died with him, we will also live with him;</verse>
<verse>if we endure, we will also reign with him. If we disown him, he will also disown us;</verse>
<verse>if we are faithless, he will remain faithful, for he cannot disown himself.</verse>
<verse>Keep reminding them of these things. Warn them before God against quarreling about words; it is of no value, and only ruins those who listen.</verse>
<verse>Do your best to present yourself to God as one approved, a workman who does not need to be ashamed and who correctly handles the word of truth.</verse>
<verse>Avoid godless chatter, because those who indulge in it will become more and more ungodly.</verse>
<verse>Their teaching will spread like gangrene. Among them are Hymenaeus and Philetus,</verse>
<verse>who have wandered away from the truth. They say that the resurrection has already taken place, and they destroy the faith of some.</verse>
<verse>Nevertheless, God's solid foundation stands firm, sealed with this inscription: "The Lord knows those who are his," and, "Everyone who confesses the name of the Lord must turn away from wickedness."</verse>
<verse>In a large house there are articles not only of gold and silver, but also of wood and clay; some are for noble purposes and some for ignoble.</verse>
<verse>If a man cleanses himself from the latter, he will be an instrument for noble purposes, made holy, useful to the Master and prepared to do any good work.</verse>
<verse>Flee the evil desires of youth, and pursue righteousness, faith, love and peace, along with those who call on the Lord out of a pure heart.</verse>
<verse>Don't have anything to do with foolish and stupid arguments, because you know they produce quarrels.</verse>
<verse>And the Lord's servant must not quarrel; instead, he must be kind to everyone, able to teach, not resentful.</verse>
<verse>Those who oppose him he must gently instruct, in the hope that God will grant them repentance leading them to a knowledge of the truth,</verse>
<verse>and that they will come to their senses and escape from the trap of the devil, who has taken them captive to do his will.</verse>
</chapter>