<chapter translation="NIV" testament="New" book="2 Timothy" book-id="55" n="4">
<verse>In the presence of God and of Christ Jesus, who will judge the living and the dead, and in view of his appearing and his kingdom, I give you this charge:</verse>
<verse>Preach the Word; be prepared in season and out of season; correct, rebuke and encourage--with great patience and careful instruction.</verse>
<verse>For the time will come when men will not put up with sound doctrine. Instead, to suit their own desires, they will gather around them a great number of teachers to say what their itching ears want to hear.</verse>
<verse>They will turn their ears away from the truth and turn aside to myths.</verse>
<verse>But you, keep your head in all situations, endure hardship, do the work of an evangelist, discharge all the duties of your ministry.</verse>
<verse>For I am already being poured out like a drink offering, and the time has come for my departure.</verse>
<verse>I have fought the good fight, I have finished the race, I have kept the faith.</verse>
<verse>Now there is in store for me the crown of righteousness, which the Lord, the righteous Judge, will award to me on that day--and not only to me, but also to all who have longed for his appearing.</verse>
<verse>Do your best to come to me quickly,</verse>
<verse>for Demas, because he loved this world, has deserted me and has gone to Thessalonica. Crescens has gone to Galatia, and Titus to Dalmatia.</verse>
<verse>Only Luke is with me. Get Mark and bring him with you, because he is helpful to me in my ministry.</verse>
<verse>I sent Tychicus to Ephesus.</verse>
<verse>When you come, bring the cloak that I left with Carpus at Troas, and my scrolls, especially the parchments.</verse>
<verse>Alexander the metalworker did me a great deal of harm. The Lord will repay him for what he has done.</verse>
<verse>You too should be on your guard against him, because he strongly opposed our message.</verse>
<verse>At my first defense, no one came to my support, but everyone deserted me. May it not be held against them.</verse>
<verse>But the Lord stood at my side and gave me strength, so that through me the message might be fully proclaimed and all the Gentiles might hear it. And I was delivered from the lion's mouth.</verse>
<verse>The Lord will rescue me from every evil attack and will bring me safely to his heavenly kingdom. To him be glory for ever and ever. Amen.</verse>
<verse>Greet Priscilla and Aquila and the household of Onesiphorus.</verse>
<verse>Erastus stayed in Corinth, and I left Trophimus sick in Miletus.</verse>
<verse>Do your best to get here before winter. Eubulus greets you, and so do Pudens, Linus, Claudia and all the brothers.</verse>
<verse>The Lord be with your spirit. Grace be with you.</verse>
</chapter>