<?xml version="1.0"?>
<chapter translation="KJV" testament="Old" book="Ecclesiastes" n="10">
      <verse>Dead flies cause the ointment of the apothecary to send forth a stinking savour: <supplied>so doth</supplied> a little folly him that is in reputation for wisdom <supplied>and</supplied> honour.
</verse><verse>A wise man&#x2019;s heart <supplied>is</supplied> at his right hand; but a fool&#x2019;s heart at his left.
</verse><verse>Yea also, when he that is a fool walketh by the way, his wisdom faileth <supplied>him,</supplied> and he saith to every one <supplied>that</supplied> he <supplied>is</supplied> a fool.
</verse><verse>If the spirit of the ruler rise up against thee, leave not thy place; for yielding pacifieth great offences.
</verse><verse>There is an evil <supplied>which</supplied> I have seen under the sun, as an error <supplied>which</supplied> proceedeth from the ruler:
</verse><verse>Folly is set in great dignity, and the rich sit in low place.
</verse><verse>I have seen servants upon horses, and princes walking as servants upon the earth.
</verse><verse>He that diggeth a pit shall fall into it; and whoso breaketh an hedge, a serpent shall bite him.
</verse><verse>Whoso removeth stones shall be hurt therewith; <supplied>and</supplied> he that cleaveth wood shall be endangered thereby.
</verse><verse>If the iron be blunt, and he do not whet the edge, then must he put to more strength: but wisdom <supplied>is</supplied> profitable to direct.
</verse><verse>Surely the serpent will bite without enchantment; and a babbler is no better.
</verse><verse>The words of a wise man&#x2019;s mouth <supplied>are</supplied> gracious; but the lips of a fool will swallow up himself.
</verse><verse>The beginning of the words of his mouth <supplied>is</supplied> foolishness: and the end of his talk <supplied>is</supplied> mischievous madness.
</verse><verse>A fool also is full of words: a man cannot tell what shall be; and what shall be after him, who can tell him?
</verse><verse>The labour of the foolish wearieth every one of them, because he knoweth not how to go to the city.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>Woe to thee, O land, when thy king <supplied>is</supplied> a child, and thy princes eat in the morning!
</verse><verse>Blessed <supplied>art</supplied> thou, O land, when thy king <supplied>is</supplied> the son of nobles, and thy princes eat in due season, for strength, and not for drunkenness!
     
      </verse>
      <verse>By much slothfulness the building decayeth; and through idleness of the hands the house droppeth through.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>A feast is made for laughter, and wine maketh merry: but money answereth all <supplied>things.</supplied>
     
      </verse>
      <verse>Curse not the king, no not in thy thought; and curse not the rich in thy bedchamber: for a bird of the air shall carry the voice, and that which hath wings shall tell the matter.
     
      </verse>
      </chapter>
