<chapter translation="MSG" testament="New" book="Ephesians" book-id="49" n="4">
<verse>In light of all this, here's what I want you to do. While I'm locked up here, a prisoner for the Master, I want you to get out there and walk--better yet, run!-on the road God called you to travel. I don't want any of you sitting around on your hands. I don't want anyone strolling off, down some path that goes nowhere.</verse>
<verse>And mark that you do this with humility and discipline--not in fits and starts, but steadily, pouring yourselves out for each other in acts of love,</verse>
<verse>alert at noticing differences and quick at mending fences.</verse>
<verse>You were all called to travel on the same road and in the same direction, so stay together, both outwardly and inwardly.</verse>
<verse>You have one Master, one faith, one baptism,</verse>
<verse>one God and Father of all, who rules over all, works through all, and is present in all. Everything you are and think and do is permeated with Oneness.</verse>
<verse>But that doesn't mean you should all look and speak and act the same. Out of the generosity of Christ, each of us is given his own gift.</verse>
<verse>The text for this is, He climbed the high mountain, He captured the enemy and seized the booty, He handed it all out in gifts to the people.</verse>
<verse>It's true, is it not, that the One who climbed up also climbed down, down to the valley of earth?</verse>
<verse>And the One who climbed down is the One who climbed back up, up to highest heaven. He handed out gifts above and below, filled heaven with his gifts,</verse>
<verse>filled earth with his gifts. He handed out gifts of apostle, prophet, evangelist, and pastor-teacher</verse>
<verse>to train Christians in skilled servant work, working within Christ's body, the church,</verse>
<verse>until we're all moving rhythmically and easily with each other, efficient and graceful in response to God's Son, fully mature adults, fully developed within and without, fully alive like Christ. 114No prolonged infancies among us, please. We'll not tolerate babes in the woods, small children who are an easy mark for impostors.</verse>
<verse>No prolonged infancies among us, please. We'll not tolerate babes in the woods, small children who are an easy mark for impostors.</verse>
<verse>God wants us to grow up, to know the whole truth and tell it in love--like Christ in everything. We take our lead from Christ, who is the source of everything we do.</verse>
<verse>He keeps us in step with each other. His very breath and blood flow through us, nourishing us so that we will grow up healthy in God, robust in love.</verse>
<verse>And so I insist--and God backs me up on this--that there be no going along with the crowd, the empty-headed, mindless crowd.</verse>
<verse>They've refused for so long to deal with God that they've lost touch not only with God but with reality itself.</verse>
<verse>They can't think straight anymore. Feeling no pain, they let themselves go in sexual obsession, addicted to every sort of perversion.</verse>
<verse>But that's no life for you. You learned Christ!</verse>
<verse>My assumption is that you have paid careful attention to him, been well instructed in the truth precisely as we have it in Jesus.</verse>
<verse>Since, then, we do not have the excuse of ignorance, everything--and I do mean everything--connected with that old way of life has to go. It's rotten through and through. Get rid of it! And then take on an entirely new way of life--a God-fashioned life,</verse>
<verse>a life renewed from the inside</verse>
<verse>and working itself into your conduct as God accurately reproduces his character in you.</verse>
<verse>What this adds up to, then, is this: no more lies, no more pretense. Tell your neighbor the truth. In Christ's body we're all connected to each other, after all. When you lie to others, you end up lying to yourself.</verse>
<verse>Go ahead and be angry. You do well to be angry--but don't use your anger as fuel for revenge. And don't stay angry. Don't go to bed angry.</verse>
<verse>Don't give the Devil that kind of foothold in your life.</verse>
<verse>Did you used to make ends meet by stealing? Well, no more! Get an honest job so that you can help others who can't work.</verse>
<verse>Watch the way you talk. Let nothing foul or dirty come out of your mouth. Say only what helps, each word a gift.</verse>
<verse>Don't grieve God. Don't break his heart. His Holy Spirit, moving and breathing in you, is the most intimate part of your life, making you fit for himself. Don't take such a gift for granted.</verse>
<verse>Make a clean break with all cutting, backbiting, profane talk.</verse>
<verse>Be gentle with one another, sensitive. Forgive one another as quickly and thoroughly as God in Christ forgave you.</verse>
</chapter>