<chapter translation="NIV" testament="New" book="Romans" book-id="45" n="9">
<verse>I speak the truth in Christ--I am not lying, my conscience confirms it in the Holy Spirit--</verse>
<verse>I have great sorrow and unceasing anguish in my heart.</verse>
<verse>For I could wish that I myself were cursed and cut off from Christ for the sake of my brothers, those of my own race,</verse>
<verse>the people of Israel. Theirs is the adoption as sons; theirs the divine glory, the covenants, the receiving of the law, the temple worship and the promises.</verse>
<verse>Theirs are the patriarchs, and from them is traced the human ancestry of Christ, who is God over all, forever praised! Amen.</verse>
<verse>It is not as though God's word had failed. For not all who are descended from Israel are Israel.</verse>
<verse>Nor because they are his descendants are they all Abraham's children. On the contrary, "It is through Isaac that your offspring will be reckoned."</verse>
<verse>In other words, it is not the natural children who are God's children, but it is the children of the promise who are regarded as Abraham's offspring.</verse>
<verse>For this was how the promise was stated: "At the appointed time I will return, and Sarah will have a son."</verse>
<verse>Not only that, but Rebekah's children had one and the same father, our father Isaac.</verse>
<verse>Yet, before the twins were born or had done anything good or bad--in order that God's purpose in election might stand:</verse>
<verse>not by works but by him who calls--she was told, "The older will serve the younger."</verse>
<verse>Just as it is written: "Jacob I loved, but Esau I hated."</verse>
<verse>What then shall we say? Is God unjust? Not at all!</verse>
<verse>For he says to Moses, "I will have mercy on whom I have mercy, and I will have compassion on whom I have compassion."</verse>
<verse>It does not, therefore, depend on man's desire or effort, but on God's mercy.</verse>
<verse>For the Scripture says to Pharaoh: "I raised you up for this very purpose, that I might display my power in you and that my name might be proclaimed in all the earth."</verse>
<verse>Therefore God has mercy on whom he wants to have mercy, and he hardens whom he wants to harden.</verse>
<verse>One of you will say to me: "Then why does God still blame us? For who resists his will?"</verse>
<verse>But who are you, O man, to talk back to God? "Shall what is formed say to him who formed it, 'Why did you make me like this?'"</verse>
<verse>Does not the potter have the right to make out of the same lump of clay some pottery for noble purposes and some for common use?</verse>
<verse>What if God, choosing to show his wrath and make his power known, bore with great patience the objects of his wrath--prepared for destruction?</verse>
<verse>What if he did this to make the riches of his glory known to the objects of his mercy, whom he prepared in advance for glory--</verse>
<verse>even us, whom he also called, not only from the Jews but also from the Gentiles?</verse>
<verse>As he says in Hosea: "I will call them 'my people' who are not my people; and I will call her 'my loved one' who is not my loved one,"</verse>
<verse>and, "It will happen that in the very place where it was said to them, 'You are not my people,' they will be called 'sons of the living God.'"</verse>
<verse>Isaiah cries out concerning Israel: "Though the number of the Israelites be like the sand by the sea, only the remnant will be saved.</verse>
<verse>For the Lord will carry out his sentence on earth with speed and finality."</verse>
<verse>It is just as Isaiah said previously: "Unless the Lord Almighty had left us descendants, we would have become like Sodom, we would have been like Gomorrah."</verse>
<verse>What then shall we say? That the Gentiles, who did not pursue righteousness, have obtained it, a righteousness that is by faith;</verse>
<verse>but Israel, who pursued a law of righteousness, has not attained it.</verse>
<verse>Why not? Because they pursued it not by faith but as if it were by works. They stumbled over the "stumbling stone."</verse>
<verse>As it is written: "See, I lay in Zion a stone that causes men to stumble and a rock that makes them fall, and the one who trusts in him will never be put to shame."</verse>
</chapter>