<?xml version="1.0"?>
<chapter translation="KJV" testament="Old" book="Isaiah" n="13">
      <verse>The burden of Babylon, which Isaiah the son of Amoz did see.
</verse><verse>Lift ye up a banner upon the high mountain, exalt the voice unto them, shake the hand, that they may go into the gates of the nobles.
</verse><verse>I have commanded my sanctified ones, I have also called my mighty ones for mine anger, <supplied>even</supplied> them that rejoice in my highness.
</verse><verse>The noise of a multitude in the mountains, like as of a great people; a tumultuous noise of the kingdoms of nations gathered together: the LORD of hosts mustereth the host of the battle.
</verse><verse>They come from a far country, from the end of heaven, <supplied>even</supplied> the LORD, and the weapons of his indignation, to destroy the whole land.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>Howl ye; for the day of the LORD <supplied>is</supplied> at hand; it shall come as a destruction from the Almighty.
</verse><verse>Therefore shall all hands be faint, and every man&#x2019;s heart shall melt:
</verse><verse>And they shall be afraid: pangs and sorrows shall take hold of them; they shall be in pain as a woman that travaileth: they shall be amazed one at another; their faces <supplied>shall be as</supplied> flames.
</verse><verse>Behold, the day of the LORD cometh, cruel both with wrath and fierce anger, to lay the land desolate: and he shall destroy the sinners thereof out of it.
</verse><verse>For the stars of heaven and the constellations thereof shall not give their light: the sun shall be darkened in his going forth, and the moon shall not cause her light to shine.
</verse><verse>And I will punish the world for <supplied>their</supplied> evil, and the wicked for their iniquity; and I will cause the arrogancy of the proud to cease, and will lay low the haughtiness of the terrible.
</verse><verse>I will make a man more precious than fine gold; even a man than the golden wedge of Ophir.
</verse><verse>Therefore I will shake the heavens, and the earth shall remove out of her place, in the wrath of the LORD of hosts, and in the day of his fierce anger.
</verse><verse>And it shall be as the chased roe, and as a sheep that no man taketh up: they shall every man turn to his own people, and flee every one into his own land.
</verse><verse>Every one that is found shall be thrust through; and every one that is joined <supplied>unto them</supplied> shall fall by the sword.
</verse><verse>Their children also shall be dashed to pieces before their eyes; their houses shall be spoiled, and their wives ravished.
</verse><verse>Behold, I will stir up the Medes against them, which shall not regard silver; and <supplied>as for</supplied> gold, they shall not delight in it.
</verse><verse><supplied>Their</supplied> bows also shall dash the young men to pieces; and they shall have no pity on the fruit of the womb; their eye shall not spare children.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>And Babylon, the glory of kingdoms, the beauty of the Chaldees&#x2019; excellency, shall be as when God overthrew Sodom and Gomorrah.
</verse><verse>It shall never be inhabited, neither shall it be dwelt in from generation to generation: neither shall the Arabian pitch tent there; neither shall the shepherds make their fold there.
</verse><verse>But wild beasts of the desert shall lie there; and their houses shall be full of doleful creatures; and owls shall dwell there, and satyrs shall dance there.
</verse><verse>And the wild beasts of the islands shall cry in their desolate houses, and dragons in <supplied>their</supplied> pleasant palaces: and her time <supplied>is</supplied> near to come, and her days shall not be prolonged.
     
      </verse>
      </chapter>
