<?xml version="1.0"?>
<chapter translation="KJV" testament="Old" book="Isaiah" n="21" book-chapters="66">
      <verse>The burden of the desert of the sea. As whirlwinds in the south pass through; <supplied>so</supplied> it cometh from the desert, from a terrible land.
</verse><verse>A grievous vision is declared unto me; the treacherous dealer dealeth treacherously, and the spoiler spoileth. Go up, O Elam: besiege, O Media; all the sighing thereof have I made to cease.
</verse><verse>Therefore are my loins filled with pain: pangs have taken hold upon me, as the pangs of a woman that travaileth: I was bowed down at the hearing <supplied>of it;</supplied> I was dismayed at the seeing <supplied>of it. </supplied></verse><verse>My heart panted, fearfulness
affrighted me: the night of my pleasure hath he turned into fear unto me.
</verse><verse>Prepare the table, watch in the watchtower, eat, drink: arise, ye princes, <supplied>and</supplied> anoint the shield.
</verse><verse>For thus hath the Lord said unto me, Go, set a watchman, let him declare what he seeth.
</verse><verse>And he saw a chariot <supplied>with</supplied> a couple of horsemen, a chariot of asses, <supplied>and</supplied> a chariot of camels; and he hearkened diligently with much heed:
</verse><verse>And he cried, A lion: My lord, I stand continually upon the watchtower in the daytime, and I am set in my ward whole nights:
</verse><verse>And, behold, here cometh a chariot of men, <supplied>with</supplied> a couple of horsemen. And he answered and said, Babylon is fallen, is fallen; and all the graven images of her gods he hath broken unto the ground.
</verse><verse>O my threshing, and the corn of my floor: that which I have heard of the LORD of hosts, the God of Israel, have I declared unto you.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>The burden of Dumah. He calleth to me out of Seir, Watchman, what of the night? Watchman, what of the night?
</verse><verse>The watchman said, The morning cometh, and also the night: if ye will enquire, enquire ye: return, come.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>The burden upon Arabia. In the forest in Arabia shall ye lodge, O ye travelling companies of Dedanim.
</verse><verse>The inhabitants of the land of Tema brought water to him that was thirsty, they prevented with their bread him that fled.
</verse><verse>For they fled from the swords, from the drawn sword, and from the bent bow, and from the grievousness of war.
</verse><verse>For thus hath the Lord said unto me, Within a year, according to the years of an hireling, and all the glory of Kedar shall fail:
</verse><verse>And the residue of the number of archers, the mighty men of the children of Kedar, shall be diminished: for the LORD God of Israel hath spoken <supplied>it.</supplied>
     
      </verse>
      </chapter>
