<?xml version="1.0"?>
<chapter translation="KJV" testament="Old" book="Isaiah" n="24" book-chapters="66">
      <verse>Behold, the LORD maketh the earth empty, and maketh it waste, and turneth it upside down, and scattereth abroad the inhabitants thereof.
</verse><verse>And it shall be, as with the people, so with the priest; as with the servant, so with his master; as with the maid, so with her mistress; as with the buyer, so with the seller; as with the lender, so with the borrower; as with the taker of
usury, so with the giver of usury to him.
</verse><verse>The land shall be utterly emptied, and utterly spoiled: for the LORD hath spoken this word.
</verse><verse>The earth mourneth <supplied>and</supplied> fadeth away, the world languisheth <supplied>and</supplied> fadeth away, the haughty people of the earth do languish.
</verse><verse>The earth also is defiled under the inhabitants thereof; because they have transgressed the laws, changed the ordinance, broken the everlasting covenant.
</verse><verse>Therefore hath the curse devoured the earth, and they that dwell therein are desolate: therefore the inhabitants of the earth are burned, and few men left.
</verse><verse>The new wine mourneth, the vine languisheth, all the merryhearted do sigh.
</verse><verse>The mirth of tabrets ceaseth, the noise of them that rejoice endeth, the joy of the harp ceaseth.
</verse><verse>They shall not drink wine with a song; strong drink shall be bitter to them that drink it.
</verse><verse>The city of confusion is broken down: every house is shut up, that no man may come in.
</verse><verse><supplied>There is</supplied> a crying for wine in the streets; all joy is darkened, the mirth of the land is gone.
</verse><verse>In the city is left desolation, and the gate is smitten with destruction.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>When thus it shall be in the midst of the land among the people, <supplied>there shall be</supplied> as the shaking of an olive tree, <supplied>and</supplied> as the gleaning grapes when the vintage is done.
</verse><verse>They shall lift up their voice, they shall sing for the majesty of the LORD, they shall cry aloud from the sea.
</verse><verse>Wherefore glorify ye the LORD in the fires, <supplied>even</supplied> the name of the LORD God of Israel in the isles of the sea.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>From the uttermost part of the earth have we heard songs, <supplied>even</supplied> glory to the righteous. But I said, My leanness, my leanness, woe unto me! the treacherous dealers have dealt treacherously; yea, the treacherous dealers have dealt very
treacherously.
</verse><verse>Fear, and the pit, and the snare, <supplied>are</supplied> upon thee, O inhabitant of the earth.
</verse><verse>And it shall come to pass, <supplied>that</supplied> he who fleeth from the noise of the fear shall fall into the pit; and he that cometh up out of the midst of the pit shall be taken in the snare: for the windows from on high are open, and the foundations
of the earth do shake.
</verse><verse>The earth is utterly broken down, the earth is clean dissolved, the earth is moved exceedingly.
</verse><verse>The earth shall reel to and fro like a drunkard, and shall be removed like a cottage; and the transgression thereof shall be heavy upon it; and it shall fall, and not rise again.
</verse><verse>And it shall come to pass in that day, <supplied>that</supplied> the LORD shall punish the host of the high ones <supplied>that are</supplied> on high, and the kings of the earth upon the earth.
</verse><verse>And they shall be gathered together, <supplied>as</supplied> prisoners are gathered in the pit, and shall be shut up in the prison, and after many days shall they be visited.
</verse><verse>Then the moon shall be confounded, and the sun ashamed, when the LORD of hosts shall reign in mount Zion, and in Jerusalem, and before his ancients gloriously.
     
      </verse>
      </chapter>
