<?xml version="1.0"?>
<chapter translation="KJV" testament="Old" book="Isaiah" n="41" book-chapters="66">
      <verse>Keep silence before me, O islands; and let the people renew <supplied>their</supplied> strength: let them come near; then let them speak: let us come near together to judgment.
</verse><verse>Who raised up the righteous <supplied>man</supplied> from the east, called him to his foot, gave the nations before him, and made <supplied>him</supplied> rule over kings? he gave <supplied>them</supplied> as the dust to his sword, <supplied>and</supplied> as driven stubble to his bow.
</verse><verse>He pursued them, <supplied>and</supplied> passed safely; <supplied>even</supplied> by the way <supplied>that</supplied> he had not gone with his feet.
</verse><verse>Who hath wrought and done <supplied>it,</supplied> calling the generations from the beginning? I the LORD, the first, and with the last; I <supplied>am</supplied> he.
</verse><verse>The isles saw <supplied>it,</supplied> and feared; the ends of the earth were afraid, drew near, and came.
</verse><verse>They helped every one his neighbour; and <supplied>every one</supplied> said to his brother, Be of good courage.
</verse><verse>So the carpenter encouraged the goldsmith, <supplied>and</supplied> he that smootheth <supplied>with</supplied> the hammer him that smote the anvil, saying, It is ready for the sodering: and he fastened it with nails, <supplied>that</supplied> it should not be moved.
</verse><verse>But thou, Israel, <supplied>art</supplied> my servant, Jacob whom I have chosen, the seed of Abraham my friend.
</verse><verse><supplied>Thou</supplied> whom I have taken from the ends of the earth, and called thee from the chief men thereof, and said unto thee, Thou <supplied>art</supplied> my servant; I have chosen thee, and not cast thee away.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>Fear thou not; for I <supplied>am</supplied> with thee: be not dismayed; for I <supplied>am</supplied> thy God: I will strengthen thee; yea, I will help thee; yea, I will uphold thee with the right hand of my righteousness.
</verse><verse>Behold, all they that were incensed against thee shall be ashamed and confounded: they shall be as nothing; and they that strive with thee shall perish.
</verse><verse>Thou shalt seek them, and shalt not find them, <supplied>even</supplied> them that contended with thee: they that war against thee shall be as nothing, and as a thing of nought.
</verse><verse>For I the LORD thy God will hold thy right hand, saying unto thee, Fear not; I will help thee.
</verse><verse>Fear not, thou worm Jacob, <supplied>and</supplied> ye men of Israel; I will help thee, saith the LORD, and thy redeemer, the Holy One of Israel.
</verse><verse>Behold, I will make thee a new sharp threshing instrument having teeth: thou shalt thresh the mountains, and beat <supplied>them</supplied> small, and shalt make the hills as chaff.
</verse><verse>Thou shalt fan them, and the wind shall carry them away, and the whirlwind shall scatter them: and thou shalt rejoice in the LORD, <supplied>and</supplied> shalt glory in the Holy One of Israel.
</verse><verse><supplied>When</supplied> the poor and needy seek water, and <supplied>there is</supplied> none, <supplied>and</supplied> their tongue faileth for thirst, I the LORD will hear them, <supplied>I</supplied> the God of Israel will not forsake them.
</verse><verse>I will open rivers in high places, and fountains in the midst of the valleys: I will make the wilderness a pool of water, and the dry land springs of water.
</verse><verse>I will plant in the wilderness the cedar, the shittah tree, and the myrtle, and the oil tree; I will set in the desert the fir tree, <supplied>and</supplied> the pine, and the box tree together:
</verse><verse>That they may see, and know, and consider, and understand together, that the hand of the LORD hath done this, and the Holy One of Israel hath created it.
</verse><verse>Produce your cause, saith the LORD; bring forth your strong <supplied>reasons,</supplied> saith the King of Jacob.
</verse><verse>Let them bring <supplied>them</supplied> forth, and shew us what shall happen: let them shew the former things, what they <supplied>be,</supplied> that we may consider them, and know the latter end of them; or declare us things for to come.
</verse><verse>Shew the things that are to come hereafter, that we may know that ye <supplied>are</supplied> gods: yea, do good, or do evil, that we may be dismayed, and behold <supplied>it</supplied> together.
</verse><verse>Behold, ye <supplied>are</supplied> of nothing, and your work of nought: an abomination <supplied>is he that</supplied> chooseth you.
</verse><verse>I have raised up <supplied>one</supplied> from the north, and he shall come: from the rising of the sun shall he call upon my name: and he shall come upon princes as <supplied>upon</supplied> morter, and as the potter treadeth clay.
</verse><verse>Who hath declared from the beginning, that we may know? and beforetime, that we may say, <supplied>He is</supplied> righteous? yea, <supplied>there is</supplied> none that sheweth, yea, <supplied>there is</supplied> none that declareth, yea, <supplied>there is</supplied> none that heareth your
words.
</verse><verse>The first <supplied>shall say</supplied> to Zion, Behold, behold them: and I will give to Jerusalem one that bringeth good tidings.
</verse><verse>For I beheld, and <supplied>there was</supplied> no man; even among them, and <supplied>there was</supplied> no counsellor, that, when I asked of them, could answer a word.
</verse><verse>Behold, they <supplied>are</supplied> all vanity; their works <supplied>are</supplied> nothing: their molten images <supplied>are</supplied> wind and confusion.
     
      </verse>
      </chapter>
