<chapter translation="KJV" testament="Old" book="ISA" n="51">
      <verse>Hearken to me, ye that follow after righteousness, ye that seek the LORD: look unto the rock <supplied>whence</supplied> ye are hewn, and to the hole of the pit <supplied>whence</supplied> ye are digged.
</verse><verse>Look unto Abraham your father, and unto Sarah <supplied>that</supplied> bare you: for I called him alone, and blessed him, and increased him.
</verse><verse>For the LORD shall comfort Zion: he will comfort all her waste places; and he will make her wilderness like Eden, and her desert like the garden of the LORD; joy and gladness shall be found therein, thanksgiving, and the voice of melody.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>Hearken unto me, my people; and give ear unto me, O my nation: for a law shall proceed from me, and I will make my judgment to rest for a light of the people.
</verse><verse>My righteousness <supplied>is</supplied> near; my salvation is gone forth, and mine arms shall judge the people; the isles shall wait upon me, and on mine arm shall they trust.
</verse><verse>Lift up your eyes to the heavens, and look upon the earth beneath: for the heavens shall vanish away like smoke, and the earth shall wax old like a garment, and they that dwell therein shall die in like manner: but my salvation shall be for
ever, and my righteousness shall not be abolished.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>Hearken unto me, ye that know righteousness, the people in whose heart <supplied>is</supplied> my law; fear ye not the reproach of men, neither be ye afraid of their revilings.
</verse><verse>For the moth shall eat them up like a garment, and the worm shall eat them like wool: but my righteousness shall be for ever, and my salvation from generation to generation.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>Awake, awake, put on strength, O arm of the LORD; awake, as in the ancient days, in the generations of old. <supplied>Art</supplied> thou not it that hath cut Rahab, <supplied>and</supplied> wounded the dragon?
</verse><verse><supplied>Art</supplied> thou not it which hath dried the sea, the waters of the great deep; that hath made the depths of the sea a way for the ransomed to pass over?
</verse><verse>Therefore the redeemed of the LORD shall return, and come with singing unto Zion; and everlasting joy <supplied>shall be</supplied> upon their head: they shall obtain gladness and joy; <supplied>and</supplied> sorrow and mourning shall flee away.
</verse><verse>I, <supplied>even</supplied> I, <supplied>am</supplied> he that comforteth you: who <supplied>art</supplied> thou, that thou shouldest be afraid of a man <supplied>that</supplied> shall die, and of the son of man <supplied>which</supplied> shall be made as grass;
</verse><verse>And forgettest the LORD thy maker, that hath stretched forth the heavens, and laid the foundations of the earth; and hast feared continually every day because of the fury of the oppressor, as if he were ready to destroy? and where <supplied>is</supplied>
the fury of the oppressor?
</verse><verse>The captive exile hasteneth that he may be loosed, and that he should not die in the pit, nor that his bread should fail.
</verse><verse>But I <supplied>am</supplied> the LORD thy God, that divided the sea, whose waves roared: The LORD of hosts <supplied>is</supplied> his name.
</verse><verse>And I have put my words in thy mouth, and I have covered thee in the shadow of mine hand, that I may plant the heavens, and lay the foundations of the earth, and say unto Zion, Thou <supplied>art</supplied> my people.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>Awake, awake, stand up, O Jerusalem, which hast drunk at the hand of the LORD the cup of his fury; thou hast drunken the dregs of the cup of trembling, <supplied>and</supplied> wrung <supplied>them</supplied> out.
</verse><verse><supplied>There is</supplied> none to guide her among all the sons <supplied>whom</supplied> she hath brought forth; neither <supplied>is there any</supplied> that taketh her by the hand of all the sons <supplied>that</supplied> she hath brought up.
</verse><verse>These two <supplied>things</supplied> are come unto thee; who shall be sorry for thee? desolation, and destruction, and the famine, and the sword: by whom shall I comfort thee?
</verse><verse>Thy sons have fainted, they lie at the head of all the streets, as a wild bull in a net: they are full of the fury of the LORD, the rebuke of thy God.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>Therefore hear now this, thou afflicted, and drunken, but not with wine:
</verse><verse>Thus saith thy Lord the LORD, and thy God <supplied>that</supplied> pleadeth the cause of his people, Behold, I have taken out of thine hand the cup of trembling, <supplied>even</supplied> the dregs of the cup of my fury; thou shalt no more drink it again:
</verse><verse>But I will put it into the hand of them that afflict thee; which have said to thy soul, Bow down, that we may go over: and thou hast laid thy body as the ground, and as the street, to them that went over.
     
      </verse>
      </chapter>