<?xml version="1.0"?>
<chapter translation="KJV" testament="Old" book="Isaiah" n="57" book-chapters="66">
      <verse>The righteous perisheth, and no man layeth <supplied>it</supplied> to heart: and merciful men <supplied>are</supplied> taken away, none considering that the righteous is taken away from the evil <supplied>to come. </supplied></verse><verse>He shall enter into peace: they shall rest in
their beds, <supplied>each one</supplied> walking <supplied>in</supplied> his uprightness.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>But draw near hither, ye sons of the sorceress, the seed of the adulterer and the whore.
</verse><verse>Against whom do ye sport yourselves? against whom make ye a wide mouth, <supplied>and</supplied> draw out the tongue? <supplied>are</supplied> ye not children of transgression, a seed of falsehood,
</verse><verse>Enflaming yourselves with idols under every green tree, slaying the children in the valleys under the clifts of the rocks?
</verse><verse>Among the smooth <supplied>stones</supplied> of the stream <supplied>is</supplied> thy portion; they, they <supplied>are</supplied> thy lot: even to them hast thou poured a drink offering, thou hast offered a meat offering. Should I receive comfort in these?
</verse><verse>Upon a lofty and high mountain hast thou set thy bed: even thither wentest thou up to offer sacrifice.
</verse><verse>Behind the doors also and the posts hast thou set up thy remembrance: for thou hast discovered <supplied>thyself to another</supplied> than me, and art gone up; thou hast enlarged thy bed, and made thee <supplied>a covenant</supplied> with them; thou lovedst their bed
where thou sawest <supplied>it. </supplied></verse><verse>And thou wentest to the king with ointment, and didst increase thy perfumes, and didst send thy messengers far off, and didst debase <supplied>thyself even</supplied> unto hell.
</verse><verse>Thou art wearied in the greatness of thy way; <supplied>yet</supplied> saidst thou not, There is no hope: thou hast found the life of thine hand; therefore thou wast not grieved.
</verse><verse>And of whom hast thou been afraid or feared, that thou hast lied, and hast not remembered me, nor laid <supplied>it</supplied> to thy heart? have not I held my peace even of old, and thou fearest me not?
</verse><verse>I will declare thy righteousness, and thy works; for they shall not profit thee.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>When thou criest, let thy companies deliver thee; but the wind shall carry them all away; vanity shall take <supplied>them:</supplied> but he that putteth his trust in me shall possess the land, and shall inherit my holy mountain;
</verse><verse>And shall say, Cast ye up, cast ye up, prepare the way, take up the stumblingblock out of the way of my people.
</verse><verse>For thus saith the high and lofty One that inhabiteth eternity, whose name <supplied>is</supplied> Holy; I dwell in the high and holy <supplied>place,</supplied> with him also <supplied>that is</supplied> of a contrite and humble spirit, to revive the spirit of the humble, and to
revive the heart of the contrite ones.
</verse><verse>For I will not contend for ever, neither will I be always wroth: for the spirit should fail before me, and the souls <supplied>which</supplied> I have made.
</verse><verse>For the iniquity of his covetousness was I wroth, and smote him: I hid me, and was wroth, and he went on frowardly in the way of his heart.
</verse><verse>I have seen his ways, and will heal him: I will lead him also, and restore comforts unto him and to his mourners.
</verse><verse>I create the fruit of the lips; Peace, peace to <supplied>him that is</supplied> far off, and to <supplied>him that is</supplied> near, saith the LORD; and I will heal him.
</verse><verse>But the wicked <supplied>are</supplied> like the troubled sea, when it cannot rest, whose waters cast up mire and dirt.
</verse><verse><supplied>There is</supplied> no peace, saith my God, to the wicked.
     
      </verse>
      </chapter>
