<?xml version="1.0"?>
<chapter translation="KJV" testament="Old" book="Isaiah" n="64">
      <verse>Oh that thou wouldest rend the heavens, that thou wouldest come down, that the mountains might flow down at thy presence,
</verse><verse>As <supplied>when</supplied> the melting fire burneth, the fire causeth the waters to boil, to make thy name known to thine adversaries, <supplied>that</supplied> the nations may tremble at thy presence!
</verse><verse>When thou didst terrible things <supplied>which</supplied> we looked not for, thou camest down, the mountains flowed down at thy presence.
</verse><verse>For since the beginning of the world <supplied>men</supplied> have not heard, nor perceived by the ear, neither hath the eye seen, O God, beside thee, <supplied>what</supplied> he hath prepared for him that waiteth for him.
</verse><verse>Thou meetest him that rejoiceth and worketh righteousness, <supplied>those that</supplied> remember thee in thy ways: behold, thou art wroth; for we have sinned: in those is continuance, and we shall be saved.
</verse><verse>But we are all as an unclean <supplied>thing,</supplied> and all our righteousnesses <supplied>are</supplied> as filthy rags; and we all do fade as a leaf; and our iniquities, like the wind, have taken us away.
</verse><verse>And <supplied>there is</supplied> none that calleth upon thy name, that stirreth up himself to take hold of thee: for thou hast hid thy face from us, and hast consumed us, because of our iniquities.
</verse><verse>But now, O LORD, thou <supplied>art</supplied> our father; we <supplied>are</supplied> the clay, and thou our potter; and we all <supplied>are</supplied> the work of thy hand.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>Be not wroth very sore, O LORD, neither remember iniquity for ever: behold, see, we beseech thee, we <supplied>are</supplied> all thy people.
</verse><verse>Thy holy cities are a wilderness, Zion is a wilderness, Jerusalem a desolation.
</verse><verse>Our holy and our beautiful house, where our fathers praised thee, is burned up with fire: and all our pleasant things are laid waste.
</verse><verse>Wilt thou refrain thyself for these <supplied>things,</supplied> O LORD? wilt thou hold thy peace, and afflict us very sore?
     
      </verse>
      </chapter>
