<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="2 Chronicles" book-id="14" n="1">
<verse>Solomon son of David took a firm grip on the reins of his kingdom. GOD was with him and gave him much help.</verse>
<verse>Solomon addressed all Israel--the commanders and captains, the judges, every leader, and all the heads of families.</verse>
<verse>Then Solomon and the entire company went to the worship center at Gibeon--that's where the Tent of Meeting of God was, the one that Moses the servant of GOD had made in the wilderness.</verse>
<verse>The Chest of God, though, was in Jerusalem--David had brought it up from Kiriath Jearim, prepared a special place for it, and pitched a tent for it.</verse>
<verse>But the Bronze Altar that Bezalel son of Uri, the son of Hur, had made was in Gibeon, in its place before the Tabernacle of GOD; and that is where Solomon and the congregation gathered to pray.</verse>
<verse>Solomon worshiped GOD at the Bronze Altar in front of the Tent of Meeting; he sacrificed a thousand Whole-Burnt-Offerings on it.</verse>
<verse>That night God appeared to Solomon. God said, "What do you want from me? Ask."</verse>
<verse>Solomon answered, "You were extravagantly generous with David my father, and now you have made me king in his place.</verse>
<verse>Establish, GOD, the words you spoke to my father, for you've given me a staggering task, ruling this mob of people.</verse>
<verse>Yes, give me wisdom and knowledge as I come and go among this people--for who on his own is capable of leading these, your glorious people?"</verse>
<verse>God answered Solomon, "This is what has come out of your heart: You didn't grasp for money, wealth, fame, and the doom of your enemies; you didn't even ask for a long life. You asked for wisdom and knowledge so you could govern well my people over whom I've made you king.</verse>
<verse>Because of this, you get what you asked for--wisdom and knowledge. And I'm presenting you the rest as a bonus--money, wealth, and fame beyond anything the kings before or after you had or will have."</verse>
<verse>Then Solomon left the worship center at Gibeon and the Tent of Meeting and went to Jerusalem. He set to work as king of Israel.</verse>
<verse>Solomon collected chariots and horses: 1,400 chariots and 12,000 horses! He stabled them in the special chariot-cities as well as in Jerusalem.</verse>
<verse>The king made silver and gold as common as rocks, and cedar as common as the fig trees in the lowland hills.</verse>
<verse>His horses were brought in from Egypt and Cilicia, specially acquired by the king's agents.</verse>
<verse>Chariots from Egypt went for fifteen pounds of silver and a horse for about three and three-quarters of a pound of silver. Solomon carried on a brisk horse-trading business with the Hittite and Aramean royal houses.</verse>
</chapter>