<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="2 Chronicles" book-id="14" n="16">
<verse>But in the thirty-sixth year of Asa's reign, Baasha king of Israel attacked. He started it by building a fort at Ramah and closing the border between Israel and Judah to keep Asa king of Judah from leaving or entering.</verse>
<verse>Asa took silver and gold from the treasuries of The Temple of GOD and the royal palace and sent it to Ben-Hadad, king of Aram who lived in Damascus, with this message:</verse>
<verse>"Let's make a treaty like the one between our fathers. I'm showing my good faith with this gift of silver and gold. Break your deal with Baasha king of Israel so he'll quit fighting against me."</verse>
<verse>Ben-Hadad went along with King Asa and sent his troops against the towns of Israel. They sacked Ijon, Dan, Abel Maim, and all the store-cities of Naphtali.</verse>
<verse>When Baasha got the report, he quit fortifying Ramah.</verse>
<verse>Then King Asa issued orders to his people in Judah to haul away the logs and stones Baasha had used in the fortification of Ramah and used them himself to fortify Geba and Mizpah.</verse>
<verse>Just after that, Hanani the seer came to Asa king of Judah and said, "Because you went for help to the king of Aram and didn't ask GOD for help, you've lost a victory over the army of the king of Aram.</verse>
<verse>Didn't the Ethiopians and Libyans come against you with superior forces, completely outclassing you with their chariots and cavalry? But you asked GOD for help and he gave you the victory.</verse>
<verse>GOD is always on the alert, constantly on the lookout for people who are totally committed to him. You were foolish to go for human help when you could have had God's help. Now you're in trouble--one round of war after another."</verse>
<verse>At that, Asa lost his temper. Angry, he put Hanani in the stocks. At the same time Asa started abusing some of the people.</verse>
<verse>A full account of Asa is written in The Chronicles of the Kings of Judah.</verse>
<verse>In the thirty-ninth year of his reign Asa came down with a severe case of foot infection. He didn't ask GOD for help, but went instead to the doctors.</verse>
<verse>Then Asa died; he died in the forty-first year of his reign.</verse>
<verse>They buried him in a mausoleum that he had built for himself in the City of David. They laid him in a crypt full of aromatic oils and spices. Then they had a huge bonfire in his memory.</verse>
</chapter>