<chapter translation="NASB" testament="New" book="John" book_id="43" n="10">
<verse>"Truly, truly, I say to you, he who does not enter by the door into the fold of the sheep, but climbs up some other way, he is a thief and a robber.</verse>
<verse>"But he who enters by the door is a shepherd of the sheep.</verse>
<verse>"To him the doorkeeper opens, and the sheep hear his voice, and he calls his own sheep by name and leads them out.</verse>
<verse>"When he puts forth all his own, he goes ahead of them, and the sheep follow him because they know his voice.</verse>
<verse>"A stranger they simply will not follow, but will flee from him, because they do not know the voice of strangers."</verse>
<verse>This figure of speech Jesus spoke to them, but they did not understand what those things were which He had been saying to them.</verse>
<verse>So Jesus said to them again, "Truly, truly, I say to you, I am the door of the sheep.</verse>
<verse>"All who came before Me are thieves and robbers, but the sheep did not hear them.</verse>
<verse>"I am the door; if anyone enters through Me, he will be saved, and will go in and out and find pasture.</verse>
<verse>"The thief comes only to steal and kill and destroy; I came that they may have life, and have it abundantly.</verse>
<verse>"I am the good shepherd; the good shepherd lays down His life for the sheep.</verse>
<verse>"He who is a hired hand, and not a shepherd, who is not the owner of the sheep, sees the wolf coming, and leaves the sheep and flees, and the wolf snatches them and scatters them.</verse>
<verse>"He flees because he is a hired hand and is not concerned about the sheep.</verse>
<verse>"I am the good shepherd, and I know My own and My own know Me,</verse>
<verse>even as the Father knows Me and I know the Father; and I lay down My life for the sheep.</verse>
<verse>"I have other sheep, which are not of this fold; I must bring them also, and they will hear My voice; and they will become one flock with one shepherd.</verse>
<verse>"For this reason the Father loves Me, because I lay down My life so that I may take it again.</verse>
<verse>"No one has taken it away from Me, but I lay it down on My own initiative. I have authority to lay it down, and I have authority to take it up again. This commandment I received from My Father."</verse>
<verse>A division occurred again among the Jews because of these words.</verse>
<verse>Many of them were saying, "He has a demon and is insane. Why do you listen to Him?"</verse>
<verse>Others were saying, "These are not the sayings of one demon-possessed. A demon cannot open the eyes of the blind, can he?"</verse>
<verse>At that time the Feast of the Dedication took place at Jerusalem;</verse>
<verse>it was winter, and Jesus was walking in the temple in the portico of Solomon.</verse>
<verse>The Jews then gathered around Him, and were saying to Him, "How long will You keep us in suspense? If You are the Christ, tell us plainly."</verse>
<verse>Jesus answered them, "I told you, and you do not believe; the works that I do in My Father's name, these testify of Me.</verse>
<verse>"But you do not believe because you are not of My sheep.</verse>
<verse>"My sheep hear My voice, and I know them, and they follow Me;</verse>
<verse>and I give eternal life to them, and they will never perish; and no one will snatch them out of My hand.</verse>
<verse>"My Father, who has given them to Me, is greater than all; and no one is able to snatch them out of the Father's hand.</verse>
<verse>"I and the Father are one."</verse>
<verse>The Jews picked up stones again to stone Him.</verse>
<verse>Jesus answered them, "I showed you many good works from the Father; for which of them are you stoning Me?"</verse>
<verse>The Jews answered Him, "For a good work we do not stone You, but for blasphemy; and because You, being a man, make Yourself out to be God."</verse>
<verse>Jesus answered them, "Has it not been written in your Law, 'I SAID, YOU ARE GODS'?</verse>
<verse>"If he called them gods, to whom the word of God came (and the Scripture cannot be broken),</verse>
<verse>do you say of Him, whom the Father sanctified and sent into the world, 'You are blaspheming,' because I said, 'I am the Son of God'?</verse>
<verse>"If I do not do the works of My Father, do not believe Me;</verse>
<verse>but if I do them, though you do not believe Me, believe the works, so that you may know and understand that the Father is in Me, and I in the Father."</verse>
<verse>Therefore they were seeking again to seize Him, and He eluded their grasp.</verse>
<verse>And He went away again beyond the Jordan to the place where John was first baptizing, and He was staying there.</verse>
<verse>Many came to Him and were saying, "While John performed no sign, yet everything John said about this man was true."</verse>
<verse>Many believed in Him there.</verse>
</chapter>