<chapter translation="NASB" testament="New" book="John" book_id="43" n="16">
<verse>"These things I have spoken to you so that you may be kept from stumbling.</verse>
<verse>"They will make you outcasts from the synagogue, but an hour is coming for everyone who kills you to think that he is offering service to God.</verse>
<verse>"These things they will do because they have not known the Father or Me.</verse>
<verse>"But these things I have spoken to you, so that when their hour comes, you may remember that I told you of them. These things I did not say to you at the beginning, because I was with you.</verse>
<verse>"But now I am going to Him who sent Me; and none of you asks Me, 'Where are You going?'</verse>
<verse>"But because I have said these things to you, sorrow has filled your heart.</verse>
<verse>"But I tell you the truth, it is to your advantage that I go away; for if I do not go away, the Helper will not come to you; but if I go, I will send Him to you.</verse>
<verse>"And He, when He comes, will convict the world concerning sin and righteousness and judgment;</verse>
<verse>concerning sin, because they do not believe in Me;</verse>
<verse>and concerning righteousness, because I go to the Father and you no longer see Me;</verse>
<verse>and concerning judgment, because the ruler of this world has been judged.</verse>
<verse>"I have many more things to say to you, but you cannot bear them now.</verse>
<verse>"But when He, the Spirit of truth, comes, He will guide you into all the truth; for He will not speak on His own initiative, but whatever He hears, He will speak; and He will disclose to you what is to come.</verse>
<verse>"He will glorify Me, for He will take of Mine and will disclose it to you.</verse>
<verse>"All things that the Father has are Mine; therefore I said that He takes of Mine and will disclose it to you.</verse>
<verse>"A little while, and you will no longer see Me; and again a little while, and you will see Me."</verse>
<verse>Some of His disciples then said to one another, "What is this thing He is telling us, 'A little while, and you will not see Me; and again a little while, and you will see Me'; and, 'because I go to the Father'?"</verse>
<verse>So they were saying, "What is this that He says, 'A little while'? We do not know what He is talking about."</verse>
<verse>Jesus knew that they wished to question Him, and He said to them, "Are you deliberating together about this, that I said, 'A little while, and you will not see Me, and again a little while, and you will see Me'?</verse>
<verse>"Truly, truly, I say to you, that you will weep and lament, but the world will rejoice; you will grieve, but your grief will be turned into joy.</verse>
<verse>"Whenever a woman is in labor she has pain, because her hour has come; but when she gives birth to the child, she no longer remembers the anguish because of the joy that a child has been born into the world.</verse>
<verse>"Therefore you too have grief now; but I will see you again, and your heart will rejoice, and no one will take your joy away from you.</verse>
<verse>"In that day you will not question Me about anything. Truly, truly, I say to you, if you ask the Father for anything in My name, He will give it to you.</verse>
<verse>"Until now you have asked for nothing in My name; ask and you will receive, so that your joy may be made full.</verse>
<verse>"These things I have spoken to you in figurative language; an hour is coming when I will no longer speak to you in figurative language, but will tell you plainly of the Father.</verse>
<verse>"In that day you will ask in My name, and I do not say to you that I will request of the Father on your behalf;</verse>
<verse>for the Father Himself loves you, because you have loved Me and have believed that I came forth from the Father.</verse>
<verse>"I came forth from the Father and have come into the world; I am leaving the world again and going to the Father."</verse>
<verse>His disciples said, "Lo, now You are speaking plainly and are not using a figure of speech.</verse>
<verse>"Now we know that You know all things, and have no need for anyone to question You; by this we believe that You came from God."</verse>
<verse>Jesus answered them, "Do you now believe?</verse>
<verse>"Behold, an hour is coming, and has already come, for you to be scattered, each to his own home, and to leave Me alone; and yet I am not alone, because the Father is with Me.</verse>
<verse>"These things I have spoken to you, so that in Me you may have peace. In the world you have tribulation, but take courage; I have overcome the world."</verse>
</chapter>