<chapter translation="NASB" testament="New" book="John" book-id="43" n="19">
<verse>Pilate then took Jesus and scourged Him.</verse>
<verse>And the soldiers twisted together a crown of thorns and put it on His head, and put a purple robe on Him;</verse>
<verse>and they began to come up to Him and say, "Hail, King of the Jews!" and to give Him slaps in the face.</verse>
<verse>Pilate came out again and said to them, "Behold, I am bringing Him out to you so that you may know that I find no guilt in Him."</verse>
<verse>Jesus then came out, wearing the crown of thorns and the purple robe. Pilate said to them, "Behold, the Man!"</verse>
<verse>So when the chief priests and the officers saw Him, they cried out saying, "Crucify, crucify!" Pilate said to them, "Take Him yourselves and crucify Him, for I find no guilt in Him."</verse>
<verse>The Jews answered him, "We have a law, and by that law He ought to die because He made Himself out to be the Son of God."</verse>
<verse>Therefore when Pilate heard this statement, he was even more afraid;</verse>
<verse>and he entered into the Praetorium again and said to Jesus, "Where are You from?" But Jesus gave him no answer.</verse>
<verse>So Pilate said to Him, "You do not speak to me? Do You not know that I have authority to release You, and I have authority to crucify You?"</verse>
<verse>Jesus answered, "You would have no authority over Me, unless it had been given you from above; for this reason he who delivered Me to you has the greater sin."</verse>
<verse>As a result of this Pilate made efforts to release Him, but the Jews cried out saying, "If you release this Man, you are no friend of Caesar; everyone who makes himself out to be a king opposes Caesar."</verse>
<verse>Therefore when Pilate heard these words, he brought Jesus out, and sat down on the judgment seat at a place called The Pavement, but in Hebrew, Gabbatha.</verse>
<verse>Now it was the day of preparation for the Passover; it was about the sixth hour. And he said to the Jews, "Behold, your King!"</verse>
<verse>So they cried out, "Away with Him, away with Him, crucify Him!" Pilate said to them, "Shall I crucify your King?" The chief priests answered, "We have no king but Caesar."</verse>
<verse>So he then handed Him over to them to be crucified.</verse>
<verse>They took Jesus, therefore, and He went out, bearing His own cross, to the place called the Place of a Skull, which is called in Hebrew, Golgotha.</verse>
<verse>There they crucified Him, and with Him two other men, one on either side, and Jesus in between.</verse>
<verse>Pilate also wrote an inscription and put it on the cross. It was written, "JESUS THE NAZARENE, THE KING OF THE JEWS."</verse>
<verse>Therefore many of the Jews read this inscription, for the place where Jesus was crucified was near the city; and it was written in Hebrew, Latin and in Greek.</verse>
<verse>So the chief priests of the Jews were saying to Pilate, "Do not write, 'The King of the Jews'; but that He said, 'I am King of the Jews.'"</verse>
<verse>Pilate answered, "What I have written I have written."</verse>
<verse>Then the soldiers, when they had crucified Jesus, took His outer garments and made four parts, a part to every soldier and also the tunic; now the tunic was seamless, woven in one piece.</verse>
<verse>So they said to one another, "Let us not tear it, but cast lots for it, to decide whose it shall be"; this was to fulfill the Scripture: "THEY DIVIDED MY OUTER GARMENTS AMONG THEM, AND FOR MY CLOTHING THEY CAST LOTS."</verse>
<verse>Therefore the soldiers did these things. But standing by the cross of Jesus were His mother, and His mother's sister, Mary the wife of Clopas, and Mary Magdalene.</verse>
<verse>When Jesus then saw His mother, and the disciple whom He loved standing nearby, He said to His mother, "Woman, behold, your son!"</verse>
<verse>Then He said to the disciple, "Behold, your mother!" From that hour the disciple took her into his own household.</verse>
<verse>After this, Jesus, knowing that all things had already been accomplished, to fulfill the Scripture, said, "I am thirsty."</verse>
<verse>A jar full of sour wine was standing there; so they put a sponge full of the sour wine upon a branch of hyssop and brought it up to His mouth.</verse>
<verse>Therefore when Jesus had received the sour wine, He said, "It is finished!" And He bowed His head and gave up His spirit.</verse>
<verse>Then the Jews, because it was the day of preparation, so that the bodies would not remain on the cross on the Sabbath (for that Sabbath was a high day), asked Pilate that their legs might be broken, and that they might be taken away.</verse>
<verse>So the soldiers came, and broke the legs of the first man and of the other who was crucified with Him;</verse>
<verse>but coming to Jesus, when they saw that He was already dead, they did not break His legs.</verse>
<verse>But one of the soldiers pierced His side with a spear, and immediately blood and water came out.</verse>
<verse>And he who has seen has testified, and his testimony is true; and he knows that he is telling the truth, so that you also may believe.</verse>
<verse>For these things came to pass to fulfill the Scripture, "NOT A BONE OF HIM SHALL BE BROKEN."</verse>
<verse>And again another Scripture says, "THEY SHALL LOOK ON HIM WHOM THEY PIERCED."</verse>
<verse>After these things Joseph of Arimathea, being a disciple of Jesus, but a secret one for fear of the Jews, asked Pilate that he might take away the body of Jesus; and Pilate granted permission. So he came and took away His body.</verse>
<verse>Nicodemus, who had first come to Him by night, also came, bringing a mixture of myrrh and aloes, about a hundred pounds weight.</verse>
<verse>So they took the body of Jesus and bound it in linen wrappings with the spices, as is the burial custom of the Jews.</verse>
<verse>Now in the place where He was crucified there was a garden, and in the garden a new tomb in which no one had yet been laid.</verse>
<verse>Therefore because of the Jewish day of preparation, since the tomb was nearby, they laid Jesus there.</verse>
</chapter>