<chapter translation="NASB" testament="New" book="John" book-id="43" n="21">
<verse>After these things Jesus manifested Himself again to the disciples at the Sea of Tiberias, and He manifested Himself in this way.</verse>
<verse>Simon Peter, and Thomas called Didymus, and Nathanael of Cana in Galilee, and the sons of Zebedee, and two others of His disciples were together.</verse>
<verse>Simon Peter said to them, "I am going fishing." They said to him, "We will also come with you." They went out and got into the boat; and that night they caught nothing.</verse>
<verse>But when the day was now breaking, Jesus stood on the beach; yet the disciples did not know that it was Jesus.</verse>
<verse>So Jesus said to them, "Children, you do not have any fish, do you?" They answered Him, "No."</verse>
<verse>And He said to them, "Cast the net on the right-hand side of the boat and you will find a catch." So they cast, and then they were not able to haul it in because of the great number of fish.</verse>
<verse>Therefore that disciple whom Jesus loved said to Peter, "It is the Lord." So when Simon Peter heard that it was the Lord, he put his outer garment on (for he was stripped for work), and threw himself into the sea.</verse>
<verse>But the other disciples came in the little boat, for they were not far from the land, but about one hundred yards away, dragging the net full of fish.</verse>
<verse>So when they got out on the land, they saw a charcoal fire already laid and fish placed on it, and bread.</verse>
<verse>Jesus said to them, "Bring some of the fish which you have now caught."</verse>
<verse>Simon Peter went up and drew the net to land, full of large fish, a hundred and fifty-three; and although there were so many, the net was not torn.</verse>
<verse>Jesus said to them, "Come and have breakfast." None of the disciples ventured to question Him, "Who are You?" knowing that it was the Lord.</verse>
<verse>Jesus came and took the bread and gave it to them, and the fish likewise.</verse>
<verse>This is now the third time that Jesus was manifested to the disciples, after He was raised from the dead.</verse>
<verse>So when they had finished breakfast, Jesus said to Simon Peter, "Simon, son of John, do you love Me more than these?" He said to Him, "Yes, Lord; You know that I love You." He said to him, "Tend My lambs."</verse>
<verse>He said to him again a second time, "Simon, son of John, do you love Me?" He said to Him, "Yes, Lord; You know that I love You." He said to him, "Shepherd My sheep."</verse>
<verse>He said to him the third time, "Simon, son of John, do you love Me?" Peter was grieved because He said to him the third time, "Do you love Me?" And he said to Him, "Lord, You know all things; You know that I love You." Jesus said to him, "Tend My sheep.</verse>
<verse>"Truly, truly, I say to you, when you were younger, you used to gird yourself and walk wherever you wished; but when you grow old, you will stretch out your hands and someone else will gird you, and bring you where you do not wish to go."</verse>
<verse>Now this He said, signifying by what kind of death he would glorify God. And when He had spoken this, He said to him, "Follow Me!"</verse>
<verse>Peter, turning around, saw the disciple whom Jesus loved following them; the one who also had leaned back on His bosom at the supper and said, "Lord, who is the one who betrays You?"</verse>
<verse>So Peter seeing him said to Jesus, "Lord, and what about this man?"</verse>
<verse>Jesus said to him, "If I want him to remain until I come, what is that to you? You follow Me!"</verse>
<verse>Therefore this saying went out among the brethren that that disciple would not die; yet Jesus did not say to him that he would not die, but only, "If I want him to remain until I come, what is that to you?"</verse>
<verse>This is the disciple who is testifying to these things and wrote these things, and we know that his testimony is true.</verse>
<verse>And there are also many other things which Jesus did, which if they were written in detail, I suppose that even the world itself would not contain the books that would be written.</verse>
</chapter>