<chapter translation="MSG" testament="New" book="Mark" book-id="41" n="1">
<verse>The good news of Jesus Christ--the Message!-begins here,</verse>
<verse>following to the letter the scroll of the prophet Isaiah. Watch closely: I'm sending my preacher ahead of you; He'll make the road smooth for you.</verse>
<verse>Thunder in the desert! Prepare for God's arrival! Make the road smooth and straight!</verse>
<verse>John the Baptizer appeared in the wild, preaching a baptism of life-change that leads to forgiveness of sins.</verse>
<verse>People thronged to him from Judea and Jerusalem and, as they confessed their sins, were baptized by him in the Jordan River into a changed life.</verse>
<verse>John wore a camel-hair habit, tied at the waist with a leather belt. He ate locusts and wild field honey.</verse>
<verse>As he preached he said, "The real action comes next: The star in this drama, to whom I'm a mere stagehand, will change your life.</verse>
<verse>I'm baptizing you here in the river, turning your old life in for a kingdom life. His baptism--a holy baptism by the Holy Spirit--will change you from the inside out."</verse>
<verse>At this time, Jesus came from Nazareth in Galilee and was baptized by John in the Jordan.</verse>
<verse>The moment he came out of the water, he saw the sky split open and God's Spirit, looking like a dove, come down on him.</verse>
<verse>Along with the Spirit, a voice: "You are my Son, chosen and marked by my love, pride of my life."</verse>
<verse>At once, this same Spirit pushed Jesus out into the wild.</verse>
<verse>For forty wilderness days and nights he was tested by Satan. Wild animals were his companions, and angels took care of him.</verse>
<verse>After John was arrested, Jesus went to Galilee preaching the Message of God:</verse>
<verse>"Time's up! God's kingdom is here. Change your life and believe the Message."</verse>
<verse>Passing along the beach of Lake Galilee, he saw Simon and his brother Andrew net-fishing. Fishing was their regular work.</verse>
<verse>Jesus said to them, "Come with me. I'll make a new kind of fisherman out of you. I'll show you how to catch men and women instead of perch and bass."</verse>
<verse>They didn't ask questions. They dropped their nets and followed.</verse>
<verse>A dozen yards or so down the beach, he saw the brothers James and John, Zebedee's sons. They were in the boat, mending their fishnets.</verse>
<verse>Right off, he made the same offer. Immediately, they left their father Zebedee, the boat, and the hired hands, and followed.</verse>
<verse>Then they entered Capernaum. When the Sabbath arrived, Jesus lost no time in getting to the meeting place. He spent the day there teaching.</verse>
<verse>They were surprised at his teaching--so forthright, so confident--not quibbling and quoting like the religion scholars.</verse>
<verse>Suddenly, while still in the meeting place, he was interrupted by a man who was deeply disturbed and yelling out,</verse>
<verse>"What business do you have here with us, Jesus? Nazarene! I know what you're up to! You're the Holy One of God, and you've come to destroy us!"</verse>
<verse>Jesus shut him up: "Quiet! Get out of him!"</verse>
<verse>The afflicting spirit threw the man into spasms, protesting loudly--and got out.</verse>
<verse>Everyone there was incredulous, buzzing with curiosity. "What's going on here? A new teaching that does what it says? He shuts up defiling, demonic spirits and sends them packing!"</verse>
<verse>News of this traveled fast and was soon all over Galilee.</verse>
<verse>Directly on leaving the meeting place, they came to Simon and Andrew's house, accompanied by James and John.</verse>
<verse>Simon's mother-in-law was sick in bed, burning up with fever. They told Jesus.</verse>
<verse>He went to her, took her hand, and raised her up. No sooner had the fever left than she was up fixing dinner for them.</verse>
<verse>That evening, after the sun was down, they brought sick and evil-afflicted people to him,</verse>
<verse>the whole city lined up at his door!</verse>
<verse>He cured their sick bodies and tormented spirits. Because the demons knew his true identity, he didn't let them say a word.</verse>
<verse>While it was still night, way before dawn, he got up and went out to a secluded spot and prayed.</verse>
<verse>Simon and those with him went looking for him.</verse>
<verse>They found him and said, "Everybody's looking for you."</verse>
<verse>Jesus said, "Let's go to the rest of the villages so I can preach there also. This is why I've come."</verse>
<verse>He went to their meeting places all through Galilee, preaching and throwing out the demons.</verse>
<verse>A leper came to him, begging on his knees, "If you want to, you can cleanse me."</verse>
<verse>Deeply moved, Jesus put out his hand, touched him, and said, "I want to. Be clean."</verse>
<verse>Then and there the leprosy was gone, his skin smooth and healthy.</verse>
<verse>Jesus dismissed him with strict orders:</verse>
<verse>"Say nothing to anyone. Take the offering for cleansing that Moses prescribed and present yourself to the priest. This will validate your healing to the people."</verse>
<verse>But as soon as the man was out of earshot, he told everyone he met what had happened, spreading the news all over town. So Jesus kept to out-of-the-way places, no longer able to move freely in and out of the city. But people found him, and came from all over.</verse>
</chapter>