<?xml version="1.0"?>
<chapter translation="KJV" testament="Old" book="Psalm" n="108" book_id="19">
      A Song <supplied>or</supplied> Psalm of David.
      
      
      
       
        <verse>O God, my heart is fixed; I will sing and give praise, even with my glory.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Awake, psaltery and harp: I <supplied>myself</supplied> will awake early.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>I will praise thee, O LORD, among the people: and I will sing praises unto thee among the nations.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>For thy mercy <supplied>is</supplied> great above the heavens: and thy truth <supplied>reacheth</supplied> unto the clouds.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Be thou exalted, O God, above the heavens: and thy glory above all the earth;
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>That thy beloved may be delivered: save <supplied>with</supplied> thy right hand, and answer me.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>God hath spoken in his holiness; I will rejoice, I will divide Shechem, and mete out the valley of Succoth.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Gilead <supplied>is</supplied> mine; Manasseh <supplied>is</supplied> mine; Ephraim also <supplied>is</supplied> the strength of mine head; Judah <supplied>is</supplied> my lawgiver;
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Moab <supplied>is</supplied> my washpot; over Edom will I cast out my shoe; over Philistia will I triumph.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Who will bring me into the strong city? who will lead me into Edom?
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>
        <supplied>Wilt</supplied> not <supplied>thou,</supplied> O God, <supplied>who</supplied> hast cast us off? and wilt not thou, O God, go forth with our hosts?
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Give us help from trouble: for vain <supplied>is</supplied> the help of man.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Through God we shall do valiantly: for he <supplied>it is that</supplied> shall tread down our enemies.
      
      
       
      
      
       
        </verse>
        </chapter>
