<?xml version="1.0"?>
<chapter translation="KJV" testament="Old" book="Psalm" n="119" book-id="19">
      ALEPH.
      
      
      
       
        <verse>Blessed <supplied>are</supplied> the undefiled in the way, who walk in the law of the LORD.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Blessed <supplied>are</supplied> they that keep his testimonies, <supplied>and that</supplied> seek him with the whole heart.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>They also do no iniquity: they walk in his ways.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Thou hast commanded <supplied>us</supplied> to keep thy precepts diligently.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>O that my ways were directed to keep thy statutes!
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Then shall I not be ashamed, when I have respect unto all thy commandments.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>I will praise thee with uprightness of heart, when I shall have learned thy righteous judgments.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>I will keep thy statutes: O forsake me not utterly.
      
      
       
      
      
       
      
      
       BETH.
      
      
       
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Wherewithal shall a young man cleanse his way? by taking heed <supplied>thereto</supplied> according to thy word.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>With my whole heart have I sought thee: O let me not wander from thy commandments.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Thy word have I hid in mine heart, that I might not sin against thee.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Blessed <supplied>art</supplied> thou, O LORD: teach me thy statutes.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>With my lips have I declared all the judgments of thy mouth.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>I have rejoiced in the way of thy testimonies, as <supplied>much as</supplied> in all riches.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>I will meditate in thy precepts, and have respect unto thy ways.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>I will delight myself in thy statutes: I will not forget thy word.
      
      
       
      
      
       
      
      
       GIMEL.
      
      
       
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Deal bountifully with thy servant, <supplied>that</supplied> I may live, and keep thy word.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Open thou mine eyes, that I may behold wondrous things out of thy law.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>I <supplied>am</supplied> a stranger in the earth: hide not thy commandments from me.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>My soul breaketh for the longing <supplied>that it hath</supplied> unto thy judgments at all times.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Thou hast rebuked the proud <supplied>that are</supplied> cursed, which do err from thy commandments.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Remove from me reproach and contempt; for I have kept thy testimonies.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Princes also did sit <supplied>and</supplied> speak against me: <supplied>but</supplied> thy servant did meditate in thy statutes.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Thy testimonies also <supplied>are</supplied> my delight <supplied>and</supplied> my counsellors.
      
      
       
      
      
       
      
      
       DALETH.
      
      
       
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>My soul cleaveth unto the dust: quicken thou me according to thy word.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>I have declared my ways, and thou heardest me: teach me thy statutes.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Make me to understand the way of thy precepts: so shall I talk of thy wondrous works.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>My soul melteth for heaviness: strengthen thou me according unto thy word.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Remove from me the way of lying: and grant me thy law graciously.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>I have chosen the way of truth: thy judgments have I laid <supplied>before me.</supplied>
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>I have stuck unto thy testimonies: O LORD, put me not to shame.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>I will run the way of thy commandments, when thou shalt enlarge my heart.
      
      
       
      
      
       
      
      
       HE.
      
      
       
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Teach me, O LORD, the way of thy statutes; and I shall keep it <supplied>unto</supplied> the end.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Give me understanding, and I shall keep thy law; yea, I shall observe it with <supplied>my</supplied> whole heart.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Make me to go in the path of thy commandments; for therein do I delight.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Incline my heart unto thy testimonies, and not to covetousness.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Turn away mine eyes from beholding vanity; <supplied>and</supplied> quicken thou me in thy way.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Stablish thy word unto thy servant, who <supplied>is devoted</supplied> to thy fear.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Turn away my reproach which I fear: for thy judgments <supplied>are</supplied> good.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Behold, I have longed after thy precepts: quicken me in thy righteousness.
      
      
       
      
      
       
      
      
       VAU.
      
      
       
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Let thy mercies come also unto me, O LORD, <supplied>even</supplied> thy salvation, according to thy word.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>So shall I have wherewith to answer him that reproacheth me: for I trust in thy word.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>And take not the word of truth utterly out of my mouth; for I have hoped in thy judgments.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>So shall I keep thy law continually for ever and ever.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>And I will walk at liberty: for I seek thy precepts.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>I will speak of thy testimonies also before kings, and will not be ashamed.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>And I will delight myself in thy commandments, which I have loved.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>My hands also will I lift up unto thy commandments, which I have loved; and I will meditate in thy statutes.
      
      
       
      
      
       
      
      
       ZAIN
      
      
       
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Remember the word unto thy servant, upon which thou hast caused me to hope.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>This <supplied>is</supplied> my comfort in my affliction: for thy word hath quickened me.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>The proud have had me greatly in derision: <supplied>yet</supplied> have I not declined from thy law.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>I remembered thy judgments of old, O LORD; and have comforted myself.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Horror hath taken hold upon me because of the wicked that forsake thy law.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Thy statutes have been my songs in the house of my pilgrimage.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>I have remembered thy name, O LORD, in the night, and have kept thy law.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>This I had, because I kept thy precepts.
      
      
       
      
      
       
      
      
       CHETH.
      
      
       
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>
        <supplied>Thou art</supplied> my portion, O LORD: I have said that I would keep thy words.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>I intreated thy favour with <supplied>my</supplied> whole heart: be merciful unto me according to thy word.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>I thought on my ways, and turned my feet unto thy testimonies.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>I made haste, and delayed not to keep thy commandments.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>The bands of the wicked have robbed me: <supplied>but</supplied> I have not forgotten thy law.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>At midnight I will rise to give thanks unto thee because of thy righteous judgments.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>I <supplied>am</supplied> a companion of all <supplied>them</supplied> that fear thee, and of them that keep thy precepts.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>The earth, O LORD, is full of thy mercy: teach me thy statutes.
      
      
       
      
      
       
      
      
       TETH.
      
      
       
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Thou hast dealt well with thy servant, O LORD, according unto thy word.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Teach me good judgment and knowledge: for I have believed thy commandments.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Before I was afflicted I went astray: but now have I kept thy word.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Thou <supplied>art</supplied> good, and doest good; teach me thy statutes.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>The proud have forged a lie against me: <supplied>but</supplied> I will keep thy precepts with <supplied>my</supplied> whole heart.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Their heart is as fat as grease; <supplied>but</supplied> I delight in thy law.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>
        <supplied>It is</supplied> good for me that I have been afflicted; that I might learn thy statutes.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>The law of thy mouth <supplied>is</supplied> better unto me than thousands of gold and silver.
      
      
       
      
      
       
      
      
       JOD.
      
      
       
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Thy hands have made me and fashioned me: give me understanding, that I may learn thy commandments.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>They that fear thee will be glad when they see me; because I have hoped in thy word.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>I know, O LORD, that thy judgments <supplied>are</supplied> right, and that <supplied>thou</supplied> in faithfulness hast afflicted me.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Let, I pray thee, thy merciful kindness be for my comfort, according to thy word unto thy servant.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Let thy tender mercies come unto me, that I may live: for thy law <supplied>is</supplied> my delight.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Let the proud be ashamed; for they dealt perversely with me without a cause: <supplied>but</supplied> I will meditate in thy precepts.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Let those that fear thee turn unto me, and those that have known thy testimonies.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Let my heart be sound in thy statutes; that I be not ashamed.
      
      
       
      
      
       
      
      
       CAPH.
      
      
       
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>My soul fainteth for thy salvation: <supplied>but</supplied> I hope in thy word.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Mine eyes fail for thy word, saying, When wilt thou comfort me?
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>For I am become like a bottle in the smoke; <supplied>yet</supplied> do I not forget thy statutes.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>How many <supplied>are</supplied> the days of thy servant? when wilt thou execute judgment on them that persecute me?
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>The proud have digged pits for me, which <supplied>are</supplied> not after thy law.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>All thy commandments <supplied>are</supplied> faithful: they persecute me wrongfully; help thou me.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>They had almost consumed me upon earth; but I forsook not thy precepts.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Quicken me after thy lovingkindness; so shall I keep the testimony of thy mouth.
      
      
       
      
      
       
      
      
       LAMED.
      
      
       
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>For ever, O LORD, thy word is settled in heaven.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Thy faithfulness <supplied>is</supplied> unto all generations: thou hast established the earth, and it abideth.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>They continue this day according to thine ordinances: for all <supplied>are</supplied> thy servants.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Unless thy law <supplied>had been</supplied> my delights, I should then have perished in mine affliction.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>I will never forget thy precepts: for with them thou hast quickened me.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>I <supplied>am</supplied> thine, save me; for I have sought thy precepts.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>The wicked have waited for me to destroy me: <supplied>but</supplied> I will consider thy testimonies.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>I have seen an end of all perfection: <supplied>but</supplied> thy commandment <supplied>is</supplied> exceeding broad.
      
      
       
      
      
       
      
      
       MEM.
      
      
       
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>O how love I thy law! it <supplied>is</supplied> my meditation all the day.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Thou through thy commandments hast made me wiser than mine enemies: for they <supplied>are</supplied> ever with me.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>I have more understanding than all my teachers: for thy testimonies <supplied>are</supplied> my meditation.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>I understand more than the ancients, because I keep thy precepts.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>I have refrained my feet from every evil way, that I might keep thy word.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>I have not departed from thy judgments: for thou hast taught me.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>How sweet are thy words unto my taste! <supplied>yea, sweeter</supplied> than honey to my mouth!
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Through thy precepts I get understanding: therefore I hate every false way.
      
      
       
      
      
       
      
      
       NUN.
      
      
       
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Thy word <supplied>is</supplied> a lamp unto my feet, and a light unto my path.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>I have sworn, and I will perform <supplied>it,</supplied> that I will keep thy righteous judgments.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>I am afflicted very much: quicken me, O LORD, according unto thy word.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Accept, I beseech thee, the freewill offerings of my mouth, O LORD, and teach me thy judgments.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>My soul <supplied>is</supplied> continually in my hand: yet do I not forget thy law.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>The wicked have laid a snare for me: yet I erred not from thy precepts.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Thy testimonies have I taken as an heritage for ever: for they <supplied>are</supplied> the rejoicing of my heart.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>I have inclined mine heart to perform thy statutes alway, <supplied>even unto</supplied> the end.
      
      
       
      
      
       
      
      
       SAMECH.
      
      
       
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>I hate <supplied>vain</supplied> thoughts: but thy law do I love.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Thou <supplied>art</supplied> my hiding place and my shield: I hope in thy word.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Depart from me, ye evildoers: for I will keep the commandments of my God.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Uphold me according unto thy word, that I may live: and let me not be ashamed of my hope.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Hold thou me up, and I shall be safe: and I will have respect unto thy statutes continually.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Thou hast trodden down all them that err from thy statutes: for their deceit <supplied>is</supplied> falsehood.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Thou puttest away all the wicked of the earth <supplied>like</supplied> dross: therefore I love thy testimonies.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>My flesh trembleth for fear of thee; and I am afraid of thy judgments.
      
      
       
      
      
       
      
      
       AIN.
      
      
       
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>I have done judgment and justice: leave me not to mine oppressors.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Be surety for thy servant for good: let not the proud oppress me.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Mine eyes fail for thy salvation, and for the word of thy righteousness.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Deal with thy servant according unto thy mercy, and teach me thy statutes.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>I <supplied>am</supplied> thy servant; give me understanding, that I may know thy testimonies.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>
        <supplied>It is</supplied> time for <supplied>thee,</supplied> LORD, to work: <supplied>for</supplied> they have made void thy law.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Therefore I love thy commandments above gold; yea, above fine gold.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Therefore I esteem all <supplied>thy</supplied> precepts <supplied>concerning</supplied> all <supplied>things to be</supplied> right; <supplied>and</supplied> I hate every false way.
      
      
       
      
      
       
      
      
       PE.
      
      
       
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Thy testimonies <supplied>are</supplied> wonderful: therefore doth my soul keep them.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>The entrance of thy words giveth light; it giveth understanding unto the simple.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>I opened my mouth, and panted: for I longed for thy commandments.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Look thou upon me, and be merciful unto me, as thou usest to do unto those that love thy name.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Order my steps in thy word: and let not any iniquity have dominion over me.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Deliver me from the oppression of man: so will I keep thy precepts.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Make thy face to shine upon thy servant; and teach me thy statutes.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Rivers of waters run down mine eyes, because they keep not thy law.
      
      
       
      
      
       
      
      
       TZADDE.
      
      
       
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Righteous <supplied>art</supplied> thou, O LORD, and upright <supplied>are</supplied> thy judgments.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Thy testimonies <supplied>that</supplied> thou hast commanded <supplied>are</supplied> righteous and very faithful.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>My zeal hath consumed me, because mine enemies have forgotten thy words.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Thy word <supplied>is</supplied> very pure: therefore thy servant loveth it.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>I <supplied>am</supplied> small and despised: <supplied>yet</supplied> do not I forget thy precepts.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Thy righteousness <supplied>is</supplied> an everlasting righteousness, and thy law <supplied>is</supplied> the truth.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Trouble and anguish have taken hold on me: <supplied>yet</supplied> thy commandments <supplied>are</supplied> my delights.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>The righteousness of thy testimonies <supplied>is</supplied> everlasting: give me understanding, and I shall live.
      
      
       
      
      
       
      
      
       KOPH.
      
      
       
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>I cried with <supplied>my</supplied> whole heart; hear me, O LORD: I will keep thy statutes.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>I cried unto thee; save me, and I shall keep thy testimonies.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>I prevented the dawning of the morning, and cried: I hoped in thy word.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Mine eyes prevent the <supplied>night</supplied> watches, that I might meditate in thy word.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Hear my voice according unto thy lovingkindness: O LORD, quicken me according to thy judgment.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>They draw nigh that follow after mischief: they are far from thy law.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Thou <supplied>art</supplied> near, O LORD; and all thy commandments <supplied>are</supplied> truth.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Concerning thy testimonies, I have known of old that thou hast founded them for ever.
      
      
       
      
      
       
      
      
       RESH.
      
      
       
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Consider mine affliction, and deliver me: for I do not forget thy law.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Plead my cause, and deliver me: quicken me according to thy word.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Salvation <supplied>is</supplied> far from the wicked: for they seek not thy statutes.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Great <supplied>are</supplied> thy tender mercies, O LORD: quicken me according to thy judgments.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Many <supplied>are</supplied> my persecutors and mine enemies; <supplied>yet</supplied> do I not decline from thy testimonies.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>I beheld the transgressors, and was grieved; because they kept not thy word.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Consider how I love thy precepts: quicken me, O LORD, according to thy lovingkindness.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Thy word <supplied>is</supplied> true <supplied>from</supplied> the beginning: and every one of thy righteous judgments <supplied>endureth</supplied> for ever.
      
      
       
      
      
       
      
      
       SCHIN.
      
      
       
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Princes have persecuted me without a cause: but my heart standeth in awe of thy word.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>I rejoice at thy word, as one that findeth great spoil.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>I hate and abhor lying: <supplied>but</supplied> thy law do I love.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Seven times a day do I praise thee because of thy righteous judgments.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Great peace have they which love thy law: and nothing shall offend them.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>LORD, I have hoped for thy salvation, and done thy commandments.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>My soul hath kept thy testimonies; and I love them exceedingly.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>I have kept thy precepts and thy testimonies: for all my ways <supplied>are</supplied> before thee.
      
      
       
      
      
       
      
      
       TAU.
      
      
       
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Let my cry come near before thee, O LORD: give me understanding according to thy word.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Let my supplication come before thee: deliver me according to thy word.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>My lips shall utter praise, when thou hast taught me thy statutes.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>My tongue shall speak of thy word: for all thy commandments <supplied>are</supplied> righteousness.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Let thine hand help me; for I have chosen thy precepts.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>I have longed for thy salvation, O LORD; and thy law <supplied>is</supplied> my delight.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Let my soul live, and it shall praise thee; and let thy judgments help me.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>I have gone astray like a lost sheep; seek thy servant; for I do not forget thy commandments.
      
      
       
      
      
       
        </verse>
        </chapter>
