<?xml version="1.0"?>
<chapter translation="KJV" testament="Old" book="Psalm" n="135" book-id="19">
      
       
        <verse>Praise ye the LORD. Praise ye the name of the LORD; praise <supplied>him,</supplied> O ye servants of the LORD.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Ye that stand in the house of the LORD, in the courts of the house of our God,
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Praise the LORD; for the LORD <supplied>is</supplied> good: sing praises unto his name; for <supplied>it is</supplied> pleasant.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>For the LORD hath chosen Jacob unto himself, <supplied>and</supplied> Israel for his peculiar treasure.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>For I know that the LORD <supplied>is</supplied> great, and <supplied>that</supplied> our Lord <supplied>is</supplied> above all gods.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Whatsoever the LORD pleased, <supplied>that</supplied> did he in heaven, and in earth, in the seas, and all deep places.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>He causeth the vapours to ascend from the ends of the earth; he maketh lightnings for the rain; he bringeth the wind out of his treasuries.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Who smote the firstborn of Egypt, both of man and beast.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>
        <supplied>Who</supplied> sent tokens and wonders into the midst of thee, O Egypt, upon Pharaoh, and upon all his servants.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Who smote great nations, and slew mighty kings;
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Sihon king of the Amorites, and Og king of Bashan, and all the kingdoms of Canaan:
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>And gave their land <supplied>for</supplied> an heritage, an heritage unto Israel his people.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Thy name, O LORD, <supplied>endureth</supplied> for ever; <supplied>and</supplied> thy memorial, O LORD, throughout all generations.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>For the LORD will judge his people, and he will repent himself concerning his servants.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>The idols of the heathen <supplied>are</supplied> silver and gold, the work of men&#x2019;s hands.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>They have mouths, but they speak not; eyes have they, but they see not;
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>They have ears, but they hear not; neither is there <supplied>any</supplied> breath in their mouths.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>They that make them are like unto them: <supplied>so is</supplied> every one that trusteth in them.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Bless the LORD, O house of Israel: bless the LORD, O house of Aaron:
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Bless the LORD, O house of Levi: ye that fear the LORD, bless the LORD.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Blessed be the LORD out of Zion, which dwelleth at Jerusalem. Praise ye the LORD.
      
      
       
      
      
       
        </verse>
        </chapter>
