<?xml version="1.0"?>
<chapter translation="KJV" testament="Old" book="Psalm" n="62" book_id="19">
      To the chief Musician, to Jeduthun, A Psalm of David.
      
      
      
       
        <verse>Truly my soul waiteth upon God: from him <supplied>cometh</supplied> my salvation.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>He only <supplied>is</supplied> my rock and my salvation; <supplied>he is</supplied> my defence; I shall not be greatly moved.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>How long will ye imagine mischief against a man? ye shall be slain all of you: as a bowing wall <supplied>shall ye be, and as</supplied> a tottering fence.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>They only consult to cast <supplied>him</supplied> down from his excellency: they delight in lies: they bless with their mouth, but they curse inwardly. Selah.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>My soul, wait thou only upon God; for my expectation <supplied>is</supplied> from him.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>He only <supplied>is</supplied> my rock and my salvation: <supplied>he is</supplied> my defence; I shall not be moved.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>In God <supplied>is</supplied> my salvation and my glory: the rock of my strength, <supplied>and</supplied> my refuge, <supplied>is</supplied> in God.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Trust in him at all times; <supplied>ye</supplied> people, pour out your heart before him: God <supplied>is</supplied> a refuge for us. Selah.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Surely men of low degree <supplied>are</supplied> vanity, <supplied>and</supplied> men of high degree <supplied>are</supplied> a lie: to be laid in the balance, they <supplied>are</supplied> altogether <supplied>lighter</supplied> than vanity.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Trust not in oppression, and become not vain in robbery: if riches increase, set not your heart <supplied>upon them.</supplied>
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>God hath spoken once; twice have I heard this; that power <supplied>belongeth</supplied> unto God.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Also unto thee, O Lord, <supplied>belongeth</supplied> mercy: for thou renderest to every man according to his work.
      
      
       
      
      
       
        </verse>
        </chapter>
