<?xml version="1.0"?>
<chapter translation="KJV" testament="Old" book="Psalm" n="84" book-id="19">
      To the chief Musician upon Gittith, A Psalm for the sons of Korah.
      
      
      
       
        <verse>How amiable <supplied>are</supplied> thy tabernacles, O LORD of hosts!
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>My soul longeth, yea, even fainteth for the courts of the LORD: my heart and my flesh crieth out for the living God.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Yea, the sparrow hath found an house, and the swallow a nest for herself, where she may lay her young, <supplied>even</supplied> thine altars, O LORD of hosts, my King, and my God.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Blessed <supplied>are</supplied> they that dwell in thy house: they will be still praising thee. Selah.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Blessed <supplied>is</supplied> the man whose strength <supplied>is</supplied> in thee; in whose heart <supplied>are</supplied> the ways <supplied>of them.</supplied>
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>
        <supplied>Who</supplied> passing through the valley of Baca make it a well; the rain also filleth the pools.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>They go from strength to strength, <supplied>every one of them</supplied> in Zion appeareth before God.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>O LORD God of hosts, hear my prayer: give ear, O God of Jacob. Selah.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Behold, O God our shield, and look upon the face of thine anointed.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>For a day in thy courts <supplied>is</supplied> better than a thousand. I had rather be a doorkeeper in the house of my God, than to dwell in the tents of wickedness.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>For the LORD God <supplied>is</supplied> a sun and shield: the LORD will give grace and glory: no good <supplied>thing</supplied> will he withhold from them that walk uprightly.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>O LORD of hosts, blessed <supplied>is</supplied> the man that trusteth in thee.
      
      
       
      
      
       
        </verse>
        </chapter>
