<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Genesis" book-id="1" n="10">
<verse>Now these are the records of the generations of Shem, Ham, and Japheth, the sons of Noah; and sons were born to them after the flood.</verse>
<verse>The sons of Japheth were Gomer and Magog and Madai and Javan and Tubal and Meshech and Tiras.</verse>
<verse>The sons of Gomer were Ashkenaz and Riphath and Togarmah.</verse>
<verse>The sons of Javan were Elishah and Tarshish, Kittim and Dodanim.</verse>
<verse>From these the coastlands of the nations were separated into their lands, every one according to his language, according to their families, into their nations.</verse>
<verse>The sons of Ham were Cush and Mizraim and Put and Canaan.</verse>
<verse>The sons of Cush were Seba and Havilah and Sabtah and Raamah and Sabteca; and the sons of Raamah were Sheba and Dedan.</verse>
<verse>Now Cush became the father of Nimrod; he became a mighty one on the earth.</verse>
<verse>He was a mighty hunter before the LORD; therefore it is said, "Like Nimrod a mighty hunter before the LORD."</verse>
<verse>The beginning of his kingdom was Babel and Erech and Accad and Calneh, in the land of Shinar.</verse>
<verse>From that land he went forth into Assyria, and built Nineveh and Rehoboth-Ir and Calah,</verse>
<verse>and Resen between Nineveh and Calah; that is the great city.</verse>
<verse>Mizraim became the father of Ludim and Anamim and Lehabim and Naphtuhim</verse>
<verse>and Pathrusim and Casluhim (from which came the Philistines) and Caphtorim.</verse>
<verse>Canaan became the father of Sidon, his firstborn, and Heth</verse>
<verse>and the Jebusite and the Amorite and the Girgashite</verse>
<verse>and the Hivite and the Arkite and the Sinite</verse>
<verse>and the Arvadite and the Zemarite and the Hamathite; and afterward the families of the Canaanite were spread abroad.</verse>
<verse>The territory of the Canaanite extended from Sidon as you go toward Gerar, as far as Gaza; as you go toward Sodom and Gomorrah and Admah and Zeboiim, as far as Lasha.</verse>
<verse>These are the sons of Ham, according to their families, according to their languages, by their lands, by their nations.</verse>
<verse>Also to Shem, the father of all the children of Eber, and the older brother of Japheth, children were born.</verse>
<verse>The sons of Shem were Elam and Asshur and Arpachshad and Lud and Aram.</verse>
<verse>The sons of Aram were Uz and Hul and Gether and Mash.</verse>
<verse>Arpachshad became the father of Shelah; and Shelah became the father of Eber.</verse>
<verse>Two sons were born to Eber; the name of the one was Peleg, for in his days the earth was divided; and his brother's name was Joktan.</verse>
<verse>Joktan became the father of Almodad and Sheleph and Hazarmaveth and Jerah</verse>
<verse>and Hadoram and Uzal and Diklah</verse>
<verse>and Obal and Abimael and Sheba</verse>
<verse>and Ophir and Havilah and Jobab; all these were the sons of Joktan.</verse>
<verse>Now their settlement extended from Mesha as you go toward Sephar, the hill country of the east.</verse>
<verse>These are the sons of Shem, according to their families, according to their languages, by their lands, according to their nations.</verse>
<verse>These are the families of the sons of Noah, according to their genealogies, by their nations; and out of these the nations were separated on the earth after the flood.</verse>
</chapter>