<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Genesis" book-id="1" n="16">
<verse>Now Sarai, Abram's wife had borne him no children, and she had an Egyptian maid whose name was Hagar.</verse>
<verse>So Sarai said to Abram, "Now behold, the LORD has prevented me from bearing children. Please go in to my maid; perhaps I will obtain children through her." And Abram listened to the voice of Sarai.</verse>
<verse>After Abram had lived ten years in the land of Canaan, Abram's wife Sarai took Hagar the Egyptian, her maid, and gave her to her husband Abram as his wife.</verse>
<verse>He went in to Hagar, and she conceived; and when she saw that she had conceived, her mistress was despised in her sight.</verse>
<verse>And Sarai said to Abram, "May the wrong done me be upon you. I gave my maid into your arms, but when she saw that she had conceived, I was despised in her sight. May the LORD judge between you and me."</verse>
<verse>But Abram said to Sarai, "Behold, your maid is in your power; do to her what is good in your sight." So Sarai treated her harshly, and she fled from her presence.</verse>
<verse>Now the angel of the LORD found her by a spring of water in the wilderness, by the spring on the way to Shur.</verse>
<verse>He said, "Hagar, Sarai's maid, where have you come from and where are you going?" And she said, "I am fleeing from the presence of my mistress Sarai."</verse>
<verse>Then the angel of the LORD said to her, "Return to your mistress, and submit yourself to her authority."</verse>
<verse>Moreover, the angel of the LORD said to her, "I will greatly multiply your descendants so that they will be too many to count."</verse>
<verse>The angel of the LORD said to her further, "Behold, you are with child, And you will bear a son; And you shall call his name Ishmael, Because the LORD has given heed to your affliction.</verse>
<verse>"He will be a wild donkey of a man, His hand will be against everyone, And everyone's hand will be against him; And he will live to the east of all his brothers."</verse>
<verse>Then she called the name of the LORD who spoke to her, "You are a God who sees"; for she said, "Have I even remained alive here after seeing Him?"</verse>
<verse>Therefore the well was called Beer-lahai-roi; behold, it is between Kadesh and Bered.</verse>
<verse>So Hagar bore Abram a son; and Abram called the name of his son, whom Hagar bore, Ishmael.</verse>
<verse>Abram was eighty-six years old when Hagar bore Ishmael to him.</verse>
</chapter>