<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Genesis" book-id="1" n="25">
<verse>Now Abraham took another wife, whose name was Keturah.</verse>
<verse>She bore to him Zimran and Jokshan and Medan and Midian and Ishbak and Shuah.</verse>
<verse>Jokshan became the father of Sheba and Dedan. And the sons of Dedan were Asshurim and Letushim and Leummim.</verse>
<verse>The sons of Midian were Ephah and Epher and Hanoch and Abida and Eldaah. All these were the sons of Keturah.</verse>
<verse>Now Abraham gave all that he had to Isaac;</verse>
<verse>but to the sons of his concubines, Abraham gave gifts while he was still living, and sent them away from his son Isaac eastward, to the land of the east.</verse>
<verse>These are all the years of Abraham's life that he lived, one hundred and seventy-five years.</verse>
<verse>Abraham breathed his last and died in a ripe old age, an old man and satisfied with life; and he was gathered to his people.</verse>
<verse>Then his sons Isaac and Ishmael buried him in the cave of Machpelah, in the field of Ephron the son of Zohar the Hittite, facing Mamre,</verse>
<verse>the field which Abraham purchased from the sons of Heth; there Abraham was buried with Sarah his wife.</verse>
<verse>It came about after the death of Abraham, that God blessed his son Isaac; and Isaac lived by Beer-lahai-roi.</verse>
<verse>Now these are the records of the generations of Ishmael, Abraham's son, whom Hagar the Egyptian, Sarah's maid, bore to Abraham;</verse>
<verse>and these are the names of the sons of Ishmael, by their names, in the order of their birth: Nebaioth, the firstborn of Ishmael, and Kedar and Adbeel and Mibsam</verse>
<verse>and Mishma and Dumah and Massa,</verse>
<verse>Hadad and Tema, Jetur, Naphish and Kedemah.</verse>
<verse>These are the sons of Ishmael and these are their names, by their villages, and by their camps; twelve princes according to their tribes.</verse>
<verse>These are the years of the life of Ishmael, one hundred and thirty-seven years; and he breathed his last and died, and was gathered to his people.</verse>
<verse>They settled from Havilah to Shur which is east of Egypt as one goes toward Assyria; he settled in defiance of all his relatives.</verse>
<verse>Now these are the records of the generations of Isaac, Abraham's son: Abraham became the father of Isaac;</verse>
<verse>and Isaac was forty years old when he took Rebekah, the daughter of Bethuel the Aramean of Paddan-aram, the sister of Laban the Aramean, to be his wife.</verse>
<verse>Isaac prayed to the LORD on behalf of his wife, because she was barren; and the LORD answered him and Rebekah his wife conceived.</verse>
<verse>But the children struggled together within her; and she said, "If it is so, why then am I this way?" So she went to inquire of the LORD.</verse>
<verse>The LORD said to her, "Two nations are in your womb; And two peoples will be separated from your body; And one people shall be stronger than the other; And the older shall serve the younger."</verse>
<verse>When her days to be delivered were fulfilled, behold, there were twins in her womb.</verse>
<verse>Now the first came forth red, all over like a hairy garment; and they named him Esau.</verse>
<verse>Afterward his brother came forth with his hand holding on to Esau's heel, so his name was called Jacob; and Isaac was sixty years old when she gave birth to them.</verse>
<verse>When the boys grew up, Esau became a skillful hunter, a man of the field, but Jacob was a peaceful man, living in tents.</verse>
<verse>Now Isaac loved Esau, because he had a taste for game, but Rebekah loved Jacob.</verse>
<verse>When Jacob had cooked stew, Esau came in from the field and he was famished;</verse>
<verse>and Esau said to Jacob, "Please let me have a swallow of that red stuff there, for I am famished." Therefore his name was called Edom.</verse>
<verse>But Jacob said, "First sell me your birthright."</verse>
<verse>Esau said, "Behold, I am about to die; so of what use then is the birthright to me?"</verse>
<verse>And Jacob said, "First swear to me"; so he swore to him, and sold his birthright to Jacob.</verse>
<verse>Then Jacob gave Esau bread and lentil stew; and he ate and drank, and rose and went on his way. Thus Esau despised his birthright.</verse>
</chapter>