<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Genesis" book-id="1" n="4">
<verse>Now the man had relations with his wife Eve, and she conceived and gave birth to Cain, and she said, "I have gotten a manchild with the help of the LORD."</verse>
<verse>Again, she gave birth to his brother Abel. And Abel was a keeper of flocks, but Cain was a tiller of the ground.</verse>
<verse>So it came about in the course of time that Cain brought an offering to the LORD of the fruit of the ground.</verse>
<verse>Abel, on his part also brought of the firstlings of his flock and of their fat portions. And the LORD had regard for Abel and for his offering;</verse>
<verse>but for Cain and for his offering He had no regard. So Cain became very angry and his countenance fell.</verse>
<verse>Then the LORD said to Cain, "Why are you angry? And why has your countenance fallen?</verse>
<verse>"If you do well, will not your countenance be lifted up? And if you do not do well, sin is crouching at the door; and its desire is for you, but you must master it."</verse>
<verse>Cain told Abel his brother. And it came about when they were in the field, that Cain rose up against Abel his brother and killed him.</verse>
<verse>Then the LORD said to Cain, "Where is Abel your brother?" And he said, "I do not know. Am I my brother's keeper?"</verse>
<verse>He said, "What have you done? The voice of your brother's blood is crying to Me from the ground.</verse>
<verse>"Now you are cursed from the ground, which has opened its mouth to receive your brother's blood from your hand.</verse>
<verse>"When you cultivate the ground, it will no longer yield its strength to you; you will be a vagrant and a wanderer on the earth."</verse>
<verse>Cain said to the LORD, "My punishment is too great to bear!</verse>
<verse>"Behold, You have driven me this day from the face of the ground; and from Your face I will be hidden, and I will be a vagrant and a wanderer on the earth, and whoever finds me will kill me."</verse>
<verse>So the LORD said to him, "Therefore whoever kills Cain, vengeance will be taken on him sevenfold." And the LORD appointed a sign for Cain, so that no one finding him would slay him.</verse>
<verse>Then Cain went out from the presence of the LORD, and settled in the land of Nod, east of Eden.</verse>
<verse>Cain had relations with his wife and she conceived, and gave birth to Enoch; and he built a city, and called the name of the city Enoch, after the name of his son.</verse>
<verse>Now to Enoch was born Irad, and Irad became the father of Mehujael, and Mehujael became the father of Methushael, and Methushael became the father of Lamech.</verse>
<verse>Lamech took to himself two wives: the name of the one was Adah, and the name of the other, Zillah.</verse>
<verse>Adah gave birth to Jabal; he was the father of those who dwell in tents and have livestock.</verse>
<verse>His brother's name was Jubal; he was the father of all those who play the lyre and pipe.</verse>
<verse>As for Zillah, she also gave birth to Tubal-cain, the forger of all implements of bronze and iron; and the sister of Tubal-cain was Naamah.</verse>
<verse>Lamech said to his wives, "Adah and Zillah, Listen to my voice, You wives of Lamech, Give heed to my speech, For I have killed a man for wounding me; And a boy for striking me;</verse>
<verse>If Cain is avenged sevenfold, Then Lamech seventy-sevenfold."</verse>
<verse>Adam had relations with his wife again; and she gave birth to a son, and named him Seth, for, she said, "God has appointed me another offspring in place of Abel, for Cain killed him."</verse>
<verse>To Seth, to him also a son was born; and he called his name Enosh. Then men began to call upon the name of the LORD.</verse>
</chapter>