<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Genesis" book-id="1" n="9">
<verse>And God blessed Noah and his sons and said to them, "Be fruitful and multiply, and fill the earth.</verse>
<verse>"The fear of you and the terror of you will be on every beast of the earth and on every bird of the sky; with everything that creeps on the ground, and all the fish of the sea, into your hand they are given.</verse>
<verse>"Every moving thing that is alive shall be food for you; I give all to you, as I gave the green plant.</verse>
<verse>"Only you shall not eat flesh with its life, that is, its blood.</verse>
<verse>"Surely I will require your lifeblood; from every beast I will require it. And from every man, from every man's brother I will require the life of man.</verse>
<verse>"Whoever sheds man's blood, By man his blood shall be shed, For in the image of God He made man.</verse>
<verse>"As for you, be fruitful and multiply; Populate the earth abundantly and multiply in it."</verse>
<verse>Then God spoke to Noah and to his sons with him, saying,</verse>
<verse>"Now behold, I Myself do establish My covenant with you, and with your descendants after you;</verse>
<verse>and with every living creature that is with you, the birds, the cattle, and every beast of the earth with you; of all that comes out of the ark, even every beast of the earth.</verse>
<verse>"I establish My covenant with you; and all flesh shall never again be cut off by the water of the flood, neither shall there again be a flood to destroy the earth."</verse>
<verse>God said, "This is the sign of the covenant which I am making between Me and you and every living creature that is with you, for all successive generations;</verse>
<verse>I set My bow in the cloud, and it shall be for a sign of a covenant between Me and the earth.</verse>
<verse>"It shall come about, when I bring a cloud over the earth, that the bow will be seen in the cloud,</verse>
<verse>and I will remember My covenant, which is between Me and you and every living creature of all flesh; and never again shall the water become a flood to destroy all flesh.</verse>
<verse>"When the bow is in the cloud, then I will look upon it, to remember the everlasting covenant between God and every living creature of all flesh that is on the earth."</verse>
<verse>And God said to Noah, "This is the sign of the covenant which I have established between Me and all flesh that is on the earth."</verse>
<verse>Now the sons of Noah who came out of the ark were Shem and Ham and Japheth; and Ham was the father of Canaan.</verse>
<verse>These three were the sons of Noah, and from these the whole earth was populated.</verse>
<verse>Then Noah began farming and planted a vineyard.</verse>
<verse>He drank of the wine and became drunk, and uncovered himself inside his tent.</verse>
<verse>Ham, the father of Canaan, saw the nakedness of his father, and told his two brothers outside.</verse>
<verse>But Shem and Japheth took a garment and laid it upon both their shoulders and walked backward and covered the nakedness of their father; and their faces were turned away, so that they did not see their father's nakedness.</verse>
<verse>When Noah awoke from his wine, he knew what his youngest son had done to him.</verse>
<verse>So he said, "Cursed be Canaan; A servant of servants He shall be to his brothers."</verse>
<verse>He also said, "Blessed be the LORD, The God of Shem; And let Canaan be his servant.</verse>
<verse>"May God enlarge Japheth, And let him dwell in the tents of Shem; And let Canaan be his servant."</verse>
<verse>Noah lived three hundred and fifty years after the flood.</verse>
<verse>So all the days of Noah were nine hundred and fifty years, and he died.</verse>
</chapter>