<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="1 Kings" book-id="11" n="11">
<verse>King Solomon was obsessed with women. Pharaoh's daughter was only the first of the many foreign women he loved--Moabite, Ammonite, Edomite, Sidonian, and Hittite.</verse>
<verse>He took them from the surrounding pagan nations of which GOD had clearly warned Israel, "You must not marry them; they'll seduce you into infatuations with their gods." Solomon fell in love with them anyway, refusing to give them up.</verse>
<verse>He had seven hundred royal wives and three hundred concubines--a thousand women in all! And they did seduce him away from God.</verse>
<verse>As Solomon grew older, his wives beguiled him with their alien gods and he became unfaithful--he didn't stay true to his GOD as his father David had done.</verse>
<verse>Solomon took up with Ashtoreth, the whore goddess of the Sidonians, and Molech, the horrible god of the Ammonites.</verse>
<verse>Solomon openly defied GOD; he did not follow in his father David's footsteps.</verse>
<verse>He went on to build a sacred shrine to Chemosh, the horrible god of Moab, and to Molech, the horrible god of the Ammonites, on a hill just east of Jerusalem.</verse>
<verse>He built similar shrines for all his foreign wives, who then polluted the countryside with the smoke and stench of their sacrifices.</verse>
<verse>GOD was furious with Solomon for abandoning the GOD of Israel, the God who had twice appeared to him</verse>
<verse>and had so clearly commanded him not to fool around with other gods. Solomon faithlessly disobeyed GOD's orders.</verse>
<verse>GOD said to Solomon, "Since this is the way it is with you, that you have no intention of keeping faith with me and doing what I have commanded, I'm going to rip the kingdom from you and hand it over to someone else.</verse>
<verse>But out of respect for your father David I won't do it in your lifetime. It's your son who will pay--I'll rip it right out of his grasp.</verse>
<verse>Even then I won't take it all; I'll leave him one tribe in honor of my servant David and out of respect for my chosen city Jerusalem."</verse>
<verse>GOD incited Hadad, a descendant of the king of Edom, into hostile actions against Solomon.</verse>
<verse>Years earlier, when David devastated Edom, Joab, commander of the army, on his way to bury the dead, massacred all the men of Edom.</verse>
<verse>Joab and his army stayed there for six months, making sure they had killed every man in Edom.</verse>
<verse>Hadad, just a boy at the time, had escaped with some of the Edomites who had worked for his father.</verse>
<verse>Their escape route took them through Midian to Paran. They picked up some men in Paran and went on to Egypt and to Pharaoh king of Egypt, who gave Hadad a house, food, and even land.</verse>
<verse>Pharaoh liked him so well that he gave him the sister of his wife, Queen Tahpenes, in marriage.</verse>
<verse>She bore Hadad a son named Genubath who was raised like one of the royal family. Genubath grew up in the palace with Pharaoh's children.</verse>
<verse>While living in Egypt, Hadad heard that both David and Joab, commander of the army, were dead. He approached Pharaoh and said, "Send me off with your blessing--I want to return to my country."</verse>
<verse>"But why?" said Pharaoh. "Why would you want to leave here? Hasn't everything been to your liking?Everything has been just fine," said Hadad, "but I want to go home--give me a good send-off!" [JC]</verse>
<verse>Then God incited another adversary against Solomon, Rezon son of Eliada, who had deserted from his master, Hadadezer king of Zobah.</verse>
<verse>After David's slaughter of the Arameans, Rezon collected a band of outlaws and became their leader. They later settled in Damascus, where Rezon eventually took over as king.</verse>
<verse>Like Hadad, Rezon was a thorn in Israel's side all of Solomon's life. He was king over Aram, and he hated Israel.</verse>
<verse>And then, the last straw: Jeroboam son of Nebat rebelled against the king. He was an Ephraimite from Zeredah, his mother a widow named Zeruah. He served in Solomon's administration.</verse>
<verse>This is why he rebelled. Solomon had built the outer defense system (the Millo) and had restored the fortifications that were in disrepair from the time of his father David.</verse>
<verse>Jeroboam stood out during the construction as strong and able. When Solomon observed what a good worker he was, he put the young man in charge of the entire workforce of the tribe of Joseph.</verse>
<verse>One day Jeroboam was walking down the road out of Jerusalem. Ahijah the prophet of Shiloh, wearing a brand-new cloak, met him. The two of them were alone on that remote stretch of road.</verse>
<verse>Ahijah took off the new cloak that he was wearing and ripped it into twelve pieces.</verse>
<verse>Then he said to Jeroboam, "Take ten of these pieces for yourself; this is by order of the GOD of Israel: See what I'm doing--I'm ripping the kingdom out of Solomon's hands and giving you ten of the tribes.</verse>
<verse>In honor of my servant David and out of respect for Jerusalem, the city I especially chose, he will get one tribe.</verse>
<verse>And here's the reason: He faithlessly abandoned me and went off worshiping Ashtoreth goddess of the Sidonians, Chemosh god of the Moabites, and Molech god of the Ammonites. He hasn't lived the way I have shown him, hasn't done what I have wanted, and hasn't followed directions or obeyed orders as his father David did.</verse>
<verse>"Still, I won't take the whole kingdom away from him. I'll stick with him through his lifetime because of my servant David whom I chose and who did follow my directions and obey my orders.</verse>
<verse>But after that I'll remove the kingdom from his son's control and give you ten tribes.</verse>
<verse>I'll leave one tribe to his son, to maintain a witness to my servant David in Jerusalem, the city I chose as a memorial to my Name.</verse>
<verse>"But I have taken you in hand. Rule to your heart's content! You are to be the king of Israel.</verse>
<verse>If you listen to what I tell you and live the way I show you and do what pleases me, following directions and obeying orders as my servant David did, I'll stick with you no matter what. I'll build you a kingdom as solid as the one I built for David. Israel will be yours!</verse>
<verse>I am bringing pain and trouble on David's descendants, but the trials won't last forever."</verse>
<verse>Solomon ordered the assassination of Jeroboam, but he got away to Egypt and found asylum there with King Shishak. He remained in exile there until Solomon died.</verse>
<verse>The rest of Solomon's life and rule, his work and his wisdom, you can read for yourself in The Chronicles of Solomon.</verse>
<verse>Solomon ruled in Jerusalem over all Israel for forty years.</verse>
<verse>He died and was buried in the City of David his father. His son Rehoboam was the next king.</verse>
</chapter>