<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="1 Kings" book_id="11" n="17">
<verse>And then this happened: Elijah the Tishbite, from among the settlers of Gilead, confronted Ahab: "As surely as GOD lives, the God of Israel before whom I stand in obedient service, the next years are going to see a total drought--not a drop of dew or rain unless I say otherwise."</verse>
<verse>GOD then told Elijah,</verse>
<verse>"Get out of here, and fast. Head east and hide out at the Kerith Ravine on the other side of the Jordan River.</verse>
<verse>You can drink fresh water from the brook; I've ordered the ravens to feed you."</verse>
<verse>Elijah obeyed GOD's orders. He went and camped in the Kerith canyon on the other side of the Jordan.</verse>
<verse>And sure enough, ravens brought him his meals, both breakfast and supper, and he drank from the brook.</verse>
<verse>Eventually the brook dried up because of the drought.</verse>
<verse>Then GOD spoke to him:</verse>
<verse>"Get up and go to Zarephath in Sidon and live there. I've instructed a woman who lives there, a widow, to feed you."</verse>
<verse>So he got up and went to Zarephath. As he came to the entrance of the village he met a woman, a widow, gathering firewood. He asked her, "Please, would you bring me a little water in a jug? I need a drink."</verse>
<verse>As she went to get it, he called out, "And while you're at it, would you bring me something to eat?"</verse>
<verse>She said, "I swear, as surely as your GOD lives, I don't have so much as a biscuit. I have a handful of flour in a jar and a little oil in a bottle; you found me scratching together just enough firewood to make a last meal for my son and me. After we eat it, we'll die."</verse>
<verse>Elijah said to her, "Don't worry about a thing. Go ahead and do what you've said. But first make a small biscuit for me and bring it back here. Then go ahead and make a meal from what's left for you and your son.</verse>
<verse>This is the word of the GOD of Israel: "The jar of flour will not run out and the bottle of oil will not become empty before GOD sends rain on the land and ends this drought.'"</verse>
<verse>And she went right off and did it, did just as Elijah asked. And it turned out as he said--daily food for her and her family.</verse>
<verse>The jar of meal didn't run out and the bottle of oil didn't become empty: GOD's promise fulfilled to the letter, exactly as Elijah had delivered it!</verse>
<verse>Later on the woman's son became sick. The sickness took a turn for the worse--and then he stopped breathing.</verse>
<verse>The woman said to Elijah, "Why did you ever show up here in the first place--a holy man barging in, exposing my sins, and killing my son?"</verse>
<verse>Elijah said, "Hand me your son." He then took him from her bosom, carried him up to the loft where he was staying, and laid him on his bed.</verse>
<verse>Then he prayed, "O GOD, my God, why have you brought this terrible thing on this widow who has opened her home to me? Why have you killed her son?"</verse>
<verse>Three times he stretched himself out full-length on the boy, praying with all his might, "GOD, my God, put breath back into this boy's body!"</verse>
<verse>GOD listened to Elijah's prayer and put breath back into his body--he was alive!</verse>
<verse>Elijah picked the boy up, carried him downstairs from the loft, and gave him to his mother. "Here's your son," said Elijah, "alive!"</verse>
<verse>The woman said to Elijah, "I see it all now--you are a holy man. When you speak, GOD speaks--a true word!"</verse>
</chapter>