<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="1 Kings" book_id="11" n="19">
<verse>Ahab reported to Jezebel everything that Elijah had done, including the massacre of the prophets.</verse>
<verse>Jezebel immediately sent a messenger to Elijah with her threat: "The gods will get you for this and I'll get even with you! By this time tomorrow you'll be as dead as any one of those prophets."</verse>
<verse>When Elijah saw how things were, he ran for dear life to Beersheba, far in the south of Judah. He left his young servant there</verse>
<verse>and then went on into the desert another day's journey. He came to a lone broom bush and collapsed in its shade, wanting in the worst way to be done with it all--to just die: "Enough of this, GOD! Take my life--I'm ready to join my ancestors in the grave!"</verse>
<verse>Exhausted, he fell asleep under the lone broom bush. Suddenly an angel shook him awake and said, "Get up and eat!"</verse>
<verse>He looked around and, to his surprise, right by his head were a loaf of bread baked on some coals and a jug of water. He ate the meal and went back to sleep.</verse>
<verse>The angel of GOD came back, shook him awake again, and said, "Get up and eat some more--you've got a long journey ahead of you."</verse>
<verse>He got up, ate and drank his fill, and set out. Nourished by that meal, he walked forty days and nights, all the way to the mountain of God, to Horeb.</verse>
<verse>When he got there, he crawled into a cave and went to sleep. Then the word of GOD came to him: "So Elijah, what are you doing here?"</verse>
<verse>"I've been working my heart out for the GOD-of-the-Angel-Armies," said Elijah. "The people of Israel have abandoned your covenant, destroyed the places of worship, and murdered your prophets. I'm the only one left, and now they're trying to kill me."</verse>
<verse>Then he was told, "Go, stand on the mountain at attention before GOD. GOD will pass by." A hurricane wind ripped through the mountains and shattered the rocks before GOD, but GOD wasn't to be found in the wind; after the wind an earthquake, but GOD wasn't in the earthquake;</verse>
<verse>and after the earthquake fire, but GOD wasn't in the fire; and after the fire a gentle and quiet whisper.</verse>
<verse>When Elijah heard the quiet voice, he muffled his face with his great cloak, went to the mouth of the cave, and stood there. A quiet voice asked, "So Elijah, now tell me, what are you doing here?"</verse>
<verse>Elijah said it again, "I've been working my heart out for GOD, the GOD-of-the-Angel-Armies, because the people of Israel have abandoned your covenant, destroyed your places of worship, and murdered your prophets. I'm the only one left, and now they're trying to kill me."</verse>
<verse>GOD said, "Go back the way you came through the desert to Damascus. When you get there anoint Hazael; make him king over Aram.</verse>
<verse>Then anoint Jehu son of Nimshi; make him king over Israel. Finally, anoint Elisha son of Shaphat from Abel Meholah to succeed you as prophet.</verse>
<verse>Anyone who escapes death by Hazael will be killed by Jehu; and anyone who escapes death by Jehu will be killed by Elisha.</verse>
<verse>Meanwhile, I'm preserving for myself seven thousand souls: the knees that haven't bowed to the god Baal, the mouths that haven't kissed his image."</verse>
<verse>Elijah went straight out and found Elisha son of Shaphat in a field where there were twelve pairs of yoked oxen at work plowing; Elisha was in charge of the twelfth pair. Elijah went up to him and threw his cloak over him.</verse>
<verse>Elisha deserted the oxen, ran after Elijah, and said, "Please! Let me kiss my father and mother good-bye--then I'll follow you.Go ahead," said Elijah, "but, mind you, don't forget what I've just done to you."</verse>
<verse>So Elisha left; he took his yoke of oxen and butchered them. He made a fire with the plow and tackle and then boiled the meat--a true farewell meal for the family. Then he left and followed Elijah, becoming his right-hand man.</verse>
</chapter>