<?xml version="1.0"?>
<chapter translation="KJV" testament="Old" book="Genesis" n="46" book_id="1">
      <verse>And Israel took his journey with all that he had, and came to Beer-sheba, and offered sacrifices unto the God of his father Isaac.
</verse><verse>And God spake unto Israel in the visions of the night, and said, Jacob, Jacob. And he said, Here <supplied>am</supplied> I.
</verse><verse>And he said, I <supplied>am</supplied> God, the God of thy father: fear not to go down into Egypt; for I will there make of thee a great nation:
</verse><verse>I will go down with thee into Egypt; and I will also surely bring thee up <supplied>again:</supplied> and Joseph shall put his hand upon thine eyes.
</verse><verse>And Jacob rose up from Beer-sheba: and the sons of Israel carried Jacob their father, and their little ones, and their wives, in the wagons which Pharaoh had sent to carry him.
</verse><verse>And they took their cattle, and their goods, which they had gotten in the land of Canaan, and came into Egypt, Jacob, and all his seed with him:
</verse><verse>His sons, and his sons&#x2019; sons with him, his daughters, and his sons&#x2019; daughters, and all his seed brought he with him into Egypt.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>And these <supplied>are</supplied> the names of the children of Israel, which came into Egypt, Jacob and his sons: Reuben, Jacob&#x2019;s firstborn.
</verse><verse>And the sons of Reuben; Hanoch, and Phallu, and Hezron, and Carmi.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>And the sons of Simeon; Jemuel, and Jamin, and Ohad, and Jachin, and Zohar, and Shaul the son of a Canaanitish woman.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>And the sons of Levi; Gershon, Kohath, and Merari.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>And the sons of Judah; Er, and Onan, and Shelah, and Pharez, and Zarah: but Er and Onan died in the land of Canaan. And the sons of Pharez were Hezron and Hamul.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>And the sons of Issachar; Tola, and Phuvah, and Job, and Shimron.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>And the sons of Zebulun; Sered, and Elon, and Jahleel.
</verse><verse>These <supplied>be</supplied> the sons of Leah, which she bare unto Jacob in Padan-aram, with his daughter Dinah: all the souls of his sons and his daughters <supplied>were</supplied> thirty and three.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>And the sons of Gad; Ziphion, and Haggi, Shuni, and Ezbon, Eri, and Arodi, and Areli.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>And the sons of Asher; Jimnah, and Ishuah, and Isui, and Beriah, and Serah their sister: and the sons of Beriah; Heber, and Malchiel.
</verse><verse>These <supplied>are</supplied> the sons of Zilpah, whom Laban gave to Leah his daughter, and these she bare unto Jacob, <supplied>even</supplied> sixteen souls.
</verse><verse>The sons of Rachel Jacob&#x2019;s wife; Joseph, and Benjamin.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>And unto Joseph in the land of Egypt were born Manasseh and Ephraim, which Asenath the daughter of Poti-pherah priest of On bare unto him.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>And the sons of Benjamin were Belah, and Becher, and Ashbel, Gera, and Naaman, Ehi, and Rosh, Muppim, and Huppim, and Ard.
</verse><verse>These <supplied>are</supplied> the sons of Rachel, which were born to Jacob: all the souls <supplied>were</supplied> fourteen.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>And the sons of Dan; Hushim.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>And the sons of Naphtali; Jahzeel, and Guni, and Jezer, and Shillem.
</verse><verse>These <supplied>are</supplied> the sons of Bilhah, which Laban gave unto Rachel his daughter, and she bare these unto Jacob: all the souls <supplied>were</supplied> seven.
</verse><verse>All the souls that came with Jacob into Egypt, which came out of his loins, besides Jacob&#x2019;s sons&#x2019; wives, all the souls <supplied>were</supplied> threescore and six;
</verse><verse>And the sons of Joseph, which were born him in Egypt, <supplied>were</supplied> two souls: all the souls of the house of Jacob, which came into Egypt, <supplied>were</supplied> threescore and ten.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>And he sent Judah before him unto Joseph, to direct his face unto Goshen; and they came into the land of Goshen.
</verse><verse>And Joseph made ready his chariot, and went up to meet Israel his father, to Goshen, and presented himself unto him; and he fell on his neck, and wept on his neck a good while.
</verse><verse>And Israel said unto Joseph, Now let me die, since I have seen thy face, because thou <supplied>art</supplied> yet alive.
</verse><verse>And Joseph said unto his brethren, and unto his father&#x2019;s house, I will go up, and shew Pharaoh, and say unto him, My brethren, and my father&#x2019;s house, which <supplied>were</supplied> in the land of Canaan, are come unto me;
</verse><verse>And the men <supplied>are</supplied> shepherds, for their trade hath been to feed cattle; and they have brought their flocks, and their herds, and all that they have.
</verse><verse>And it shall come to pass, when Pharaoh shall call you, and shall say, What <supplied>is</supplied> your occupation?
</verse><verse>That ye shall say, Thy servants&#x2019; trade hath been about cattle from our youth even until now, both we, <supplied>and</supplied> also our fathers: that ye may dwell in the land of Goshen; for every shepherd <supplied>is</supplied> an abomination unto the Egyptians.
     
      </verse>
      </chapter>
