<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Ezekiel" book-id="26" n="19">
<verse>"Take up a lament concerning the princes of Israel</verse>
<verse>and say: "'What a lioness was your mother among the lions! She lay down among the young lions and reared her cubs.</verse>
<verse>She brought up one of her cubs, and he became a strong lion. He learned to tear the prey and he devoured men.</verse>
<verse>The nations heard about him, and he was trapped in their pit. They led him with hooks to the land of Egypt.</verse>
<verse>"'When she saw her hope unfulfilled, her expectation gone, she took another of her cubs and made him a strong lion.</verse>
<verse>He prowled among the lions, for he was now a strong lion. He learned to tear the prey and he devoured men.</verse>
<verse>He broke down their strongholds and devastated their towns. The land and all who were in it were terrified by his roaring.</verse>
<verse>Then the nations came against him, those from regions round about. They spread their net for him, and he was trapped in their pit.</verse>
<verse>With hooks they pulled him into a cage and brought him to the king of Babylon. They put him in prison, so his roar was heard no longer on the mountains of Israel.</verse>
<verse>"'Your mother was like a vine in your vineyard planted by the water; it was fruitful and full of branches because of abundant water.</verse>
<verse>Its branches were strong, fit for a ruler's scepter. It towered high above the thick foliage, conspicuous for its height and for its many branches.</verse>
<verse>But it was uprooted in fury and thrown to the ground. The east wind made it shrivel, it was stripped of its fruit; its strong branches withered and fire consumed them.</verse>
<verse>Now it is planted in the desert, in a dry and thirsty land.</verse>
<verse>Fire spread from one of its main branches and consumed its fruit. No strong branch is left on it fit for a ruler's scepter.' This is a lament and is to be used as a lament."</verse>
</chapter>