<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Ezekiel" book-id="26" n="25">
<verse>The word of the LORD came to me:</verse>
<verse>"Son of man, set your face against the Ammonites and prophesy against them.</verse>
<verse>Say to them, 'Hear the word of the Sovereign LORD. This is what the Sovereign LORD says: Because you said "Aha!" over my sanctuary when it was desecrated and over the land of Israel when it was laid waste and over the people of Judah when they went into exile,</verse>
<verse>therefore I am going to give you to the people of the East as a possession. They will set up their camps and pitch their tents among you; they will eat your fruit and drink your milk.</verse>
<verse>I will turn Rabbah into a pasture for camels and Ammon into a resting place for sheep. Then you will know that I am the LORD.</verse>
<verse>For this is what the Sovereign LORD says: Because you have clapped your hands and stamped your feet, rejoicing with all the malice of your heart against the land of Israel,</verse>
<verse>therefore I will stretch out my hand against you and give you as plunder to the nations. I will cut you off from the nations and exterminate you from the countries. I will destroy you, and you will know that I am the LORD.'"</verse>
<verse>"This is what the Sovereign LORD says: 'Because Moab and Seir said, "Look, the house of Judah has become like all the other nations,"</verse>
<verse>therefore I will expose the flank of Moab, beginning at its frontier towns-Beth Jeshimoth, Baal Meon and Kiriathaim-the glory of that land.</verse>
<verse>I will give Moab along with the Ammonites to the people of the East as a possession, so that the Ammonites will not be remembered among the nations;</verse>
<verse>and I will inflict punishment on Moab. Then they will know that I am the LORD.'"</verse>
<verse>"This is what the Sovereign LORD says: 'Because Edom took revenge on the house of Judah and became very guilty by doing so,</verse>
<verse>therefore this is what the Sovereign LORD says: I will stretch out my hand against Edom and kill its men and their animals. I will lay it waste, and from Teman to Dedan they will fall by the sword.</verse>
<verse>I will take vengeance on Edom by the hand of my people Israel, and they will deal with Edom in accordance with my anger and my wrath; they will know my vengeance, declares the Sovereign LORD.'"</verse>
<verse>"This is what the Sovereign LORD says: 'Because the Philistines acted in vengeance and took revenge with malice in their hearts, and with ancient hostility sought to destroy Judah,</verse>
<verse>therefore this is what the Sovereign LORD says: I am about to stretch out my hand against the Philistines, and I will cut off the Kerethites and destroy those remaining along the coast.</verse>
<verse>I will carry out great vengeance on them and punish them in my wrath. Then they will know that I am the LORD, when I take vengeance on them.'"</verse>
</chapter>