<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Ezekiel" book_id="26" n="28">
<verse>The word of the LORD came to me:</verse>
<verse>"Son of man, say to the ruler of Tyre, 'This is what the Sovereign LORD says: "'In the pride of your heart you say, "I am a god; I sit on the throne of a god in the heart of the seas." But you are a man and not a god, though you think you are as wise as a god.</verse>
<verse>Are you wiser than Daniel? Is no secret hidden from you?</verse>
<verse>By your wisdom and understanding you have gained wealth for yourself and amassed gold and silver in your treasuries.</verse>
<verse>By your great skill in trading you have increased your wealth, and because of your wealth your heart has grown proud.</verse>
<verse>"'Therefore this is what the Sovereign LORD says: "'Because you think you are wise, as wise as a god,</verse>
<verse>I am going to bring foreigners against you, the most ruthless of nations; they will draw their swords against your beauty and wisdom and pierce your shining splendor.</verse>
<verse>They will bring you down to the pit, and you will die a violent death in the heart of the seas.</verse>
<verse>Will you then say, "I am a god," in the presence of those who kill you? You will be but a man, not a god, in the hands of those who slay you.</verse>
<verse>You will die the death of the uncircumcised at the hands of foreigners. I have spoken, declares the Sovereign LORD.'"</verse>
<verse>The word of the LORD came to me:</verse>
<verse>"Son of man, take up a lament concerning the king of Tyre and say to him: 'This is what the Sovereign LORD says: "'You were the model of perfection, full of wisdom and perfect in beauty.</verse>
<verse>You were in Eden, the garden of God; every precious stone adorned you: ruby, topaz and emerald, chrysolite, onyx and jasper, sapphire, turquoise and beryl. Your settings and mountings were made of gold; on the day you were created they were prepared.</verse>
<verse>You were anointed as a guardian cherub, for so I ordained you. You were on the holy mount of God; you walked among the fiery stones.</verse>
<verse>You were blameless in your ways from the day you were created till wickedness was found in you.</verse>
<verse>Through your widespread trade you were filled with violence, and you sinned. So I drove you in disgrace from the mount of God, and I expelled you, O guardian cherub, from among the fiery stones.</verse>
<verse>Your heart became proud on account of your beauty, and you corrupted your wisdom because of your splendor. So I threw you to the earth; I made a spectacle of you before kings.</verse>
<verse>By your many sins and dishonest trade you have desecrated your sanctuaries. So I made a fire come out from you, and it consumed you, and I reduced you to ashes on the ground in the sight of all who were watching.</verse>
<verse>All the nations who knew you are appalled at you; you have come to a horrible end and will be no more.'"</verse>
<verse>The word of the LORD came to me:</verse>
<verse>"Son of man, set your face against Sidon; prophesy against her</verse>
<verse>and say: 'This is what the Sovereign LORD says: "'I am against you, O Sidon, and I will gain glory within you. They will know that I am the LORD, when I inflict punishment on her and show myself holy within her.</verse>
<verse>I will send a plague upon her and make blood flow in her streets. The slain will fall within her, with the sword against her on every side. Then they will know that I am the LORD.</verse>
<verse>"'No longer will the people of Israel have malicious neighbors who are painful briers and sharp thorns. Then they will know that I am the Sovereign LORD.</verse>
<verse>"'This is what the Sovereign LORD says: When I gather the people of Israel from the nations where they have been scattered, I will show myself holy among them in the sight of the nations. Then they will live in their own land, which I gave to my servant Jacob.</verse>
<verse>They will live there in safety and will build houses and plant vineyards; they will live in safety when I inflict punishment on all their neighbors who maligned them. Then they will know that I am the LORD their God.'"</verse>
</chapter>