<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Zechariah" book-id="38" n="10">
<verse>Ask rain from the LORD at the time of the spring rain--The LORD who makes the storm clouds; And He will give them showers of rain, vegetation in the field to each man.</verse>
<verse>For the teraphim speak iniquity, And the diviners see lying visions And tell false dreams; They comfort in vain. Therefore the people wander like sheep, They are afflicted, because there is no shepherd.</verse>
<verse>"My anger is kindled against the shepherds, And I will punish the male goats; For the LORD of hosts has visited His flock, the house of Judah, And will make them like His majestic horse in battle.</verse>
<verse>"From them will come the cornerstone, From them the tent peg, From them the bow of battle, From them every ruler, all of them together.</verse>
<verse>"They will be as mighty men, Treading down the enemy in the mire of the streets in battle; And they will fight, for the LORD will be with them; And the riders on horses will be put to shame.</verse>
<verse>"I will strengthen the house of Judah, And I will save the house of Joseph, And I will bring them back, Because I have had compassion on them; And they will be as though I had not rejected them, For I am the LORD their God and I will answer them.</verse>
<verse>"Ephraim will be like a mighty man, And their heart will be glad as if from wine; Indeed, their children will see it and be glad, Their heart will rejoice in the LORD.</verse>
<verse>"I will whistle for them to gather them together, For I have redeemed them; And they will be as numerous as they were before.</verse>
<verse>"When I scatter them among the peoples, They will remember Me in far countries, And they with their children will live and come back.</verse>
<verse>"I will bring them back from the land of Egypt And gather them from Assyria; And I will bring them into the land of Gilead and Lebanon Until no room can be found for them.</verse>
<verse>"And they will pass through the sea of distress And He will strike the waves in the sea, So that all the depths of the Nile will dry up; And the pride of Assyria will be brought down And the scepter of Egypt will depart.</verse>
<verse>"And I will strengthen them in the LORD, And in His name they will walk," declares the LORD.</verse>
</chapter>