<?xml version="1.0"?>
<chapter translation="KJV" testament="Old" book="Song of Solomon" n="2" chapters="8">
      <verse>I <supplied>am</supplied> the rose of Sharon, <supplied>and</supplied> the lily of the valleys.
</verse><verse>As the lily among thorns, so <supplied>is</supplied> my love among the daughters.
</verse><verse>As the apple tree among the trees of the wood, so <supplied>is</supplied> my beloved among the sons. I sat down under his shadow with great delight, and his fruit <supplied>was</supplied> sweet to my taste.
</verse><verse>He brought me to the banqueting house, and his banner over me <supplied>was</supplied> love.
</verse><verse>Stay me with flagons, comfort me with apples: for I <supplied>am</supplied> sick of love.
</verse><verse>His left hand <supplied>is</supplied> under my head, and his right hand doth embrace me.
</verse><verse>I charge you, O ye daughters of Jerusalem, by the roes, and by the hinds of the field, that ye stir not up, nor awake <supplied>my</supplied> love, till he please.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>The voice of my beloved! behold, he cometh leaping upon the mountains, skipping upon the hills.
</verse><verse>My beloved is like a roe or a young hart: behold, he standeth behind our wall, he looketh forth at the windows, shewing himself through the lattice.
</verse><verse>My beloved spake, and said unto me, Rise up, my love, my fair one, and come away.
</verse><verse>For, lo, the winter is past, the rain is over <supplied>and</supplied> gone;
</verse><verse>The flowers appear on the earth; the time of the singing <supplied>of birds</supplied> is come, and the voice of the turtle is heard in our land;
</verse><verse>The fig tree putteth forth her green figs, and the vines <supplied>with</supplied> the tender grape give a <supplied>good</supplied> smell. Arise, my love, my fair one, and come away.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>O my dove, <supplied>that art</supplied> in the clefts of the rock, in the secret <supplied>places</supplied> of the stairs, let me see thy countenance, let me hear thy voice; for sweet <supplied>is</supplied> thy voice, and thy countenance <supplied>is</supplied> comely.
</verse><verse>Take us the foxes, the little foxes, that spoil the vines: for our vines <supplied>have</supplied> tender grapes.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>My beloved <supplied>is</supplied> mine, and I <supplied>am</supplied> his: he feedeth among the lilies.
</verse><verse>Until the day break, and the shadows flee away, turn, my beloved, and be thou like a roe or a young hart upon the mountains of Bether.
     
      </verse>
      </chapter>
