<chapter translation="MSG" testament="New" book="Acts" book_id="44" n="17">
<verse>They took the road south through Amphipolis and Apollonia to Thessalonica, where there was a community of Jews.</verse>
<verse>Paul went to their meeting place, as he usually did when he came to a town, and for three Sabbaths running he preached to them from the Scriptures.</verse>
<verse>He opened up the texts so they understood what they'd been reading all their lives: that the Messiah absolutely had to be put to death and raised from the dead--there were no other options--and that "this Jesus I'm introducing you to is that Messiah."</verse>
<verse>Some of them were won over and joined ranks with Paul and Silas, among them a great many God-fearing Greeks and a considerable number of women from the aristocracy.</verse>
<verse>But the hard-line Jews became furious over the conversions. Mad with jealousy, they rounded up a bunch of brawlers off the streets and soon had an ugly mob terrorizing the city as they hunted down Paul and Silas. They broke into Jason's house, thinking that Paul and Silas were there.</verse>
<verse>When they couldn't find them, they collared Jason and his friends instead and dragged them before the city fathers, yelling hysterically, "These people are out to destroy the world, and now they've shown up on our doorstep, attacking everything we hold dear!</verse>
<verse>And Jason is hiding them, these traitors and turncoats who say Jesus is king and Caesar is nothing!"</verse>
<verse>The city fathers and the crowd of people were totally alarmed by what they heard.</verse>
<verse>They made Jason and his friends post heavy bail and let them go while they investigated the charges.</verse>
<verse>That night, under cover of darkness, their friends got Paul and Silas out of town as fast as they could. They sent them to Berea, where they again met with the Jewish community.</verse>
<verse>They were treated a lot better there than in Thessalonica. The Jews received Paul's message with enthusiasm and met with him daily, examining the Scriptures to see if they supported what he said.</verse>
<verse>A lot of them became believers, including many Greeks who were prominent in the community, women and men of influence.</verse>
<verse>But it wasn't long before reports got back to the Thessalonian hard-line Jews that Paul was at it again, preaching the Word of God, this time in Berea. They lost no time responding, and created a mob scene there, too.</verse>
<verse>With the help of his friends, Paul gave them the slip--caught a boat and put out to sea. Silas and Timothy stayed behind.</verse>
<verse>The men who helped Paul escape got him as far as Athens and left him there. Paul sent word back with them to Silas and Timothy: "Come as quickly as you can!"</verse>
<verse>The longer Paul waited in Athens for Silas and Timothy, the angrier he got--all those idols! The city was a junkyard of idols.</verse>
<verse>He discussed it with the Jews and other like-minded people at their meeting place. And every day he went out on the streets and talked with anyone who happened along.</verse>
<verse>He got to know some of the Epicurean and Stoic intellectuals pretty well through these conversations. Some of them dismissed him with sarcasm: "What an airhead!" But others, listening to him go on about Jesus and the resurrection, were intrigued: "That's a new slant on the gods. Tell us more."</verse>
<verse>These people got together and asked him to make a public presentation over at the Areopagus, where things were a little quieter. They said, "This is a new one on us. We've never heard anything quite like it. Where did you come up with this anyway?</verse>
<verse>Explain it so we can understand."</verse>
<verse>Downtown Athens was a great place for gossip. There were always people hanging around, natives and tourists alike, waiting for the latest tidbit on most anything.</verse>
<verse>So Paul took his stand in the open space at the Areopagus and laid it out for them. "It is plain to see that you Athenians take your religion seriously.</verse>
<verse>When I arrived here the other day, I was fascinated with all the shrines I came across. And then I found one inscribed, TO THE GOD NOBODY KNOWS. I'm here to introduce you to this God so you can worship intelligently, know who you're dealing with.</verse>
<verse>"The God who made the world and everything in it, this Master of sky and land, doesn't live in custom-made shrines</verse>
<verse>or need the human race to run errands for him, as if he couldn't take care of himself. He makes the creatures; the creatures don't make him.</verse>
<verse>Starting from scratch, he made the entire human race and made the earth hospitable, with plenty of time and space for living</verse>
<verse>so we could seek after God, and not just grope around in the dark but actually find him. He doesn't play hide-and-seek with us. He's not remote; he's near.</verse>
<verse>We live and move in him, can't get away from him! One of your poets said it well: "We're the God-created.'</verse>
<verse>Well, if we are the God-created, it doesn't make a lot of sense to think we could hire a sculptor to chisel a god out of stone for us, does it?</verse>
<verse>"God overlooks it as long as you don't know any better--but that time is past. The unknown is now known, and he's calling for a radical life-change.</verse>
<verse>He has set a day when the entire human race will be judged and everything set right. And he has already appointed the judge, confirming him before everyone by raising him from the dead."</verse>
<verse>At the phrase "raising him from the dead," the listeners split: Some laughed at him and walked off making jokes; others said, "Let's do this again. We want to hear more."</verse>
<verse>But that was it for the day, and Paul left.</verse>
<verse>There were still others, it turned out, who were convinced then and there, and stuck with Paul--among them Dionysius the Areopagite and a woman named Damaris.</verse>
</chapter>