<chapter translation="MSG" testament="New" book="Acts" book_id="44" n="18">
<verse>After Athens, Paul went to Corinth.</verse>
<verse>That is where he discovered Aquila, a Jew born in Pontus, and his wife, Priscilla. They had just arrived from Italy, part of the general expulsion of Jews from Rome ordered by Claudius.</verse>
<verse>Paul moved in with them, and they worked together at their common trade of tentmaking.</verse>
<verse>But every Sabbath he was at the meeting place, doing his best to convince both Jews and Greeks about Jesus.</verse>
<verse>When Silas and Timothy arrived from Macedonia, Paul was able to give all his time to preaching and teaching, doing everything he could to persuade the Jews that Jesus was in fact God's Messiah.</verse>
<verse>But no such luck. All they did was argue contentiously and contradict him at every turn. Totally exasperated, Paul had finally had it with them and gave it up as a bad job. "Have it your way, then," he said. "You've made your bed; now lie in it. From now on I'm spending my time with the other nations."</verse>
<verse>He walked out and went to the home of Titius Justus, a God-fearing man who lived right next to the Jews' meeting place.</verse>
<verse>But Paul's efforts with the Jews weren't a total loss, for Crispus, the meeting-place president, put his trust in the Master. His entire family believed with him. In the course of listening to Paul, a great many Corinthians believed and were baptized.</verse>
<verse>One night the Master spoke to Paul in a dream: "Keep it up, and don't let anyone intimidate or silence you.</verse>
<verse>No matter what happens, I'm with you and no one is going to be able to hurt you. You have no idea how many people I have on my side in this city."</verse>
<verse>That was all he needed to stick it out. He stayed another year and a half, faithfully teaching the Word of God to the Corinthians.</verse>
<verse>But when Gallio was governor of Achaia province, the Jews got up a campaign against Paul, hauled him into court,</verse>
<verse>and filed chcrges: "This man is seducing people into acts of worship that are illegal."</verse>
<verse>Just as Paul was about to defend himself, Gallio interrupted and said to the Jews, "If this was a matter of criminal conduct, I would gladly hear you out.</verse>
<verse>But it sounds to me like one more Jewish squabble, another of your endless hairsplitting quarrels over religion. Take care of it on your own time. I can't be bothered with this nonsense,"</verse>
<verse>and he cleared them out of the courtroom.</verse>
<verse>Now the street rabble turned on Sosthenes, the new meeting-place president, and beat him up in plain sight of the court. Gallio didn't raise a finger. He could not have cared less.</verse>
<verse>Paul stayed a while longer in Corinth, but then it was time to take leave of his friends. Saying his good-byes, he sailed for Syria, Priscilla and Aquila with him. Before boarding the ship in the harbor town of Cenchrea, he had his head shaved as part of a vow he had taken.</verse>
<verse>They landed in Ephesus, where Priscilla and Aquila got off and stayed. Paul left the ship briefly to go to the meeting place and preach to the Jews.</verse>
<verse>They wanted him to stay longer, but he said he couldn't.</verse>
<verse>But after saying good-bye, he promised, "I'll be back, God willing." From Ephesus</verse>
<verse>he sailed to Caesarea. He greeted the assembly of Christians there, and then went on to Antioch, completing the journey.</verse>
<verse>After spending a considerable time with the Antioch Christians, Paul set off again for Galatia and Phrygia, retracing his old tracks, one town after another, putting fresh heart into the disciples.</verse>
<verse>A man named Apollos came to Ephesus. He was a Jew, born in Alexandria, Egypt, and a terrific speaker, eloquent and powerful in his preaching of the Scriptures.</verse>
<verse>He was well-educated in the way of the Master and fiery in his enthusiasm. Apollos was accurate in everything he taught about Jesus up to a point, but he only went as far as the baptism of John.</verse>
<verse>He preached with power in the meeting place. When Priscilla and Aquila heard him, they took him aside and told him the rest of the story.</verse>
<verse>When Apollos decided to go on to Achaia province, his Ephesian friends gave their blessing and wrote a letter of recommendation for him, urging the disciples there to welcome him with open arms. The welcome paid off: Apollos turned out to be a great help to those who had become believers through God's immense generosity.</verse>
<verse>He was particularly effective in public debate with the Jews as he brought out proof after convincing proof from the Scriptures that Jesus was in fact God's Messiah.</verse>
</chapter>