<?xml version="1.0"?>
<chapter translation="KJV" testament="Old" book="Job" n="22">
      <verse>Then Eliphaz the Temanite answered and said,
</verse><verse>Can a man be profitable unto God, as he that is wise may be profitable unto himself?
</verse><verse><supplied>Is it</supplied> any pleasure to the Almighty, that thou art righteous? or <supplied>is it</supplied> gain <supplied>to him</supplied> that thou makest thy ways perfect?
</verse><verse>Will he reprove thee for fear of thee? will he enter with thee into judgment?
</verse><verse><supplied>Is</supplied> not thy wickedness great? and thine iniquities infinite?
</verse><verse>For thou hast taken a pledge from thy brother for nought, and stripped the naked of their clothing.
</verse><verse>Thou hast not given water to the weary to drink, and thou hast withholden bread from the hungry.
</verse><verse>But <supplied>as for</supplied> the mighty man, he had the earth; and the honourable man dwelt in it.
</verse><verse>Thou hast sent widows away empty, and the arms of the fatherless have been broken.
</verse><verse>Therefore snares <supplied>are</supplied> round about thee, and sudden fear troubleth thee;
</verse><verse>Or darkness, <supplied>that</supplied> thou canst not see; and abundance of waters cover thee.
</verse><verse><supplied>Is</supplied> not God in the height of heaven? and behold the height of the stars, how high they are!
</verse><verse>And thou sayest, How doth God know? can he judge through the dark cloud?
</verse><verse>Thick clouds <supplied>are</supplied> a covering to him, that he seeth not; and he walketh in the circuit of heaven.
</verse><verse>Hast thou marked the old way which wicked men have trodden?
</verse><verse>Which were cut down out of time, whose foundation was overflown with a flood:
</verse><verse>Which said unto God, Depart from us: and what can the Almighty do for them?
</verse><verse>Yet he filled their houses with good <supplied>things:</supplied> but the counsel of the wicked is far from me.
</verse><verse>The righteous see <supplied>it,</supplied> and are glad: and the innocent laugh them to scorn.
</verse><verse>Whereas our substance is not cut down, but the remnant of them the fire consumeth.
</verse><verse>Acquaint now thyself with him, and be at peace: thereby good shall come unto thee.
</verse><verse>Receive, I pray thee, the law from his mouth, and lay up his words in thine heart.
</verse><verse>If thou return to the Almighty, thou shalt be built up, thou shalt put away iniquity far from thy tabernacles.
</verse><verse>Then shalt thou lay up gold as dust, and the <supplied>gold</supplied> of Ophir as the stones of the brooks.
</verse><verse>Yea, the Almighty shall be thy defence, and thou shalt have plenty of silver.
</verse><verse>For then shalt thou have thy delight in the Almighty, and shalt lift up thy face unto God.
</verse><verse>Thou shalt make thy prayer unto him, and he shall hear thee, and thou shalt pay thy vows.
</verse><verse>Thou shalt also decree a thing, and it shall be established unto thee: and the light shall shine upon thy ways.
</verse><verse>When <supplied>men</supplied> are cast down, then thou shalt say, <supplied>There is</supplied> lifting up; and he shall save the humble person.
</verse><verse>He shall deliver the island of the innocent: and it is delivered by the pureness of thine hands.
     
      </verse>
      </chapter>
