<?xml version="1.0"?>
<chapter translation="KJV" testament="Old" book="Job" n="33" chapters="42">
      <verse>Wherefore, Job, I pray thee, hear my speeches, and hearken to all my words.
</verse><verse>Behold, now I have opened my mouth, my tongue hath spoken in my mouth.
</verse><verse>My words <supplied>shall be of</supplied> the uprightness of my heart: and my lips shall utter knowledge clearly.
</verse><verse>The Spirit of God hath made me, and the breath of the Almighty hath given me life.
</verse><verse>If thou canst answer me, set <supplied>thy words</supplied> in order before me, stand up.
</verse><verse>Behold, I <supplied>am</supplied> according to thy wish in God&#x2019;s stead: I also am formed out of the clay.
</verse><verse>Behold, my terror shall not make thee afraid, neither shall my hand be heavy upon thee.
</verse><verse>Surely thou hast spoken in mine hearing, and I have heard the voice of <supplied>thy</supplied> words, <supplied>saying, </supplied></verse><verse>I am clean without transgression, I <supplied>am</supplied> innocent; neither <supplied>is there</supplied> iniquity in me.
</verse><verse>Behold, he findeth occasions against me, he counteth me for his enemy,
</verse><verse>He putteth my feet in the stocks, he marketh all my paths.
</verse><verse>Behold, <supplied>in</supplied> this thou art not just: I will answer thee, that God is greater than man.
</verse><verse>Why dost thou strive against him? for he giveth not account of any of his matters.
</verse><verse>For God speaketh once, yea twice, <supplied>yet man</supplied> perceiveth it not.
</verse><verse>In a dream, in a vision of the night, when deep sleep falleth upon men, in slumberings upon the bed;
</verse><verse>Then he openeth the ears of men, and sealeth their instruction,
</verse><verse>That he may withdraw man <supplied>from his</supplied> purpose, and hide pride from man.
</verse><verse>He keepeth back his soul from the pit, and his life from perishing by the sword.
</verse><verse>He is chastened also with pain upon his bed, and the multitude of his bones with strong <supplied>pain: </supplied></verse><verse>So that his life abhorreth bread, and his soul dainty meat.
</verse><verse>His flesh is consumed away, that it cannot be seen; and his bones <supplied>that</supplied> were not seen stick out.
</verse><verse>Yea, his soul draweth near unto the grave, and his life to the destroyers.
</verse><verse>If there be a messenger with him, an interpreter, one among a thousand, to shew unto man his uprightness:
</verse><verse>Then he is gracious unto him, and saith, Deliver him from going down to the pit: I have found a ransom.
</verse><verse>His flesh shall be fresher than a child&#x2019;s: he shall return to the days of his youth:
</verse><verse>He shall pray unto God, and he will be favourable unto him: and he shall see his face with joy: for he will render unto man his righteousness.
</verse><verse>He looketh upon men, and <supplied>if any</supplied> say, I have sinned, and perverted <supplied>that which was</supplied> right, and it profited me not;
</verse><verse>He will deliver his soul from going into the pit, and his life shall see the light.
</verse><verse>Lo, all these <supplied>things</supplied> worketh God oftentimes with man,
</verse><verse>To bring back his soul from the pit, to be enlightened with the light of the living.
</verse><verse>Mark well, O Job, hearken unto me: hold thy peace, and I will speak.
</verse><verse>If thou hast any thing to say, answer me: speak, for I desire to justify thee.
</verse><verse>If not, hearken unto me: hold thy peace, and I shall teach thee wisdom.
     
      </verse>
      </chapter>
