<chapter translation="KJV" testament="Old" book="JOB" n="39">
      <verse>Knowest thou the time when the wild goats of the rock bring forth? <supplied>or</supplied> canst thou mark when the hinds do calve?
</verse><verse>Canst thou number the months <supplied>that</supplied> they fulfil? or knowest thou the time when they bring forth?
</verse><verse>They bow themselves, they bring forth their young ones, they cast out their sorrows.
</verse><verse>Their young ones are in good liking, they grow up with corn; they go forth, and return not unto them.
</verse><verse>Who hath sent out the wild ass free? or who hath loosed the bands of the wild ass?
</verse><verse>Whose house I have made the wilderness, and the barren land his dwellings.
</verse><verse>He scorneth the multitude of the city, neither regardeth he the crying of the driver.
</verse><verse>The range of the mountains <supplied>is</supplied> his pasture, and he searcheth after every green thing.
</verse><verse>Will the unicorn be willing to serve thee, or abide by thy crib?
</verse><verse>Canst thou bind the unicorn with his band in the furrow? or will he harrow the valleys after thee?
</verse><verse>Wilt thou trust him, because his strength <supplied>is</supplied> great? or wilt thou leave thy labour to him?
</verse><verse>Wilt thou believe him, that he will bring home thy seed, and gather <supplied>it into</supplied> thy barn?
</verse><verse><supplied>Gavest thou</supplied> the goodly wings unto the peacocks? or wings and feathers unto the ostrich?
</verse><verse>Which leaveth her eggs in the earth, and warmeth them in dust,
</verse><verse>And forgetteth that the foot may crush them, or that the wild beast may break them.
</verse><verse>She is hardened against her young ones, as though <supplied>they were</supplied> not hers: her labour is in vain without fear;
</verse><verse>Because God hath deprived her of wisdom, neither hath he imparted to her understanding.
</verse><verse>What time she lifteth up herself on high, she scorneth the horse and his rider.
</verse><verse>Hath thou given the horse strength? hast thou clothed his neck with thunder?
</verse><verse>Canst thou make him afraid as a grasshopper? the glory of his nostrils <supplied>is</supplied> terrible.
</verse><verse>He paweth in the valley, and rejoiceth in <supplied>his</supplied> strength: he goeth on to meet the armed men.
</verse><verse>He mocketh at fear, and is not affrighted; neither turneth he back from the sword.
</verse><verse>The quiver rattleth against him, the glittering spear and the shield.
</verse><verse>He swalloweth the ground with fierceness and rage: neither believeth he that <supplied>it is</supplied> the sound of the trumpet.
</verse><verse>He saith among the trumpets, Ha, ha; and he smelleth the battle afar off, the thunder of the captains, and the shouting.
</verse><verse>Doth the hawk fly by thy wisdom, <supplied>and</supplied> stretch her wings toward the south?
</verse><verse>Doth the eagle mount up at thy command, and make her nest on high?
</verse><verse>She dwelleth and abideth on the rock, upon the crag of the rock, and the strong place.
</verse><verse>From thence she seeketh the prey, <supplied>and</supplied> her eyes behold afar off.
</verse><verse>Her young ones also suck up blood: and where the slain <supplied>are,</supplied> there <supplied>is</supplied> she.
     
      </verse>
      </chapter>