<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Hosea" book-id="28" n="7">
<verse>"Every time I gave Israel a fresh start, wiped the slate clean and got them going again, Ephraim soon filled the slate with new sins, the treachery of Samaria written out in bold print. Two-faced and double-tongued, they steal you blind, pick you clean.</verse>
<verse>It never crosses their mind that I keep account of their every crime. They're mud-spattered head to toe with the residue of sin. I see who they are and what they've done.</verse>
<verse>"They entertain the king with their evil circus, delight the princes with their acrobatic lies.</verse>
<verse>They're a bunch of overheated adulterers, like an oven that holds its heat From the kneading of the dough to the rising of the bread.</verse>
<verse>On the royal holiday the princes get drunk on wine and the frenzy of the mocking mob.</verse>
<verse>They're like wood stoves, red-hot with lust. Through the night their passion is banked; in the morning it blazes up, flames hungrily licking.</verse>
<verse>Murderous and volcanic, they incinerate their rulers. Their kings fall one by one, and no one pays any attention to me.</verse>
<verse>"Ephraim mingles with the pagans, dissipating himself. Ephraim is half-baked.</verse>
<verse>Strangers suck him dry but he doesn't even notice. His hair has turned gray--he doesn't notice.</verse>
<verse>Bloated by arrogance, big as a house, Israel's a public disgrace. Israel lumbers along oblivious to GOD, despite all the signs, ignoring GOD.</verse>
<verse>"Ephraim is bird-brained, mindless, clueless, First chirping after Egypt, then fluttering after Assyria.</verse>
<verse>I'll throw my net over them. I'll clip their wings. I'll teach them to mind me!</verse>
<verse>Doom! They've run away from home. Now they're really in trouble! They've defied me. And I'm supposed to help them while they feed me a line of lies?</verse>
<verse>Instead of crying out to me in heartfelt prayer, they whoop it up in bed with their whores, Gash themselves bloody in their sex-and-religion orgies, but turn their backs on me.</verse>
<verse>I'm the one who gave them good minds and healthy bodies, and how am I repaid? With evil scheming!</verse>
<verse>They turn, but not to me--turn here, then there, like a weather vane. Their rulers will be cut down, murdered--just deserts for their mocking blasphemies. And the final sentence? Ridicule in the court of world opinion.</verse>
</chapter>