<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Hosea" book_id="28" n="9">
<verse>Don't waste your life in wild orgies, Israel. Don't party away your life with the heathen. You walk away from your God at the drop of a hat and like a whore sell yourself promiscuously at every sex-and-religion party on the street.</verse>
<verse>All that party food won't fill you up. You'll end up hungrier than ever.</verse>
<verse>At this rate you'll not last long in GOD's land: Some of you are going to end up bankrupt in Egypt. Some of you will be disillusioned in Assyria.</verse>
<verse>As refugees in Egypt and Assyria, you won't have much chance to worship GOD- Sentenced to rations of bread and water, and your souls polluted by the spirit-dirty air. You'll be starved for GOD, exiled from GOD's own country.</verse>
<verse>Will you be homesick for the old Holy Days? Will you miss festival worship of GOD?</verse>
<verse>Be warned! When you escape from the frying pan of disaster, you'll fall into the fire of Egypt. Egypt will give you a fine funeral! What use will all your god-inspired silver be then as you eke out a living in a field of weeds? [JC]</verse>
<verse>Time's up. Doom's at the doorstep. It's payday! Did Israel bluster, "The prophet is crazy! The "man of the Spirit' is nuts!"? Think again. Because of your great guilt, you're in big trouble.</verse>
<verse>The prophet is looking out for Ephraim, working under God's orders. But everyone is trying to trip him up. He's hated right in God's house, of all places.</verse>
<verse>The people are going from bad to worse, rivaling that ancient and unspeakable crime at Gibeah. God's keeping track of their guilt. He'll make them pay for their sins.</verse>
<verse>"Long ago when I came upon Israel, it was like finding grapes out in the desert. When I found your ancestors, it was like finding a fig tree bearing fruit for the first time. But when they arrived at Baal-peor, that pagan shrine, they took to sin like a pig to filth, wallowing in the mud with their newfound friends.</verse>
<verse>Ephraim is fickle and scattered, like a flock of blackbirds, their beauty dissipated in confusion and clamor, Frenetic and noisy, frigid and barren, and nothing to show for it--neither conception nor childbirth.</verse>
<verse>Even if they did give birth, I'd declare them unfit parents and take away their children! Yes indeed--a black day for them when I turn my back and walk off!</verse>
<verse>I see Ephraim letting his children run wild. He might just as well take them and kill them outright!"</verse>
<verse>Give it to them, GOD! But what? Give them a dried-up womb and shriveled breasts.</verse>
<verse>"All their evil came out into the open at the pagan shrine at Gilgal. Oh, how I hated them there! Because of their evil practices, I'll kick them off my land. I'm wasting no more love on them. Their leaders are a bunch of rebellious adolescents.</verse>
<verse>Ephraim is hit hard--roots withered, no more fruit. Even if by some miracle they had children, the dear babies wouldn't live--I'd make sure of that!"</verse>
<verse>My God has washed his hands of them. They wouldn't listen. They're doomed to be wanderers, vagabonds among the godless nations.</verse>
</chapter>