<chapter translation="ESV" testament="Old" book="Genesis" book_id="1" n="25">
<verse>Abraham took another wife, whose name was Keturah.</verse>
<verse>She bore him Zimran, Jokshan, Medan, Midian, Ishbak, and Shuah.</verse>
<verse>Jokshan fathered Sheba and Dedan. The sons of Dedan were Asshurim, Letushim, and Leummim.</verse>
<verse>The sons of Midian were Ephah, Epher, Hanoch, Abida, and Eldaah. All these were the children of Keturah.</verse>
<verse>Abraham gave all he had to Isaac.</verse>
<verse>But to the sons of his concubines Abraham gave gifts, and while he was still living he sent them away from his son Isaac, eastward to the east country.</verse>
<verse>These are the days of the years of Abraham's life, 175 years.</verse>
<verse>Abraham breathed his last and died in a good old age, an old man and full of years, and was gathered to his people.</verse>
<verse>Isaac and Ishmael his sons buried him in the cave of Machpelah, in the field of Ephron the son of Zohar the Hittite, east of Mamre,</verse>
<verse>the field that Abraham purchased from the Hittites. There Abraham was buried, with Sarah his wife.</verse>
<verse>After the death of Abraham, God blessed Isaac his son. And Isaac settled at Beer-lahai-roi.</verse>
<verse>These are the generations of Ishmael, Abraham's son, whom Hagar the Egyptian, Sarah's servant, bore to Abraham.</verse>
<verse>These are the names of the sons of Ishmael, named in the order of their birth: Nebaioth, the firstborn of Ishmael; and Kedar, Adbeel, Mibsam,</verse>
<verse>Mishma, Dumah, Massa,</verse>
<verse>Hadad, Tema, Jetur, Naphish, and Kedemah.</verse>
<verse>These are the sons of Ishmael and these are their names, by their villages and by their encampments, twelve princes according to their tribes.</verse>
<verse>(These are the years of the life of Ishmael: 137 years. He breathed his last and died, and was gathered to his people.)</verse>
<verse>They settled from Havilah to Shur, which is opposite Egypt in the direction of Assyria. He settled over against all his kinsmen.</verse>
<verse>These are the generations of Isaac, Abraham's son: Abraham fathered Isaac,</verse>
<verse>and Isaac was forty years old when he took Rebekah to be his wife, the daughter of Bethuel the Aramean of Paddan-aram, the sister of Laban the Aramean.</verse>
<verse>And Isaac prayed to the LORD for his wife, because she was barren. And the LORD granted his prayer, and Rebekah his wife conceived.</verse>
<verse>The children struggled together within her, and she said, "If it is thus, why is this happening to me?" So she went to inquire of the LORD.</verse>
<verse>And the LORD said to her, "Two nations are in your womb, and two peoples from within you shall be divided; the one shall be stronger than the other, the older shall serve the younger."</verse>
<verse>When her days to give birth were completed, behold, there were twins in her womb.</verse>
<verse>The first came out red, all his body like a hairy cloak, so they called his name Esau.</verse>
<verse>Afterward his brother came out with his hand holding Esau's heel, so his name was called Jacob. Isaac was sixty years old when she bore them.</verse>
<verse>When the boys grew up, Esau was a skillful hunter, a man of the field, while Jacob was a quiet man, dwelling in tents.</verse>
<verse>Isaac loved Esau because he ate of his game, but Rebekah loved Jacob.</verse>
<verse>Once when Jacob was cooking stew, Esau came in from the field, and he was exhausted.</verse>
<verse>And Esau said to Jacob, "Let me eat some of that red stew, for I am exhausted!" (Therefore his name was called Edom. )</verse>
<verse>Jacob said, "Sell me your birthright now."</verse>
<verse>Esau said, "I am about to die; of what use is a birthright to me?"</verse>
<verse>Jacob said, "Swear to me now." So he swore to him and sold his birthright to Jacob.</verse>
<verse>Then Jacob gave Esau bread and lentil stew, and he ate and drank and rose and went his way. Thus Esau despised his birthright.</verse>
</chapter>