<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Ecclesiastes" book_id="21" n="10">
<verse>Dead flies in perfume make it stink,	And a little foolishness decomposes much wisdom.</verse>
<verse>Wise thinking leads to right living; Stupid thinking leads to wrong living.</verse>
<verse>Fools on the road have no sense of direction. The way they walk tells the story: "There goes the fool again!"</verse>
<verse>If a ruler loses his temper against you, don't panic; A calm disposition quiets intemperate rage. [JC]</verse>
<verse>Here's a piece of bad business I've seen on this earth, An error that can be blamed on whoever is in charge:</verse>
<verse>Immaturity is given a place of prominence, While maturity is made to take a back seat.</verse>
<verse>I've seen unproven upstarts riding in style, While experienced veterans are put out to pasture. [JC]</verse>
<verse>Caution: The trap you set might catch you. Warning: Your accomplice in crime might double-cross you.</verse>
<verse>Safety first: Quarrying stones is dangerous. Be alert: Felling trees is hazardous.</verse>
<verse>Remember: The duller the ax the harder the work; Use your head: The more brains, the less muscle.</verse>
<verse>If the snake bites before it's been charmed, What's the point in then sending for the charmer? [JC]</verse>
<verse>The words of a wise person are gracious. The talk of a fool self-destructs--</verse>
<verse>He starts out talking nonsense And ends up spouting insanity and evil.</verse>
<verse>Fools talk way too much, Chattering stuff they know nothing about.</verse>
<verse>A decent day's work so fatigues fools That they can't find their way back to town. [JC]</verse>
<verse>Unlucky the land whose king is a young pup, And whose princes party all night.</verse>
<verse>Lucky the land whose king is mature, Where the princes behave themselves And don't drink themselves silly. [JC]</verse>
<verse>A shiftless man lives in a tumbledown shack; A lazy woman ends up with a leaky roof.</verse>
<verse>Laughter and bread go together, And wine gives sparkle to life--But it's money that makes the world go around.</verse>
<verse>Don't bad-mouth your leaders, not even under your breath, And don't abuse your betters, even in the privacy of your home. Loose talk has a way of getting picked up and spread around. Little birds drop the crumbs of your gossip far and wide.</verse>
</chapter>