<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Ecclesiastes" book_id="21" n="12">
<verse>Honor and enjoy your Creator while you're still young,	Before the years take their toll and your vigor wanes,</verse>
<verse>Before your vision dims and the world blurs And the winter years keep you close to the fire.</verse>
<verse>In old age, your body no longer serves you so well. Muscles slacken, grip weakens, joints stiffen. The shades are pulled down on the world.</verse>
<verse>You can't come and go at will. Things grind to a halt. The hum of the household fades away. You are wakened now by bird-song.</verse>
<verse>Hikes to the mountains are a thing of the past. Even a stroll down the road has its terrors. Your hair turns apple-blossom white, Adorning a fragile and impotent matchstick body. Yes, you're well on your way to eternal rest, While your friends make plans for your funeral.</verse>
<verse>Life, lovely while it lasts, is soon over. Life as we know it, precious and beautiful, ends.</verse>
<verse>The body is put back in the same ground it came from. The spirit returns to God, who first breathed it.</verse>
<verse>It's all smoke, nothing but smoke. The Quester says that everything's smoke.</verse>
<verse>Besides being wise himself, the Quester also taught others knowledge. He weighed, examined, and arranged many proverbs.</verse>
<verse>The Quester did his best to find the right words and write the plain truth.</verse>
<verse>The words of the wise prod us to live well. They're like nails hammered home, holding life together. They are given by God, the one Shepherd.</verse>
<verse>But regarding anything beyond this, dear friend, go easy. There's no end to the publishing of books, and constant study wears you out so you're no good for anything else.</verse>
<verse>The last and final word is this: Fear God. Do what he tells you.</verse>
<verse>And that's it. Eventually God will bring everything that we do out into the open and judge it according to its hidden intent, whether it's good or evil.</verse>
</chapter>