<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Ecclesiastes" book_id="21" n="2">
<verse>I said to myself, "Let's go for it--experiment with pleasure, have a good time!" But there was nothing to it, nothing but smoke.</verse>
<verse>What do I think of the fun-filled life? Insane! Inane! My verdict on the pursuit of happiness? Who needs it?</verse>
<verse>With the help of a bottle of wine and all the wisdom I could muster, I tried my level best to penetrate the absurdity of life. I wanted to get a handle on anything useful we mortals might do during the years we spend on this earth.</verse>
<verse>Oh, I did great things: built houses, planted vineyards,</verse>
<verse>designed gardens and parks and planted a variety of fruit trees in them,</verse>
<verse>made pools of water to irrigate the groves of trees.</verse>
<verse>I bought slaves, male and female, OSOSwho had children, giving me even more slaves; then I acquired large herds and flocks, larger than any before me in Jerusalem.</verse>
<verse>I piled up silver and gold, loot from kings and kingdoms. I gathered a chorus of singers to entertain me with song, and--most exquisite of all pleasures--voluptuous maidens for my bed.</verse>
<verse>Oh, how I prospered! I left all my predecessors in Jerusalem far behind, left them behind in the dust. What's more, I kept a clear head through it all.</verse>
<verse>Everything I wanted I took--I never said no to myself. I gave in to every impulse, held back nothing. I sucked the marrow of pleasure out of every task--my reward to myself for a hard day's work!</verse>
<verse>Then I took a good look at everything I'd done, looked at all the sweat and hard work. But when I looked, I saw nothing but smoke. Smoke and spitting into the wind. There was nothing to any of it. Nothing.</verse>
<verse>And then I took a hard look at what's smart and what's stupid. What's left to do after you've been king? That's a hard act to follow. You just do what you can, and that's it.</verse>
<verse>But I did see that it's better to be smart than stupid, just as light is better than darkness.</verse>
<verse>Even so, though the smart ones see where they're going and the stupid ones grope in the dark, they're all the same in the end. One fate for all--and that's it.</verse>
<verse>When I realized that my fate's the same as the fool's, I had to ask myself, "So why bother being wise?" It's all smoke, nothing but smoke.</verse>
<verse>The smart and the stupid both disappear out of sight. In a day or two they're both forgotten. Yes, both the smart and the stupid die, and that's it.</verse>
<verse>I hate life. As far as I can see, what happens on earth is a bad business. It's smoke--and spitting into the wind.</verse>
<verse>And I hated everything I'd accomplished and accumulated on this earth. I can't take it with me--no, I have to leave it to whoever comes after me.</verse>
<verse>Whether they're worthy or worthless--and who's to tell?-they'll take over the earthly results of my intense thinking and hard work. Smoke.</verse>
<verse>That's when I called it quits, gave up on anything that could be hoped for on this earth.</verse>
<verse>What's the point of working your fingers to the bone if you hand over what you worked for to someone who never lifted a finger for it? Smoke, that's what it is. A bad business from start to finish.</verse>
<verse>So what do you get from a life of hard labor?</verse>
<verse>Pain and grief from dawn to dusk. Never a decent night's rest. Nothing but smoke.</verse>
<verse>The best you can do with your life is have a good time and get by the best you can. The way I see it, that's it--divine fate.</verse>
<verse>Whether we feast or fast, it's up to God.</verse>
<verse>God may give wisdom and knowledge and joy to his favorites, but sinners are assigned a life of hard labor, and end up turning their wages over to God's favorites. Nothing but smoke--and spitting into the wind.</verse>
</chapter>