<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Ecclesiastes" book-id="21" n="7">
<verse>A good reputation is better than a fat bank account.	Your death date tells more than your birth date.</verse>
<verse>You learn more at a funeral than at a feast--After all, that's where we'll end up. We might discover something from it.</verse>
<verse>Crying is better than laughing. It blotches the face but it scours the heart.</verse>
<verse>Sages invest themselves in hurt and grieving. Fools waste their lives in fun and games.</verse>
<verse>You'll get more from the rebuke of a sage Than from the song and dance of fools.</verse>
<verse>The giggles of fools are like the crackling of twigs Under the cooking pot. And like smoke.</verse>
<verse>Brutality stupefies even the wise And destroys the strongest heart.</verse>
<verse>Endings are better than beginnings. Sticking to it is better than standing out.</verse>
<verse>Don't be quick to fly off the handle. Anger boomerangs. You can spot a fool by the lumps on his head.</verse>
<verse>Don't always be asking, "Where are the good old days?" Wise folks don't ask questions like that.</verse>
<verse>Wisdom is better when it's paired with money, Especially if you get both while you're still living.</verse>
<verse>Double protection: wisdom and wealth! Plus this bonus: Wisdom energizes its owner.</verse>
<verse>Take a good look at God's work. Who could simplify and reduce Creation's curves and angles To a plain straight line?</verse>
<verse>On a good day, enjoy yourself; On a bad day, examine your conscience. God arranges for both kinds of days So that we won't take anything for granted.</verse>
<verse>I've seen it all in my brief and pointless life--here a good person cut down in the middle of doing good, there a bad person living a long life of sheer evil.</verse>
<verse>So don't knock yourself out being good, and don't go overboard being wise. Believe me, you won't get anything out of it.</verse>
<verse>But don't press your luck by being bad, either. And don't be reckless. Why die needlessly?</verse>
<verse>It's best to stay in touch with both sides of an issue. A person who fears God deals responsibly with all of reality, not just a piece of it.</verse>
<verse>Wisdom puts more strength in one wise person Than ten strong men give to a city.</verse>
<verse>There's not one totally good person on earth, Not one who is truly pure and sinless.</verse>
<verse>Don't eavesdrop on the conversation of others. What if the gossip's about you and you'd rather not hear it?</verse>
<verse>You've done that a few times, haven't you--said things Behind someone's back you wouldn't say to his face?</verse>
<verse>I tested everything in my search for wisdom. I set out to be wise, but it was beyond me,</verse>
<verse>far beyond me, and deep--oh so deep! Does anyone ever find it?</verse>
<verse>I concentrated with all my might, studying and exploring and seeking wisdom--the meaning of life. I also wanted to identify evil and stupidity, foolishness and craziness.</verse>
<verse>One discovery: A woman can be a bitter pill to swallow, full of seductive scheming and grasping. The lucky escape her; the undiscerning get caught.</verse>
<verse>At least this is my experience--what I, the Quester, have pieced together as I've tried to make sense of life.</verse>
<verse>But the wisdom I've looked for I haven't found. I didn't find one man or woman in a thousand worth my while.</verse>
<verse>Yet I did spot one ray of light in this murk: God made men and women true and upright; we're the ones who've made a mess of things.</verse>
</chapter>