<chapter translation="ESV" testament="New" book="1 Timothy" book-id="54" n="3">
<verse>The saying is trustworthy: If anyone aspires to the office of overseer, he desires a noble task.</verse>
<verse>Therefore an overseer must be above reproach, the husband of one wife, sober-minded, self-controlled, respectable, hospitable, able to teach,</verse>
<verse>not a drunkard, not violent but gentle, not quarrelsome, not a lover of money.</verse>
<verse>He must manage his own household well, with all dignity keeping his children submissive,</verse>
<verse>for if someone does not know how to manage his own household, how will he care for God's church?</verse>
<verse>He must not be a recent convert, or he may become puffed up with conceit and fall into the condemnation of the devil.</verse>
<verse>Moreover, he must be well thought of by outsiders, so that he may not fall into disgrace, into a snare of the devil.</verse>
<verse>Deacons likewise must be dignified, not double-tongued, not addicted to much wine, not greedy for dishonest gain.</verse>
<verse>They must hold the mystery of the faith with a clear conscience.</verse>
<verse>And let them also be tested first; then let them serve as deacons if they prove themselves blameless.</verse>
<verse>Their wives likewise must be dignified, not slanderers, but sober-minded, faithful in all things.</verse>
<verse>Let deacons each be the husband of one wife, managing their children and their own households well.</verse>
<verse>For those who serve well as deacons gain a good standing for themselves and also great confidence in the faith that is in Christ Jesus.</verse>
<verse>I hope to come to you soon, but I am writing these things to you so that,</verse>
<verse>if I delay, you may know how one ought to behave in the household of God, which is the church of the living God, a pillar and buttress of truth.</verse>
<verse>Great indeed, we confess, is the mystery of godliness: He was manifested in the flesh, vindicated by the Spirit, seen by angels, proclaimed among the nations, believed on in the world, taken up in glory.</verse>
</chapter>