<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="1 Samuel" book_id="9" n="1">
<verse>There once was a man who lived in Ramathaim. He was descended from the old Zuph family in the Ephraim hills. His name was Elkanah. (He was connected with the Zuphs from Ephraim through his father Jeroham, his grandfather Elihu, and his great-grandfather Tohu.)</verse>
<verse>He had two wives. The first was Hannah; the second was Peninnah. Peninnah had children; Hannah did not.</verse>
<verse>Every year this man went from his hometown up to Shiloh to worship and offer a sacrifice to GOD-of-the-Angel-Armies. Eli and his two sons, Hophni and Phinehas, served as the priests of GOD there.</verse>
<verse>When Elkanah sacrificed, he passed helpings from the sacrificial meal around to his wife Peninnah and all her children,</verse>
<verse>but he always gave an especially generous helping to Hannah because he loved her so much, and because GOD had not given her children.</verse>
<verse>But her rival wife taunted her cruelly, rubbing it in and never letting her forget that GOD had not given her children.</verse>
<verse>This went on year after year. Every time she went to the sanctuary of GOD she could expect to be taunted. Hannah was reduced to tears and had no appetite.</verse>
<verse>Her husband Elkanah said, "Oh, Hannah, why are you crying? Why aren't you eating? And why are you so upset? Am I not of more worth to you than ten sons?"</verse>
<verse>So Hannah ate. Then she pulled herself together, slipped away quietly, and entered the sanctuary. The priest Eli was on duty at the entrance to GOD's Temple in the customary seat.</verse>
<verse>Crushed in soul, Hannah prayed to GOD and cried and cried--inconsolably.</verse>
<verse>Then she made a vow: Oh, GOD-of-the-Angel-Armies, If you'll take a good, hard look at my pain, If you'll quit neglecting me and go into action for me By giving me a son, I'll give him completely, unreservedly to you. I'll set him apart for a life of holy discipline.</verse>
<verse>It so happened that as she continued in prayer before GOD, Eli was watching her closely.</verse>
<verse>Hannah was praying in her heart, silently. Her lips moved, but no sound was heard. Eli jumped to the conclusion that she was drunk.</verse>
<verse>He approached her and said, "You're drunk! How long do you plan to keep this up? Sober up, woman!"</verse>
<verse>Hannah said, "Oh no, sir--please! I'm a woman hard used. I haven't been drinking. Not a drop of wine or beer. The only thing I've been pouring out is my heart, pouring it out to GOD.</verse>
<verse>Don't for a minute think I'm a bad woman. It's because I'm so desperately unhappy and in such pain that I've stayed here so long."</verse>
<verse>Eli answered her, "Go in peace. And may the God of Israel give you what you have asked of him."</verse>
<verse>"Think well of me--and pray for me!" she said, and went her way. Then she ate heartily, her face radiant.</verse>
<verse>Up before dawn, they worshiped GOD and returned home to Ramah. Elkanah slept with Hannah his wife, and GOD began making the necessary arrangements in response to what she had asked.</verse>
<verse>Before the year was out, Hannah had conceived and given birth to a son. She named him Samuel, explaining, "I asked GOD for him."</verse>
<verse>When Elkanah next took his family on their annual trip to Shiloh to worship GOD, offering sacrifices and keeping his vow,</verse>
<verse>Hannah didn't go. She told her husband, "After the child is weaned, I'll bring him myself and present him before GOD-and that's where he'll stay, for good."</verse>
<verse>Elkanah said to his wife, "Do what you think is best. Stay home until you have weaned him. Yes! Let GOD complete what he has begun!" So she did. She stayed home and nursed her son until she had weaned him.</verse>
<verse>Then she took him up to Shiloh, bringing also the makings of a generous sacrificial meal--a prize bull, flour, and wine. The child was so young to be sent off!</verse>
<verse>They first butchered the bull, then brought the child to Eli.</verse>
<verse>Hannah said, "Excuse me, sir. Would you believe that I'm the very woman who was standing before you at this very spot, praying to GOD?</verse>
<verse>I prayed for this child, and GOD gave me what I asked for.</verse>
<verse>And now I have dedicated him to GOD. He's dedicated to GOD for life." Then and there, they worshiped GOD.</verse>
</chapter>