<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="1 Samuel" book-id="9" n="16">
<verse>GOD addressed Samuel: "So, how long are you going to mope over Saul? You know I've rejected him as king over Israel. Fill your flask with anointing oil and get going. I'm sending you to Jesse of Bethlehem. I've spotted the very king I want among his sons."</verse>
<verse>"I can't do that," said Samuel. "Saul will hear about it and kill me." GOD said, "Take a heifer with you and announce, "I've come to lead you in worship of GOD, with this heifer as a sacrifice.'</verse>
<verse>Make sure Jesse gets invited. I'll let you know what to do next. I'll point out the one you are to anoint."</verse>
<verse>Samuel did what GOD told him. When he arrived at Bethlehem, the town fathers greeted him, but apprehensively. "Is there something wrong?"</verse>
<verse>"Nothing's wrong. I've come to sacrifice this heifer and lead you in the worship of GOD. Prepare yourselves, be consecrated, and join me in worship." He made sure Jesse and his sons were also consecrated and called to worship.</verse>
<verse>When they arrived, Samuel took one look at Eliab and thought, "Here he is! GOD's anointed!"</verse>
<verse>But GOD told Samuel, "Looks aren't everything. Don't be impressed with his looks and stature. I've already eliminated him. GOD judges persons differently than humans do. Men and women look at the face; GOD looks into the heart."</verse>
<verse>Jesse then called up Abinadab and presented him to Samuel. Samuel said, "This man isn't GOD's choice either."</verse>
<verse>Next Jesse presented Shammah. Samuel said, "No, this man isn't either."</verse>
<verse>Jesse presented his seven sons to Samuel. Samuel was blunt with Jesse, "GOD hasn't chosen any of these."</verse>
<verse>Then he asked Jesse, "Is this it? Are there no more sons?Well, yes, there's the runt. But he's out tending the sheep." Samuel ordered Jesse, "Go get him. We're not moving from this spot until he's here."</verse>
<verse>Jesse sent for him. He was brought in, the very picture of health--bright-eyed, good-looking. GOD said, "Up on your feet! Anoint him! This is the one."</verse>
<verse>Samuel took his flask of oil and anointed him, with his brothers standing around watching. The Spirit of GOD entered David like a rush of wind, God vitally empowering him for the rest of his life. Samuel left and went home to Ramah.</verse>
<verse>At that very moment the Spirit of GOD left Saul and in its place a black mood sent by GOD settled on him. He was terrified.</verse>
<verse>Saul's advisors said, "This awful tormenting depression from God is making your life miserable.</verse>
<verse>O master, let us help. Let us look for someone who can play the harp. When the black mood from God moves in, he'll play his music and you'll feel better."</verse>
<verse>Saul told his servants, "Go ahead. Find me someone who can play well and bring him to me."</verse>
<verse>One of the young men spoke up, "I know someone. I've seen him myself: the son of Jesse of Bethlehem, an excellent musician. He's also courageous, of age, well-spoken, and good-looking. And GOD is with him."</verse>
<verse>So Saul sent messengers to Jesse requesting, "Send your son David to me, the one who tends the sheep."</verse>
<verse>Jesse took a donkey, loaded it with a couple of loaves of bread, a flask of wine, and a young goat, and sent his son David with it to Saul.</verse>
<verse>David came to Saul and stood before him. Saul liked him immediately and made him his right-hand man.</verse>
<verse>Saul sent word back to Jesse: "Thank you. David will stay here. He's just the one I was looking for. I'm very impressed by him."</verse>
<verse>After that, whenever the bad depression from God tormented Saul, David got out his harp and played. That would calm Saul down, and he would feel better as the moodiness lifted.</verse>
</chapter>