<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Song of Solomon" book_id="22" n="2">
<verse>I am a rose of Sharon, a lily of the valleys.</verse>
<verse>Like a lily among thorns is my darling among the maidens.</verse>
<verse>Like an apple tree among the trees of the forest is my lover among the young men. I delight to sit in his shade, and his fruit is sweet to my taste.</verse>
<verse>He has taken me to the banquet hall, and his banner over me is love.</verse>
<verse>Strengthen me with raisins, refresh me with apples, for I am faint with love.</verse>
<verse>His left arm is under my head, and his right arm embraces me.</verse>
<verse>Daughters of Jerusalem, I charge you by the gazelles and by the does of the field: Do not arouse or awaken love until it so desires.</verse>
<verse>Listen! My lover! Look! Here he comes, leaping across the mountains, bounding over the hills.</verse>
<verse>My lover is like a gazelle or a young stag. Look! There he stands behind our wall, gazing through the windows, peering through the lattice.</verse>
<verse>My lover spoke and said to me, "Arise, my darling, my beautiful one, and come with me.</verse>
<verse>See! The winter is past; the rains are over and gone.</verse>
<verse>Flowers appear on the earth; the season of singing has come, the cooing of doves is heard in our land.</verse>
<verse>The fig tree forms its early fruit; the blossoming vines spread their fragrance. Arise, come, my darling; my beautiful one, come with me."</verse>
<verse>My dove in the clefts of the rock, in the hiding places on the mountainside, show me your face, let me hear your voice; for your voice is sweet, and your face is lovely.</verse>
<verse>Catch for us the foxes, the little foxes that ruin the vineyards, our vineyards that are in bloom.</verse>
<verse>My lover is mine and I am his; he browses among the lilies.</verse>
<verse>Until the day breaks and the shadows flee, turn, my lover, and be like a gazelle or like a young stag on the rugged hills.</verse>
</chapter>