<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Song of Solomon" book_id="22" n="8">
<verse>If only you were to me like a brother, who was nursed at my mother's breasts! Then, if I found you outside, I would kiss you, and no one would despise me.</verse>
<verse>I would lead you and bring you to my mother's house- she who has taught me. I would give you spiced wine to drink, the nectar of my pomegranates.</verse>
<verse>His left arm is under my head and his right arm embraces me.</verse>
<verse>Daughters of Jerusalem, I charge you: Do not arouse or awaken love until it so desires.</verse>
<verse>Who is this coming up from the desert leaning on her lover? Under the apple tree I roused you; there your mother conceived you, there she who was in labor gave you birth.</verse>
<verse>Place me like a seal over your heart, like a seal on your arm; for love is as strong as death, its jealousy unyielding as the grave. It burns like blazing fire, like a mighty flame.</verse>
<verse>Many waters cannot quench love; rivers cannot wash it away. If one were to give all the wealth of his house for love, it would be utterly scorned.</verse>
<verse>We have a young sister, and her breasts are not yet grown. What shall we do for our sister for the day she is spoken for?</verse>
<verse>If she is a wall, we will build towers of silver on her. If she is a door, we will enclose her with panels of cedar.</verse>
<verse>I am a wall, and my breasts are like towers. Thus I have become in his eyes like one bringing contentment.</verse>
<verse>Solomon had a vineyard in Baal Hamon; he let out his vineyard to tenants. Each was to bring for its fruit a thousand shekels of silver.</verse>
<verse>But my own vineyard is mine to give; the thousand shekels are for you, O Solomon, and two hundred are for those who tend its fruit.</verse>
<verse>You who dwell in the gardens with friends in attendance, let me hear your voice!</verse>
<verse>Come away, my lover, and be like a gazelle or like a young stag on the spice-laden mountains.</verse>
</chapter>