<?xml version="1.0"?>
<chapter translation="KJV" testament="Old" book="Proverbs" n="2" chapters="31">
      <verse>My son, if thou wilt receive my words, and hide my commandments with thee;
</verse><verse>So that thou incline thine ear unto wisdom, <supplied>and</supplied> apply thine heart to understanding;
</verse><verse>Yea, if thou criest after knowledge, <supplied>and</supplied> liftest up thy voice for understanding;
</verse><verse>If thou seekest her as silver, and searchest for her as <supplied>for</supplied> hid treasures;
</verse><verse>Then shalt thou understand the fear of the LORD, and find the knowledge of God.
</verse><verse>For the LORD giveth wisdom: out of his mouth <supplied>cometh</supplied> knowledge and understanding.
</verse><verse>He layeth up sound wisdom for the righteous: <supplied>he is</supplied> a buckler to them that walk uprightly.
</verse><verse>He keepeth the paths of judgment, and preserveth the way of his saints.
</verse><verse>Then shalt thou understand righteousness, and judgment, and equity; <supplied>yea,</supplied> every good path.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>When wisdom entereth into thine heart, and knowledge is pleasant unto thy soul;
</verse><verse>Discretion shall preserve thee, understanding shall keep thee:
</verse><verse>To deliver thee from the way of the evil <supplied>man,</supplied> from the man that speaketh froward things;
</verse><verse>Who leave the paths of uprightness, to walk in the ways of darkness;
</verse><verse>Who rejoice to do evil, <supplied>and</supplied> delight in the frowardness of the wicked;
</verse><verse>Whose ways <supplied>are</supplied> crooked, and <supplied>they</supplied> froward in their paths:
</verse><verse>To deliver thee from the strange woman, <supplied>even</supplied> from the stranger <supplied>which</supplied> flattereth with her words;
</verse><verse>Which forsaketh the guide of her youth, and forgetteth the covenant of her God.
</verse><verse>For her house inclineth unto death, and her paths unto the dead.
</verse><verse>None that go unto her return again, neither take they hold of the paths of life.
</verse><verse>That thou mayest walk in the way of good <supplied>men,</supplied> and keep the paths of the righteous.
</verse><verse>For the upright shall dwell in the land, and the perfect shall remain in it.
</verse><verse>But the wicked shall be cut off from the earth, and the transgressors shall be rooted out of it.
     
      </verse>
      </chapter>
