<chapter translation="KJV" testament="Old" book="PRO" n="28">
      <verse>The wicked flee when no man pursueth: but the righteous are bold as a lion.
</verse><verse>For the transgression of a land many <supplied>are</supplied> the princes thereof: but by a man of understanding <supplied>and</supplied> knowledge the state <supplied>thereof</supplied> shall be prolonged.
</verse><verse>A poor man that oppresseth the poor <supplied>is like</supplied> a sweeping rain which leaveth no food.
</verse><verse>They that forsake the law praise the wicked: but such as keep the law contend with them.
</verse><verse>Evil men understand not judgment: but they that seek the LORD understand all <supplied>things. </supplied></verse><verse>Better <supplied>is</supplied> the poor that walketh in his uprightness, than <supplied>he that is</supplied> perverse <supplied>in his</supplied> ways, though he <supplied>be</supplied> rich.
</verse><verse>Whoso keepeth the law <supplied>is</supplied> a wise son: but he that is a companion of riotous <supplied>men</supplied> shameth his father.
</verse><verse>He that by usury and unjust gain increaseth his substance, he shall gather it for him that will pity the poor.
</verse><verse>He that turneth away his ear from hearing the law, even his prayer <supplied>shall be</supplied> abomination.
</verse><verse>Whoso causeth the righteous to go astray in an evil way, he shall fall himself into his own pit: but the upright shall have good <supplied>things</supplied> in possession.
</verse><verse>The rich man <supplied>is</supplied> wise in his own conceit; but the poor that hath understanding searcheth him out.
</verse><verse>When righteous <supplied>men</supplied> do rejoice, <supplied>there is</supplied> great glory: but when the wicked rise, a man is hidden.
</verse><verse>He that covereth his sins shall not prosper: but whoso confesseth and forsaketh <supplied>them</supplied> shall have mercy.
</verse><verse>Happy <supplied>is</supplied> the man that feareth alway: but he that hardeneth his heart shall fall into mischief.
</verse><verse><supplied>As</supplied> a roaring lion, and a ranging bear; <supplied>so is</supplied> a wicked ruler over the poor people.
</verse><verse>The prince that wanteth understanding <supplied>is</supplied> also a great oppressor: <supplied>but</supplied> he that hateth covetousness shall prolong <supplied>his</supplied> days.
</verse><verse>A man that doeth violence to the blood of <supplied>any</supplied> person shall flee to the pit; let no man stay him.
</verse><verse>Whoso walketh uprightly shall be saved: but <supplied>he that is</supplied> perverse <supplied>in his</supplied> ways shall fall at once.
</verse><verse>He that tilleth his land shall have plenty of bread: but he that followeth after vain <supplied>persons</supplied> shall have poverty enough.
</verse><verse>A faithful man shall abound with blessings: but he that maketh haste to be rich shall not be innocent.
</verse><verse>To have respect of persons <supplied>is</supplied> not good: for for a piece of bread <supplied>that</supplied> man will transgress.
</verse><verse>He that hasteth to be rich <supplied>hath</supplied> an evil eye, and considereth not that poverty shall come upon him.
</verse><verse>He that rebuketh a man afterwards shall find more favour than he that flattereth with the tongue.
</verse><verse>Whoso robbeth his father or his mother, and saith, <supplied>It is</supplied> no transgression; the same <supplied>is</supplied> the companion of a destroyer.
</verse><verse>He that is of a proud heart stirreth up strife: but he that putteth his trust in the LORD shall be made fat.
</verse><verse>He that trusteth in his own heart is a fool: but whoso walketh wisely, he shall be delivered.
</verse><verse>He that giveth unto the poor shall not lack: but he that hideth his eyes shall have many a curse.
</verse><verse>When the wicked rise, men hide themselves: but when they perish, the righteous increase.
     
      </verse>
      </chapter>