<chapter translation="NASB" testament="New" book="Mark" book-id="41" n="1">
<verse>The beginning of the gospel of Jesus Christ, the Son of God.</verse>
<verse>As it is written in Isaiah the prophet: "BEHOLD, I SEND MY MESSENGER AHEAD OF YOU, WHO WILL PREPARE YOUR WAY;</verse>
<verse>THE VOICE OF ONE CRYING IN THE WILDERNESS, 'MAKE READY THE WAY OF THE LORD, MAKE HIS PATHS STRAIGHT.'"</verse>
<verse>John the Baptist appeared in the wilderness preaching a baptism of repentance for the forgiveness of sins.</verse>
<verse>And all the country of Judea was going out to him, and all the people of Jerusalem; and they were being baptized by him in the Jordan River, confessing their sins.</verse>
<verse>John was clothed with camel's hair and wore a leather belt around his waist, and his diet was locusts and wild honey.</verse>
<verse>And he was preaching, and saying, "After me One is coming who is mightier than I, and I am not fit to stoop down and untie the thong of His sandals.</verse>
<verse>"I baptized you with water; but He will baptize you with the Holy Spirit."</verse>
<verse>In those days Jesus came from Nazareth in Galilee and was baptized by John in the Jordan.</verse>
<verse>Immediately coming up out of the water, He saw the heavens opening, and the Spirit like a dove descending upon Him;</verse>
<verse>and a voice came out of the heavens: "You are My beloved Son, in You I am well-pleased."</verse>
<verse>Immediately the Spirit impelled Him to go out into the wilderness.</verse>
<verse>And He was in the wilderness forty days being tempted by Satan; and He was with the wild beasts, and the angels were ministering to Him.</verse>
<verse>Now after John had been taken into custody, Jesus came into Galilee, preaching the gospel of God,</verse>
<verse>and saying, "The time is fulfilled, and the kingdom of God is at hand; repent and believe in the gospel."</verse>
<verse>As He was going along by the Sea of Galilee, He saw Simon and Andrew, the brother of Simon, casting a net in the sea; for they were fishermen.</verse>
<verse>And Jesus said to them, "Follow Me, and I will make you become fishers of men."</verse>
<verse>Immediately they left their nets and followed Him.</verse>
<verse>Going on a little farther, He saw James the son of Zebedee, and John his brother, who were also in the boat mending the nets.</verse>
<verse>Immediately He called them; and they left their father Zebedee in the boat with the hired servants, and went away to follow Him.</verse>
<verse>They went into Capernaum; and immediately on the Sabbath He entered the synagogue and began to teach.</verse>
<verse>They were amazed at His teaching; for He was teaching them as one having authority, and not as the scribes.</verse>
<verse>Just then there was a man in their synagogue with an unclean spirit; and he cried out,</verse>
<verse>saying, "What business do we have with each other, Jesus of Nazareth? Have You come to destroy us? I know who You are--the Holy One of God!"</verse>
<verse>And Jesus rebuked him, saying, "Be quiet, and come out of him!"</verse>
<verse>Throwing him into convulsions, the unclean spirit cried out with a loud voice and came out of him.</verse>
<verse>They were all amazed, so that they debated among themselves, saying, "What is this? A new teaching with authority! He commands even the unclean spirits, and they obey Him."</verse>
<verse>Immediately the news about Him spread everywhere into all the surrounding district of Galilee.</verse>
<verse>And immediately after they came out of the synagogue, they came into the house of Simon and Andrew, with James and John.</verse>
<verse>Now Simon's mother-in-law was lying sick with a fever; and immediately they spoke to Jesus about her.</verse>
<verse>And He came to her and raised her up, taking her by the hand, and the fever left her, and she waited on them.</verse>
<verse>When evening came, after the sun had set, they began bringing to Him all who were ill and those who were demon-possessed.</verse>
<verse>And the whole city had gathered at the door.</verse>
<verse>And He healed many who were ill with various diseases, and cast out many demons; and He was not permitting the demons to speak, because they knew who He was.</verse>
<verse>In the early morning, while it was still dark, Jesus got up, left the house, and went away to a secluded place, and was praying there.</verse>
<verse>Simon and his companions searched for Him;</verse>
<verse>they found Him, and said to Him, "Everyone is looking for You."</verse>
<verse>He said to them, "Let us go somewhere else to the towns nearby, so that I may preach there also; for that is what I came for."</verse>
<verse>And He went into their synagogues throughout all Galilee, preaching and casting out the demons.</verse>
<verse>And a leper came to Jesus, beseeching Him and falling on his knees before Him, and saying, "If You are willing, You can make me clean."</verse>
<verse>Moved with compassion, Jesus stretched out His hand and touched him, and said to him, "I am willing; be cleansed."</verse>
<verse>Immediately the leprosy left him and he was cleansed.</verse>
<verse>And He sternly warned him and immediately sent him away,</verse>
<verse>and He said to him, "See that you say nothing to anyone; but go, show yourself to the priest and offer for your cleansing what Moses commanded, as a testimony to them."</verse>
<verse>But he went out and began to proclaim it freely and to spread the news around, to such an extent that Jesus could no longer publicly enter a city, but stayed out in unpopulated areas; and they were coming to Him from everywhere.</verse>
</chapter>