<chapter translation="NASB" testament="New" book="Mark" book_id="41" n="4">
<verse>He began to teach again by the sea. And such a very large crowd gathered to Him that He got into a boat in the sea and sat down; and the whole crowd was by the sea on the land.</verse>
<verse>And He was teaching them many things in parables, and was saying to them in His teaching,</verse>
<verse>"Listen to this! Behold, the sower went out to sow;</verse>
<verse>as he was sowing, some seed fell beside the road, and the birds came and ate it up.</verse>
<verse>"Other seed fell on the rocky ground where it did not have much soil; and immediately it sprang up because it had no depth of soil.</verse>
<verse>"And after the sun had risen, it was scorched; and because it had no root, it withered away.</verse>
<verse>"Other seed fell among the thorns, and the thorns came up and choked it, and it yielded no crop.</verse>
<verse>"Other seeds fell into the good soil, and as they grew up and increased, they yielded a crop and produced thirty, sixty, and a hundredfold."</verse>
<verse>And He was saying, "He who has ears to hear, let him hear."</verse>
<verse>As soon as He was alone, His followers, along with the twelve, began asking Him about the parables.</verse>
<verse>And He was saying to them, "To you has been given the mystery of the kingdom of God, but those who are outside get everything in parables,</verse>
<verse>so that WHILE SEEING, THEY MAY SEE AND NOT PERCEIVE, AND WHILE HEARING, THEY MAY HEAR AND NOT UNDERSTAND, OTHERWISE THEY MIGHT RETURN AND BE FORGIVEN."</verse>
<verse>And He said to them, "Do you not understand this parable? How will you understand all the parables?</verse>
<verse>"The sower sows the word.</verse>
<verse>"These are the ones who are beside the road where the word is sown; and when they hear, immediately Satan comes and takes away the word which has been sown in them.</verse>
<verse>"In a similar way these are the ones on whom seed was sown on the rocky places, who, when they hear the word, immediately receive it with joy;</verse>
<verse>and they have no firm root in themselves, but are only temporary; then, when affliction or persecution arises because of the word, immediately they fall away.</verse>
<verse>"And others are the ones on whom seed was sown among the thorns; these are the ones who have heard the word,</verse>
<verse>but the worries of the world, and the deceitfulness of riches, and the desires for other things enter in and choke the word, and it becomes unfruitful.</verse>
<verse>"And those are the ones on whom seed was sown on the good soil; and they hear the word and accept it and bear fruit, thirty, sixty, and a hundredfold."</verse>
<verse>And He was saying to them, "A lamp is not brought to be put under a basket, is it, or under a bed? Is it not brought to be put on the lampstand?</verse>
<verse>"For nothing is hidden, except to be revealed; nor has anything been secret, but that it would come to light.</verse>
<verse>"If anyone has ears to hear, let him hear."</verse>
<verse>And He was saying to them, "Take care what you listen to. By your standard of measure it will be measured to you; and more will be given you besides.</verse>
<verse>"For whoever has, to him more shall be given; and whoever does not have, even what he has shall be taken away from him."</verse>
<verse>And He was saying, "The kingdom of God is like a man who casts seed upon the soil;</verse>
<verse>and he goes to bed at night and gets up by day, and the seed sprouts and grows--how, he himself does not know.</verse>
<verse>"The soil produces crops by itself; first the blade, then the head, then the mature grain in the head.</verse>
<verse>"But when the crop permits, he immediately puts in the sickle, because the harvest has come."</verse>
<verse>And He said, "How shall we picture the kingdom of God, or by what parable shall we present it?</verse>
<verse>"It is like a mustard seed, which, when sown upon the soil, though it is smaller than all the seeds that are upon the soil,</verse>
<verse>yet when it is sown, it grows up and becomes larger than all the garden plants and forms large branches; so that THE BIRDS OF THE AIR can NEST UNDER ITS SHADE."</verse>
<verse>With many such parables He was speaking the word to them, so far as they were able to hear it;</verse>
<verse>and He did not speak to them without a parable; but He was explaining everything privately to His own disciples.</verse>
<verse>On that day, when evening came, He said to them, "Let us go over to the other side."</verse>
<verse>Leaving the crowd, they took Him along with them in the boat, just as He was; and other boats were with Him.</verse>
<verse>And there arose a fierce gale of wind, and the waves were breaking over the boat so much that the boat was already filling up.</verse>
<verse>Jesus Himself was in the stern, asleep on the cushion; and they woke Him and said to Him, "Teacher, do You not care that we are perishing?"</verse>
<verse>And He got up and rebuked the wind and said to the sea, "Hush, be still." And the wind died down and it became perfectly calm.</verse>
<verse>And He said to them, "Why are you afraid? Do you still have no faith?"</verse>
<verse>They became very much afraid and said to one another, "Who then is this, that even the wind and the sea obey Him?"</verse>
</chapter>