<chapter translation="KJV" testament="New" book="2PE" n="3">
      <verse>This second epistle, beloved, I now write unto you; in <supplied>both</supplied> which I stir up your pure minds by way of remembrance:
</verse><verse>That ye may be mindful of the words which were spoken before by the holy prophets, and of the commandment of us the apostles of the Lord and Saviour:
</verse><verse>Knowing this first, that there shall come in the last days scoffers, walking after their own lusts,
</verse><verse>And saying, Where is the promise of his coming? for since the fathers fell asleep, all things continue as <supplied>they were</supplied> from the beginning of the creation.
</verse><verse>For this they willingly are ignorant of, that by the word of God the heavens were of old, and the earth standing out of the water and in the water:
</verse><verse>Whereby the world that then was, being overflowed with water, perished:
</verse><verse>But the heavens and the earth, which are now, by the same word are kept in store, reserved unto fire against the day of judgment and perdition of ungodly men.
</verse><verse>But, beloved, be not ignorant of this one thing, that one day <supplied>is</supplied> with the Lord as a thousand years, and a thousand years as one day.
</verse><verse>The Lord is not slack concerning his promise, as some men count slackness; but is longsuffering to us-ward, not willing that any should perish, but that all should come to repentance.
</verse><verse>But the day of the Lord will come as a thief in the night; in the which the heavens shall pass away with a great noise, and the elements shall melt with fervent heat, the earth also and the works that are therein shall be burned up.
</verse><verse><supplied>Seeing</supplied> then <supplied>that</supplied> all these things shall be dissolved, what manner <supplied>of persons</supplied> ought ye to be in <supplied>all</supplied> holy conversation and godliness,
</verse><verse>Looking for and hasting unto the coming of the day of God, wherein the heavens being on fire shall be dissolved, and the elements shall melt with fervent heat?
</verse><verse>Nevertheless we, according to his promise, look for new heavens and a new earth, wherein dwelleth righteousness.
</verse><verse>Wherefore, beloved, seeing that ye look for such things, be diligent that ye may be found of him in peace, without spot, and blameless.
</verse><verse>And account <supplied>that</supplied> the longsuffering of our Lord <supplied>is</supplied> salvation; even as our beloved brother Paul also according to the wisdom given unto him hath written unto you;
</verse><verse>As also in all <supplied>his</supplied> epistles, speaking in them of these things; in which are some things hard to be understood, which they that are unlearned and unstable wrest, as <supplied>they do</supplied> also the other scriptures, unto their own destruction.
</verse><verse>Ye therefore, beloved, seeing ye know <supplied>these things</supplied> before, beware lest ye also, being led away with the error of the wicked, fall from your own stedfastness.
</verse><verse>But grow in grace, and <supplied>in</supplied> the knowledge of our Lord and Saviour Jesus Christ. To him <supplied>be</supplied> glory both now and for ever. Amen.
     
     
      </verse>
      </chapter>