<?xml version="1.0"?>
<chapter translation="KJV" testament="Old" book="Psalm" n="103">
      A <supplied>Psalm</supplied> of David.
      
      
      
       
        <verse>Bless the LORD, O my soul: and all that is within me, <supplied>bless</supplied> his holy name.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Bless the LORD, O my soul, and forget not all his benefits:
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Who forgiveth all thine iniquities; who healeth all thy diseases;
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Who redeemeth thy life from destruction; who crowneth thee with lovingkindness and tender mercies;
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Who satisfieth thy mouth with good <supplied>things; so that</supplied> thy youth is renewed like the eagle&#x2019;s.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>The LORD executeth righteousness and judgment for all that are oppressed.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>He made known his ways unto Moses, his acts unto the children of Israel.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>The LORD <supplied>is</supplied> merciful and gracious, slow to anger, and plenteous in mercy.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>He will not always chide: neither will he keep <supplied>his anger</supplied> for ever.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>He hath not dealt with us after our sins; nor rewarded us according to our iniquities.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>For as the heaven is high above the earth, <supplied>so</supplied> great is his mercy toward them that fear him.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>As far as the east is from the west, <supplied>so</supplied> far hath he removed our transgressions from us.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Like as a father pitieth <supplied>his</supplied> children, <supplied>so</supplied> the LORD pitieth them that fear him.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>For he knoweth our frame; he remembereth that we <supplied>are</supplied> dust.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>
        <supplied>As for</supplied> man, his days <supplied>are</supplied> as grass: as a flower of the field, so he flourisheth.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>For the wind passeth over it, and it is gone; and the place thereof shall know it no more.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>But the mercy of the LORD <supplied>is</supplied> from everlasting to everlasting upon them that fear him, and his righteousness unto children&#x2019;s children;
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>To such as keep his covenant, and to those that remember his commandments to do them.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>The LORD hath prepared his throne in the heavens; and his kingdom ruleth over all.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Bless the LORD, ye his angels, that excel in strength, that do his commandments, hearkening unto the voice of his word.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Bless ye the LORD, all <supplied>ye</supplied> his hosts; <supplied>ye</supplied> ministers of his, that do his pleasure.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Bless the LORD, all his works in all places of his dominion: bless the LORD, O my soul.
      
      
       
      
      
       
        </verse>
        </chapter>
