<?xml version="1.0"?>
<chapter translation="KJV" testament="Old" book="Psalm" n="115">
      
       
        <verse>Not unto us, O LORD, not unto us, but unto thy name give glory, for thy mercy, <supplied>and</supplied> for thy truth&#x2019;s sake.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Wherefore should the heathen say, Where <supplied>is</supplied> now their God?
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>But our God <supplied>is</supplied> in the heavens: he hath done whatsoever he hath pleased.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Their idols <supplied>are</supplied> silver and gold, the work of men&#x2019;s hands.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>They have mouths, but they speak not: eyes have they, but they see not:
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>They have ears, but they hear not: noses have they, but they smell not:
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>They have hands, but they handle not: feet have they, but they walk not: neither speak they through their throat.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>They that make them are like unto them; <supplied>so is</supplied> every one that trusteth in them.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>O Israel, trust thou in the LORD: he <supplied>is</supplied> their help and their shield.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>O house of Aaron, trust in the LORD: he <supplied>is</supplied> their help and their shield.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Ye that fear the LORD, trust in the LORD: he <supplied>is</supplied> their help and their shield.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>The LORD hath been mindful of us: he will bless <supplied>us;</supplied> he will bless the house of Israel; he will bless the house of Aaron.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>He will bless them that fear the LORD, <supplied>both</supplied> small and great.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>The LORD shall increase you more and more, you and your children.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Ye <supplied>are</supplied> blessed of the LORD which made heaven and earth.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>The heaven, <supplied>even</supplied> the heavens, <supplied>are</supplied> the LORD&#x2019;S: but the earth hath he given to the children of men.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>The dead praise not the LORD, neither any that go down into silence.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>But we will bless the LORD from this time forth and for evermore. Praise the LORD.
      
      
       
      
      
       
        </verse>
        </chapter>
