<?xml version="1.0"?>
<chapter translation="KJV" testament="Old" book="Psalm" n="116">
      
       
        <verse>I love the LORD, because he hath heard my voice <supplied>and</supplied> my supplications.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Because he hath inclined his ear unto me, therefore will I call upon <supplied>him</supplied> as long as I live.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>The sorrows of death compassed me, and the pains of hell gat hold upon me: I found trouble and sorrow.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Then called I upon the name of the LORD; O LORD, I beseech thee, deliver my soul.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Gracious <supplied>is</supplied> the LORD, and righteous; yea, our God <supplied>is</supplied> merciful.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>The LORD preserveth the simple: I was brought low, and he helped me.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Return unto thy rest, O my soul; for the LORD hath dealt bountifully with thee.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>For thou hast delivered my soul from death, mine eyes from tears, <supplied>and</supplied> my feet from falling.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>I will walk before the LORD in the land of the living.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>I believed, therefore have I spoken: I was greatly afflicted:
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>I said in my haste, All men <supplied>are</supplied> liars.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>What shall I render unto the LORD <supplied>for</supplied> all his benefits toward me?
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>I will take the cup of salvation, and call upon the name of the LORD.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>I will pay my vows unto the LORD now in the presence of all his people.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Precious in the sight of the LORD <supplied>is</supplied> the death of his saints.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>O LORD, truly I <supplied>am</supplied> thy servant; I <supplied>am</supplied> thy servant, <supplied>and</supplied> the son of thine handmaid: thou hast loosed my bonds.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>I will offer to thee the sacrifice of thanksgiving, and will call upon the name of the LORD.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>I will pay my vows unto the LORD now in the presence of all his people,
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>In the courts of the LORD&#x2019;S house, in the midst of thee, O Jerusalem. Praise ye the LORD.
      
      
       
      
      
       
        </verse>
        </chapter>
