<?xml version="1.0"?>
<chapter translation="KJV" testament="Old" book="Psalm" n="148" chapters="150">
      
       
        <verse>Praise ye the LORD. Praise ye the LORD from the heavens: praise him in the heights.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Praise ye him, all his angels: praise ye him, all his hosts.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Praise ye him, sun and moon: praise him, all ye stars of light.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Praise him, ye heavens of heavens, and ye waters that <supplied>be</supplied> above the heavens.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Let them praise the name of the LORD: for he commanded, and they were created.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>He hath also stablished them for ever and ever: he hath made a decree which shall not pass.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Praise the LORD from the earth, ye dragons, and all deeps:
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Fire, and hail; snow, and vapours; stormy wind fulfilling his word:
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Mountains, and all hills; fruitful trees, and all cedars:
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Beasts, and all cattle; creeping things, and flying fowl:
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Kings of the earth, and all people; princes, and all judges of the earth:
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Both young men, and maidens; old men, and children:
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Let them praise the name of the LORD: for his name alone is excellent; his glory <supplied>is</supplied> above the earth and heaven.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>He also exalteth the horn of his people, the praise of all his saints; <supplied>even</supplied> of the children of Israel, a people near unto him. Praise ye the LORD.
      
      
       
      
      
       
        </verse>
        </chapter>
