<?xml version="1.0"?>
<chapter translation="KJV" testament="Old" book="Psalm" n="16" book-chapters="150">
      Michtam of David.
      
      
      
       
        <verse>Preserve me, O God: for in thee do I put my trust.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>
        <supplied>O my soul,</supplied> thou hast said unto the LORD, Thou <supplied>art</supplied> my Lord: my goodness <supplied>extendeth</supplied> not to thee;
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>
        <supplied>But</supplied> to the saints that <supplied>are</supplied> in the earth, and <supplied>to</supplied> the excellent, in whom <supplied>is</supplied> all my delight.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Their sorrows shall be multiplied <supplied>that</supplied> hasten <supplied>after</supplied> another <supplied>god:</supplied> their drink offerings of blood will I not offer, nor take up their names into my lips.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>The LORD <supplied>is</supplied> the portion of mine inheritance and of my cup: thou maintainest my lot.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>The lines are fallen unto me in pleasant <supplied>places;</supplied> yea, I have a goodly heritage.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>I will bless the LORD, who hath given me counsel: my reins also instruct me in the night seasons.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>I have set the LORD always before me: because <supplied>he is</supplied> at my right hand, I shall not be moved.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Therefore my heart is glad, and my glory rejoiceth: my flesh also shall rest in hope.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>For thou wilt not leave my soul in hell; neither wilt thou suffer thine Holy One to see corruption.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Thou wilt shew me the path of life: in thy presence <supplied>is</supplied> fulness of joy; at thy right hand <supplied>there are</supplied> pleasures for evermore.
      
      
       
      
      
       
        </verse>
        </chapter>
