<?xml version="1.0"?>
<chapter translation="KJV" testament="Old" book="Psalm" n="19" chapters="150">
      To the chief Musician, A Psalm of David.
      
      
      
       
        <verse>The heavens declare the glory of God; and the firmament sheweth his handywork.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Day unto day uttereth speech, and night unto night sheweth knowledge.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>
        <supplied>There is</supplied> no speech nor language, <supplied>where</supplied> their voice is not heard.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Their line is gone out through all the earth, and their words to the end of the world. In them hath he set a tabernacle for the sun,
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Which <supplied>is</supplied> as a bridegroom coming out of his chamber, <supplied>and</supplied> rejoiceth as a strong man to run a race.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>His going forth <supplied>is</supplied> from the end of the heaven, and his circuit unto the ends of it: and there is nothing hid from the heat thereof.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>The law of the LORD <supplied>is</supplied> perfect, converting the soul: the testimony of the LORD <supplied>is</supplied> sure, making wise the simple.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>The statutes of the LORD <supplied>are</supplied> right, rejoicing the heart: the commandment of the LORD <supplied>is</supplied> pure, enlightening the eyes.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>The fear of the LORD <supplied>is</supplied> clean, enduring for ever: the judgments of the LORD <supplied>are</supplied> true <supplied>and</supplied> righteous altogether.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>More to be desired <supplied>are they</supplied> than gold, yea, than much fine gold: sweeter also than honey and the honeycomb.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Moreover by them is thy servant warned: <supplied>and</supplied> in keeping of them <supplied>there is</supplied> great reward.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Who can understand <supplied>his</supplied> errors? cleanse thou me from secret <supplied>faults.</supplied>
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Keep back thy servant also from presumptuous <supplied>sins;</supplied> let them not have dominion over me: then shall I be upright, and I shall be innocent from the great transgression.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Let the words of my mouth, and the meditation of my heart, be acceptable in thy sight, O LORD, my strength, and my redeemer.
      
      
       
      
      
       
        </verse>
        </chapter>
