<?xml version="1.0"?>
<chapter translation="KJV" testament="Old" book="Psalm" n="73">
      A Psalm of Asaph.
      
      
      
       
        <verse>Truly God <supplied>is</supplied> good to Israel, <supplied>even</supplied> to such as are of a clean heart.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>But as for me, my feet were almost gone; my steps had well nigh slipped.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>For I was envious at the foolish, <supplied>when</supplied> I saw the prosperity of the wicked.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>For <supplied>there are</supplied> no bands in their death: but their strength <supplied>is</supplied> firm.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>They <supplied>are</supplied> not in trouble <supplied>as other</supplied> men; neither are they plagued like <supplied>other</supplied> men.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Therefore pride compasseth them about as a chain; violence covereth them <supplied>as</supplied> a garment.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Their eyes stand out with fatness: they have more than heart could wish.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>They are corrupt, and speak wickedly <supplied>concerning</supplied> oppression: they speak loftily.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>They set their mouth against the heavens, and their tongue walketh through the earth.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Therefore his people return hither: and waters of a full <supplied>cup</supplied> are wrung out to them.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>And they say, How doth God know? and is there knowledge in the most High?
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Behold, these <supplied>are</supplied> the ungodly, who prosper in the world; they increase <supplied>in</supplied> riches.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Verily I have cleansed my heart <supplied>in</supplied> vain, and washed my hands in innocency.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>For all the day long have I been plagued, and chastened every morning.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>If I say, I will speak thus; behold, I should offend <supplied>against</supplied> the generation of thy children.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>When I thought to know this, it <supplied>was</supplied> too painful for me;
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Until I went into the sanctuary of God; <supplied>then</supplied> understood I their end.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Surely thou didst set them in slippery places: thou castedst them down into destruction.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>How are they <supplied>brought</supplied> into desolation, as in a moment! they are utterly consumed with terrors.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>As a dream when <supplied>one</supplied> awaketh; <supplied>so,</supplied> O Lord, when thou awakest, thou shalt despise their image.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Thus my heart was grieved, and I was pricked in my reins.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>So foolish <supplied>was</supplied> I, and ignorant: I was <supplied>as</supplied> a beast before thee.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Nevertheless I <supplied>am</supplied> continually with thee: thou hast holden <supplied>me</supplied> by my right hand.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Thou shalt guide me with thy counsel, and afterward receive me <supplied>to</supplied> glory.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>Whom have I in heaven <supplied>but thee?</supplied> and <supplied>there is</supplied> none upon earth <supplied>that</supplied> I desire beside thee.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>My flesh and my heart faileth: <supplied>but</supplied> God <supplied>is</supplied> the strength of my heart, and my portion for ever.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>For, lo, they that are far from thee shall perish: thou hast destroyed all them that go a whoring from thee.
      
      
       
        </verse>
        <verse>But <supplied>it is</supplied> good for me to draw near to God: I have put my trust in the Lord GOD, that I may declare all thy works.
      
      
       
      
      
       
        </verse>
        </chapter>
