<chapter translation="NASB" testament="New" book="1 Timothy" book_id="54" n="1">
<verse>Paul, an apostle of Christ Jesus according to the commandment of God our Savior, and of Christ Jesus, who is our hope,</verse>
<verse>To Timothy, my true child in the faith: Grace, mercy and peace from God the Father and Christ Jesus our Lord.</verse>
<verse>As I urged you upon my departure for Macedonia, remain on at Ephesus so that you may instruct certain men not to teach strange doctrines,</verse>
<verse>nor to pay attention to myths and endless genealogies, which give rise to mere speculation rather than furthering the administration of God which is by faith.</verse>
<verse>But the goal of our instruction is love from a pure heart and a good conscience and a sincere faith.</verse>
<verse>For some men, straying from these things, have turned aside to fruitless discussion,</verse>
<verse>wanting to be teachers of the Law, even though they do not understand either what they are saying or the matters about which they make confident assertions.</verse>
<verse>But we know that the Law is good, if one uses it lawfully,</verse>
<verse>realizing the fact that law is not made for a righteous person, but for those who are lawless and rebellious, for the ungodly and sinners, for the unholy and profane, for those who kill their fathers or mothers, for murderers</verse>
<verse>and immoral men and homosexuals and kidnappers and liars and perjurers, and whatever else is contrary to sound teaching,</verse>
<verse>according to the glorious gospel of the blessed God, with which I have been entrusted.</verse>
<verse>I thank Christ Jesus our Lord, who has strengthened me, because He considered me faithful, putting me into service,</verse>
<verse>even though I was formerly a blasphemer and a persecutor and a violent aggressor. Yet I was shown mercy because I acted ignorantly in unbelief;</verse>
<verse>and the grace of our Lord was more than abundant, with the faith and love which are found in Christ Jesus.</verse>
<verse>It is a trustworthy statement, deserving full acceptance, that Christ Jesus came into the world to save sinners, among whom I am foremost of all.</verse>
<verse>Yet for this reason I found mercy, so that in me as the foremost, Jesus Christ might demonstrate His perfect patience as an example for those who would believe in Him for eternal life.</verse>
<verse>Now to the King eternal, immortal, invisible, the only God, be honor and glory forever and ever. Amen.</verse>
<verse>This command I entrust to you, Timothy, my son, in accordance with the prophecies previously made concerning you, that by them you fight the good fight,</verse>
<verse>keeping faith and a good conscience, which some have rejected and suffered shipwreck in regard to their faith.</verse>
<verse>Among these are Hymenaeus and Alexander, whom I have handed over to Satan, so that they will be taught not to blaspheme.</verse>
</chapter>