<chapter translation="NASB" testament="New" book="1 Timothy" book_id="54" n="4">
<verse>But the Spirit explicitly says that in later times some will fall away from the faith, paying attention to deceitful spirits and doctrines of demons,</verse>
<verse>by means of the hypocrisy of liars seared in their own conscience as with a branding iron,</verse>
<verse>men who forbid marriage and advocate abstaining from foods which God has created to be gratefully shared in by those who believe and know the truth.</verse>
<verse>For everything created by God is good, and nothing is to be rejected if it is received with gratitude;</verse>
<verse>for it is sanctified by means of the word of God and prayer.</verse>
<verse>In pointing out these things to the brethren, you will be a good servant of Christ Jesus, constantly nourished on the words of the faith and of the sound doctrine which you have been following.</verse>
<verse>But have nothing to do with worldly fables fit only for old women. On the other hand, discipline yourself for the purpose of godliness;</verse>
<verse>for bodily discipline is only of little profit, but godliness is profitable for all things, since it holds promise for the present life and also for the life to come.</verse>
<verse>It is a trustworthy statement deserving full acceptance.</verse>
<verse>For it is for this we labor and strive, because we have fixed our hope on the living God, who is the Savior of all men, especially of believers.</verse>
<verse>Prescribe and teach these things.</verse>
<verse>Let no one look down on your youthfulness, but rather in speech, conduct, love, faith and purity, show yourself an example of those who believe.</verse>
<verse>Until I come, give attention to the public reading of Scripture, to exhortation and teaching.</verse>
<verse>Do not neglect the spiritual gift within you, which was bestowed on you through prophetic utterance with the laying on of hands by the presbytery.</verse>
<verse>Take pains with these things; be absorbed in them, so that your progress will be evident to all.</verse>
<verse>Pay close attention to yourself and to your teaching; persevere in these things, for as you do this you will ensure salvation both for yourself and for those who hear you.</verse>
</chapter>