<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Jeremiah" book_id="24" n="30">
<verse>This is the word that came to Jeremiah from the LORD:</verse>
<verse>"This is what the LORD, the God of Israel, says: 'Write in a book all the words I have spoken to you.</verse>
<verse>The days are coming,' declares the LORD, 'when I will bring my people Israel and Judah back from captivity and restore them to the land I gave their forefathers to possess,' says the LORD."</verse>
<verse>These are the words the LORD spoke concerning Israel and Judah:</verse>
<verse>"This is what the LORD says: "'Cries of fear are heard- terror, not peace.</verse>
<verse>Ask and see: Can a man bear children? Then why do I see every strong man with his hands on his stomach like a woman in labor, every face turned deathly pale?</verse>
<verse>How awful that day will be! None will be like it. It will be a time of trouble for Jacob, but he will be saved out of it.</verse>
<verse>"'In that day,' declares the LORD Almighty, 'I will break the yoke off their necks and will tear off their bonds; no longer will foreigners enslave them.</verse>
<verse>Instead, they will serve the LORD their God and David their king, whom I will raise up for them.</verse>
<verse>"'So do not fear, O Jacob my servant; do not be dismayed, O Israel,' declares the LORD. 'I will surely save you out of a distant place, your descendants from the land of their exile. Jacob will again have peace and security, and no one will make him afraid.</verse>
<verse>I am with you and will save you,' declares the LORD. 'Though I completely destroy all the nations among which I scatter you, I will not completely destroy you. I will discipline you but only with justice; I will not let you go entirely unpunished.'</verse>
<verse>"This is what the LORD says: "'Your wound is incurable, your injury beyond healing.</verse>
<verse>There is no one to plead your cause, no remedy for your sore, no healing for you.</verse>
<verse>All your allies have forgotten you; they care nothing for you. I have struck you as an enemy would and punished you as would the cruel, because your guilt is so great and your sins so many.</verse>
<verse>Why do you cry out over your wound, your pain that has no cure? Because of your great guilt and many sins I have done these things to you.</verse>
<verse>"'But all who devour you will be devoured; all your enemies will go into exile. Those who plunder you will be plundered; all who make spoil of you I will despoil.</verse>
<verse>But I will restore you to health and heal your wounds,' declares the LORD, 'because you are called an outcast, Zion for whom no one cares.'</verse>
<verse>"This is what the LORD says: "'I will restore the fortunes of Jacob's tents and have compassion on his dwellings; the city will be rebuilt on her ruins, and the palace will stand in its proper place.</verse>
<verse>From them will come songs of thanksgiving and the sound of rejoicing. I will add to their numbers, and they will not be decreased; I will bring them honor, and they will not be disdained.</verse>
<verse>Their children will be as in days of old, and their community will be established before me; I will punish all who oppress them.</verse>
<verse>Their leader will be one of their own; their ruler will arise from among them. I will bring him near and he will come close to me, for who is he who will devote himself to be close to me?' declares the LORD.</verse>
<verse>"'So you will be my people, and I will be your God.'"</verse>
<verse>See, the storm of the LORD will burst out in wrath, a driving wind swirling down on the heads of the wicked.</verse>
<verse>The fierce anger of the LORD will not turn back until he fully accomplishes the purposes of his heart. In days to come you will understand this.</verse>
</chapter>