<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Jeremiah" book_id="24" n="48">
<verse>Concerning Moab: This is what the LORD Almighty, the God of Israel, says: "Woe to Nebo, for it will be ruined. Kiriathaim will be disgraced and captured; the stronghold will be disgraced and shattered.</verse>
<verse>Moab will be praised no more; in Heshbon men will plot her downfall: 'Come, let us put an end to that nation.' You too, O Madmen, will be silenced; the sword will pursue you.</verse>
<verse>Listen to the cries from Horonaim, cries of great havoc and destruction.</verse>
<verse>Moab will be broken; her little ones will cry out.</verse>
<verse>They go up the way to Luhith, weeping bitterly as they go; on the road down to Horonaim anguished cries over the destruction are heard.</verse>
<verse>Flee! Run for your lives; become like a bush in the desert.</verse>
<verse>Since you trust in your deeds and riches, you too will be taken captive, and Chemosh will go into exile, together with his priests and officials.</verse>
<verse>The destroyer will come against every town, and not a town will escape. The valley will be ruined and the plateau destroyed, because the LORD has spoken.</verse>
<verse>Put salt on Moab, for she will be laid waste; her towns will become desolate, with no one to live in them.</verse>
<verse>"A curse on him who is lax in doing the LORD's work! A curse on him who keeps his sword from bloodshed!</verse>
<verse>"Moab has been at rest from youth, like wine left on its dregs, not poured from one jar to another- she has not gone into exile. So she tastes as she did, and her aroma is unchanged.</verse>
<verse>But days are coming," declares the LORD, "when I will send men who pour from jars, and they will pour her out; they will empty her jars and smash her jugs.</verse>
<verse>Then Moab will be ashamed of Chemosh, as the house of Israel was ashamed when they trusted in Bethel.</verse>
<verse>"How can you say, 'We are warriors, men valiant in battle'?</verse>
<verse>Moab will be destroyed and her towns invaded; her finest young men will go down in the slaughter," declares the King, whose name is the LORD Almighty.</verse>
<verse>"The fall of Moab is at hand; her calamity will come quickly.</verse>
<verse>Mourn for her, all who live around her, all who know her fame; say, 'How broken is the mighty scepter, how broken the glorious staff!'</verse>
<verse>"Come down from your glory and sit on the parched ground, O inhabitants of the Daughter of Dibon, for he who destroys Moab will come up against you and ruin your fortified cities.</verse>
<verse>Stand by the road and watch, you who live in Aroer. Ask the man fleeing and the woman escaping, ask them, 'What has happened?'</verse>
<verse>Moab is disgraced, for she is shattered. Wail and cry out! Announce by the Arnon that Moab is destroyed.</verse>
<verse>Judgment has come to the plateau- to Holon, Jahzah and Mephaath,</verse>
<verse>to Dibon, Nebo and Beth Diblathaim,</verse>
<verse>to Kiriathaim, Beth Gamul and Beth Meon,</verse>
<verse>to Kerioth and Bozrah- to all the towns of Moab, far and near.</verse>
<verse>Moab's horn is cut off; her arm is broken," declares the LORD.</verse>
<verse>"Make her drunk, for she has defied the LORD. Let Moab wallow in her vomit; let her be an object of ridicule.</verse>
<verse>Was not Israel the object of your ridicule? Was she caught among thieves, that you shake your head in scorn whenever you speak of her?</verse>
<verse>Abandon your towns and dwell among the rocks, you who live in Moab. Be like a dove that makes its nest at the mouth of a cave.</verse>
<verse>"We have heard of Moab's pride- her overweening pride and conceit, her pride and arrogance and the haughtiness of her heart.</verse>
<verse>I know her insolence but it is futile," declares the LORD, "and her boasts accomplish nothing.</verse>
<verse>Therefore I wail over Moab, for all Moab I cry out, I moan for the men of Kir Hareseth.</verse>
<verse>I weep for you, as Jazer weeps, O vines of Sibmah. Your branches spread as far as the sea; they reached as far as the sea of Jazer. The destroyer has fallen on your ripened fruit and grapes.</verse>
<verse>Joy and gladness are gone from the orchards and fields of Moab. I have stopped the flow of wine from the presses; no one treads them with shouts of joy. Although there are shouts, they are not shouts of joy.</verse>
<verse>"The sound of their cry rises from Heshbon to Elealeh and Jahaz, from Zoar as far as Horonaim and Eglath Shelishiyah, for even the waters of Nimrim are dried up.</verse>
<verse>In Moab I will put an end to those who make offerings on the high places and burn incense to their gods," declares the LORD.</verse>
<verse>"So my heart laments for Moab like a flute; it laments like a flute for the men of Kir Hareseth. The wealth they acquired is gone.</verse>
<verse>Every head is shaved and every beard cut off; every hand is slashed and every waist is covered with sackcloth.</verse>
<verse>On all the roofs in Moab and in the public squares there is nothing but mourning, for I have broken Moab like a jar that no one wants," declares the LORD.</verse>
<verse>"How shattered she is! How they wail! How Moab turns her back in shame! Moab has become an object of ridicule, an object of horror to all those around her."</verse>
<verse>This is what the LORD says: "Look! An eagle is swooping down, spreading its wings over Moab.</verse>
<verse>Kerioth will be captured and the strongholds taken. In that day the hearts of Moab's warriors will be like the heart of a woman in labor.</verse>
<verse>Moab will be destroyed as a nation because she defied the LORD.</verse>
<verse>Terror and pit and snare await you, O people of Moab," declares the LORD.</verse>
<verse>"Whoever flees from the terror will fall into a pit, whoever climbs out of the pit will be caught in a snare; for I will bring upon Moab the year of her punishment," declares the LORD.</verse>
<verse>"In the shadow of Heshbon the fugitives stand helpless, for a fire has gone out from Heshbon, a blaze from the midst of Sihon; it burns the foreheads of Moab, the skulls of the noisy boasters.</verse>
<verse>Woe to you, O Moab! The people of Chemosh are destroyed; your sons are taken into exile and your daughters into captivity.</verse>
<verse>"Yet I will restore the fortunes of Moab in days to come," declares the LORD. Here ends the judgment on Moab.</verse>
</chapter>