<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Jeremiah" book-id="24" n="9">
<verse>Oh, that my head were a spring of water and my eyes a fountain of tears! I would weep day and night for the slain of my people.</verse>
<verse>Oh, that I had in the desert a lodging place for travelers, so that I might leave my people and go away from them; for they are all adulterers, a crowd of unfaithful people.</verse>
<verse>"They make ready their tongue like a bow, to shoot lies; it is not by truth that they triumph in the land. They go from one sin to another; they do not acknowledge me," declares the LORD.</verse>
<verse>"Beware of your friends; do not trust your brothers. For every brother is a deceiver, and every friend a slanderer.</verse>
<verse>Friend deceives friend, and no one speaks the truth. They have taught their tongues to lie; they weary themselves with sinning.</verse>
<verse>You live in the midst of deception; in their deceit they refuse to acknowledge me," declares the LORD.</verse>
<verse>Therefore this is what the LORD Almighty says: "See, I will refine and test them, for what else can I do because of the sin of my people?</verse>
<verse>Their tongue is a deadly arrow; it speaks with deceit. With his mouth each speaks cordially to his neighbor, but in his heart he sets a trap for him.</verse>
<verse>Should I not punish them for this?" declares the LORD. "Should I not avenge myself on such a nation as this?"</verse>
<verse>I will weep and wail for the mountains and take up a lament concerning the desert pastures. They are desolate and untraveled, and the lowing of cattle is not heard. The birds of the air have fled and the animals are gone.</verse>
<verse>"I will make Jerusalem a heap of ruins, a haunt of jackals; and I will lay waste the towns of Judah so no one can live there."</verse>
<verse>What man is wise enough to understand this? Who has been instructed by the LORD and can explain it? Why has the land been ruined and laid waste like a desert that no one can cross?</verse>
<verse>The LORD said, "It is because they have forsaken my law, which I set before them; they have not obeyed me or followed my law.</verse>
<verse>Instead, they have followed the stubbornness of their hearts; they have followed the Baals, as their fathers taught them."</verse>
<verse>Therefore, this is what the LORD Almighty, the God of Israel, says: "See, I will make this people eat bitter food and drink poisoned water.</verse>
<verse>I will scatter them among nations that neither they nor their fathers have known, and I will pursue them with the sword until I have destroyed them."</verse>
<verse>This is what the LORD Almighty says: "Consider now! Call for the wailing women to come; send for the most skillful of them.</verse>
<verse>Let them come quickly and wail over us till our eyes overflow with tears and water streams from our eyelids.</verse>
<verse>The sound of wailing is heard from Zion: 'How ruined we are! How great is our shame! We must leave our land because our houses are in ruins.'"</verse>
<verse>Now, O women, hear the word of the LORD; open your ears to the words of his mouth. Teach your daughters how to wail; teach one another a lament.</verse>
<verse>Death has climbed in through our windows and has entered our fortresses; it has cut off the children from the streets and the young men from the public squares.</verse>
<verse>Say, "This is what the LORD declares: "'The dead bodies of men will lie like refuse on the open field, like cut grain behind the reaper, with no one to gather them.'"</verse>
<verse>This is what the LORD says: "Let not the wise man boast of his wisdom or the strong man boast of his strength or the rich man boast of his riches,</verse>
<verse>but let him who boasts boast about this: that he understands and knows me, that I am the LORD, who exercises kindness, justice and righteousness on earth, for in these I delight," declares the LORD.</verse>
<verse>"The days are coming," declares the LORD, "when I will punish all who are circumcised only in the flesh-</verse>
<verse>Egypt, Judah, Edom, Ammon, Moab and all who live in the desert in distant places. For all these nations are really uncircumcised, and even the whole house of Israel is uncircumcised in heart."</verse>
</chapter>