<chapter translation="NIV" testament="New" book="Luke" book-id="42" n="15">
<verse>Now the tax collectors and "sinners" were all gathering around to hear him.</verse>
<verse>But the Pharisees and the teachers of the law muttered, "This man welcomes sinners and eats with them."</verse>
<verse>Then Jesus told them this parable:</verse>
<verse>"Suppose one of you has a hundred sheep and loses one of them. Does he not leave the ninety-nine in the open country and go after the lost sheep until he finds it?</verse>
<verse>And when he finds it, he joyfully puts it on his shoulders</verse>
<verse>and goes home. Then he calls his friends and neighbors together and says, 'Rejoice with me; I have found my lost sheep.'</verse>
<verse>I tell you that in the same way there will be more rejoicing in heaven over one sinner who repents than over ninety-nine righteous persons who do not need to repent.</verse>
<verse>"Or suppose a woman has ten silver coins and loses one. Does she not light a lamp, sweep the house and search carefully until she finds it?</verse>
<verse>And when she finds it, she calls her friends and neighbors together and says, 'Rejoice with me; I have found my lost coin.'</verse>
<verse>In the same way, I tell you, there is rejoicing in the presence of the angels of God over one sinner who repents."</verse>
<verse>Jesus continued: "There was a man who had two sons.</verse>
<verse>The younger one said to his father, 'Father, give me my share of the estate.' So he divided his property between them.</verse>
<verse>"Not long after that, the younger son got together all he had, set off for a distant country and there squandered his wealth in wild living.</verse>
<verse>After he had spent everything, there was a severe famine in that whole country, and he began to be in need.</verse>
<verse>So he went and hired himself out to a citizen of that country, who sent him to his fields to feed pigs.</verse>
<verse>He longed to fill his stomach with the pods that the pigs were eating, but no one gave him anything.</verse>
<verse>"When he came to his senses, he said, 'How many of my father's hired men have food to spare, and here I am starving to death!</verse>
<verse>I will set out and go back to my father and say to him: Father, I have sinned against heaven and against you.</verse>
<verse>I am no longer worthy to be called your son; make me like one of your hired men.'</verse>
<verse>So he got up and went to his father. "But while he was still a long way off, his father saw him and was filled with compassion for him; he ran to his son, threw his arms around him and kissed him.</verse>
<verse>"The son said to him, 'Father, I have sinned against heaven and against you. I am no longer worthy to be called your son. '</verse>
<verse>"But the father said to his servants, 'Quick! Bring the best robe and put it on him. Put a ring on his finger and sandals on his feet.</verse>
<verse>Bring the fattened calf and kill it. Let's have a feast and celebrate.</verse>
<verse>For this son of mine was dead and is alive again; he was lost and is found.' So they began to celebrate.</verse>
<verse>"Meanwhile, the older son was in the field. When he came near the house, he heard music and dancing.</verse>
<verse>So he called one of the servants and asked him what was going on.</verse>
<verse>'Your brother has come,' he replied, 'and your father has killed the fattened calf because he has him back safe and sound.'</verse>
<verse>"The older brother became angry and refused to go in. So his father went out and pleaded with him.</verse>
<verse>But he answered his father, 'Look! All these years I've been slaving for you and never disobeyed your orders. Yet you never gave me even a young goat so I could celebrate with my friends.</verse>
<verse>But when this son of yours who has squandered your property with prostitutes comes home, you kill the fattened calf for him!'</verse>
<verse>"'My son,' the father said, 'you are always with me, and everything I have is yours.</verse>
<verse>But we had to celebrate and be glad, because this brother of yours was dead and is alive again; he was lost and is found.'"</verse>
</chapter>