<chapter translation="NIV" testament="New" book="Luke" book_id="42" n="22">
<verse>Now the Feast of Unleavened Bread, called the Passover, was approaching,</verse>
<verse>and the chief priests and the teachers of the law were looking for some way to get rid of Jesus, for they were afraid of the people.</verse>
<verse>Then Satan entered Judas, called Iscariot, one of the Twelve.</verse>
<verse>And Judas went to the chief priests and the officers of the temple guard and discussed with them how he might betray Jesus.</verse>
<verse>They were delighted and agreed to give him money.</verse>
<verse>He consented, and watched for an opportunity to hand Jesus over to them when no crowd was present.</verse>
<verse>Then came the day of Unleavened Bread on which the Passover lamb had to be sacrificed.</verse>
<verse>Jesus sent Peter and John, saying, "Go and make preparations for us to eat the Passover."</verse>
<verse>"Where do you want us to prepare for it?" they asked.</verse>
<verse>He replied, "As you enter the city, a man carrying a jar of water will meet you. Follow him to the house that he enters,</verse>
<verse>and say to the owner of the house, 'The Teacher asks: Where is the guest room, where I may eat the Passover with my disciples?'</verse>
<verse>He will show you a large upper room, all furnished. Make preparations there."</verse>
<verse>They left and found things just as Jesus had told them. So they prepared the Passover.</verse>
<verse>When the hour came, Jesus and his apostles reclined at the table.</verse>
<verse>And he said to them, "I have eagerly desired to eat this Passover with you before I suffer.</verse>
<verse>For I tell you, I will not eat it again until it finds fulfillment in the kingdom of God."</verse>
<verse>After taking the cup, he gave thanks and said, "Take this and divide it among you.</verse>
<verse>For I tell you I will not drink again of the fruit of the vine until the kingdom of God comes."</verse>
<verse>And he took bread, gave thanks and broke it, and gave it to them, saying, "This is my body given for you; do this in remembrance of me."</verse>
<verse>In the same way, after the supper he took the cup, saying, "This cup is the new covenant in my blood, which is poured out for you.</verse>
<verse>But the hand of him who is going to betray me is with mine on the table.</verse>
<verse>The Son of Man will go as it has been decreed, but woe to that man who betrays him."</verse>
<verse>They began to question among themselves which of them it might be who would do this.</verse>
<verse>Also a dispute arose among them as to which of them was considered to be greatest.</verse>
<verse>Jesus said to them, "The kings of the Gentiles lord it over them; and those who exercise authority over them call themselves Benefactors.</verse>
<verse>But you are not to be like that. Instead, the greatest among you should be like the youngest, and the one who rules like the one who serves.</verse>
<verse>For who is greater, the one who is at the table or the one who serves? Is it not the one who is at the table? But I am among you as one who serves.</verse>
<verse>You are those who have stood by me in my trials.</verse>
<verse>And I confer on you a kingdom, just as my Father conferred one on me,</verse>
<verse>so that you may eat and drink at my table in my kingdom and sit on thrones, judging the twelve tribes of Israel.</verse>
<verse>"Simon, Simon, Satan has asked to sift you as wheat.</verse>
<verse>But I have prayed for you, Simon, that your faith may not fail. And when you have turned back, strengthen your brothers."</verse>
<verse>But he replied, "Lord, I am ready to go with you to prison and to death."</verse>
<verse>Jesus answered, "I tell you, Peter, before the rooster crows today, you will deny three times that you know me."</verse>
<verse>Then Jesus asked them, "When I sent you without purse, bag or sandals, did you lack anything?Nothing," they answered.</verse>
<verse>He said to them, "But now if you have a purse, take it, and also a bag; and if you don't have a sword, sell your cloak and buy one.</verse>
<verse>It is written: 'And he was numbered with the transgressors'; and I tell you that this must be fulfilled in me. Yes, what is written about me is reaching its fulfillment."</verse>
<verse>The disciples said, "See, Lord, here are two swords.That is enough," he replied.</verse>
<verse>Jesus went out as usual to the Mount of Olives, and his disciples followed him.</verse>
<verse>On reaching the place, he said to them, "Pray that you will not fall into temptation."</verse>
<verse>He withdrew about a stone's throw beyond them, knelt down and prayed,</verse>
<verse>"Father, if you are willing, take this cup from me; yet not my will, but yours be done."</verse>
<verse>An angel from heaven appeared to him and strengthened him.</verse>
<verse>And being in anguish, he prayed more earnestly, and his sweat was like drops of blood falling to the ground.</verse>
<verse>When he rose from prayer and went back to the disciples, he found them asleep, exhausted from sorrow.</verse>
<verse>"Why are you sleeping?" he asked them. "Get up and pray so that you will not fall into temptation."</verse>
<verse>While he was still speaking a crowd came up, and the man who was called Judas, one of the Twelve, was leading them. He approached Jesus to kiss him,</verse>
<verse>but Jesus asked him, "Judas, are you betraying the Son of Man with a kiss?"</verse>
<verse>When Jesus' followers saw what was going to happen, they said, "Lord, should we strike with our swords?"</verse>
<verse>And one of them struck the servant of the high priest, cutting off his right ear.</verse>
<verse>But Jesus answered, "No more of this!" And he touched the man's ear and healed him.</verse>
<verse>Then Jesus said to the chief priests, the officers of the temple guard, and the elders, who had come for him, "Am I leading a rebellion, that you have come with swords and clubs?</verse>
<verse>Every day I was with you in the temple courts, and you did not lay a hand on me. But this is your hour--when darkness reigns."</verse>
<verse>Then seizing him, they led him away and took him into the house of the high priest. Peter followed at a distance.</verse>
<verse>But when they had kindled a fire in the middle of the courtyard and had sat down together, Peter sat down with them.</verse>
<verse>A servant girl saw him seated there in the firelight. She looked closely at him and said, "This man was with him."</verse>
<verse>But he denied it. "Woman, I don't know him," he said.</verse>
<verse>A little later someone else saw him and said, "You also are one of them.Man, I am not!" Peter replied.</verse>
<verse>About an hour later another asserted, "Certainly this fellow was with him, for he is a Galilean."</verse>
<verse>Peter replied, "Man, I don't know what you're talking about!" Just as he was speaking, the rooster crowed.</verse>
<verse>The Lord turned and looked straight at Peter. Then Peter remembered the word the Lord had spoken to him: "Before the rooster crows today, you will disown me three times."</verse>
<verse>And he went outside and wept bitterly.</verse>
<verse>The men who were guarding Jesus began mocking and beating him.</verse>
<verse>They blindfolded him and demanded, "Prophesy! Who hit you?"</verse>
<verse>And they said many other insulting things to him.</verse>
<verse>At daybreak the council of the elders of the people, both the chief priests and teachers of the law, met together, and Jesus was led before them.</verse>
<verse>"If you are the Christ, "they said, "tell us."</verse>
<verse>Jesus answered, "If I tell you, you will not believe me, and if I asked you, you would not answer.</verse>
<verse>But from now on, the Son of Man will be seated at the right hand of the mighty God."</verse>
<verse>They all asked, "Are you then the Son of God?" He replied, "You are right in saying I am."</verse>
<verse>Then they said, "Why do we need any more testimony? We have heard it from his own lips."</verse>
</chapter>