<chapter translation="NIV" testament="New" book="Luke" book-id="42" n="24">
<verse>On the first day of the week, very early in the morning, the women took the spices they had prepared and went to the tomb.</verse>
<verse>They found the stone rolled away from the tomb,</verse>
<verse>but when they entered, they did not find the body of the Lord Jesus.</verse>
<verse>While they were wondering about this, suddenly two men in clothes that gleamed like lightning stood beside them.</verse>
<verse>In their fright the women bowed down with their faces to the ground, but the men said to them, "Why do you look for the living among the dead?</verse>
<verse>He is not here; he has risen! Remember how he told you, while he was still with you in Galilee:</verse>
<verse>'The Son of Man must be delivered into the hands of sinful men, be crucified and on the third day be raised again.'"</verse>
<verse>Then they remembered his words.</verse>
<verse>When they came back from the tomb, they told all these things to the Eleven and to all the others.</verse>
<verse>It was Mary Magdalene, Joanna, Mary the mother of James, and the others with them who told this to the apostles.</verse>
<verse>But they did not believe the women, because their words seemed to them like nonsense.</verse>
<verse>Peter, however, got up and ran to the tomb. Bending over, he saw the strips of linen lying by themselves, and he went away, wondering to himself what had happened.</verse>
<verse>Now that same day two of them were going to a village called Emmaus, about seven miles from Jerusalem.</verse>
<verse>They were talking with each other about everything that had happened.</verse>
<verse>As they talked and discussed these things with each other, Jesus himself came up and walked along with them;</verse>
<verse>but they were kept from recognizing him.</verse>
<verse>He asked them, "What are you discussing together as you walk along?"</verse>
<verse>They stood still, their faces downcast. One of them, named Cleopas, asked him, "Are you only a visitor to Jerusalem and do not know the things that have happened there in these days?"</verse>
<verse>"What things?" he asked.</verse>
<verse>"About Jesus of Nazareth," they replied. "He was a prophet, powerful in word and deed before God and all the people. The chief priests and our rulers handed him over to be sentenced to death, and they crucified him;</verse>
<verse>but we had hoped that he was the one who was going to redeem Israel. And what is more, it is the third day since all this took place.</verse>
<verse>In addition, some of our women amazed us. They went to the tomb early this morning</verse>
<verse>but didn't find his body. They came and told us that they had seen a vision of angels, who said he was alive.</verse>
<verse>Then some of our companions went to the tomb and found it just as the women had said, but him they did not see."</verse>
<verse>He said to them, "How foolish you are, and how slow of heart to believe all that the prophets have spoken!</verse>
<verse>Did not the Christ have to suffer these things and then enter his glory?"</verse>
<verse>And beginning with Moses and all the Prophets, he explained to them what was said in all the Scriptures concerning himself.</verse>
<verse>As they approached the village to which they were going, Jesus acted as if he were going farther.</verse>
<verse>But they urged him strongly, "Stay with us, for it is nearly evening; the day is almost over." So he went in to stay with them.</verse>
<verse>When he was at the table with them, he took bread, gave thanks, broke it and began to give it to them.</verse>
<verse>Then their eyes were opened and they recognized him, and he disappeared from their sight.</verse>
<verse>They asked each other, "Were not our hearts burning within us while he talked with us on the road and opened the Scriptures to us?"</verse>
<verse>They got up and returned at once to Jerusalem. There they found the Eleven and those with them, assembled together</verse>
<verse>and saying, "It is true! The Lord has risen and has appeared to Simon."</verse>
<verse>Then the two told what had happened on the way, and how Jesus was recognized by them when he broke the bread.</verse>
<verse>While they were still talking about this, Jesus himself stood among them and said to them, "Peace be with you."</verse>
<verse>They were startled and frightened, thinking they saw a ghost.</verse>
<verse>He said to them, "Why are you troubled, and why do doubts rise in your minds?</verse>
<verse>Look at my hands and my feet. It is I myself! Touch me and see; a ghost does not have flesh and bones, as you see I have."</verse>
<verse>When he had said this, he showed them his hands and feet.</verse>
<verse>And while they still did not believe it because of joy and amazement, he asked them, "Do you have anything here to eat?"</verse>
<verse>They gave him a piece of broiled fish,</verse>
<verse>and he took it and ate it in their presence.</verse>
<verse>He said to them, "This is what I told you while I was still with you: Everything must be fulfilled that is written about me in the Law of Moses, the Prophets and the Psalms."</verse>
<verse>Then he opened their minds so they could understand the Scriptures.</verse>
<verse>He told them, "This is what is written: The Christ will suffer and rise from the dead on the third day,</verse>
<verse>and repentance and forgiveness of sins will be preached in his name to all nations, beginning at Jerusalem.</verse>
<verse>You are witnesses of these things.</verse>
<verse>I am going to send you what my Father has promised; but stay in the city until you have been clothed with power from on high."</verse>
<verse>When he had led them out to the vicinity of Bethany, he lifted up his hands and blessed them.</verse>
<verse>While he was blessing them, he left them and was taken up into heaven.</verse>
<verse>Then they worshiped him and returned to Jerusalem with great joy.</verse>
<verse>And they stayed continually at the temple, praising God.</verse>
</chapter>