<chapter translation="NIV" testament="New" book="Luke" book_id="42" n="3">
<verse>In the fifteenth year of the reign of Tiberius Caesar--when Pontius Pilate was governor of Judea, Herod tetrarch of Galilee, his brother Philip tetrarch of Iturea and Traconitis, and Lysanias tetrarch of Abilene--</verse>
<verse>during the high priesthood of Annas and Caiaphas, the word of God came to John son of Zechariah in the desert.</verse>
<verse>He went into all the country around the Jordan, preaching a baptism of repentance for the forgiveness of sins.</verse>
<verse>As is written in the book of the words of Isaiah the prophet: "A voice of one calling in the desert, 'Prepare the way for the Lord, make straight paths for him.</verse>
<verse>Every valley shall be filled in, every mountain and hill made low. The crooked roads shall become straight, the rough ways smooth.</verse>
<verse>And all mankind will see God's salvation.'"</verse>
<verse>John said to the crowds coming out to be baptized by him, "You brood of vipers! Who warned you to flee from the coming wrath?</verse>
<verse>Produce fruit in keeping with repentance. And do not begin to say to yourselves, 'We have Abraham as our father.' For I tell you that out of these stones God can raise up children for Abraham.</verse>
<verse>The ax is already at the root of the trees, and every tree that does not produce good fruit will be cut down and thrown into the fire."</verse>
<verse>"What should we do then?" the crowd asked.</verse>
<verse>John answered, "The man with two tunics should share with him who has none, and the one who has food should do the same."</verse>
<verse>Tax collectors also came to be baptized. "Teacher," they asked, "what should we do?"</verse>
<verse>"Don't collect any more than you are required to," he told</verse>
<verse>them. Then some soldiers asked him, "And what should we do?" He replied, "Don't extort money and don't accuse people falsely--be content with your pay."</verse>
<verse>The people were waiting expectantly and were all wondering in their hearts if John might possibly be the Christ.</verse>
<verse>John answered them all, "I baptize you with water. But one more powerful than I will come, the thongs of whose sandals I am not worthy to untie. He will baptize you with the Holy Spirit and with fire.</verse>
<verse>His winnowing fork is in his hand to clear his threshing floor and to gather the wheat into his barn, but he will burn up the chaff with unquenchable fire."</verse>
<verse>And with many other words John exhorted the people and preached the good news to them.</verse>
<verse>But when John rebuked Herod the tetrarch because of Herodias, his brother's wife, and all the other evil things he had done,</verse>
<verse>Herod added this to them all: He locked John up in prison.</verse>
<verse>When all the people were being baptized, Jesus was baptized too. And as he was praying, heaven was opened</verse>
<verse>and the Holy Spirit descended on him in bodily form like a dove. And a voice came from heaven: "You are my Son, whom I love; with you I am well pleased."</verse>
<verse>Now Jesus himself was about thirty years old when he began his ministry. He was the son, so it was thought, of Joseph,</verse>
<verse>the son of Heli, the son of Matthat, the son of Levi, the son of Melki, the son of Jannai, the son of Joseph,</verse>
<verse>the son of Mattathias, the son of Amos, the son of Nahum, the son of Esli,</verse>
<verse>the son of Naggai, the son of Maath, the son of Mattathias, the son of Semein, the son of Josech, the son of Joda,</verse>
<verse>the son of Joanan, the son of Rhesa, the son of Zerubbabel, the son of Shealtiel,</verse>
<verse>the son of Neri, the son of Melki, the son of Addi, the son of Cosam, the son of Elmadam, the son of Er,</verse>
<verse>the son of Joshua, the son of Eliezer, the son of Jorim, the son of Matthat,</verse>
<verse>the son of Levi, the son of Simeon, the son of Judah, the son of Joseph, the son of Jonam, the son of Eliakim,</verse>
<verse>the son of Melea, the son of Menna, the son of Mattatha, the son of Nathan,</verse>
<verse>the son of David, the son of Jesse, the son of Obed, the son of Boaz, the son of Salmon, the son of Nahshon,</verse>
<verse>the son of Amminadab, the son of Ram, the son of Hezron, the son of Perez,</verse>
<verse>the son of Judah, the son of Jacob, the son of Isaac, the son of Abraham, the son of Terah, the son of Nahor,</verse>
<verse>the son of Serug, the son of Reu, the son of Peleg, the son of Eber,</verse>
<verse>the son of Shelah, the son of Cainan, the son of Arphaxad, the son of Shem, the son of Noah, the son of Lamech,</verse>
<verse>the son of Methuselah, the son of Enoch, the son of Jared, the son of Mahalalel,</verse>
<verse>the son of Kenan, the son of Enosh, the son of Seth, the son of Adam, the son of God.</verse>
</chapter>