<chapter translation="KJV" testament="Old" book="LEV" n="25">
      <verse>And the LORD spake unto Moses in mount Sinai, saying,
</verse><verse>Speak unto the children of Israel, and say unto them, When ye come into the land which I give you, then shall the land keep a sabbath unto the LORD.
</verse><verse>Six years thou shalt sow thy field, and six years thou shalt prune thy vineyard, and gather in the fruit thereof;
</verse><verse>But in the seventh year shall be a sabbath of rest unto the land, a sabbath for the LORD: thou shalt neither sow thy field, nor prune thy vineyard.
</verse><verse>That which groweth of its own accord of thy harvest thou shalt not reap, neither gather the grapes of thy vine undressed: <supplied>for</supplied> it is a year of rest unto the land.
</verse><verse>And the sabbath of the land shall be meat for you; for thee, and for thy servant, and for thy maid, and for thy hired servant, and for thy stranger that sojourneth with thee,
</verse><verse>And for thy cattle, and for the beast that <supplied>are</supplied> in thy land, shall all the increase thereof be meat.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>And thou shalt number seven sabbaths of years unto thee, seven times seven years; and the space of the seven sabbaths of years shall be unto thee forty and nine years.
</verse><verse>Then shalt thou cause the trumpet of the jubile to sound on the tenth <supplied>day</supplied> of the seventh month, in the day of atonement shall ye make the trumpet sound throughout all your land.
</verse><verse>And ye shall hallow the fiftieth year, and proclaim liberty throughout <supplied>all</supplied> the land unto all the inhabitants thereof: it shall be a jubile unto you; and ye shall return every man unto his possession, and ye shall return every man unto
his family.
</verse><verse>A jubile shall that fiftieth year be unto you: ye shall not sow, neither reap that which groweth of itself in it, nor gather <supplied>the grapes</supplied> in it of thy vine undressed.
</verse><verse>For it <supplied>is</supplied> the jubile; it shall be holy unto you: ye shall eat the increase thereof out of the field.
</verse><verse>In the year of this jubile ye shall return every man unto his possession.
</verse><verse>And if thou sell <supplied>ought</supplied> unto thy neighbour, or buyest ought of thy neighbour’s hand, ye shall not oppress one another:
</verse><verse>According to the number of years after the jubile thou shalt buy of thy neighbour, <supplied>and</supplied> according unto the number of years of the fruits he shall sell unto thee:
</verse><verse>According to the multitude of years thou shalt increase the price thereof, and according to the fewness of years thou shalt diminish the price of it: for <supplied>according</supplied> to the number <supplied>of the years</supplied> of the fruits doth he sell unto
thee.
</verse><verse>Ye shall not therefore oppress one another; but thou shalt fear thy God: for I <supplied>am</supplied> the LORD your God.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>Wherefore ye shall do my statutes, and keep my judgments, and do them; and ye shall dwell in the land in safety.
</verse><verse>And the land shall yield her fruit, and ye shall eat your fill, and dwell therein in safety.
</verse><verse>And if ye shall say, What shall we eat the seventh year? behold, we shall not sow, nor gather in our increase:
</verse><verse>Then I will command my blessing upon you in the sixth year, and it shall bring forth fruit for three years.
</verse><verse>And ye shall sow the eighth year, and eat <supplied>yet</supplied> of old fruit until the ninth year; until her fruits come in ye shall eat <supplied>of</supplied> the old <supplied>store.</supplied>
     
      </verse>
      <verse>The land shall not be sold for ever: for the land <supplied>is</supplied> mine; for ye <supplied>are</supplied> strangers and sojourners with me.
</verse><verse>And in all the land of your possession ye shall grant a redemption for the land.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>If thy brother be waxen poor, and hath sold away <supplied>some</supplied> of his possession, and if any of his kin come to redeem it, then shall he redeem that which his brother sold.
</verse><verse>And if the man have none to redeem it, and himself be able to redeem it;
</verse><verse>Then let him count the years of the sale thereof, and restore the overplus unto the man to whom he sold it; that he may return unto his possession.
</verse><verse>But if he be not able to restore <supplied>it</supplied> to him, then that which is sold shall remain in the hand of him that hath bought it until the year of jubile: and in the jubile it shall go out, and he shall return unto his possession.
</verse><verse>And if a man sell a dwelling house in a walled city, then he may redeem it within a whole year after it is sold; <supplied>within</supplied> a full year may he redeem it.
</verse><verse>And if it be not redeemed within the space of a full year, then the house that <supplied>is</supplied> in the walled city shall be established for ever to him that bought it throughout his generations: it shall not go out in the jubile.
</verse><verse>But the houses of the villages which have no wall round about them shall be counted as the fields of the country: they may be redeemed, and they shall go out in the jubile.
</verse><verse>Notwithstanding the cities of the Levites, <supplied>and</supplied> the houses of the cities of their possession, may the Levites redeem at any time.
</verse><verse>And if a man purchase of the Levites, then the house that was sold, and the city of his possession, shall go out in <supplied>the year of</supplied> jubile: for the houses of the cities of the Levites <supplied>are</supplied> their possession among the children of
Israel.
</verse><verse>But the field of the suburbs of their cities may not be sold; for it is their perpetual possession.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>And if thy brother be waxen poor, and fallen in decay with thee; then thou shalt relieve him: <supplied>yea, though he be</supplied> a stranger, or a sojourner; that he may live with thee.
</verse><verse>Take thou no usury of him, or increase: but fear thy God; that thy brother may live with thee.
</verse><verse>Thou shalt not give him thy money upon usury, nor lend him thy victuals for increase.
</verse><verse>I <supplied>am</supplied> the LORD your God, which brought you forth out of the land of Egypt, to give you the land of Canaan, <supplied>and</supplied> to be your God.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>And if thy brother <supplied>that dwelleth</supplied> by thee be waxen poor, and be sold unto thee; thou shalt not compel him to serve as a bondservant:
</verse><verse><supplied>But</supplied> as an hired servant, <supplied>and</supplied> as a sojourner, he shall be with thee, <supplied>and</supplied> shall serve thee unto the year of jubile:
</verse><verse>And <supplied>then</supplied> shall he depart from thee, <supplied>both</supplied> he and his children with him, and shall return unto his own family, and unto the possession of his fathers shall he return.
</verse><verse>For they <supplied>are</supplied> my servants, which I brought forth out of the land of Egypt: they shall not be sold as bondmen.
</verse><verse>Thou shalt not rule over him with rigour; but shalt fear thy God.
</verse><verse>Both thy bondmen, and thy bondmaids, which thou shalt have, <supplied>shall be</supplied> of the heathen that are round about you; of them shall ye buy bondmen and bondmaids.
</verse><verse>Moreover of the children of the strangers that do sojourn among you, of them shall ye buy, and of their families that <supplied>are</supplied> with you, which they begat in your land: and they shall be your possession.
</verse><verse>And ye shall take them as an inheritance for your children after you, to inherit <supplied>them for</supplied> a possession; they shall be your bondmen for ever: but over your brethren the children of Israel, ye shall not rule one over another with
rigour.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>And if a sojourner or stranger wax rich by thee, and thy brother <supplied>that dwelleth</supplied> by him wax poor, and sell himself unto the stranger <supplied>or</supplied> sojourner by thee, or to the stock of the stranger’s family:
</verse><verse>After that he is sold he may be redeemed again; one of his brethren may redeem him:
</verse><verse>Either his uncle, or his uncle’s son, may redeem him, or <supplied>any</supplied> that is nigh of kin unto him of his family may redeem him; or if he be able, he may redeem himself.
</verse><verse>And he shall reckon with him that bought him from the year that he was sold to him unto the year of jubile: and the price of his sale shall be according unto the number of years, according to the time of an hired servant shall it be with him.
</verse><verse>If <supplied>there be</supplied> yet many years <supplied>behind,</supplied> according unto them he shall give again the price of his redemption out of the money that he was bought for.
</verse><verse>And if there remain but few years unto the year of jubile, then he shall count with him, <supplied>and</supplied> according unto his years shall he give him again the price of his redemption.
</verse><verse><supplied>And</supplied> as a yearly hired servant shall he be with him: <supplied>and the other</supplied> shall not rule with rigour over him in thy sight.
</verse><verse>And if he be not redeemed in these <supplied>years,</supplied> then he shall go out in the year of jubile, <supplied>both</supplied> he, and his children with him.
</verse><verse>For unto me the children of Israel <supplied>are</supplied> servants; they <supplied>are</supplied> my servants whom I brought forth out of the land of Egypt: I <supplied>am</supplied> the LORD your God.
     
      </verse>
      </chapter>