<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Nehemiah" book-id="16" n="11">
<verse>The leaders of the people were already living in Jerusalem, so the rest of the people drew lots to get one out of ten to move to Jerusalem, the holy city, while the other nine remained in their towns.</verse>
<verse>The people applauded those who voluntarily offered to live in Jerusalem.</verse>
<verse>These are the leaders in the province who resided in Jerusalem (some Israelites, priests, Levites, Temple staff, and descendants of Solomon's slaves lived in the towns of Judah on their own property in various towns;</verse>
<verse>others from both Judah and Benjamin lived in Jerusalem): From the family of Judah: Athaiah son of Uzziah, the son of Zechariah, the son of Amariah, the son of Shephatiah, the son of Mahalalel, from the family line of Perez;</verse>
<verse>Maaseiah son of Baruch, the son of Col-Hozeh, the son of Hazaiah, the son of Adaiah, the son of Joiarib, the son of Zechariah, the son of the Shilonite.</verse>
<verse>The descendants of Perez who lived in Jerusalem numbered 468 valiant men.</verse>
<verse>From the family of Benjamin: Sallu son of Meshullam, the son of Joed, the son of Pedaiah, the son of Kolaiah, the son of Maaseiah, the son of Ithiel, the son of Jeshaiah,</verse>
<verse>and his brothers Gabbai and Sallai: 928 men.</verse>
<verse>Joel son of Zicri was their chief and Judah son of Hassenuah was second in command over the city.</verse>
<verse>From the priests: Jedaiah son of Joiarib; Jakin;</verse>
<verse>Seraiah son of Hilkiah, the son of Meshullam, the son of Zadok, the son of Meraioth, the son of Ahitub, supervisor of The Temple of God,</verse>
<verse>along with their associates responsible for work in The Temple: 822 men. Also Adaiah son of Jeroham, the son of Pelaliah, the son of Amzi, the son of Zechariah, the son of Pashhur, the son of Malkijah,</verse>
<verse>and his associates who were heads of families: 242 men; Amashsai son of Azarel, the son of Ahzai, the son of Meshillemoth, the son of Immer,</verse>
<verse>and his associates, all valiant men: 128 men. Their commander was Zabdiel son of Haggedolim.</verse>
<verse>From the Levites: Shemaiah son of Hasshub, the son of Azrikam, the son of Hashabiah, the son of Bunni;</verse>
<verse>Shabbethai and Jozabad, two of the leaders of the Levites who were in charge of the outside work of The Temple of God;</verse>
<verse>Mattaniah son of Mica, the son of Zabdi, the son of Asaph, the director who led in thanksgiving and prayer; Bakbukiah, second among his associates; and Abda son of Shammua, the son of Galal, the son of Jeduthun.</verse>
<verse>The Levites in the holy city totaled 284.</verse>
<verse>From the security guards: Akkub, Talmon, and their associates who kept watch over the gates: 172 men.</verse>
<verse>The rest of the Israelites, priests, and Levites were in all the towns of Judah, each on his own family property.</verse>
<verse>The Temple staff lived on the hill Ophel. Ziha and Gishpa were responsible for them.</verse>
<verse>The chief officer over the Levites in Jerusalem was Uzzi son of Bani, the son of Hashabiah, the son of Mattaniah, the son of Mica. Uzzi was one of Asaph's descendants, singers who led worship in The Temple of God.</verse>
<verse>The singers got their orders from the king, who drew up their daily schedule.</verse>
<verse>Pethahiah son of Meshezabel, a descendant of Zerah son of Judah, represented the people's concerns at the royal court.</verse>
<verse>Some of the Judeans lived in the villages near their farms: Kiriath Arba (Hebron) and suburbs Dibon and suburbs Jekabzeel and suburbs</verse>
<verse>Jeshua	 Moladah Beth Pelet</verse>
<verse>Hazar Shual Beersheba and suburbs</verse>
<verse>Ziklag Meconah and suburbs</verse>
<verse>En Rimmon Zorah Jarmuth</verse>
<verse>Zanoah Adullam and their towns Lachish and its fields Azekah and suburbs. They were living all the way from Beersheba to the Valley of Hinnom.</verse>
<verse>The Benjaminites from Geba lived in: Micmash Aijah Bethel and its suburbs</verse>
<verse>Anathoth Nob and Ananiah</verse>
<verse>Hazor Ramah and Gittaim</verse>
<verse>Hadid, Zeboim, and Neballat</verse>
<verse>Lod and Ono and the Valley of the Craftsmen.</verse>
<verse>Also some of the Levitical groups of Judah were assigned to Benjamin.</verse>
</chapter>