<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Nehemiah" book_id="16" n="3">
<verse>The high priest Eliashib and his fellow priests were up and at it: They went to work on the Sheep Gate; they repaired it and hung its doors, continuing on as far as the Tower of the Hundred and the Tower of Hananel.</verse>
<verse>The men of Jericho worked alongside them; and next to them, Zaccur son of Imri.</verse>
<verse>The Fish Gate was built by the Hassenaah brothers; they repaired it, hung its doors, and installed its bolts and bars.</verse>
<verse>Meremoth son of Uriah, the son of Hakkoz, worked; next to him Meshullam son of Berekiah, the son of Meshezabel; next to him Zadok son of Baana;</verse>
<verse>and next to him the Tekoites (except for their nobles, who wouldn't work with their master and refused to get their hands dirty with such work).</verse>
<verse>The Jeshanah Gate was rebuilt by Joiada son of Paseah and Meshullam son of Besodeiah; they repaired it, hung its doors, and installed its bolts and bars.</verse>
<verse>Melatiah the Gibeonite, Jadon the Meronothite, and the men of Gibeon and Mizpah, which was under the rule of the governor from across the Euphrates, worked alongside them.</verse>
<verse>Uzziel son of Harhaiah of the goldsmiths' guild worked next to him, and next to him Hananiah, one of the perfumers. They rebuilt the wall of Jerusalem as far as the Broad Wall.</verse>
<verse>The next section was worked on by Rephaiah son of Hur, mayor of a half-district of Jerusalem.</verse>
<verse>Next to him Jedaiah son of Harumaph rebuilt the front of his house; Hattush son of Hashabneiah worked next to him.</verse>
<verse>Malkijah son of Harim and Hasshub son of Pahath-Moab rebuilt another section that included the Tower of Furnaces.</verse>
<verse>Working next to him was Shallum son of Hallohesh, mayor of the other half-district of Jerusalem, along with his daughters.</verse>
<verse>The Valley Gate was rebuilt by Hanun and villagers of Zanoah; they repaired it, hung its doors, and installed its bolts and bars. They went on to repair 1,500 feet of the wall, as far as the Dung Gate.</verse>
<verse>The Dung Gate itself was rebuilt by Malkijah son of Recab, the mayor of the district of Beth Hakkerem; he repaired it, hung its doors, and installed its bolts and bars.</verse>
<verse>The Fountain Gate was rebuilt by Shallun son of Col-Hozeh, mayor of the Mizpah district; he repaired it, roofed it, hung its doors, and installed its bolts and bars. He also rebuilt the wall of the Pool of Siloam at the King's Garden as far as the steps that go down from the City of David.</verse>
<verse>After him came Nehemiah son of Azbuk, mayor of half the district of Beth Zur. He worked from just in front of the Tomb of David as far as the Pool and the House of Heroes.</verse>
<verse>Levites under Rehum son of Bani were next in line. Alongside them, Hashabiah, mayor of half the district of Keilah, represented his district in the rebuilding.</verse>
<verse>Next to him their brothers continued the rebuilding under Binnui son of Henadad, mayor of the other half-district of Keilah.</verse>
<verse>The section from in front of the Ascent to the Armory as far as the Angle was rebuilt by Ezer son of Jeshua, the mayor of Mizpah.</verse>
<verse>From the Angle to the door of the house of Eliashib the high priest was done by Baruch son of Zabbai.</verse>
<verse>Meremoth son of Uriah, the son of Hakkoz, took it from the door of Eliashib's house to the end of Eliashib's house.</verse>
<verse>Priests from the neighborhood went on from there.</verse>
<verse>Benjamin and Hasshub worked on the wall in front of their house, and Azariah son of Maaseiah, the son of Ananiah, did the work alongside his house.</verse>
<verse>The section from the house of Azariah to the Angle at the Corner was rebuilt by Binnui son of Henadad.</verse>
<verse>Palal son of Uzai worked opposite the Angle and the tower that projects from the Upper Palace of the king near the Court of the Guard. Next to him Pedaiah son of Parosh</verse>
<verse>and The Temple support staff who lived on the hill of Ophel worked up to the point opposite the Water Gate eastward and the projecting tower.</verse>
<verse>The men of Tekoa did the section from the great projecting tower as far as the wall of Ophel.</verse>
<verse>Above the Horse Gate the priests worked, each priest repairing the wall in front of his own house.</verse>
<verse>After them Zadok son of Immer rebuilt in front of his house and after him Shemaiah son of Shecaniah, the keeper of the East Gate;</verse>
<verse>then Hananiah son of Shelemiah and Hanun, the sixth son of Zalaph; then Meshullam son of Berekiah rebuilt the wall in front of his storage shed.</verse>
<verse>Malkijah the goldsmith repaired the wall as far as the house of The Temple support staff and merchants, up to the Inspection Gate, and the Upper Room at the Corner.</verse>
<verse>The goldsmiths and the merchants made the repairs between the Upper Room at the Corner and the Sheep Gate.</verse>
</chapter>