<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Nehemiah" book-id="16" n="8">
<verse>By the time the seventh month arrived, the People of Israel were settled in their towns. Then all the people gathered as one person in the town square in front of the Water Gate and asked the scholar Ezra to bring the Book of The Revelation of Moses that GOD had commanded for Israel.</verse>
<verse>So Ezra the priest brought The Revelation to the congregation, which was made up of both men and women--everyone capable of understanding. It was the first day of the seventh month.</verse>
<verse>He read it facing the town square at the Water Gate from early dawn until noon in the hearing of the men and women, all who could understand it. And all the people listened--they were all ears--to the Book of The Revelation.</verse>
<verse>The scholar Ezra stood on a wooden platform constructed for the occasion. He was flanked on the right by Mattithiah, Shema, Anaiah, Uriah, Hilkiah, and Maaseiah, and on the left by Pedaiah, Mishael, Malkijah, Hashum, Hashbaddanah, Zechariah, and Meshullam.</verse>
<verse>Ezra opened the book. Every eye was on him (he was standing on the raised platform) and as he opened the book everyone stood.</verse>
<verse>Then Ezra praised GOD, the great God, and all the people responded, "Oh Yes! Yes!" with hands raised high. And then they fell to their knees in worship of GOD, their faces to the ground.</verse>
<verse>Jeshua, Bani, Sherebiah, Jamin, Akkub, Shabbethai, Hodiah, Maaseiah, Kelita, Azariah, Jozabad, Hanan, and Pelaiah, all Levites, explained The Revelation while people stood, listening respectfully.</verse>
<verse>They translated the Book of The Revelation of God so the people could understand it and then explained the reading.</verse>
<verse>Nehemiah the governor, along with Ezra the priest and scholar and the Levites who were teaching the people, said to all the people, "This day is holy to GOD, your God. Don't weep and carry on." They said this because all the people were weeping as they heard the words of The Revelation.</verse>
<verse>He continued, "Go home and prepare a feast, holiday food and drink; and share it with those who don't have anything: This day is holy to God. Don't feel bad. The joy of GOD is your strength!"</verse>
<verse>The Levites calmed the people, "Quiet now. This is a holy day. Don't be upset."</verse>
<verse>So the people went off to feast, eating and drinking and including the poor in a great celebration. Now they got it; they understood the reading that had been given to them. [JC]</verse>
<verse>On the second day of the month the family heads of all the people, the priests, and the Levites gathered around Ezra the scholar to get a deeper understanding of the words of The Revelation.</verse>
<verse>They found written in The Revelation that GOD commanded through Moses that the People of Israel are to live in booths during the festival of the seventh month.</verse>
<verse>So they published this decree and had it posted in all their cities and in Jerusalem: "Go into the hills and collect olive branches, pine branches, myrtle branches, palm branches, and any other leafy branches to make booths, as it is written." [JC]</verse>
<verse>So the people went out, brought in branches, and made themselves booths on their roofs, courtyards, the courtyards of The Temple of God, the Water Gate plaza, and the Ephraim Gate plaza.</verse>
<verse>The entire congregation that had come back from exile made booths and lived in them. The People of Israel hadn't done this from the time of Joshua son of Nun until that very day--a terrific day! Great joy!</verse>
<verse>Ezra read from the Book of The Revelation of God each day, from the first to the last day--they celebrated the feast for seven days. On the eighth day they held a solemn assembly in accordance with the decree.</verse>
</chapter>