<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Isaiah" book_id="23" n="13">
<verse>An oracle concerning Babylon that Isaiah son of Amoz saw:</verse>
<verse>Raise a banner on a bare hilltop, shout to them; beckon to them to enter the gates of the nobles.</verse>
<verse>I have commanded my holy ones; I have summoned my warriors to carry out my wrath- those who rejoice in my triumph.</verse>
<verse>Listen, a noise on the mountains, like that of a great multitude! Listen, an uproar among the kingdoms, like nations massing together! The LORD Almighty is mustering an army for war.</verse>
<verse>They come from faraway lands, from the ends of the heavens- the LORD and the weapons of his wrath- to destroy the whole country.</verse>
<verse>Wail, for the day of the LORD is near; it will come like destruction from the Almighty.</verse>
<verse>Because of this, all hands will go limp, every man's heart will melt.</verse>
<verse>Terror will seize them, pain and anguish will grip them; they will writhe like a woman in labor. They will look aghast at each other, their faces aflame.</verse>
<verse>See, the day of the LORD is coming -a cruel day, with wrath and fierce anger- to make the land desolate and destroy the sinners within it.</verse>
<verse>The stars of heaven and their constellations will not show their light. The rising sun will be darkened and the moon will not give its light.</verse>
<verse>I will punish the world for its evil, the wicked for their sins. I will put an end to the arrogance of the haughty and will humble the pride of the ruthless.</verse>
<verse>I will make man scarcer than pure gold, more rare than the gold of Ophir.</verse>
<verse>Therefore I will make the heavens tremble; and the earth will shake from its place at the wrath of the LORD Almighty, in the day of his burning anger.</verse>
<verse>Like a hunted gazelle, like sheep without a shepherd, each will return to his own people, each will flee to his native land.</verse>
<verse>Whoever is captured will be thrust through; all who are caught will fall by the sword.</verse>
<verse>Their infants will be dashed to pieces before their eyes; their houses will be looted and their wives ravished.</verse>
<verse>See, I will stir up against them the Medes, who do not care for silver and have no delight in gold.</verse>
<verse>Their bows will strike down the young men; they will have no mercy on infants nor will they look with compassion on children.</verse>
<verse>Babylon, the jewel of kingdoms, the glory of the Babylonians' pride, will be overthrown by God like Sodom and Gomorrah.</verse>
<verse>She will never be inhabited or lived in through all generations; no Arab will pitch his tent there, no shepherd will rest his flocks there.</verse>
<verse>But desert creatures will lie there, jackals will fill her houses; there the owls will dwell, and there the wild goats will leap about.</verse>
<verse>Hyenas will howl in her strongholds, jackals in her luxurious palaces. Her time is at hand, and her days will not be prolonged.</verse>
</chapter>