<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Isaiah" book-id="23" n="19">
<verse>An oracle concerning Egypt: See, the LORD rides on a swift cloud and is coming to Egypt. The idols of Egypt tremble before him, and the hearts of the Egyptians melt within them.</verse>
<verse>"I will stir up Egyptian against Egyptian- brother will fight against brother, neighbor against neighbor, city against city, kingdom against kingdom.</verse>
<verse>The Egyptians will lose heart, and I will bring their plans to nothing; they will consult the idols and the spirits of the dead, the mediums and the spiritists.</verse>
<verse>I will hand the Egyptians over to the power of a cruel master, and a fierce king will rule over them," declares the Lord, the LORD Almighty.</verse>
<verse>The waters of the river will dry up, and the riverbed will be parched and dry.</verse>
<verse>The canals will stink; the streams of Egypt will dwindle and dry up. The reeds and rushes will wither,</verse>
<verse>also the plants along the Nile, at the mouth of the river. Every sown field along the Nile will become parched, will blow away and be no more.</verse>
<verse>The fishermen will groan and lament, all who cast hooks into the Nile; those who throw nets on the water will pine away.</verse>
<verse>Those who work with combed flax will despair, the weavers of fine linen will lose hope.</verse>
<verse>The workers in cloth will be dejected, and all the wage earners will be sick at heart.</verse>
<verse>The officials of Zoan are nothing but fools; the wise counselors of Pharaoh give senseless advice. How can you say to Pharaoh, "I am one of the wise men, a disciple of the ancient kings"?</verse>
<verse>Where are your wise men now? Let them show you and make known what the LORD Almighty has planned against Egypt.</verse>
<verse>The officials of Zoan have become fools, the leaders of Memphis are deceived; the cornerstones of her peoples have led Egypt astray.</verse>
<verse>The LORD has poured into them a spirit of dizziness; they make Egypt stagger in all that she does, as a drunkard staggers around in his vomit.</verse>
<verse>There is nothing Egypt can do- head or tail, palm branch or reed.</verse>
<verse>In that day the Egyptians will be like women. They will shudder with fear at the uplifted hand that the LORD Almighty raises against them.</verse>
<verse>And the land of Judah will bring terror to the Egyptians; everyone to whom Judah is mentioned will be terrified, because of what the LORD Almighty is planning against them.</verse>
<verse>In that day five cities in Egypt will speak the language of Canaan and swear allegiance to the LORD Almighty. One of them will be called the City of Destruction.</verse>
<verse>In that day there will be an altar to the LORD in the heart of Egypt, and a monument to the LORD at its border.</verse>
<verse>It will be a sign and witness to the LORD Almighty in the land of Egypt. When they cry out to the LORD because of their oppressors, he will send them a savior and defender, and he will rescue them.</verse>
<verse>So the LORD will make himself known to the Egyptians, and in that day they will acknowledge the LORD. They will worship with sacrifices and grain offerings; they will make vows to the LORD and keep them.</verse>
<verse>The LORD will strike Egypt with a plague; he will strike them and heal them. They will turn to the LORD, and he will respond to their pleas and heal them.</verse>
<verse>In that day there will be a highway from Egypt to Assyria. The Assyrians will go to Egypt and the Egyptians to Assyria. The Egyptians and Assyrians will worship together.</verse>
<verse>In that day Israel will be the third, along with Egypt and Assyria, a blessing on the earth.</verse>
<verse>The LORD Almighty will bless them, saying, "Blessed be Egypt my people, Assyria my handiwork, and Israel my inheritance."</verse>
</chapter>