<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Isaiah" book_id="23" n="25">
<verse>O LORD, you are my God; I will exalt you and praise your name, for in perfect faithfulness you have done marvelous things, things planned long ago.</verse>
<verse>You have made the city a heap of rubble, the fortified town a ruin, the foreigners' stronghold a city no more; it will never be rebuilt.</verse>
<verse>Therefore strong peoples will honor you; cities of ruthless nations will revere you.</verse>
<verse>You have been a refuge for the poor, a refuge for the needy in his distress, a shelter from the storm and a shade from the heat. For the breath of the ruthless is like a storm driving against a wall</verse>
<verse>and like the heat of the desert. You silence the uproar of foreigners; as heat is reduced by the shadow of a cloud, so the song of the ruthless is stilled.</verse>
<verse>On this mountain the LORD Almighty will prepare a feast of rich food for all peoples, a banquet of aged wine- the best of meats and the finest of wines.</verse>
<verse>On this mountain he will destroy the shroud that enfolds all peoples, the sheet that covers all nations;</verse>
<verse>he will swallow up death forever. The Sovereign LORD will wipe away the tears from all faces; he will remove the disgrace of his people from all the earth. The LORD has spoken.</verse>
<verse>In that day they will say, "Surely this is our God; we trusted in him, and he saved us. This is the LORD, we trusted in him; let us rejoice and be glad in his salvation."</verse>
<verse>The hand of the LORD will rest on this mountain; but Moab will be trampled under him as straw is trampled down in the manure.</verse>
<verse>They will spread out their hands in it, as a swimmer spreads out his hands to swim. God will bring down their pride despite the cleverness of their hands.</verse>
<verse>He will bring down your high fortified walls and lay them low; he will bring them down to the ground, to the very dust.</verse>
</chapter>