<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Isaiah" book_id="23" n="27">
<verse>In that day, the LORD will punish with his sword, his fierce, great and powerful sword, Leviathan the gliding serpent, Leviathan the coiling serpent; he will slay the monster of the sea.</verse>
<verse>In that day- "Sing about a fruitful vineyard:</verse>
<verse>I, the LORD, watch over it; I water it continually. I guard it day and night so that no one may harm it.</verse>
<verse>I am not angry. If only there were briers and thorns confronting me! I would march against them in battle; I would set them all on fire.</verse>
<verse>Or else let them come to me for refuge; let them make peace with me, yes, let them make peace with me."</verse>
<verse>In days to come Jacob will take root, Israel will bud and blossom and fill all the world with fruit.</verse>
<verse>Has the LORD struck her as he struck down those who struck her? Has she been killed as those were killed who killed her?</verse>
<verse>By warfare and exile you contend with her- with his fierce blast he drives her out, as on a day the east wind blows.</verse>
<verse>By this, then, will Jacob's guilt be atoned for, and this will be the full fruitage of the removal of his sin: When he makes all the altar stones to be like chalk stones crushed to pieces, no Asherah poles or incense altars will be left standing.</verse>
<verse>The fortified city stands desolate, an abandoned settlement, forsaken like the desert; there the calves graze, there they lie down; they strip its branches bare.</verse>
<verse>When its twigs are dry, they are broken off and women come and make fires with them. For this is a people without understanding; so their Maker has no compassion on them, and their Creator shows them no favor.</verse>
<verse>In that day the LORD will thresh from the flowing Euphrates to the Wadi of Egypt, and you, O Israelites, will be gathered up one by one.</verse>
<verse>And in that day a great trumpet will sound. Those who were perishing in Assyria and those who were exiled in Egypt will come and worship the LORD on the holy mountain in Jerusalem.</verse>
</chapter>