<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Isaiah" book_id="23" n="3">
<verse>See now, the Lord, the LORD Almighty, is about to take from Jerusalem and Judah both supply and support: all supplies of food and all supplies of water,</verse>
<verse>the hero and warrior, the judge and prophet, the soothsayer and elder,</verse>
<verse>the captain of fifty and man of rank, the counselor, skilled craftsman and clever enchanter.</verse>
<verse>I will make boys their officials; mere children will govern them.</verse>
<verse>People will oppress each other- man against man, neighbor against neighbor. The young will rise up against the old, the base against the honorable.</verse>
<verse>A man will seize one of his brothers at his father's home, and say, "You have a cloak, you be our leader; take charge of this heap of ruins!"</verse>
<verse>But in that day he will cry out, "I have no remedy. I have no food or clothing in my house; do not make me the leader of the people."</verse>
<verse>Jerusalem staggers, Judah is falling; their words and deeds are against the LORD, defying his glorious presence.</verse>
<verse>The look on their faces testifies against them; they parade their sin like Sodom; they do not hide it. Woe to them! They have brought disaster upon themselves.</verse>
<verse>Tell the righteous it will be well with them, for they will enjoy the fruit of their deeds.</verse>
<verse>Woe to the wicked! Disaster is upon them! They will be paid back for what their hands have done.</verse>
<verse>Youths oppress my people, women rule over them. O my people, your guides lead you astray; they turn you from the path.</verse>
<verse>The LORD takes his place in court; he rises to judge the people.</verse>
<verse>The LORD enters into judgment against the elders and leaders of his people: "It is you who have ruined my vineyard; the plunder from the poor is in your houses.</verse>
<verse>What do you mean by crushing my people and grinding the faces of the poor?" declares the Lord, the LORD Almighty.</verse>
<verse>The LORD says, "The women of Zion are haughty, walking along with outstretched necks, flirting with their eyes, tripping along with mincing steps, with ornaments jingling on their ankles.</verse>
<verse>Therefore the Lord will bring sores on the heads of the women of Zion; the LORD will make their scalps bald."</verse>
<verse>In that day the Lord will snatch away their finery: the bangles and headbands and crescent necklaces,</verse>
<verse>the earrings and bracelets and veils,</verse>
<verse>the headdresses and ankle chains and sashes, the perfume bottles and charms,</verse>
<verse>the signet rings and nose rings,</verse>
<verse>the fine robes and the capes and cloaks, the purses</verse>
<verse>and mirrors, and the linen garments and tiaras and shawls.</verse>
<verse>Instead of fragrance there will be a stench; instead of a sash, a rope; instead of well-dressed hair, baldness; instead of fine clothing, sackcloth; instead of beauty, branding.</verse>
<verse>Your men will fall by the sword, your warriors in battle.</verse>
<verse>The gates of Zion will lament and mourn; destitute, she will sit on the ground.</verse>
</chapter>