<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Isaiah" book-id="23" n="34">
<verse>Come near, you nations, and listen; pay attention, you peoples! Let the earth hear, and all that is in it, the world, and all that comes out of it!</verse>
<verse>The LORD is angry with all nations; his wrath is upon all their armies. He will totally destroy them, he will give them over to slaughter.</verse>
<verse>Their slain will be thrown out, their dead bodies will send up a stench; the mountains will be soaked with their blood.</verse>
<verse>All the stars of the heavens will be dissolved and the sky rolled up like a scroll; all the starry host will fall like withered leaves from the vine, like shriveled figs from the fig tree.</verse>
<verse>My sword has drunk its fill in the heavens; see, it descends in judgment on Edom, the people I have totally destroyed.</verse>
<verse>The sword of the LORD is bathed in blood, it is covered with fat- the blood of lambs and goats, fat from the kidneys of rams. For the LORD has a sacrifice in Bozrah and a great slaughter in Edom.</verse>
<verse>And the wild oxen will fall with them, the bull calves and the great bulls. Their land will be drenched with blood, and the dust will be soaked with fat.</verse>
<verse>For the LORD has a day of vengeance, a year of retribution, to uphold Zion's cause.</verse>
<verse>Edom's streams will be turned into pitch, her dust into burning sulfur; her land will become blazing pitch!</verse>
<verse>It will not be quenched night and day; its smoke will rise forever. From generation to generation it will lie desolate; no one will ever pass through it again.</verse>
<verse>The desert owl and screech owl will possess it; the great owl and the raven will nest there. God will stretch out over Edom the measuring line of chaos and the plumb line of desolation.</verse>
<verse>Her nobles will have nothing there to be called a kingdom, all her princes will vanish away.</verse>
<verse>Thorns will overrun her citadels, nettles and brambles her strongholds. She will become a haunt for jackals, a home for owls.</verse>
<verse>Desert creatures will meet with hyenas, and wild goats will bleat to each other; there the night creatures will also repose and find for themselves places of rest.</verse>
<verse>The owl will nest there and lay eggs, she will hatch them, and care for her young under the shadow of her wings; there also the falcons will gather, each with its mate.</verse>
<verse>Look in the scroll of the LORD and read: None of these will be missing, not one will lack her mate. For it is his mouth that has given the order, and his Spirit will gather them together.</verse>
<verse>He allots their portions; his hand distributes them by measure. They will possess it forever and dwell there from generation to generation.</verse>
</chapter>