<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Isaiah" book-id="23" n="46">
<verse>Bel bows down, Nebo stoops low; their idols are borne by beasts of burden. The images that are carried about are burdensome, a burden for the weary.</verse>
<verse>They stoop and bow down together; unable to rescue the burden, they themselves go off into captivity.</verse>
<verse>"Listen to me, O house of Jacob, all you who remain of the house of Israel, you whom I have upheld since you were conceived, and have carried since your birth.</verse>
<verse>Even to your old age and gray hairs I am he, I am he who will sustain you. I have made you and I will carry you; I will sustain you and I will rescue you.</verse>
<verse>"To whom will you compare me or count me equal? To whom will you liken me that we may be compared?</verse>
<verse>Some pour out gold from their bags and weigh out silver on the scales; they hire a goldsmith to make it into a god, and they bow down and worship it.</verse>
<verse>They lift it to their shoulders and carry it; they set it up in its place, and there it stands. From that spot it cannot move. Though one cries out to it, it does not answer; it cannot save him from his troubles.</verse>
<verse>"Remember this, fix it in mind, take it to heart, you rebels.</verse>
<verse>Remember the former things, those of long ago; I am God, and there is no other; I am God, and there is none like me.</verse>
<verse>I make known the end from the beginning, from ancient times, what is still to come. I say: My purpose will stand, and I will do all that I please.</verse>
<verse>From the east I summon a bird of prey; from a far-off land, a man to fulfill my purpose. What I have said, that will I bring about; what I have planned, that will I do.</verse>
<verse>Listen to me, you stubborn-hearted, you who are far from righteousness.</verse>
<verse>I am bringing my righteousness near, it is not far away; and my salvation will not be delayed. I will grant salvation to Zion, my splendor to Israel.</verse>
</chapter>