<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Isaiah" book-id="23" n="56">
<verse>This is what the LORD says: "Maintain justice and do what is right, for my salvation is close at hand and my righteousness will soon be revealed.</verse>
<verse>Blessed is the man who does this, the man who holds it fast, who keeps the Sabbath without desecrating it, and keeps his hand from doing any evil."</verse>
<verse>Let no foreigner who has bound himself to the LORD say, "The LORD will surely exclude me from his people." And let not any eunuch complain, "I am only a dry tree."</verse>
<verse>For this is what the LORD says: "To the eunuchs who keep my Sabbaths, who choose what pleases me and hold fast to my covenant-</verse>
<verse>to them I will give within my temple and its walls a memorial and a name better than sons and daughters; I will give them an everlasting name that will not be cut off.</verse>
<verse>And foreigners who bind themselves to the LORD to serve him, to love the name of the LORD, and to worship him, all who keep the Sabbath without desecrating it and who hold fast to my covenant-</verse>
<verse>these I will bring to my holy mountain and give them joy in my house of prayer. Their burnt offerings and sacrifices will be accepted on my altar; for my house will be called a house of prayer for all nations."</verse>
<verse>The Sovereign LORD declares- he who gathers the exiles of Israel: "I will gather still others to them besides those already gathered."</verse>
<verse>Come, all you beasts of the field, come and devour, all you beasts of the forest!</verse>
<verse>Israel's watchmen are blind, they all lack knowledge; they are all mute dogs, they cannot bark; they lie around and dream, they love to sleep.</verse>
<verse>They are dogs with mighty appetites; they never have enough. They are shepherds who lack understanding; they all turn to their own way, each seeks his own gain.</verse>
<verse>"Come," each one cries, "let me get wine! Let us drink our fill of beer! And tomorrow will be like today, or even far better."</verse>
</chapter>