<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Isaiah" book_id="23" n="57">
<verse>The righteous perish, and no one ponders it in his heart; devout men are taken away, and no one understands that the righteous are taken away to be spared from evil.</verse>
<verse>Those who walk uprightly enter into peace; they find rest as they lie in death.</verse>
<verse>"But you-come here, you sons of a sorceress, you offspring of adulterers and prostitutes!</verse>
<verse>Whom are you mocking? At whom do you sneer and stick out your tongue? Are you not a brood of rebels, the offspring of liars?</verse>
<verse>You burn with lust among the oaks and under every spreading tree; you sacrifice your children in the ravines and under the overhanging crags.</verse>
<verse>The idols among the smooth stones of the ravines are your portion; they, they are your lot. Yes, to them you have poured out drink offerings and offered grain offerings. In the light of these things, should I relent?</verse>
<verse>You have made your bed on a high and lofty hill; there you went up to offer your sacrifices.</verse>
<verse>Behind your doors and your doorposts you have put your pagan symbols. Forsaking me, you uncovered your bed, you climbed into it and opened it wide; you made a pact with those whose beds you love, and you looked on their nakedness.</verse>
<verse>You went to Molech with olive oil and increased your perfumes. You sent your ambassadors far away; you descended to the grave itself!</verse>
<verse>You were wearied by all your ways, but you would not say, 'It is hopeless.' You found renewal of your strength, and so you did not faint.</verse>
<verse>"Whom have you so dreaded and feared that you have been false to me, and have neither remembered me nor pondered this in your hearts? Is it not because I have long been silent that you do not fear me?</verse>
<verse>I will expose your righteousness and your works, and they will not benefit you.</verse>
<verse>When you cry out for help, let your collection of idols save you! The wind will carry all of them off, a mere breath will blow them away. But the man who makes me his refuge will inherit the land and possess my holy mountain."</verse>
<verse>And it will be said: "Build up, build up, prepare the road! Remove the obstacles out of the way of my people."</verse>
<verse>For this is what the high and lofty One says- he who lives forever, whose name is holy: "I live in a high and holy place, but also with him who is contrite and lowly in spirit, to revive the spirit of the lowly and to revive the heart of the contrite.</verse>
<verse>I will not accuse forever, nor will I always be angry, for then the spirit of man would grow faint before me- the breath of man that I have created.</verse>
<verse>I was enraged by his sinful greed; I punished him, and hid my face in anger, yet he kept on in his willful ways.</verse>
<verse>I have seen his ways, but I will heal him; I will guide him and restore comfort to him,</verse>
<verse>creating praise on the lips of the mourners in Israel. Peace, peace, to those far and near," says the LORD. "And I will heal them."</verse>
<verse>But the wicked are like the tossing sea, which cannot rest, whose waves cast up mire and mud.</verse>
<verse>"There is no peace," says my God, "for the wicked."</verse>
</chapter>