<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Isaiah" book_id="23" n="62">
<verse>For Zion's sake I will not keep silent, for Jerusalem's sake I will not remain quiet, till her righteousness shines out like the dawn, her salvation like a blazing torch.</verse>
<verse>The nations will see your righteousness, and all kings your glory; you will be called by a new name that the mouth of the LORD will bestow.</verse>
<verse>You will be a crown of splendor in the LORD's hand, a royal diadem in the hand of your God.</verse>
<verse>No longer will they call you Deserted, or name your land Desolate. But you will be called Hephzibah, and your land Beulah; for the LORD will take delight in you, and your land will be married.</verse>
<verse>As a young man marries a maiden, so will your sons marry you; as a bridegroom rejoices over his bride, so will your God rejoice over you.</verse>
<verse>I have posted watchmen on your walls, O Jerusalem; they will never be silent day or night. You who call on the LORD, give yourselves no rest,</verse>
<verse>and give him no rest till he establishes Jerusalem and makes her the praise of the earth.</verse>
<verse>The LORD has sworn by his right hand and by his mighty arm: "Never again will I give your grain as food for your enemies, and never again will foreigners drink the new wine for which you have toiled;</verse>
<verse>but those who harvest it will eat it and praise the LORD, and those who gather the grapes will drink it in the courts of my sanctuary."</verse>
<verse>Pass through, pass through the gates! Prepare the way for the people. Build up, build up the highway! Remove the stones. Raise a banner for the nations.</verse>
<verse>The LORD has made proclamation to the ends of the earth: "Say to the Daughter of Zion, 'See, your Savior comes! See, his reward is with him, and his recompense accompanies him.'"</verse>
<verse>They will be called the Holy People, the Redeemed of the LORD; and you will be called Sought After, the City No Longer Deserted.</verse>
</chapter>