<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="2 Samuel" book-id="10" n="8">
<verse>Now after this it came about that David defeated the Philistines and subdued them; and David took control of the chief city from the hand of the Philistines.</verse>
<verse>He defeated Moab, and measured them with the line, making them lie down on the ground; and he measured two lines to put to death and one full line to keep alive. And the Moabites became servants to David, bringing tribute.</verse>
<verse>Then David defeated Hadadezer, the son of Rehob king of Zobah, as he went to restore his rule at the River.</verse>
<verse>David captured from him 1,700 horsemen and 20,000 foot soldiers; and David hamstrung the chariot horses, but reserved enough of them for 100 chariots.</verse>
<verse>When the Arameans of Damascus came to help Hadadezer, king of Zobah, David killed 22,000 Arameans.</verse>
<verse>Then David put garrisons among the Arameans of Damascus, and the Arameans became servants to David, bringing tribute. And the LORD helped David wherever he went.</verse>
<verse>David took the shields of gold which were carried by the servants of Hadadezer and brought them to Jerusalem.</verse>
<verse>From Betah and from Berothai, cities of Hadadezer, King David took a very large amount of bronze.</verse>
<verse>Now when Toi king of Hamath heard that David had defeated all the army of Hadadezer,</verse>
<verse>Toi sent Joram his son to King David to greet him and bless him, because he had fought against Hadadezer and defeated him; for Hadadezer had been at war with Toi. And Joram brought with him articles of silver, of gold and of bronze.</verse>
<verse>King David also dedicated these to the LORD, with the silver and gold that he had dedicated from all the nations which he had subdued:</verse>
<verse>from Aram and Moab and the sons of Ammon and the Philistines and Amalek, and from the spoil of Hadadezer, son of Rehob, king of Zobah.</verse>
<verse>So David made a name for himself when he returned from killing 18,000 Arameans in the Valley of Salt.</verse>
<verse>He put garrisons in Edom. In all Edom he put garrisons, and all the Edomites became servants to David. And the LORD helped David wherever he went.</verse>
<verse>So David reigned over all Israel; and David administered justice and righteousness for all his people.</verse>
<verse>Joab the son of Zeruiah was over the army, and Jehoshaphat the son of Ahilud was recorder.</verse>
<verse>Zadok the son of Ahitub and Ahimelech the son of Abiathar were priests, and Seraiah was secretary.</verse>
<verse>Benaiah the son of Jehoiada was over the Cherethites and the Pelethites; and David's sons were chief ministers.</verse>
</chapter>