<?xml version="1.0"?>
<chapter translation="KJV" testament="New" book="Titus" n="3">
      <verse>Put them in mind to be subject to principalities and powers, to obey magistrates, to be ready to every good work,
</verse><verse>To speak evil of no man, to be no brawlers, <supplied>but</supplied> gentle, shewing all meekness unto all men.
</verse><verse>For we ourselves also were sometimes foolish, disobedient, deceived, serving divers lusts and pleasures, living in malice and envy, hateful, <supplied>and</supplied> hating one another.
</verse><verse>But after that the kindness and love of God our Saviour toward man appeared,
</verse><verse>Not by works of righteousness which we have done, but according to his mercy he saved us, by the washing of regeneration, and renewing of the Holy Ghost;
</verse><verse>Which he shed on us abundantly through Jesus Christ our Saviour;
</verse><verse>That being justified by his grace, we should be made heirs according to the hope of eternal life.
</verse><verse><supplied>This is</supplied> a faithful saying, and these things I will that thou affirm constantly, that they which have believed in God might be careful to maintain good works. These things are good and profitable unto men.
</verse><verse>But avoid foolish questions, and genealogies, and contentions, and strivings about the law; for they are unprofitable and vain.
</verse><verse>A man that is an heretick after the first and second admonition reject;
</verse><verse>Knowing that he that is such is subverted, and sinneth, being condemned of himself.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>When I shall send Artemas unto thee, or Tychicus, be diligent to come unto me to Nicopolis: for I have determined there to winter.
</verse><verse>Bring Zenas the lawyer and Apollos on their journey diligently, that nothing be wanting unto them.
</verse><verse>And let ours also learn to maintain good works for necessary uses, that they be not unfruitful.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>All that are with me salute thee. Greet them that love us in the faith. Grace <supplied>be</supplied> with you all. Amen.
     
     
      </verse>
      </chapter>
