<?xml version="1.0"?>
<chapter translation="KJV" testament="Old" book="Exodus" n="1" book-chapters="40">
     
      <verse>Now these <supplied>are</supplied> the names of the children of Israel, which came into Egypt; every man and his household came with Jacob.
</verse><verse>Reuben, Simeon, Levi, and Judah,
</verse><verse>Issachar, Zebulun, and Benjamin,
</verse><verse>Dan, and Naphtali, Gad, and Asher.
</verse><verse>And all the souls that came out of the loins of Jacob were seventy souls: for Joseph was in Egypt <supplied>already. </supplied></verse><verse>And Joseph died, and all his brethren, and all that generation.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>And the children of Israel were fruitful, and increased abundantly, and multiplied, and waxed exceeding mighty; and the land was filled with them.
</verse><verse>Now there arose up a new king over Egypt, which knew not Joseph.
</verse><verse>And he said unto his people, Behold, the people of the children of Israel <supplied>are</supplied> more and mightier than we:
</verse><verse>Come on, let us deal wisely with them; lest they multiply, and it come to pass, that, when there falleth out any war, they join also unto our enemies, and fight against us, and <supplied>so</supplied> get them up out of the land.
</verse><verse>Therefore they did set over them taskmasters to afflict them with their burdens. And they built for Pharaoh treasure cities, Pithom and Raamses.
</verse><verse>But the more they afflicted them, the more they multiplied and grew. And they were grieved because of the children of Israel.
</verse><verse>And the Egyptians made the children of Israel to serve with rigour:
</verse><verse>And they made their lives bitter with hard bondage, in morter, and in brick, and in all manner of service in the field: all their service, wherein they made them serve, <supplied>was</supplied> with rigour.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>And the king of Egypt spake to the Hebrew midwives, of which the name of the one <supplied>was</supplied> Shiphrah, and the name of the other Puah:
</verse><verse>And he said, When ye do the office of a midwife to the Hebrew women, and see <supplied>them</supplied> upon the stools; if it <supplied>be</supplied> a son, then ye shall kill him: but if it <supplied>be</supplied> a daughter, then she shall live.
</verse><verse>But the midwives feared God, and did not as the king of Egypt commanded them, but saved the men children alive.
</verse><verse>And the king of Egypt called for the midwives, and said unto them, Why have ye done this thing, and have saved the men children alive?
</verse><verse>And the midwives said unto Pharaoh, Because the Hebrew women <supplied>are</supplied> not as the Egyptian women; for they <supplied>are</supplied> lively, and are delivered ere the midwives come in unto them.
</verse><verse>Therefore God dealt well with the midwives: and the people multiplied, and waxed very mighty.
</verse><verse>And it came to pass, because the midwives feared God, that he made them houses.
</verse><verse>And Pharaoh charged all his people, saying, Every son that is born ye shall cast into the river, and every daughter ye shall save alive.
     
      </verse>
      </chapter>
