<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Joel" book-id="29" n="1">
<verse>The word of the LORD that came to Joel son of Pethuel.</verse>
<verse>Hear this, you elders; listen, all who live in the land. Has anything like this ever happened in your days or in the days of your forefathers?</verse>
<verse>Tell it to your children, and let your children tell it to their children, and their children to the next generation.</verse>
<verse>What the locust swarm has left the great locusts have eaten; what the great locusts have left the young locusts have eaten; what the young locusts have left other locusts have eaten.</verse>
<verse>Wake up, you drunkards, and weep! Wail, all you drinkers of wine; wail because of the new wine, for it has been snatched from your lips.</verse>
<verse>A nation has invaded my land, powerful and without number; it has the teeth of a lion, the fangs of a lioness.</verse>
<verse>It has laid waste my vines and ruined my fig trees. It has stripped off their bark and thrown it away, leaving their branches white.</verse>
<verse>Mourn like a virgin in sackcloth grieving for the husband of her youth.</verse>
<verse>Grain offerings and drink offerings are cut off from the house of the LORD. The priests are in mourning, those who minister before the LORD.</verse>
<verse>The fields are ruined, the ground is dried up; the grain is destroyed, the new wine is dried up, the oil fails.</verse>
<verse>Despair, you farmers, wail, you vine growers; grieve for the wheat and the barley, because the harvest of the field is destroyed.</verse>
<verse>The vine is dried up and the fig tree is withered; the pomegranate, the palm and the apple tree- all the trees of the field-are dried up. Surely the joy of mankind is withered away.</verse>
<verse>Put on sackcloth, O priests, and mourn; wail, you who minister before the altar. Come, spend the night in sackcloth, you who minister before my God; for the grain offerings and drink offerings are withheld from the house of your God.</verse>
<verse>Declare a holy fast; call a sacred assembly. Summon the elders and all who live in the land to the house of the LORD your God, and cry out to the LORD.</verse>
<verse>Alas for that day! For the day of the LORD is near; it will come like destruction from the Almighty.</verse>
<verse>Has not the food been cut off before our very eyes- joy and gladness from the house of our God?</verse>
<verse>The seeds are shriveled beneath the clods. The storehouses are in ruins, the granaries have been broken down, for the grain has dried up.</verse>
<verse>How the cattle moan! The herds mill about because they have no pasture; even the flocks of sheep are suffering.</verse>
<verse>To you, O LORD, I call, for fire has devoured the open pastures and flames have burned up all the trees of the field.</verse>
<verse>Even the wild animals pant for you; the streams of water have dried up and fire has devoured the open pastures.</verse>
</chapter>