<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Joel" book-id="29" n="3">
<verse>"In those days and at that time, when I restore the fortunes of Judah and Jerusalem,</verse>
<verse>I will gather all nations and bring them down to the Valley of Jehoshaphat. There I will enter into judgment against them concerning my inheritance, my people Israel, for they scattered my people among the nations and divided up my land.</verse>
<verse>They cast lots for my people and traded boys for prostitutes; they sold girls for wine that they might drink.</verse>
<verse>"Now what have you against me, O Tyre and Sidon and all you regions of Philistia? Are you repaying me for something I have done? If you are paying me back, I will swiftly and speedily return on your own heads what you have done.</verse>
<verse>For you took my silver and my gold and carried off my finest treasures to your temples.</verse>
<verse>You sold the people of Judah and Jerusalem to the Greeks, that you might send them far from their homeland.</verse>
<verse>"See, I am going to rouse them out of the places to which you sold them, and I will return on your own heads what you have done.</verse>
<verse>I will sell your sons and daughters to the people of Judah, and they will sell them to the Sabeans, a nation far away." The LORD has spoken.</verse>
<verse>Proclaim this among the nations: Prepare for war! Rouse the warriors! Let all the fighting men draw near and attack.</verse>
<verse>Beat your plowshares into swords and your pruning hooks into spears. Let the weakling say, "I am strong!"</verse>
<verse>Come quickly, all you nations from every side, and assemble there. Bring down your warriors, O LORD!</verse>
<verse>"Let the nations be roused; let them advance into the Valley of Jehoshaphat, for there I will sit to judge all the nations on every side.</verse>
<verse>Swing the sickle, for the harvest is ripe. Come, trample the grapes, for the winepress is full and the vats overflow- so great is their wickedness!"</verse>
<verse>Multitudes, multitudes in the valley of decision! For the day of the LORD is near in the valley of decision.</verse>
<verse>The sun and moon will be darkened, and the stars no longer shine.</verse>
<verse>The LORD will roar from Zion and thunder from Jerusalem; the earth and the sky will tremble. But the LORD will be a refuge for his people, a stronghold for the people of Israel.</verse>
<verse>"Then you will know that I, the LORD your God, dwell in Zion, my holy hill. Jerusalem will be holy; never again will foreigners invade her.</verse>
<verse>"In that day the mountains will drip new wine, and the hills will flow with milk; all the ravines of Judah will run with water. A fountain will flow out of the LORD's house and will water the valley of acacias.</verse>
<verse>But Egypt will be desolate, Edom a desert waste, because of violence done to the people of Judah, in whose land they shed innocent blood.</verse>
<verse>Judah will be inhabited forever and Jerusalem through all generations.</verse>
<verse>Their bloodguilt, which I have not pardoned, I will pardon." The LORD dwells in Zion!</verse>
</chapter>