<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Habakkuk" book_id="35" n="1">
<verse>The problem as God gave Habakkuk to see it:</verse>
<verse>GOD, how long do I have to cry out for help before you listen? How many times do I have to yell, "Help! Murder! Police!" before you come to the rescue?</verse>
<verse>Why do you force me to look at evil, stare trouble in the face day after day? Anarchy and violence break out, quarrels and fights all over the place.</verse>
<verse>Law and order fall to pieces. Justice is a joke. The wicked have the righteous hamstrung and stand justice on its head.</verse>
<verse>"Look around at the godless nations. Look long and hard. Brace yourself for a shock. Something's about to take place and you're going to find it hard to believe.</verse>
<verse>I'm about to raise up Babylonians to punish you, Babylonians, fierce and ferocious--World-conquering Babylon, grabbing up nations right and left,</verse>
<verse>A dreadful and terrible people, making up its own rules as it goes.</verse>
<verse>Their horses run like the wind, attack like bloodthirsty wolves. A stampede of galloping horses thunders out of nowhere. They descend like vultures circling in on carrion.</verse>
<verse>They're out to kill. Death is on their minds. They collect victims like squirrels gathering nuts.</verse>
<verse>They mock kings, poke fun at generals, Spit on forts, and leave them in the dust.</verse>
<verse>They'll all be blown away by the wind. Brazen in sin, they call strength their god."</verse>
<verse>GOD, you're from eternity, aren't you? Holy God, we aren't going to die, are we? GOD, you chose Babylonians for your judgment work? Rock-Solid God, you gave them the job of discipline?</verse>
<verse>But you can't be serious! You can't condone evil! So why don't you do something about this? Why are you silent now? This outrage! Evil men swallow up the righteous and you stand around and watch! [JC]</verse>
<verse>You're treating men and women as so many fish in the ocean, Swimming without direction, swimming but not getting anywhere.</verse>
<verse>Then this evil Babylonian arrives and goes fishing. He pulls in a good catch. He catches his limit and fills his creel--a good day of fishing! He's happy!</verse>
<verse>He praises his rod and reel, piles his fishing gear on an altar and worships it! It's made his day, and he's going to eat well tonight! [JC]</verse>
<verse>Are you going to let this go on and on? Will you let this Babylonian fisherman Fish like a weekend angler, killing people as if they're nothing but fish? [JC]</verse>
</chapter>