<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="1 Kings" book_id="11" n="17">
<verse>Now Elijah the Tishbite, from Tishbe in Gilead, said to Ahab, "As the LORD, the God of Israel, lives, whom I serve, there will be neither dew nor rain in the next few years except at my word."</verse>
<verse>Then the word of the LORD came to Elijah:</verse>
<verse>"Leave here, turn eastward and hide in the Kerith Ravine, east of the Jordan.</verse>
<verse>You will drink from the brook, and I have ordered the ravens to feed you there."</verse>
<verse>So he did what the LORD had told him. He went to the Kerith Ravine, east of the Jordan, and stayed there.</verse>
<verse>The ravens brought him bread and meat in the morning and bread and meat in the evening, and he drank from the brook.</verse>
<verse>Some time later the brook dried up because there had been no rain in the land.</verse>
<verse>Then the word of the LORD came to him:</verse>
<verse>"Go at once to Zarephath of Sidon and stay there. I have commanded a widow in that place to supply you with food."</verse>
<verse>So he went to Zarephath. When he came to the town gate, a widow was there gathering sticks. He called to her and asked, "Would you bring me a little water in a jar so I may have a drink?"</verse>
<verse>As she was going to get it, he called, "And bring me, please, a piece of bread."</verse>
<verse>"As surely as the LORD your God lives," she replied, "I don't have any bread-only a handful of flour in a jar and a little oil in a jug. I am gathering a few sticks to take home and make a meal for myself and my son, that we may eat it-and die."</verse>
<verse>Elijah said to her, "Don't be afraid. Go home and do as you have said. But first make a small cake of bread for me from what you have and bring it to me, and then make something for yourself and your son.</verse>
<verse>For this is what the LORD, the God of Israel, says: 'The jar of flour will not be used up and the jug of oil will not run dry until the day the LORD gives rain on the land.'"</verse>
<verse>She went away and did as Elijah had told her. So there was food every day for Elijah and for the woman and her family.</verse>
<verse>For the jar of flour was not used up and the jug of oil did not run dry, in keeping with the word of the LORD spoken by Elijah.</verse>
<verse>Some time later the son of the woman who owned the house became ill. He grew worse and worse, and finally stopped breathing.</verse>
<verse>She said to Elijah, "What do you have against me, man of God? Did you come to remind me of my sin and kill my son?"</verse>
<verse>"Give me your son," Elijah replied. He took him from her arms, carried him to the upper room where he was staying, and laid him on his bed.</verse>
<verse>Then he cried out to the LORD, "O LORD my God, have you brought tragedy also upon this widow I am staying with, by causing her son to die?"</verse>
<verse>Then he stretched himself out on the boy three times and cried to the LORD, "O LORD my God, let this boy's life return to him!"</verse>
<verse>The LORD heard Elijah's cry, and the boy's life returned to him, and he lived.</verse>
<verse>Elijah picked up the child and carried him down from the room into the house. He gave him to his mother and said, "Look, your son is alive!"</verse>
<verse>Then the woman said to Elijah, "Now I know that you are a man of God and that the word of the LORD from your mouth is the truth."</verse>
</chapter>