<chapter translation="ESV" testament="Old" book="1 Chronicles" book_id="13" n="1">
<verse>Adam, Seth, Enosh;</verse>
<verse>Kenan, Mahalalel, Jared;</verse>
<verse>Enoch, Methuselah, Lamech;</verse>
<verse>Noah, Shem, Ham, and Japheth.</verse>
<verse>The sons of Japheth: Gomer, Magog, Madai, Javan, Tubal, Meshech, and Tiras.</verse>
<verse>The sons of Gomer: Ashkenaz, Riphath, and Togarmah.</verse>
<verse>The sons of Javan: Elishah, Tarshish, Kittim, and Rodanim.</verse>
<verse>The sons of Ham: Cush, Egypt, Put, and Canaan.</verse>
<verse>The sons of Cush: Seba, Havilah, Sabta, Raama, and Sabteca. The sons of Raamah: Sheba and Dedan.</verse>
<verse>Cush fathered Nimrod. He was the first on earth to be a mighty man.</verse>
<verse>Egypt fathered Ludim, Anamim, Lehabim, Naphtuhim,</verse>
<verse>Pathrusim, Casluhim (from whom the Philistines came), and Caphtorim.</verse>
<verse>Canaan fathered Sidon his firstborn and Heth,</verse>
<verse>and the Jebusites, the Amorites, the Girgashites,</verse>
<verse>the Hivites, the Arkites, the Sinites,</verse>
<verse>the Arvadites, the Zemarites, and the Hamathites.</verse>
<verse>The sons of Shem: Elam, Asshur, Arpachshad, Lud, and Aram. And the sons of Aram: Uz, Hul, Gether, and Meshech.</verse>
<verse>Arpachshad fathered Shelah, and Shelah fathered Eber.</verse>
<verse>To Eber were born two sons: the name of the one was Peleg (for in his days the earth was divided), and his brother's name was Joktan.</verse>
<verse>Joktan fathered Almodad, Sheleph, Hazarmaveth, Jerah,</verse>
<verse>Hadoram, Uzal, Diklah,</verse>
<verse>Obal, Abimael, Sheba,</verse>
<verse>Ophir, Havilah, and Jobab; all these were the sons of Joktan.</verse>
<verse>Shem, Arpachshad, Shelah;</verse>
<verse>Eber, Peleg, Reu;</verse>
<verse>Serug, Nahor, Terah;</verse>
<verse>Abram, that is, Abraham.</verse>
<verse>The sons of Abraham: Isaac and Ishmael.</verse>
<verse>These are their genealogies: the firstborn of Ishmael, Nebaioth, and Kedar, Adbeel, Mibsam,</verse>
<verse>Mishma, Dumah, Massa, Hadad, Tema,</verse>
<verse>Jetur, Naphish, and Kedemah. These are the sons of Ishmael.</verse>
<verse>The sons of Keturah, Abraham's concubine: she bore Zimran, Jokshan, Medan, Midian, Ishbak, and Shuah. The sons of Jokshan: Sheba and Dedan.</verse>
<verse>The sons of Midian: Ephah, Epher, Hanoch, Abida, and Eldaah. All these were the descendants of Keturah.</verse>
<verse>Abraham fathered Isaac. The sons of Isaac: Esau and Israel.</verse>
<verse>The sons of Esau: Eliphaz, Reuel, Jeush, Jalam, and Korah.</verse>
<verse>The sons of Eliphaz: Teman, Omar, Zepho, Gatam, Kenaz, and of Timna, Amalek.</verse>
<verse>The sons of Reuel: Nahath, Zerah, Shammah, and Mizzah.</verse>
<verse>The sons of Seir: Lotan, Shobal, Zibeon, Anah, Dishon, Ezer, and Dishan.</verse>
<verse>The sons of Lotan: Hori and Hemam; and Lotan's sister was Timna.</verse>
<verse>The sons of Shobal: Alvan, Manahath, Ebal, Shepho, and Onam. The sons of Zibeon: Aiah and Anah.</verse>
<verse>The son of Anah: Dishon. The sons of Dishon: Hemdan, Eshban, Ithran, and Cheran.</verse>
<verse>The sons of Ezer: Bilhan, Zaavan, and Akan. The sons of Dishan: Uz and Aran.</verse>
<verse>These are the kings who reigned in the land of Edom before any king reigned over the people of Israel: Bela the son of Beor, the name of his city being Dinhabah.</verse>
<verse>Bela died, and Jobab the son of Zerah of Bozrah reigned in his place.</verse>
<verse>Jobab died, and Husham of the land of the Temanites reigned in his place.</verse>
<verse>Husham died, and Hadad the son of Bedad, who defeated Midian in the country of Moab, reigned in his place, the name of his city being Avith.</verse>
<verse>Hadad died, and Samlah of Masrekah reigned in his place.</verse>
<verse>Samlah died, and Shaul of Rehoboth on the Euphrates reigned in his place.</verse>
<verse>Shaul died, and Baal-hanan, the son of Achbor, reigned in his place.</verse>
<verse>Baal-hanan died, and Hadad reigned in his place, the name of his city being Pai; and his wife's name was Mehetabel, the daughter of Matred, the daughter of Mezahab.</verse>
<verse>And Hadad died.The chiefs of Edom were: chiefs Timna, Alvah, Jetheth,</verse>
<verse>Oholibamah, Elah, Pinon,</verse>
<verse>Kenaz, Teman, Mibzar,</verse>
<verse>Magdiel, and Iram; these are the chiefs of Edom.</verse>
</chapter>