<chapter translation="ESV" testament="Old" book="1 Chronicles" book_id="13" n="2">
<verse>These are the sons of Israel: Reuben, Simeon, Levi, Judah, Issachar, Zebulun,</verse>
<verse>Dan, Joseph, Benjamin, Naphtali, Gad, and Asher.</verse>
<verse>The sons of Judah: Er, Onan and Shelah; these three Bath-shua the Canaanite bore to him. Now Er, Judah's firstborn, was evil in the sight of the LORD, and he put him to death.</verse>
<verse>His daughter-in-law Tamar also bore him Perez and Zerah. Judah had five sons in all.</verse>
<verse>The sons of Perez: Hezron and Hamul.</verse>
<verse>The sons of Zerah: Zimri, Ethan, Heman, Calcol, and Dara, five in all.</verse>
<verse>The son of Carmi: Achan, the troubler of Israel, who broke faith in the matter of the devoted thing;</verse>
<verse>and Ethan's son was Azariah.</verse>
<verse>The sons of Hezron that were born to him: Jerahmeel, Ram, and Chelubai.</verse>
<verse>Ram fathered Amminadab, and Amminadab fathered Nahshon, prince of the sons of Judah.</verse>
<verse>Nahshon fathered Salmon, Salmon fathered Boaz,</verse>
<verse>Boaz fathered Obed, Obed fathered Jesse.</verse>
<verse>Jesse fathered Eliab his firstborn, Abinadab the second, Shimea the third,</verse>
<verse>Nethanel the fourth, Raddai the fifth,</verse>
<verse>Ozem the sixth, David the seventh.</verse>
<verse>And their sisters were Zeruiah and Abigail. The sons of Zeruiah: Abishai, Joab, and Asahel, three.</verse>
<verse>Abigail bore Amasa, and the father of Amasa was Jether the Ishmaelite.</verse>
<verse>Caleb the son of Hezron fathered children by his wife Azubah, and by Jerioth; and these were her sons: Jesher, Shobab, and Ardon.</verse>
<verse>When Azubah died, Caleb married Ephrath, who bore him Hur.</verse>
<verse>Hur fathered Uri, and Uri fathered Bezalel.</verse>
<verse>Afterward Hezron went in to the daughter of Machir the father of Gilead, whom he married when he was sixty years old, and she bore him Segub.</verse>
<verse>And Segub fathered Jair, who had twenty-three cities in the land of Gilead.</verse>
<verse>But Geshur and Aram took from them Havvoth-jair, Kenath, and its villages, sixty towns. All these were descendants of Machir, the father of Gilead.</verse>
<verse>After the death of Hezron, Caleb went in to Ephrathah, the wife of Hezron his father, and she bore him Ashhur, the father of Tekoa.</verse>
<verse>The sons of Jerahmeel, the firstborn of Hezron: Ram, his firstborn, Bunah, Oren, Ozem, and Ahijah.</verse>
<verse>Jerahmeel also had another wife, whose name was Atarah; she was the mother of Onam.</verse>
<verse>The sons of Ram, the firstborn of Jerahmeel: Maaz, Jamin, and Eker.</verse>
<verse>The sons of Onam: Shammai and Jada. The sons of Shammai: Nadab and Abishur.</verse>
<verse>The name of Abishur's wife was Abihail, and she bore him Ahban and Molid.</verse>
<verse>The sons of Nadab: Seled and Appaim; and Seled died childless.</verse>
<verse>The son of Appaim: Ishi. The son of Ishi: Sheshan. The son of Sheshan: Ahlai.</verse>
<verse>The sons of Jada, Shammai's brother: Jether and Jonathan; and Jether died childless.</verse>
<verse>The sons of Jonathan: Peleth and Zaza. These were the descendants of Jerahmeel.</verse>
<verse>Now Sheshan had no sons, only daughters, but Sheshan had an Egyptian slave whose name was Jarha.</verse>
<verse>So Sheshan gave his daughter in marriage to Jarha his slave, and she bore him Attai.</verse>
<verse>Attai fathered Nathan, and Nathan fathered Zabad.</verse>
<verse>Zabad fathered Ephlal, and Ephlal fathered Obed.</verse>
<verse>Obed fathered Jehu, and Jehu fathered Azariah.</verse>
<verse>Azariah fathered Helez, and Helez fathered Eleasah.</verse>
<verse>Eleasah fathered Sismai, and Sismai fathered Shallum.</verse>
<verse>Shallum fathered Jekamiah, and Jekamiah fathered Elishama.</verse>
<verse>The sons of Caleb the brother of Jerahmeel: Mareshah his firstborn, who fathered Ziph. The son of Mareshah: Hebron.</verse>
<verse>The sons of Hebron: Korah, Tappuah, Rekem and Shema.</verse>
<verse>Shema fathered Raham, the father of Jorkeam; and Rekem fathered Shammai.</verse>
<verse>The son of Shammai: Maon; and Maon fathered Beth-zur.</verse>
<verse>Ephah also, Caleb's concubine, bore Haran, Moza, and Gazez; and Haran fathered Gazez.</verse>
<verse>The sons of Jahdai: Regem, Jotham, Geshan, Pelet, Ephah, and Shaaph.</verse>
<verse>Maacah, Caleb's concubine, bore Sheber and Tirhanah.</verse>
<verse>She also bore Shaaph the father of Madmannah, Sheva the father of Machbenah and the father of Gibea; and the daughter of Caleb was Achsah.</verse>
<verse>These were the descendants of Caleb.The sons of Hur the firstborn of Ephrathah: Shobal the father of Kiriath-jearim,</verse>
<verse>Salma, the father of Bethlehem, and Hareph the father of Beth-gader.</verse>
<verse>Shobal the father of Kiriath-jearim had other sons: Haroeh, half of the Menuhoth.</verse>
<verse>And the clans of Kiriath-jearim: the Ithrites, the Puthites, the Shumathites, and the Mishraites; from these came the Zorathites and the Eshtaolites.</verse>
<verse>The sons of Salma: Bethlehem, the Netophathites, Atroth-beth-joab and half of the Manahathites, the Zorites.</verse>
<verse>The clans also of the scribes who lived at Jabez: the Tirathites, the Shimeathites and the Sucathites. These are the Kenites who came from Hammath, the father of the house of Rechab.</verse>
</chapter>