<chapter translation="ESV" testament="Old" book="1 Chronicles" book-id="13" n="8">
<verse>Benjamin fathered Bela his firstborn, Ashbel the second, Aharah the third,</verse>
<verse>Nohah the fourth, and Rapha the fifth.</verse>
<verse>And Bela had sons: Addar, Gera, Abihud,</verse>
<verse>Abishua, Naaman, Ahoah,</verse>
<verse>Gera, Shephuphan, and Huram.</verse>
<verse>These are the sons of Ehud (they were heads of fathers' houses of the inhabitants of Geba, and they were carried into exile to Manahath):</verse>
<verse>Naaman, Ahijah, and Gera, that is, Heglam, who fathered Uzza and Ahihud.</verse>
<verse>And Shaharaim fathered sons in the country of Moab after he had sent away Hushim and Baara his wives.</verse>
<verse>He fathered sons by Hodesh his wife: Jobab, Zibia, Mesha, Malcam,</verse>
<verse>Jeuz, Sachia, and Mirmah. These were his sons, heads of fathers' houses.</verse>
<verse>He also fathered sons by Hushim: Abitub and Elpaal.</verse>
<verse>The sons of Elpaal: Eber, Misham, and Shemed, who built Ono and Lod with its towns,</verse>
<verse>and Beriah and Shema (they were heads of fathers' houses of the inhabitants of Aijalon, who caused the inhabitants of Gath to flee);</verse>
<verse>and Ahio, Shashak, and Jeremoth.</verse>
<verse>Zebadiah, Arad, Eder,</verse>
<verse>Michael, Ishpah, and Joha were sons of Beriah.</verse>
<verse>Zebadiah, Meshullam, Hizki, Heber,</verse>
<verse>Ishmerai, Izliah, and Jobab were the sons of Elpaal.</verse>
<verse>Jakim, Zichri, Zabdi,</verse>
<verse>Elienai, Zillethai, Eliel,</verse>
<verse>Adaiah, Beraiah, and Shimrath were the sons of Shimei.</verse>
<verse>Ishpan, Eber, Eliel,</verse>
<verse>Abdon, Zichri, Hanan,</verse>
<verse>Hananiah, Elam, Anthothijah,</verse>
<verse>Iphdeiah, and Penuel were the sons of Shashak.</verse>
<verse>Shamsherai, Shehariah, Athaliah,</verse>
<verse>Jaareshiah, Elijah, and Zichri were the sons of Jeroham.</verse>
<verse>These were the heads of fathers' houses, according to their generations, chief men. These lived in Jerusalem.</verse>
<verse>Jeiel the father of Gibeon lived in Gibeon, and the name of his wife was Maacah.</verse>
<verse>His firstborn son: Abdon, then Zur, Kish, Baal, Nadab,</verse>
<verse>Gedor, Ahio, Zecher,</verse>
<verse>and Mikloth (he fathered Shimeah). Now these also lived opposite their kinsmen in Jerusalem, with their kinsmen.</verse>
<verse>Ner was the father of Kish, Kish of Saul, Saul of Jonathan, Malchi-shua, Abinadab and Eshbaal;</verse>
<verse>and the son of Jonathan was Merib-baal; and Merib-baal was the father of Micah.</verse>
<verse>The sons of Micah: Pithon, Melech, Tarea, and Ahaz.</verse>
<verse>Ahaz fathered Jehoaddah, and Jehoaddah fathered Alemeth, Azmaveth, and Zimri. Zimri fathered Moza.</verse>
<verse>Moza fathered Binea; Raphah was his son, Eleasah his son, Azel his son.</verse>
<verse>Azel had six sons, and these are their names: Azrikam, Bocheru, Ishmael, Sheariah, Obadiah, and Hanan. All these were the sons of Azel.</verse>
<verse>The sons of Eshek his brother: Ulam his firstborn, Jeush the second, and Eliphelet the third.</verse>
<verse>The sons of Ulam were men who were mighty warriors, bowmen, having many sons and grandsons, 150. All these were Benjaminites.</verse>
</chapter>