<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Hosea" book-id="28" n="4">
<verse>Hear the word of the LORD, you Israelites, because the LORD has a charge to bring against you who live in the land: "There is no faithfulness, no love, no acknowledgment of God in the land.</verse>
<verse>There is only cursing, lying and murder, stealing and adultery; they break all bounds, and bloodshed follows bloodshed.</verse>
<verse>Because of this the land mourns, and all who live in it waste away; the beasts of the field and the birds of the air and the fish of the sea are dying.</verse>
<verse>"But let no man bring a charge, let no man accuse another, for your people are like those who bring charges against a priest.</verse>
<verse>You stumble day and night, and the prophets stumble with you. So I will destroy your mother-</verse>
<verse>my people are destroyed from lack of knowledge. "Because you have rejected knowledge, I also reject you as my priests; because you have ignored the law of your God, I also will ignore your children.</verse>
<verse>The more the priests increased, the more they sinned against me; they exchanged their Glory for something disgraceful.</verse>
<verse>They feed on the sins of my people and relish their wickedness.</verse>
<verse>And it will be: Like people, like priests. I will punish both of them for their ways and repay them for their deeds.</verse>
<verse>"They will eat but not have enough; they will engage in prostitution but not increase, because they have deserted the LORD to give themselves</verse>
<verse>to prostitution, to old wine and new, which take away the understanding</verse>
<verse>of my people. They consult a wooden idol and are answered by a stick of wood. A spirit of prostitution leads them astray; they are unfaithful to their God.</verse>
<verse>They sacrifice on the mountaintops and burn offerings on the hills, under oak, poplar and terebinth, where the shade is pleasant. Therefore your daughters turn to prostitution and your daughters-in-law to adultery.</verse>
<verse>"I will not punish your daughters when they turn to prostitution, nor your daughters-in-law when they commit adultery, because the men themselves consort with harlots and sacrifice with shrine prostitutes- a people without understanding will come to ruin!</verse>
<verse>"Though you commit adultery, O Israel, let not Judah become guilty. "Do not go to Gilgal; do not go up to Beth Aven. And do not swear, 'As surely as the LORD lives!'</verse>
<verse>The Israelites are stubborn, like a stubborn heifer. How then can the LORD pasture them like lambs in a meadow?</verse>
<verse>Ephraim is joined to idols; leave him alone!</verse>
<verse>Even when their drinks are gone, they continue their prostitution; their rulers dearly love shameful ways.</verse>
<verse>A whirlwind will sweep them away, and their sacrifices will bring them shame.</verse>
</chapter>