<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Hosea" book-id="28" n="7">
<verse>whenever I would heal Israel, the sins of Ephraim are exposed and the crimes of Samaria revealed. They practice deceit, thieves break into houses, bandits rob in the streets;</verse>
<verse>but they do not realize that I remember all their evil deeds. Their sins engulf them; they are always before me.</verse>
<verse>"They delight the king with their wickedness, the princes with their lies.</verse>
<verse>They are all adulterers, burning like an oven whose fire the baker need not stir from the kneading of the dough till it rises.</verse>
<verse>On the day of the festival of our king the princes become inflamed with wine, and he joins hands with the mockers.</verse>
<verse>Their hearts are like an oven; they approach him with intrigue. Their passion smolders all night; in the morning it blazes like a flaming fire.</verse>
<verse>All of them are hot as an oven; they devour their rulers. All their kings fall, and none of them calls on me.</verse>
<verse>"Ephraim mixes with the nations; Ephraim is a flat cake not turned over.</verse>
<verse>Foreigners sap his strength, but he does not realize it. His hair is sprinkled with gray, but he does not notice.</verse>
<verse>Israel's arrogance testifies against him, but despite all this he does not return to the LORD his God or search for him.</verse>
<verse>"Ephraim is like a dove, easily deceived and senseless- now calling to Egypt, now turning to Assyria.</verse>
<verse>When they go, I will throw my net over them; I will pull them down like birds of the air. When I hear them flocking together, I will catch them.</verse>
<verse>Woe to them, because they have strayed from me! Destruction to them, because they have rebelled against me! I long to redeem them but they speak lies against me.</verse>
<verse>They do not cry out to me from their hearts but wail upon their beds. They gather together for grain and new wine but turn away from me.</verse>
<verse>I trained them and strengthened them, but they plot evil against me.</verse>
<verse>They do not turn to the Most High; they are like a faulty bow. Their leaders will fall by the sword because of their insolent words. For this they will be ridiculed in the land of Egypt.</verse>
</chapter>