<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="1 Kings" book_id="11" n="4">
<verse>Now King Solomon was king over all Israel.</verse>
<verse>These were his officials: Azariah the son of Zadok was the priest;</verse>
<verse>Elihoreph and Ahijah, the sons of Shisha were secretaries; Jehoshaphat the son of Ahilud was the recorder;</verse>
<verse>and Benaiah the son of Jehoiada was over the army; and Zadok and Abiathar were priests;</verse>
<verse>and Azariah the son of Nathan was over the deputies; and Zabud the son of Nathan, a priest, was the king's friend;</verse>
<verse>and Ahishar was over the household; and Adoniram the son of Abda was over the men subject to forced labor.</verse>
<verse>Solomon had twelve deputies over all Israel, who provided for the king and his household; each man had to provide for a month in the year.</verse>
<verse>These are their names: Ben-hur, in the hill country of Ephraim;</verse>
<verse>Ben-deker in Makaz and Shaalbim and Beth-shemesh and Elonbeth-hanan;</verse>
<verse>Ben-hesed, in Arubboth ( Socoh was his and all the land of Hepher);</verse>
<verse>Ben-abinadab, in all the height of Dor (Taphath the daughter of Solomon was his wife);</verse>
<verse>Baana the son of Ahilud, in Taanach and Megiddo, and all Beth-shean which is beside Zarethan below Jezreel, from Beth-shean to Abel-meholah as far as the other side of Jokmeam;</verse>
<verse>Ben-geber, in Ramoth-gilead ( the towns of Jair, the son of Manasseh, which are in Gilead were his: the region of Argob, which is in Bashan, sixty great cities with walls and bronze bars were his);</verse>
<verse>Ahinadab the son of Iddo, in Mahanaim;</verse>
<verse>Ahimaaz, in Naphtali (he also married Basemath the daughter of Solomon);</verse>
<verse>Baana the son of Hushai, in Asher and Bealoth;</verse>
<verse>Jehoshaphat the son of Paruah, in Issachar;</verse>
<verse>Shimei the son of Ela, in Benjamin;</verse>
<verse>Geber the son of Uri, in the land of Gilead, the country of Sihon king of the Amorites and of Og king of Bashan; and he was the only deputy who was in the land.</verse>
<verse>Judah and Israel were as numerous as the sand that is on the seashore in abundance; they were eating and drinking and rejoicing.</verse>
<verse>Now Solomon ruled over all the kingdoms from the River to the land of the Philistines and to the border of Egypt; they brought tribute and served Solomon all the days of his life.</verse>
<verse>Solomon's provision for one day was thirty kors of fine flour and sixty kors of meal,</verse>
<verse>ten fat oxen, twenty pasture-fed oxen, a hundred sheep besides deer, gazelles, roebucks, and fattened fowl.</verse>
<verse>For he had dominion over everything west of the River, from Tiphsah even to Gaza, over all the kings west of the River; and he had peace on all sides around about him.</verse>
<verse>So Judah and Israel lived in safety, every man under his vine and his fig tree, from Dan even to Beersheba, all the days of Solomon.</verse>
<verse>Solomon had 40,000 stalls of horses for his chariots, and 12,000 horsemen.</verse>
<verse>Those deputies provided for King Solomon and all who came to King Solomon's table, each in his month; they left nothing lacking.</verse>
<verse>They also brought barley and straw for the horses and swift steeds to the place where it should be, each according to his charge.</verse>
<verse>Now God gave Solomon wisdom and very great discernment and breadth of mind, like the sand that is on the seashore.</verse>
<verse>Solomon's wisdom surpassed the wisdom of all the sons of the east and all the wisdom of Egypt.</verse>
<verse>For he was wiser than all men, than Ethan the Ezrahite, Heman, Calcol and Darda, the sons of Mahol; and his fame was known in all the surrounding nations.</verse>
<verse>He also spoke 3,000 proverbs, and his songs were 1,005.</verse>
<verse>He spoke of trees, from the cedar that is in Lebanon even to the hyssop that grows on the wall; he spoke also of animals and birds and creeping things and fish.</verse>
<verse>Men came from all peoples to hear the wisdom of Solomon, from all the kings of the earth who had heard of his wisdom.</verse>
</chapter>