<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Leviticus" book-id="3" n="1">
<verse>GOD called Moses and spoke to him from the Tent of Meeting:</verse>
<verse>"Speak to the People of Israel. Tell them, When anyone presents an offering to GOD, present an animal from either the herd or the flock.</verse>
<verse>"If the offering is a Whole-Burnt-Offering from the herd, present a male without a defect at the entrance to the Tent of Meeting that it may be accepted by GOD.</verse>
<verse>Lay your hand on the head of the Whole-Burnt-Offering so that it may be accepted on your behalf to make atonement for you.</verse>
<verse>Slaughter the bull in GOD's presence. Aaron's sons, the priests, will make an offering of the blood by splashing it against all sides of the Altar that stands at the entrance to the Tent of Meeting.</verse>
<verse>Next, skin the Whole-Burnt-Offering and cut it up.</verse>
<verse>Aaron's sons, the priests, will prepare a fire on the Altar, carefully laying out the wood,</verse>
<verse>and then arrange the body parts, including the head and the suet, on the wood prepared for the fire on the Altar.</verse>
<verse>Scrub the entrails and legs clean. The priest will burn it all on the Altar: a Whole-Burnt-Offering, a Fire-Gift, a pleasing fragrance to GOD.</verse>
<verse>"If the Whole-Burnt-Offering comes from the flock, whether sheep or goat, present a male without defect.</verse>
<verse>Slaughter it on the north side of the Altar in GOD's presence. The sons of Aaron, the priests, will throw the blood against all sides of the Altar.</verse>
<verse>Cut it up and the priest will arrange the pieces, including the head and the suet, on the wood prepared for burning on the Altar.</verse>
<verse>Scrub the entrails and legs clean. The priest will offer it all, burning it on the Altar: a Whole-Burnt-Offering, a Fire-Gift, a pleasing fragrance to GOD.</verse>
<verse>"If a bird is presented to GOD for the Whole-Burnt-Offering it can be either a dove or a pigeon.</verse>
<verse>The priest will bring it to the Altar, wring off its head, and burn it on the Altar. But he will first drain the blood on the side of the Altar,</verse>
<verse>remove the gizzard and its contents, and throw them on the east side of the Altar where the ashes are piled.</verse>
<verse>Then rip it open by its wings but leave it in one piece and burn it on the Altar on the wood prepared for the fire: a Whole-Burnt-Offering, a Fire-Gift, a pleasing fragrance to GOD.</verse>
</chapter>