<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Leviticus" book_id="3" n="14">
<verse>GOD spoke to Moses,</verse>
<verse>"These are the instructions for the infected person at the time of his cleansing. First, bring him to the priest.</verse>
<verse>The priest will take him outside the camp and make an examination; if the infected person has been healed of the serious skin disease,</verse>
<verse>the priest will order two live, clean birds, some cedar wood, scarlet thread, and hyssop to be brought for the one to be cleansed.</verse>
<verse>The priest will order him to kill one of the birds over fresh water in a clay pot.</verse>
<verse>The priest will then take the live bird with the cedar wood, the scarlet thread, and the hyssop and dip them in the blood of the dead bird over fresh water</verse>
<verse>and then sprinkle the person being cleansed from the serious skin disease seven times and pronounce him clean. Finally, he will release the live bird in the open field.</verse>
<verse>The cleansed person, after washing his clothes, shaving off all his hair, and bathing with water, is clean. Afterwards he may again enter the camp, but he has to live outside his tent for seven days.</verse>
<verse>On the seventh day, he must shave off all his hair--from his head, beard, eyebrows, all of it. He then must wash his clothes and bathe all over with water. He will be clean.</verse>
<verse>"The next day, the eighth day, he will bring two lambs without defect and a yearling ewe without defect, along with roughly six quarts of fine flour mixed with oil.</verse>
<verse>The priest who pronounces him clean will place him and the materials for his offerings in the presence of GOD at the entrance to the Tent of Meeting.</verse>
<verse>The priest will take one of the lambs and present it and the pint of oil as a Compensation-Offering and lift them up as a Wave-Offering before GOD.</verse>
<verse>He will slaughter the lamb in the place where the Absolution-Offering and the Whole-Burnt-Offering are slaughtered, in the Holy Place, because like the Absolution-Offering, the Compensation-Offering belongs to the priest; it is most holy.</verse>
<verse>The priest will now take some of the blood of the Compensation-Offering and put it on the right earlobe of the man being cleansed, on the thumb of his right hand, and on the big toe of his right foot.</verse>
<verse>Following that he will take some oil and pour it into the palm of his left hand</verse>
<verse>and then with the finger of his right hand sprinkle oil seven times before GOD.</verse>
<verse>The priest will put some of the remaining oil on the right earlobe of the one being cleansed, on the thumb of his right hand, and on the big toe of his right foot, placing it on top of the blood of the Compensation-Offering.</verse>
<verse>He will put the rest of the oil on the head of the man being cleansed and make atonement for him before GOD.</verse>
<verse>"Finally the priest will sacrifice the Absolution-Offering and make atonement for the one to be cleansed from his uncleanness, slaughter the Whole-Burnt-Offering</verse>
<verse>and offer it with the Grain-Offering on the Altar. He has made atonement for him. He is clean.</verse>
<verse>"If he is poor and cannot afford these offerings, he will bring one male lamb as a Compensation-Offering to be offered as a Wave-Offering to make atonement for him, and with it a couple of quarts of fine flour mixed with oil for a Grain-Offering, a pint of oil,</verse>
<verse>and two doves or pigeons which he can afford, one for an Absolution-Offering and the other for a Whole-Burnt-Offering.</verse>
<verse>"On the eighth day he will bring them to the priest at the entrance to the Tent of Meeting before the presence of GOD.</verse>
<verse>The priest will take the lamb for the Compensation-Offering together with the pint of oil and wave them before GOD as a Wave-Offering.</verse>
<verse>He will slaughter the lamb for the Compensation-Offering, take some of its blood and put it on the lobe of the right ear of the one to be cleansed, on the thumb of his right hand, and on the big toe of his right foot.</verse>
<verse>The priest will pour some of the oil into the palm of his left hand,</verse>
<verse>and with his right finger sprinkle some of the oil from his palm seven times before GOD.</verse>
<verse>He will put some of the oil that is in his palm on the same places he put the blood of the Compensation-Offering, on the lobe of the right ear of the one to be cleansed, on the thumb of his right hand, and on the big toe of his right foot.</verse>
<verse>The priest will take what is left of the oil in his palm and put it on the head of the one to be cleansed, making atonement for him before GOD.</verse>
<verse>"At the last, he will sacrifice the doves or pigeons which are within his means,</verse>
<verse>one as an Absolution-Offering and the other as a Whole-Burnt-Offering along with the Grain-Offering. Following this procedure the priest will make atonement for the one to be cleansed before GOD."</verse>
<verse>These are the instructions to be followed for anyone who has a serious skin disease and cannot afford the regular offerings for his cleansing. [JC]</verse>
<verse>GOD spoke to Moses and Aaron,</verse>
<verse>"When you enter the land of Canaan, which I'm giving to you as a possession, and I put a serious fungus in a house in the land of your possession,</verse>
<verse>the householder is to go and tell the priest, "I have some kind of fungus in my house.'</verse>
<verse>The priest is to order the house vacated until he can come to examine the fungus, so that nothing in the house is declared unclean.</verse>
<verse>When the priest comes and examines the house, if the fungus on the walls of the house has greenish or rusty swelling that appears to go deeper than the surface of the wall,</verse>
<verse>the priest is to walk out the door and shut the house up for seven days.</verse>
<verse>On the seventh day he is to come back and conduct another examination; if the fungus has spread in the walls of the house,</verse>
<verse>he is to order that the stones affected by the fungus be torn out and thrown in a garbage dump outside the city.</verse>
<verse>He is to make sure the entire inside of the house is scraped and the plaster that is removed be taken away to the garbage dump outside the city.</verse>
<verse>Then he is to replace the stones and replaster the house.</verse>
<verse>"If the fungus breaks out again in the house after the stones have been torn out and the house has been scraped and plastered,</verse>
<verse>the priest is to come and conduct an examination; if the fungus has spread, it is a malignant fungus. The house is unclean.</verse>
<verse>The house has to be demolished--its stones, wood, and plaster are to be removed to the garbage dump outside the city.</verse>
<verse>Anyone who enters the house while it is closed up is unclean until evening.</verse>
<verse>Anyone who sleeps or eats in the house must wash his clothes.</verse>
<verse>"But if when the priest comes and conducts his examination, he finds that the fungus has not spread after the house has been replastered, the priest is to declare that the house is clean; the fungus is cured.</verse>
<verse>He then is to purify the house by taking two birds, some cedar wood, scarlet thread, and hyssop.</verse>
<verse>He will slaughter one bird over fresh water in a clay pot.</verse>
<verse>Then he will take the cedar wood, the hyssop, the scarlet thread, and the living bird, dip them in the blood of the killed bird and the fresh water and sprinkle the house seven times,</verse>
<verse>cleansing the house with the blood of the bird, the fresh water, the living bird, the cedar wood, the hyssop, and the scarlet thread.</verse>
<verse>Last of all, he will let the living bird loose outside the city in the open field. He has made atonement for the house; the house is clean.</verse>
<verse>"These are the procedures to be followed for every kind of serious skin disease or itch,</verse>
<verse>for mildew or fungus on clothing or in a house,</verse>
<verse>and for a swelling or blister or shiny spot</verse>
<verse>in order to determine when it is unclean and when it is clean. These are the procedures regarding infectious skin diseases and mildew and fungus."</verse>
</chapter>