<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Leviticus" book-id="3" n="18">
<verse>GOD spoke to Moses,</verse>
<verse>"Speak to the People of Israel. Tell them: I am GOD, your God.</verse>
<verse>Don't live like the people of Egypt where you used to live, and don't live like the people of Canaan where I'm bringing you. Don't do what they do.</verse>
<verse>Obey my laws and live by my decrees. I am your GOD.</verse>
<verse>Keep my decrees and laws: The person who obeys them lives by them. I am GOD.</verse>
<verse>"Don't have sex with a close relative. I am GOD.</verse>
<verse>"Don't violate your father by having sex with your mother. She is your mother. Don't have sex with her.</verse>
<verse>"Don't have sex with your father's wife. That violates your father.</verse>
<verse>"Don't have sex with your sister, whether she's your father's daughter or your mother's, whether she was born in the same house or elsewhere.</verse>
<verse>"Don't have sex with your son's daughter or your daughter's daughter. That would violate your own body.</verse>
<verse>"Don't have sex with the daughter of your father's wife born to your father. She is your sister.</verse>
<verse>"Don't have sex with your father's sister; she is your aunt, closely related to your father.</verse>
<verse>"Don't have sex with your mother's sister; she is your aunt, closely related to your mother.</verse>
<verse>"Don't violate your father's brother, your uncle, by having sex with his wife. She is your aunt.</verse>
<verse>"Don't have sex with your daughter-in-law. She is your son's wife; don't have sex with her.</verse>
<verse>"Don't have sex with your brother's wife; that would violate your brother.</verse>
<verse>"Don't have sex with both a woman and her daughter. And don't have sex with her granddaughters either. They are her close relatives. That is wicked.</verse>
<verse>"Don't marry your wife's sister as a rival wife and have sex with her while your wife is living.</verse>
<verse>"Don't have sex with a woman during the time of her menstrual period when she is unclean.</verse>
<verse>"Don't have sex with your neighbor's wife and violate yourself by her.</verse>
<verse>"Don't give any of your children to be burned in sacrifice to the god Molech--an act of sheer blasphemy of your God. I am GOD.</verse>
<verse>"Don't have sex with a man as one does with a woman. That is abhorrent.</verse>
<verse>"Don't have sex with an animal and violate yourself by it. "A woman must not have sex with an animal. That is perverse.</verse>
<verse>"Don't pollute yourself in any of these ways. This is how the nations became polluted, the ones that I am going to drive out of the land before you.</verse>
<verse>Even the land itself became polluted and I punished it for its iniquities--the land vomited up its inhabitants.</verse>
<verse>You must keep my decrees and laws--natives and foreigners both. You must not do any of these abhorrent things.</verse>
<verse>The people who lived in this land before you arrived did all these things and polluted the land.</verse>
<verse>And if you pollute it, the land will vomit you up just as it vomited up the nations that preceded you.</verse>
<verse>"Those who do any of these abhorrent things will be cut off from their people.</verse>
<verse>Keep to what I tell you; don't engage in any of the abhorrent acts that were practiced before you came. Don't pollute yourselves with them. I am GOD, your God."</verse>
</chapter>