<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Leviticus" book-id="3" n="2">
<verse>"When you present a Grain-Offering to GOD, use fine flour. Pour oil on it, put incense on it,</verse>
<verse>and bring it to Aaron's sons, the priests. One of them will take a handful of the fine flour and oil, with all the incense, and burn it on the Altar for a memorial: a Fire-Gift, a pleasing fragrance to GOD.</verse>
<verse>The rest of the Grain-Offering is for Aaron and his sons--a most holy part of the Fire-Gifts to GOD.</verse>
<verse>"When you present a Grain-Offering of oven-baked loaves, use fine flour, mixed with oil but no yeast. Or present wafers made without yeast and spread with oil.</verse>
<verse>"If you bring a Grain-Offering cooked on a griddle, use fine flour mixed with oil but without yeast.</verse>
<verse>Crumble it and pour oil on it--it's a Grain-Offering.</verse>
<verse>"If you bring a Grain-Offering deep-fried in a pan, make it of fine flour with oil.</verse>
<verse>"Bring the Grain-Offering you make from these ingredients and present it to the priest. He will bring it to the Altar,</verse>
<verse>break off a memorial piece from the Grain-Offering, and burn it on the Altar: a Fire-Gift, a pleasing fragrance to GOD.</verse>
<verse>The rest of the Grain-Offering is for Aaron and his sons--a most holy part of the gifts to GOD.</verse>
<verse>"All the Grain-Offerings that you present to GOD must be made without yeast; you must never burn any yeast or honey as a Fire-Gift to GOD.</verse>
<verse>You may offer them to GOD as an offering of firstfruits but not on the Altar as a pleasing fragrance.</verse>
<verse>Season every presentation of your Grain-Offering with salt. Don't leave the salt of the covenant with your God out of your Grain-Offerings. Present all your offerings with salt.</verse>
<verse>"If you present a Grain-Offering of firstfruits to GOD, bring crushed heads of the new grain roasted.</verse>
<verse>Put oil and incense on it--it's a Grain-Offering.</verse>
<verse>The priest will burn some of the mixed grain and oil with all the incense as a memorial--a Fire-Gift to GOD.</verse>
</chapter>