<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Leviticus" book_id="3" n="23">
<verse>GOD spoke to Moses:</verse>
<verse>"Tell the People of Israel, These are my appointed feasts, the appointed feasts of GOD which you are to decree as sacred assemblies.</verse>
<verse>"Work six days. The seventh day is a Sabbath, a day of total and complete rest, a sacred assembly. Don't do any work. Wherever you live, it is a Sabbath to GOD.</verse>
<verse>"These are the appointed feasts of GOD, the sacred assemblies which you are to announce at the times set for them:</verse>
<verse>"GOD's Passover, beginning at sundown on the fourteenth day of the first month.</verse>
<verse>"GOD's Feast of Unraised Bread, on the fifteenth day of this same month. You are to eat unraised bread for seven days.</verse>
<verse>Hold a sacred assembly on the first day; don't do any regular work.</verse>
<verse>Offer Fire-Gifts to GOD for seven days. On the seventh day hold a sacred assembly; don't do any regular work."</verse>
<verse>GOD spoke to Moses:</verse>
<verse>"Tell the People of Israel, When you arrive at the land that I am giving you and reap its harvest, bring to the priest a sheaf of the first grain that you harvest.</verse>
<verse>He will wave the sheaf before GOD for acceptance on your behalf; on the morning after Sabbath, the priest will wave it.</verse>
<verse>On the same day that you wave the sheaf, offer a year-old male lamb without defect for a Whole-Burnt-Offering to GOD</verse>
<verse>and with it the Grain-Offering of four quarts of fine flour mixed with oil--a Fire-Gift to GOD, a pleasing fragrance--and also a Drink-Offering of a quart of wine.</verse>
<verse>Don't eat any bread or roasted or fresh grain until you have presented this offering to your God. This is a perpetual decree for all your generations to come, wherever you live.</verse>
<verse>"Count seven full weeks from the morning after the Sabbath when you brought the sheaf as a Wave-Offering,</verse>
<verse>fifty days until the morning of the seventh Sabbath. Then present a new Grain-Offering to GOD.</verse>
<verse>Bring from wherever you are living two loaves of bread made from four quarts of fine flour and baked with yeast as a Wave-Offering of the first ripe grain to GOD.</verse>
<verse>In addition to the bread, offer seven yearling male lambs without defect, plus one bull and two rams. They will be a Whole-Burnt-Offering to GOD together with their Grain-Offerings and Drink-Offerings--offered as Fire-Gifts, a pleasing fragrance to GOD.</verse>
<verse>Offer one male goat for an Absolution-Offering and two yearling lambs for a Peace-Offering.</verse>
<verse>The priest will wave the two lambs before GOD as a Wave-Offering, together with the bread of the first ripe grain. They are sacred offerings to GOD for the priest.</verse>
<verse>Proclaim the day as a sacred assembly. Don't do any ordinary work. It is a perpetual decree wherever you live down through your generations.</verse>
<verse>"When you reap the harvest of your land, don't reap the corners of your field or gather the gleanings. Leave them for the poor and the foreigners. I am GOD, your God."</verse>
<verse>GOD said to Moses:</verse>
<verse>"Tell the People of Israel, On the first day of the seventh month, set aside a day of rest, a sacred assembly--mark it with loud blasts on the ram's horn.</verse>
<verse>Don't do any ordinary work. Offer a Fire-Gift to GOD."</verse>
<verse>GOD said to Moses,</verse>
<verse>"The tenth day of the seventh month is the Day of Atonement. Hold a sacred assembly, fast, and offer a Fire-Gift to GOD.</verse>
<verse>Don't work on that day because it is a day of atonement to make atonement for you before your GOD.</verse>
<verse>Anyone who doesn't fast on that day must be cut off from his people.</verse>
<verse>I will destroy from among his people anyone who works on that day.</verse>
<verse>Don't do any work that day--none. This is a perpetual decree for all the generations to come, wherever you happen to be living.</verse>
<verse>It is a Sabbath of complete and total rest, a fast day. Observe your Sabbath from the evening of the ninth day of the month until the following evening."</verse>
<verse>GOD said to Moses,</verse>
<verse>"Tell the People of Israel, GOD's Feast of Booths begins on the fifteenth day of the seventh month. It lasts seven days.</verse>
<verse>The first day is a sacred assembly; don't do any ordinary work.</verse>
<verse>Offer Fire-Gifts to GOD for seven days. On the eighth day hold a sacred assembly and offer a gift to GOD. It is a solemn convocation. Don't do any ordinary work.</verse>
<verse>"These are the appointed feasts of GOD which you will decree as sacred assemblies for presenting Fire-Gifts to GOD: the Whole-Burnt-Offerings, Grain-Offerings, sacrifices, and Drink-Offerings assigned to each day.</verse>
<verse>These are in addition to offerings for GOD's Sabbaths and also in addition to other gifts connected with whatever you have vowed and all the Freewill-Offerings you give to GOD.</verse>
<verse>"So, summing up: On the fifteenth day of the seventh month, after you have brought your crops in from your fields, celebrate the Feast of GOD for seven days. The first day is a complete rest and the eighth day is a complete rest.</verse>
<verse>On the first day, pick the best fruit from the best trees; take fronds of palm trees and branches of leafy trees and from willows by the brook and celebrate in the presence of your GOD for seven days--</verse>
<verse>yes, for seven full days celebrate it as a festival to GOD. Every year from now on, celebrate it in the seventh month.</verse>
<verse>Live in booths for seven days--every son and daughter of Israel is to move into booths</verse>
<verse>so that your descendants will know that I made the People of Israel live in booths when I brought them out of the land of Egypt. I am GOD, your God."</verse>
<verse>Moses posted the calendar for the annual appointed feasts of GOD which Israel was to celebrate.</verse>
</chapter>