<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Leviticus" book_id="3" n="4">
<verse>GOD spoke to Moses,</verse>
<verse>"Tell the Israelites: When a person sins unintentionally by straying from any of GOD's commands, breaking what must not be broken,</verse>
<verse>if it's the anointed priest who sins and so brings guilt on the people, he is to bring a bull without defect to GOD as an Absolution-Offering for the sin he has committed.</verse>
<verse>Have him bring the bull to the entrance of the Tent of Meeting in the presence of GOD, lay his hand on the bull's head, and slaughter the bull before GOD.</verse>
<verse>He is then to take some of the bull's blood, bring it into the Tent of Meeting,</verse>
<verse>dip his finger in the blood, and sprinkle some of it seven times before GOD, before the curtain of the Sanctuary.</verse>
<verse>He is to smear some of the blood on the horns of the Altar of Fragrant Incense before GOD which is in the Tent of Meeting. He is to pour the rest of the bull's blood out at the base of the Altar of Whole-Burnt-Offering at the entrance of the Tent of Meeting.</verse>
<verse>He is to remove all the fat from the bull of the Absolution-Offering, the fat which covers and is connected to the entrails,</verse>
<verse>the two kidneys and the fat that is around them at the loins, and the lobe of the liver which he takes out along with the kidneys</verse>
<verse>-the same procedure as when the fat is removed from the bull of the Peace-Offering. Finally, he is to burn all this on the Altar of Burnt Offering.</verse>
<verse>Everything else--the bull's hide, meat, head, legs, organs, and guts--</verse>
<verse>he is to take outside the camp to a clean place where the ashes are dumped and is to burn it on a wood fire.</verse>
<verse>"If the whole congregation sins unintentionally by straying from one of the commandments of GOD that must not be broken, they become guilty even though no one is aware of it.</verse>
<verse>When they do become aware of the sin they've committed, the congregation must bring a bull as an Absolution-Offering and present it at the Tent of Meeting.</verse>
<verse>The elders of the congregation will lay their hands on the bull's head in the presence of GOD and one of them will slaughter it before GOD.</verse>
<verse>The anointed priest will then bring some of the blood into the Tent of Meeting,</verse>
<verse>dip his finger in the blood, and sprinkle some of it seven times before GOD in front of the curtain.</verse>
<verse>He will smear some of the blood on the horns of the Altar which is before GOD in the Tent of Meeting and pour the rest of it at the base of the Altar of Whole-Burnt-Offering at the entrance of the Tent of Meeting.</verse>
<verse>He will remove all the fat and burn it on the Altar.</verse>
<verse>He will follow the same procedure with this bull as with the bull for the Absolution-Offering. The priest makes atonement for them and they are forgiven.</verse>
<verse>They then will take the bull outside the camp and burn it just as they burned the first bull. It's the Absolution-Offering for the congregation.</verse>
<verse>"When a ruler sins unintentionally by straying from one of the commands of his GOD which must not be broken, he is guilty.</verse>
<verse>When he becomes aware of the sin he has committed, he must bring a goat for his offering, a male without any defect,</verse>
<verse>lay his hand on the head of the goat, and slaughter it in the place where they slaughter the Whole-Burnt-Offering in the presence of GOD-it's an Absolution-Offering.</verse>
<verse>The priest will then take some of the blood of the Absolution-Offering with his finger, smear it on the horns of the Altar of Whole-Burnt-Offering, and pour the rest at the base of the Altar.</verse>
<verse>He will burn all its fat on the Altar, the same as with the fat of the Peace-Offering. "The priest makes atonement for him on account of his sin and he's forgiven.</verse>
<verse>"When an ordinary member of the congregation sins unintentionally, straying from one of the commandments of GOD which must not be broken, he is guilty.</verse>
<verse>When he is made aware of his sin, he shall bring a goat, a female without any defect, and offer it for his sin,</verse>
<verse>lay his hand on the head of the Absolution-Offering, and slaughter it at the place of the Whole-Burnt-Offering.</verse>
<verse>The priest will take some of its blood with his finger, smear it on the horns of the Altar of Whole-Burnt-Offering, and pour the rest at the base of the Altar.</verse>
<verse>Finally, he'll take out all the fat, the same as with the Peace-Offerings, and burn it on the Altar for a pleasing fragrance to GOD. "In this way, the priest makes atonement for him and he's forgiven.</verse>
<verse>"If he brings a lamb for an Absolution-Offering, he shall present a female without any defect,</verse>
<verse>lay his hand on the head of the Absolution-Offering, and slaughter it at the same place they slaughter the Whole-Burnt-Offering.</verse>
<verse>The priest will take some of the blood of the Absolution-Offering with his finger, smear it on the horns of the Altar of Burnt-Offering, and pour the rest at the base of the Altar.</verse>
<verse>He shall remove all the fat, the same as for the lamb of the Peace-Offering. Finally the priest will burn it on the Altar on top of the gifts to GOD. "In this way, the priest makes atonement for him on account of his sin and he's forgiven. [JC]</verse>
</chapter>