<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Leviticus" book-id="3" n="5">
<verse>"If you sin by not stepping up and offering yourself as a witness to something you've heard or seen in cases of wrongdoing, you'll be held responsible.</verse>
<verse>"Or if you touch anything ritually unclean, like the carcass of an unclean animal, wild or domestic, or a dead reptile, and you weren't aware of it at the time, but you're contaminated and you're guilty;</verse>
<verse>"Or if you touch human uncleanness, any sort of ritually contaminating uncleanness, and you're not aware of it at the time, but later you realize it and you're guilty;</verse>
<verse>"Or if you impulsively swear to do something, whether good or bad--some rash oath that just pops out--and you aren't aware of what you've done at the time, but later you come to realize it and you're guilty in any of these cases;</verse>
<verse>"When you are guilty, immediately confess the sin that you've committed</verse>
<verse>and bring as your penalty to GOD for the sin you have committed, a female lamb or goat from the flock for an Absolution-Offering. "In this way, the priest will make atonement for your sin.</verse>
<verse>"If you can't afford a lamb, bring as your penalty to GOD for the sin you have committed, two doves or two pigeons, one for the Absolution-Offering and the other for the Whole-Burnt-Offering.</verse>
<verse>Bring them to the priest who will first offer the one for the Absolution-Offering: He'll wring its neck but not sever it,</verse>
<verse>splash some of the blood of the Absolution-Offering against the Altar, and squeeze the rest of it out at the base. It's an Absolution-Offering.</verse>
<verse>He'll then take the second bird and offer it as a Whole-Burnt-Offering, following the procedures step-by-step. "In this way, the priest will make atonement for your sin and you're forgiven.</verse>
<verse>"If you cannot afford the two doves or pigeons, bring two quarts of fine flour for your Absolution-Offering. Don't put oil or incense on it--it's an Absolution-Offering.</verse>
<verse>Bring it to the priest; he'll take a handful from it as a memorial and burn it on the Altar with the gifts for GOD. It's an Absolution-Offering.</verse>
<verse>"The priest will make atonement for you and any of these sins you've committed and you're forgiven. The rest of the offering belongs to the priest, the same as with the Grain-Offering."</verse>
<verse>GOD spoke to Moses,</verse>
<verse>"When a person betrays his trust and unknowingly sins by straying against any of the holy things of GOD, he is to bring as his penalty to GOD a ram without any defect from the flock, the value of the ram assessed in shekels, according to the Sanctuary shekel for a Compensation-Offering.</verse>
<verse>He is to make additional compensation for the sin he has committed against any holy thing by adding twenty percent to the ram and giving it to the priest. "Thus the priest will make atonement for him with the ram of the Compensation-Offering and he's forgiven.</verse>
<verse>"If anyone sins by breaking any of the commandments of GOD which must not be broken, but without being aware of it at the time, the moment he does realize his guilt he is held responsible.</verse>
<verse>He is to bring to the priest a ram without any defect, assessed at the value of the Compensation-Offering. "Thus the priest will make atonement for him for his error that he was unaware of and he's forgiven.</verse>
<verse>It is a Compensation-Offering; he was surely guilty before God."</verse>
</chapter>