<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Leviticus" book_id="3" n="6">
<verse>GOD spoke to Moses,</verse>
<verse>"When anyone sins by betraying trust with GOD by deceiving his neighbor regarding something entrusted to him, or by robbing or cheating or threatening him;</verse>
<verse>or if he has found something lost and lies about it and swears falsely regarding any of these sins that people commonly commit--</verse>
<verse>when he sins and is found guilty, he must return what he stole or extorted, restore what was entrusted to him, return the lost thing he found,</verse>
<verse>or anything else about which he swore falsely. He must make full compensation, add twenty percent to it, and hand it over to the owner on the same day he brings his Compensation-Offering.</verse>
<verse>He must present to GOD as his Compensation-Offering a ram without any defect from the flock, assessed at the value of a Compensation-Offering.</verse>
<verse>"Thus the priest will make atonement for him before GOD and he's forgiven of any of the things that one does that bring guilt."</verse>
<verse>GOD spoke to Moses,</verse>
<verse>"Command Aaron and his sons. Tell them, These are the instructions for the Whole-Burnt-Offering. Leave the Whole-Burnt-Offering on the Altar hearth through the night until morning, with the fire kept burning on the Altar.</verse>
<verse>Then dress in your linen clothes with linen underwear next to your body. Remove the ashes remaining from the Whole-Burnt-Offering and place them beside the Altar.</verse>
<verse>Then change clothes and carry the ashes outside the camp to a clean place.</verse>
<verse>Meanwhile keep the fire on the Altar burning; it must not go out. Replenish the wood for the fire every morning, arrange the Whole-Burnt-Offering on it, and burn the fat of the Peace-Offering on top of it all.</verse>
<verse>Keep the fire burning on the Altar continuously. It must not go out. [JC]</verse>
<verse>"These are the instructions for the Grain-Offering. Aaron's sons are to present it to GOD in front of the Altar.</verse>
<verse>The priest takes a handful of the fine flour of the Grain-Offering with its oil and all its incense and burns this as a memorial on the Altar, a pleasing fragrance to GOD.</verse>
<verse>Aaron and his sons eat the rest of it. It is unraised bread and so eaten in a holy place--in the Courtyard of the Tent of Meeting.</verse>
<verse>They must not bake it with yeast. I have designated it as their share of the gifts presented to me. It is very holy, like the Absolution-Offering and the Compensation-Offering.</verse>
<verse>Any male descendant among Aaron's sons may eat it. This is a fixed rule regarding GOD's gifts, stretching down the generations. Anyone who touches these offerings must be holy." [JC]</verse>
<verse>GOD spoke to Moses,</verse>
<verse>"This is the offering which Aaron and his sons each are to present to GOD on the day he is anointed: two quarts of fine flour as a regular Grain-Offering, half in the morning and half in the evening.</verse>
<verse>Prepare it with oil on a griddle. Bring it well-mixed and then present it crumbled in pieces as a pleasing fragrance to GOD.</verse>
<verse>Aaron's son who is anointed to succeed him offers it to GOD-this is a fixed rule. The whole thing is burned.</verse>
<verse>Every Grain-Offering of a priest is burned completely; it must not be eaten." [JC]</verse>
<verse>GOD spoke to Moses,</verse>
<verse>"Tell Aaron and his sons: These are the instructions for the Absolution-Offering. Slaughter the Absolution-Offering in the place where the Whole-Burnt-Offering is slaughtered before GOD-the offering is most holy.</verse>
<verse>The priest in charge eats it in a holy place, the Courtyard of the Tent of Meeting.</verse>
<verse>Anyone who touches any of the meat must be holy. A garment that gets blood spattered on it must be washed in a holy place.</verse>
<verse>Break the clay pot in which the meat was cooked. If it was cooked in a bronze pot, scour it and rinse it with water.</verse>
<verse>Any male among the priestly families may eat it; it is most holy.</verse>
<verse>But any Absolution-Offering whose blood is brought into the Tent of Meeting to make atonement in the Sanctuary must not be eaten, it has to be burned. [JC]</verse>
</chapter>