<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Leviticus" book_id="3" n="7">
<verse>"These are the instructions for the Compensation-Offering. It is most holy.</verse>
<verse>Slaughter the Compensation-Offering in the same place that the Whole-Burnt-Offering is slaughtered. Splash its blood against all sides of the Altar.</verse>
<verse>Offer up all the fat: the fat tail, the fat covering the entrails,</verse>
<verse>the two kidneys and the fat encasing them at the loins, and the lobe of the liver that is removed with the kidneys.</verse>
<verse>The priest burns them on the Altar as a gift to GOD. It is a Compensation-Offering.</verse>
<verse>Any male from among the priests' families may eat it. But it must be eaten in a holy place; it is most holy.</verse>
<verse>"The Compensation-Offering is the same as the Absolution-Offering--the same rules apply to both. The offering belongs to the priest who makes atonement with it.</verse>
<verse>The priest who presents a Whole-Burnt-Offering for someone gets the hide for himself.</verse>
<verse>Every Grain-Offering baked in an oven or prepared in a pan or on a griddle belongs to the priest who presents it. It's his.</verse>
<verse>Every Grain-Offering, whether dry or mixed with oil, belongs equally to all the sons of Aaron. [JC]</verse>
<verse>"These are the instructions for the Peace-Offering which is presented to GOD.</verse>
<verse>If you bring it to offer thanksgiving, then along with the Thanksgiving-Offering present unraised loaves of bread mixed with oil, unraised wafers spread with oil, and cakes of fine flour, well-kneaded and mixed with oil.</verse>
<verse>Along with the Peace-Offering of thanksgiving, present loaves of yeast bread as an offering.</verse>
<verse>Bring one of each kind as an offering, a Contribution-Offering to GOD; it goes to the priest who throws the blood of the Peace-Offering.</verse>
<verse>Eat the meat from the Peace-Offering of thanksgiving the same day it is offered. Don't leave any of it overnight.</verse>
<verse>"If the offering is a Votive-Offering or a Freewill-Offering, it may be eaten the same day it is sacrificed and whatever is left over on the next day may also be eaten.</verse>
<verse>But any meat from the sacrifice that is left to the third day must be burned up.</verse>
<verse>If any of the meat from the Peace-Offering is eaten on the third day, the person who has brought it will not be accepted. It won't benefit him a bit--it has become defiled meat. And whoever eats it must take responsibility for his iniquity.</verse>
<verse>Don't eat meat that has touched anything ritually unclean; burn it up. Any other meat can be eaten by those who are ritually clean.</verse>
<verse>But if you're not ritually clean and eat meat from the Peace-Offering for GOD, you will be excluded from the congregation.</verse>
<verse>And if you touch anything ritually unclean, whether human or animal uncleanness or an obscene object, and go ahead and eat from a Peace-Offering for GOD, you'll be excluded from the congregation." [JC]</verse>
<verse>GOD spoke to Moses,</verse>
<verse>"Speak to the People of Israel. Tell them, Don't eat any fat of cattle or sheep or goats.</verse>
<verse>The fat of an animal found dead or torn by wild animals can be put to some other purpose, but you may not eat it.</verse>
<verse>If you eat fat from an animal from which a gift has been presented to GOD, you'll be excluded from the congregation.</verse>
<verse>And don't eat blood, whether of birds or animals, no matter where you end up living.</verse>
<verse>If you eat blood you'll be excluded from the congregation." [JC]</verse>
<verse>GOD spoke to Moses,</verse>
<verse>"Speak to the People of Israel. Tell them: When you present a Peace-Offering to GOD, bring some of your Peace-Offering as a special sacrifice to GOD,</verse>
<verse>a gift to GOD in your own hands. Bring the fat with the breast and then wave the breast before GOD as a Wave-Offering.</verse>
<verse>The priest will burn the fat on the Altar; Aaron and his sons get the breast.</verse>
<verse>Give the right thigh from your Peace-Offerings as a Contribution-Offering to the priest.</verse>
<verse>Give a portion of the right thigh to the son of Aaron who offers the blood and fat of the Peace-Offering as his portion.</verse>
<verse>From the Peace-Offerings of Israel, I'm giving the breast of the Wave-Offering and the thigh of the Contribution-Offering to Aaron the priest and his sons. This is their fixed compensation from the People of Israel."</verse>
<verse>From the day they are presented to serve as priests to GOD, Aaron and his sons can expect to receive these allotments from the gifts of GOD</verse>
<verse>This is what GOD commanded the People of Israel to give the priests from the day of their anointing. This is the fixed rule down through the generations.</verse>
<verse>These are the instructions for the Whole-Burnt-Offering, the Grain-Offering, the Absolution-Offering, the Compensation-Offering, the Ordination-Offering, and the Peace-Offering</verse>
<verse>which GOD gave Moses at Mount Sinai on the day he commanded the People of Israel to present their offerings to GOD in the wilderness of Sinai.</verse>
</chapter>