<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Nahum" book-id="34" n="1">
<verse>An oracle concerning Nineveh. The book of the vision of Nahum the Elkoshite.</verse>
<verse>The LORD is a jealous and avenging God; the LORD takes vengeance and is filled with wrath. The LORD takes vengeance on his foes and maintains his wrath against his enemies.</verse>
<verse>The LORD is slow to anger and great in power; the LORD will not leave the guilty unpunished. His way is in the whirlwind and the storm, and clouds are the dust of his feet.</verse>
<verse>He rebukes the sea and dries it up; he makes all the rivers run dry. Bashan and Carmel wither and the blossoms of Lebanon fade.</verse>
<verse>The mountains quake before him and the hills melt away. The earth trembles at his presence, the world and all who live in it.</verse>
<verse>Who can withstand his indignation? Who can endure his fierce anger? His wrath is poured out like fire; the rocks are shattered before him.</verse>
<verse>The LORD is good, a refuge in times of trouble. He cares for those who trust in him,</verse>
<verse>but with an overwhelming flood he will make an end of Nineveh; he will pursue his foes into darkness.</verse>
<verse>Whatever they plot against the LORD he will bring to an end; trouble will not come a second time.</verse>
<verse>They will be entangled among thorns and drunk from their wine; they will be consumed like dry stubble.</verse>
<verse>From you, O Nineveh, has one come forth who plots evil against the LORD and counsels wickedness.</verse>
<verse>This is what the LORD says: "Although they have allies and are numerous, they will be cut off and pass away. Although I have afflicted you, O Judah, I will afflict you no more.</verse>
<verse>Now I will break their yoke from your neck and tear your shackles away."</verse>
<verse>The LORD has given a command concerning you, Nineveh: "You will have no descendants to bear your name. I will destroy the carved images and cast idols that are in the temple of your gods. I will prepare your grave, for you are vile."</verse>
<verse>Look, there on the mountains, the feet of one who brings good news, who proclaims peace! Celebrate your festivals, O Judah, and fulfill your vows. No more will the wicked invade you; they will be completely destroyed.</verse>
</chapter>