<?xml version="1.0"?>
<chapter translation="KJV" testament="Old" book="1 Chronicles" n="7" book_id="13">
      <verse>Now the sons of Issachar <supplied>were,</supplied> Tola, and Puah, Jashub, and Shimrom, four.
</verse><verse>And the sons of Tola; Uzzi, and Rephaiah, and Jeriel, and Jahmai, and Jibsam, and Shemuel, heads of their father&#x2019;s house, <supplied>to wit,</supplied> of Tola: <supplied>they were</supplied> valiant men of might in their generations; whose number <supplied>was</supplied> in the days
of David two and twenty thousand and six hundred.
</verse><verse>And the sons of Uzzi; Izrahiah: and the sons of Izrahiah; Michael, and Obadiah, and Joel, Ishiah, five: all of them chief men.
</verse><verse>And with them, by their generations, after the house of their fathers, <supplied>were</supplied> bands of soldiers for war, six and thirty thousand <supplied>men:</supplied> for they had many wives and sons.
</verse><verse>And their brethren among all the families of Issachar <supplied>were</supplied> valiant men of might, reckoned in all by their genealogies fourscore and seven thousand.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>
      <supplied>The sons</supplied> of Benjamin; Bela, and Becher, and Jediael, three.
</verse><verse>And the sons of Bela; Ezbon, and Uzzi, and Uzziel, and Jerimoth, and Iri, five; heads of the house of <supplied>their</supplied> fathers, mighty men of valour; and were reckoned by their genealogies twenty and two thousand and thirty and four.
</verse><verse>And the sons of Becher; Zemira, and Joash, and Eliezer, and Elioenai, and Omri, and Jerimoth, and Abiah, and Anathoth, and Alameth. All these <supplied>are</supplied> the sons of Becher.
</verse><verse>And the number of them, after their genealogy by their generations, heads of the house of the fathers, mighty men of valour, <supplied>was</supplied> twenty thousand and two hundred.
</verse><verse>The sons also of Jediael; Bilhan: and the sons of Bilhan; Jeush, and Benjamin, and Ehud, and Chenaanah, and Zethan, and Tharshish, and Ahishahar.
</verse><verse>All these the sons of Jediael, by the heads of their fathers, mighty men of valour, <supplied>were</supplied> seventeen thousand and two hundred <supplied>soldiers,</supplied> fit to go out for war <supplied>and</supplied> battle.
</verse><verse>Shuppim also, and Huppim, the children of Ir, <supplied>and</supplied> Hushim, the sons of Aher.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>The sons of Naphtali; Jahziel, and Guni, and Jezer, and Shallum, the sons of Bilhah.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>The sons of Manasseh; Ashriel, whom she bare: <supplied>(but</supplied> his concubine the Aramitess bare Machir the father of Gilead:
</verse><verse>And Machir took to wife <supplied>the sister</supplied> of Huppim and Shuppim, whose sister&#x2019;s name <supplied>was</supplied> Maachah;) and the name of the second <supplied>was</supplied> Zelophehad: and Zelophehad had daughters.
</verse><verse>And Maachah the wife of Machir bare a son, and she called his name Peresh; and the name of his brother <supplied>was</supplied> Sheresh; and his sons <supplied>were</supplied> Ulam and Rakem.
</verse><verse>And the sons of Ulam; Bedan. These <supplied>were</supplied> the sons of Gilead, the son of Machir, the son of Manasseh.
</verse><verse>And his sister Hammoleketh bare Ishod, and Abiezer, and Mahalah.
</verse><verse>And the sons of Shemidah were, Ahian, and Shechem, and Likhi, and Aniam.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>And the sons of Ephraim; Shuthelah, and Bered his son, and Tahath his son, and Eladah his son, and Tahath his son,
     
      </verse>
      <verse>And Zabad his son, and Shuthelah his son, and Ezer, and Elead, whom the men of Gath <supplied>that were</supplied> born in <supplied>that</supplied> land slew, because they came down to take away their cattle.
</verse><verse>And Ephraim their father mourned many days, and his brethren came to comfort him.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>And when he went in to his wife, she conceived, and bare a son, and he called his name Beriah, because it went evil with his house.
</verse><verse>(And his daughter <supplied>was</supplied> Sherah, who built Beth-horon the nether, and the upper, and Uzzen-sherah.)
</verse><verse>And Rephah <supplied>was</supplied> his son, also Resheph, and Telah his son, and Tahan his son,
</verse><verse>Laadan his son, Ammihud his son, Elishama his son,
</verse><verse>Non his son, Jehoshuah his son.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>And their possessions and habitations <supplied>were,</supplied> Bethel and the towns thereof, and eastward Naaran, and westward Gezer, with the towns thereof; Shechem also and the towns thereof, unto Gaza and the towns thereof:
</verse><verse>And by the borders of the children of Manasseh, Beth-shean and her towns, Taanach and her towns, Megiddo and her towns, Dor and her towns. In these dwelt the children of Joseph the son of Israel.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>The sons of Asher; Imnah, and Isuah, and Ishuai, and Beriah, and Serah their sister.
</verse><verse>And the sons of Beriah; Heber, and Malchiel, who <supplied>is</supplied> the father of Birzavith.
</verse><verse>And Heber begat Japhlet, and Shomer, and Hotham, and Shua their sister.
</verse><verse>And the sons of Japhlet; Pasach, and Bimhal, and Ashvath. These <supplied>are</supplied> the children of Japhlet.
</verse><verse>And the sons of Shamer; Ahi, and Rohgah, Jehubbah, and Aram.
</verse><verse>And the sons of his brother Helem; Zophah, and Imna, and Shelesh, and Amal.
</verse><verse>The sons of Zophah; Suah, and Harnepher, and Shual, and Beri, and Imrah,
</verse><verse>Bezer, and Hod, and Shamma and Shilshah, and Ithran, and Beera.
</verse><verse>And the sons of Jether; Jephunneh, and Pispah, and Ara.
</verse><verse>And the sons of Ulla; Arah, and Haniel, and Rezia.
</verse><verse>All these <supplied>were</supplied> the children of Asher, heads of <supplied>their</supplied> father&#x2019;s house, choice <supplied>and</supplied> mighty men of valour, chief of the princes. And the number throughout the genealogy of them that were apt to the war <supplied>and</supplied> to battle
<supplied>was</supplied> twenty and six thousand men.
     
      </verse>
      </chapter>
