<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Joshua" book-id="6" n="12">
<verse>These are the kings that the People of Israel defeated and whose land they took on the east of the Jordan, from the Arnon Gorge to Mount Hermon, with the whole eastern side of the Arabah Valley.</verse>
<verse>Sihon king of the Amorites, who reigned from Heshbon: His rule extended from Aroer, which sits at the edge of the Arnon Gorge, from the middle of the gorge and over half of Gilead to the Gorge of the Jabbok River, which is the border of the Ammonites.</verse>
<verse>His rule included the eastern Arabah Valley from the Sea of Kinnereth to the Arabah Sea (the Salt Sea), eastward toward Beth Jeshimoth and southward to the slopes of Pisgah.</verse>
<verse>And Og king of Bashan, one of the last of the Rephaim who reigned from Ashtaroth and Edrei:</verse>
<verse>His rule extended from Mount Hermon and Salecah over the whole of Bashan to the border of the Geshurites and the Maacathites (the other half of Gilead) to the border of Sihon king of Heshbon.</verse>
<verse>Moses the servant of GOD and the People of Israel defeated them. And Moses the servant of GOD gave this land as an inheritance to the Reubenites, the Gadites, and half of the tribe of Manasseh. [JC]</verse>
<verse>And these are the kings of the land that Joshua and the People of Israel defeated in the country west of the Jordan, from Baal Gad in the Valley of Lebanon south to Mount Halak, which towers over Seir. Joshua gave this land to the tribes of Israel as a possession, according to their divisions:</verse>
<verse>lands in the mountains, the western foothills, and the Arabah Valley, on the slopes, and in the wilderness and the Negev desert (lands on which Hittites, Amorites and Canaanites, Perizzites, Hivites, and Jebusites had lived). The kings were:</verse>
<verse>The king of Jericho	one The king of Ai (near Bethel)	one</verse>
<verse>The king of Jerusalem	one The king of Hebron	one</verse>
<verse>The king of Jarmuth	one The king of Lachish	one</verse>
<verse>The king of Eglon	one The king of Gezer	one</verse>
<verse>The king of Debir	one The king of Geder	one</verse>
<verse>The king of Hormah	one The king of Arad	one</verse>
<verse>The king of Libnah	one The king of Adullam	one</verse>
<verse>The king of Makkedah	one The king of Bethel	one</verse>
<verse>The king of Tappuah	one The king of Hepher	one</verse>
<verse>The king of Aphek	one The king of Lasharon	one</verse>
<verse>The king of Madon	one The king of Hazor	one</verse>
<verse>The king of Shimron Meron	one The king of Acshaph	one</verse>
<verse>The king of Taanach	one The king of Megiddo	one</verse>
<verse>The king of Kedesh	one The king of Jokneam in Carmel 	one</verse>
<verse>The king of Dor (Naphoth Dor) 	one The king of Goyim in Gilgal	one</verse>
<verse>The king of Tirzah	one A total of thirty-one kings.</verse>
</chapter>