<chapter translation="NIV" testament="New" book="Galatians" book-id="48" n="6">
<verse>Brothers, if someone is caught in a sin, you who are spiritual should restore him gently. But watch yourself, or you also may be tempted.</verse>
<verse>Carry each other's burdens, and in this way you will fulfill the law of Christ.</verse>
<verse>If anyone thinks he is something when he is nothing, he deceives himself.</verse>
<verse>Each one should test his own actions. Then he can take pride in himself, without comparing himself to somebody else,</verse>
<verse>for each one should carry his own load.</verse>
<verse>Anyone who receives instruction in the word must share all good things with his instructor.</verse>
<verse>Do not be deceived: God cannot be mocked. A man reaps what he sows.</verse>
<verse>The one who sows to please his sinful nature, from that nature will reap destruction; the one who sows to please the Spirit, from the Spirit will reap eternal life.</verse>
<verse>Let us not become weary in doing good, for at the proper time we will reap a harvest if we do not give up.</verse>
<verse>Therefore, as we have opportunity, let us do good to all people, especially to those who belong to the family of believers.</verse>
<verse>See what large letters I use as I write to you with my own hand!</verse>
<verse>Those who want to make a good impression outwardly are trying to compel you to be circumcised. The only reason they do this is to avoid being persecuted for the cross of Christ.</verse>
<verse>Not even those who are circumcised obey the law, yet they want you to be circumcised that they may boast about your flesh.</verse>
<verse>May I never boast except in the cross of our Lord Jesus Christ, through which the world has been crucified to me, and I to the world.</verse>
<verse>Neither circumcision nor uncircumcision means anything; what counts is a new creation.</verse>
<verse>Peace and mercy to all who follow this rule, even to the Israel of God.</verse>
<verse>Finally, let no one cause me trouble, for I bear on my body the marks of Jesus.</verse>
<verse>The grace of our Lord Jesus Christ be with your spirit, brothers. Amen.</verse>
</chapter>