<chapter translation="NASB" testament="New" book="Hebrews" book_id="58" n="3">
<verse>Therefore, holy brethren, partakers of a heavenly calling, consider Jesus, the Apostle and High Priest of our confession;</verse>
<verse>He was faithful to Him who appointed Him, as Moses also was in all His house.</verse>
<verse>For He has been counted worthy of more glory than Moses, by just so much as the builder of the house has more honor than the house.</verse>
<verse>For every house is built by someone, but the builder of all things is God.</verse>
<verse>Now Moses was faithful in all His house as a servant, for a testimony of those things which were to be spoken later;</verse>
<verse>but Christ was faithful as a Son over His house--whose house we are, if we hold fast our confidence and the boast of our hope firm until the end.</verse>
<verse>Therefore, just as the Holy Spirit says, "TODAY IF YOU HEAR HIS VOICE,</verse>
<verse>DO NOT HARDEN YOUR HEARTS AS WHEN THEY PROVOKED ME, AS IN THE DAY OF TRIAL IN THE WILDERNESS,</verse>
<verse>WHERE YOUR FATHERS TRIED Me BY TESTING Me, AND SAW MY WORKS FOR FORTY YEARS.</verse>
<verse>"THEREFORE I WAS ANGRY WITH THIS GENERATION, AND SAID, 'THEY ALWAYS GO ASTRAY IN THEIR HEART, AND THEY DID NOT KNOW MY WAYS';</verse>
<verse>AS I SWORE IN MY WRATH, 'THEY SHALL NOT ENTER MY REST.'"</verse>
<verse>Take care, brethren, that there not be in any one of you an evil, unbelieving heart that falls away from the living God.</verse>
<verse>But encourage one another day after day, as long as it is still called "Today," so that none of you will be hardened by the deceitfulness of sin.</verse>
<verse>For we have become partakers of Christ, if we hold fast the beginning of our assurance firm until the end,</verse>
<verse>while it is said, "TODAY IF YOU HEAR HIS VOICE, DO NOT HARDEN YOUR HEARTS, AS WHEN THEY PROVOKED ME."</verse>
<verse>For who provoked Him when they had heard? Indeed, did not all those who came out of Egypt led by Moses?</verse>
<verse>And with whom was He angry for forty years? Was it not with those who sinned, whose bodies fell in the wilderness?</verse>
<verse>And to whom did He swear that they would not enter His rest, but to those who were disobedient?</verse>
<verse>So we see that they were not able to enter because of unbelief.</verse>
</chapter>