<chapter translation="NASB" testament="New" book="Matthew" book-id="40" n="1">
<verse>The record of the genealogy of Jesus the Messiah, the son of David, the son of Abraham:</verse>
<verse>Abraham was the father of Isaac, Isaac the father of Jacob, and Jacob the father of Judah and his brothers.</verse>
<verse>Judah was the father of Perez and Zerah by Tamar, Perez was the father of Hezron, and Hezron the father of Ram.</verse>
<verse>Ram was the father of Amminadab, Amminadab the father of Nahshon, and Nahshon the father of Salmon.</verse>
<verse>Salmon was the father of Boaz by Rahab, Boaz was the father of Obed by Ruth, and Obed the father of Jesse.</verse>
<verse>Jesse was the father of David the king. David was the father of Solomon by Bathsheba who had been the wife of Uriah.</verse>
<verse>Solomon was the father of Rehoboam, Rehoboam the father of Abijah, and Abijah the father of Asa.</verse>
<verse>Asa was the father of Jehoshaphat, Jehoshaphat the father of Joram, and Joram the father of Uzziah.</verse>
<verse>Uzziah was the father of Jotham, Jotham the father of Ahaz, and Ahaz the father of Hezekiah.</verse>
<verse>Hezekiah was the father of Manasseh, Manasseh the father of Amon, and Amon the father of Josiah.</verse>
<verse>Josiah became the father of Jeconiah and his brothers, at the time of the deportation to Babylon.</verse>
<verse>After the deportation to Babylon: Jeconiah became the father of Shealtiel, and Shealtiel the father of Zerubbabel.</verse>
<verse>Zerubbabel was the father of Abihud, Abihud the father of Eliakim, and Eliakim the father of Azor.</verse>
<verse>Azor was the father of Zadok, Zadok the father of Achim, and Achim the father of Eliud.</verse>
<verse>Eliud was the father of Eleazar, Eleazar the father of Matthan, and Matthan the father of Jacob.</verse>
<verse>Jacob was the father of Joseph the husband of Mary, by whom Jesus was born, who is called the Messiah.</verse>
<verse>So all the generations from Abraham to David are fourteen generations; from David to the deportation to Babylon, fourteen generations; and from the deportation to Babylon to the Messiah, fourteen generations.</verse>
<verse>Now the birth of Jesus Christ was as follows: when His mother Mary had been betrothed to Joseph, before they came together she was found to be with child by the Holy Spirit.</verse>
<verse>And Joseph her husband, being a righteous man and not wanting to disgrace her, planned to send her away secretly.</verse>
<verse>But when he had considered this, behold, an angel of the Lord appeared to him in a dream, saying, "Joseph, son of David, do not be afraid to take Mary as your wife; for the Child who has been conceived in her is of the Holy Spirit.</verse>
<verse>"She will bear a Son; and you shall call His name Jesus, for He will save His people from their sins."</verse>
<verse>Now all this took place to fulfill what was spoken by the Lord through the prophet:</verse>
<verse>"BEHOLD, THE VIRGIN SHALL BE WITH CHILD AND SHALL BEAR A SON, AND THEY SHALL CALL HIS NAME IMMANUEL," which translated means, "GOD WITH US."</verse>
<verse>And Joseph awoke from his sleep and did as the angel of the Lord commanded him, and took Mary as his wife,</verse>
<verse>but kept her a virgin until she gave birth to a Son; and he called His name Jesus.</verse>
</chapter>