<chapter translation="NASB" testament="New" book="Matthew" book-id="40" n="14">
<verse>At that time Herod the tetrarch heard the news about Jesus,</verse>
<verse>and said to his servants, "This is John the Baptist; he has risen from the dead, and that is why miraculous powers are at work in him."</verse>
<verse>For when Herod had John arrested, he bound him and put him in prison because of Herodias, the wife of his brother Philip.</verse>
<verse>For John had been saying to him, "It is not lawful for you to have her."</verse>
<verse>Although Herod wanted to put him to death, he feared the crowd, because they regarded John as a prophet.</verse>
<verse>But when Herod's birthday came, the daughter of Herodias danced before them and pleased Herod,</verse>
<verse>so much that he promised with an oath to give her whatever she asked.</verse>
<verse>Having been prompted by her mother, she said, "Give me here on a platter the head of John the Baptist."</verse>
<verse>Although he was grieved, the king commanded it to be given because of his oaths, and because of his dinner guests.</verse>
<verse>He sent and had John beheaded in the prison.</verse>
<verse>And his head was brought on a platter and given to the girl, and she brought it to her mother.</verse>
<verse>His disciples came and took away the body and buried it; and they went and reported to Jesus.</verse>
<verse>Now when Jesus heard about John, He withdrew from there in a boat to a secluded place by Himself; and when the people heard of this, they followed Him on foot from the cities.</verse>
<verse>When He went ashore, He saw a large crowd, and felt compassion for them and healed their sick.</verse>
<verse>When it was evening, the disciples came to Him and said, "This place is desolate and the hour is already late; so send the crowds away, that they may go into the villages and buy food for themselves."</verse>
<verse>But Jesus said to them, "They do not need to go away; you give them something to eat!"</verse>
<verse>They said to Him, "We have here only five loaves and two fish."</verse>
<verse>And He said, "Bring them here to Me."</verse>
<verse>Ordering the people to sit down on the grass, He took the five loaves and the two fish, and looking up toward heaven, He blessed the food, and breaking the loaves He gave them to the disciples, and the disciples gave them to the crowds,</verse>
<verse>and they all ate and were satisfied. They picked up what was left over of the broken pieces, twelve full baskets.</verse>
<verse>There were about five thousand men who ate, besides women and children.</verse>
<verse>Immediately He made the disciples get into the boat and go ahead of Him to the other side, while He sent the crowds away.</verse>
<verse>After He had sent the crowds away, He went up on the mountain by Himself to pray; and when it was evening, He was there alone.</verse>
<verse>But the boat was already a long distance from the land, battered by the waves; for the wind was contrary.</verse>
<verse>And in the fourth watch of the night He came to them, walking on the sea.</verse>
<verse>When the disciples saw Him walking on the sea, they were terrified, and said, "It is a ghost!" And they cried out in fear.</verse>
<verse>But immediately Jesus spoke to them, saying, "Take courage, it is I; do not be afraid."</verse>
<verse>Peter said to Him, "Lord, if it is You, command me to come to You on the water."</verse>
<verse>And He said, "Come!" And Peter got out of the boat, and walked on the water and came toward Jesus.</verse>
<verse>But seeing the wind, he became frightened, and beginning to sink, he cried out, "Lord, save me!"</verse>
<verse>Immediately Jesus stretched out His hand and took hold of him, and said to him, "You of little faith, why did you doubt?"</verse>
<verse>When they got into the boat, the wind stopped.</verse>
<verse>And those who were in the boat worshiped Him, saying, "You are certainly God's Son!"</verse>
<verse>When they had crossed over, they came to land at Gennesaret.</verse>
<verse>And when the men of that place recognized Him, they sent word into all that surrounding district and brought to Him all who were sick;</verse>
<verse>and they implored Him that they might just touch the fringe of His cloak; and as many as touched it were cured.</verse>
</chapter>