<chapter translation="NASB" testament="New" book="Matthew" book_id="40" n="15">
<verse>Then some Pharisees and scribes came to Jesus from Jerusalem and said,</verse>
<verse>"Why do Your disciples break the tradition of the elders? For they do not wash their hands when they eat bread."</verse>
<verse>And He answered and said to them, "Why do you yourselves transgress the commandment of God for the sake of your tradition?</verse>
<verse>"For God said, 'HONOR YOUR FATHER AND MOTHER,' and, 'HE WHO SPEAKS EVIL OF FATHER OR MOTHER IS TO BE PUT TO DEATH.'</verse>
<verse>"But you say, 'Whoever says to his father or mother, "Whatever I have that would help you has been given to God,"</verse>
<verse>he is not to honor his father or his mother.' And by this you invalidated the word of God for the sake of your tradition.</verse>
<verse>"You hypocrites, rightly did Isaiah prophesy of you:</verse>
<verse>'THIS PEOPLE HONORS ME WITH THEIR LIPS, BUT THEIR HEART IS FAR AWAY FROM ME.</verse>
<verse>'BUT IN VAIN DO THEY WORSHIP ME, TEACHING AS DOCTRINES THE PRECEPTS OF MEN.'"</verse>
<verse>After Jesus called the crowd to Him, He said to them, "Hear and understand.</verse>
<verse>"It is not what enters into the mouth that defiles the man, but what proceeds out of the mouth, this defiles the man."</verse>
<verse>Then the disciples came and said to Him, "Do You know that the Pharisees were offended when they heard this statement?"</verse>
<verse>But He answered and said, "Every plant which My heavenly Father did not plant shall be uprooted.</verse>
<verse>"Let them alone; they are blind guides of the blind. And if a blind man guides a blind man, both will fall into a pit."</verse>
<verse>Peter said to Him, "Explain the parable to us."</verse>
<verse>Jesus said, "Are you still lacking in understanding also?</verse>
<verse>"Do you not understand that everything that goes into the mouth passes into the stomach, and is eliminated?</verse>
<verse>"But the things that proceed out of the mouth come from the heart, and those defile the man.</verse>
<verse>"For out of the heart come evil thoughts, murders, adulteries, fornications, thefts, false witness, slanders.</verse>
<verse>"These are the things which defile the man; but to eat with unwashed hands does not defile the man."</verse>
<verse>Jesus went away from there, and withdrew into the district of Tyre and Sidon.</verse>
<verse>And a Canaanite woman from that region came out and began to cry out, saying, "Have mercy on me, Lord, Son of David; my daughter is cruelly demon-possessed."</verse>
<verse>But He did not answer her a word. And His disciples came and implored Him, saying, "Send her away, because she keeps shouting at us."</verse>
<verse>But He answered and said, "I was sent only to the lost sheep of the house of Israel."</verse>
<verse>But she came and began to bow down before Him, saying, "Lord, help me!"</verse>
<verse>And He answered and said, "It is not good to take the children's bread and throw it to the dogs."</verse>
<verse>But she said, "Yes, Lord; but even the dogs feed on the crumbs which fall from their masters' table."</verse>
<verse>Then Jesus said to her, "O woman, your faith is great; it shall be done for you as you wish." And her daughter was healed at once.</verse>
<verse>Departing from there, Jesus went along by the Sea of Galilee, and having gone up on the mountain, He was sitting there.</verse>
<verse>And large crowds came to Him, bringing with them those who were lame, crippled, blind, mute, and many others, and they laid them down at His feet; and He healed them.</verse>
<verse>So the crowd marveled as they saw the mute speaking, the crippled restored, and the lame walking, and the blind seeing; and they glorified the God of Israel.</verse>
<verse>And Jesus called His disciples to Him, and said, "I feel compassion for the people, because they have remained with Me now three days and have nothing to eat; and I do not want to send them away hungry, for they might faint on the way."</verse>
<verse>The disciples said to Him, "Where would we get so many loaves in this desolate place to satisfy such a large crowd?"</verse>
<verse>And Jesus said to them, "How many loaves do you have?" And they said, "Seven, and a few small fish."</verse>
<verse>And He directed the people to sit down on the ground;</verse>
<verse>and He took the seven loaves and the fish; and giving thanks, He broke them and started giving them to the disciples, and the disciples gave them to the people.</verse>
<verse>And they all ate and were satisfied, and they picked up what was left over of the broken pieces, seven large baskets full.</verse>
<verse>And those who ate were four thousand men, besides women and children.</verse>
<verse>And sending away the crowds, Jesus got into the boat and came to the region of Magadan.</verse>
</chapter>