<chapter translation="NASB" testament="New" book="Matthew" book_id="40" n="25">
<verse>"Then the kingdom of heaven will be comparable to ten virgins, who took their lamps and went out to meet the bridegroom.</verse>
<verse>"Five of them were foolish, and five were prudent.</verse>
<verse>"For when the foolish took their lamps, they took no oil with them,</verse>
<verse>but the prudent took oil in flasks along with their lamps.</verse>
<verse>"Now while the bridegroom was delaying, they all got drowsy and began to sleep.</verse>
<verse>"But at midnight there was a shout, 'Behold, the bridegroom! Come out to meet him.'</verse>
<verse>"Then all those virgins rose and trimmed their lamps.</verse>
<verse>"The foolish said to the prudent, 'Give us some of your oil, for our lamps are going out.'</verse>
<verse>"But the prudent answered, 'No, there will not be enough for us and you too; go instead to the dealers and buy some for yourselves.'</verse>
<verse>"And while they were going away to make the purchase, the bridegroom came, and those who were ready went in with him to the wedding feast; and the door was shut.</verse>
<verse>"Later the other virgins also came, saying, 'Lord, lord, open up for us.'</verse>
<verse>"But he answered, 'Truly I say to you, I do not know you.'</verse>
<verse>"Be on the alert then, for you do not know the day nor the hour.</verse>
<verse>"For it is just like a man about to go on a journey, who called his own slaves and entrusted his possessions to them.</verse>
<verse>"To one he gave five talents, to another, two, and to another, one, each according to his own ability; and he went on his journey.</verse>
<verse>"Immediately the one who had received the five talents went and traded with them, and gained five more talents.</verse>
<verse>"In the same manner the one who had received the two talents gained two more.</verse>
<verse>"But he who received the one talent went away, and dug a hole in the ground and hid his master's money.</verse>
<verse>"Now after a long time the master of those slaves came and settled accounts with them.</verse>
<verse>"The one who had received the five talents came up and brought five more talents, saying, 'Master, you entrusted five talents to me. See, I have gained five more talents.'</verse>
<verse>"His master said to him, 'Well done, good and faithful slave. You were faithful with a few things, I will put you in charge of many things; enter into the joy of your master.'</verse>
<verse>"Also the one who had received the two talents came up and said, 'Master, you entrusted two talents to me. See, I have gained two more talents.'</verse>
<verse>"His master said to him, 'Well done, good and faithful slave. You were faithful with a few things, I will put you in charge of many things; enter into the joy of your master.'</verse>
<verse>"And the one also who had received the one talent came up and said, 'Master, I knew you to be a hard man, reaping where you did not sow and gathering where you scattered no seed.</verse>
<verse>'And I was afraid, and went away and hid your talent in the ground. See, you have what is yours.'</verse>
<verse>"But his master answered and said to him, 'You wicked, lazy slave, you knew that I reap where I did not sow and gather where I scattered no seed.</verse>
<verse>'Then you ought to have put my money in the bank, and on my arrival I would have received my money back with interest.</verse>
<verse>'Therefore take away the talent from him, and give it to the one who has the ten talents.'</verse>
<verse>"For to everyone who has, more shall be given, and he will have an abundance; but from the one who does not have, even what he does have shall be taken away.</verse>
<verse>"Throw out the worthless slave into the outer darkness; in that place there will be weeping and gnashing of teeth.</verse>
<verse>"But when the Son of Man comes in His glory, and all the angels with Him, then He will sit on His glorious throne.</verse>
<verse>"All the nations will be gathered before Him; and He will separate them from one another, as the shepherd separates the sheep from the goats;</verse>
<verse>and He will put the sheep on His right, and the goats on the left.</verse>
<verse>"Then the King will say to those on His right, 'Come, you who are blessed of My Father, inherit the kingdom prepared for you from the foundation of the world.</verse>
<verse>'For I was hungry, and you gave Me something to eat; I was thirsty, and you gave Me something to drink; I was a stranger, and you invited Me in;</verse>
<verse>naked, and you clothed Me; I was sick, and you visited Me; I was in prison, and you came to Me.'</verse>
<verse>"Then the righteous will answer Him, 'Lord, when did we see You hungry, and feed You, or thirsty, and give You something to drink?</verse>
<verse>'And when did we see You a stranger, and invite You in, or naked, and clothe You?</verse>
<verse>'When did we see You sick, or in prison, and come to You?'</verse>
<verse>"The King will answer and say to them, 'Truly I say to you, to the extent that you did it to one of these brothers of Mine, even the least of them, you did it to Me.'</verse>
<verse>"Then He will also say to those on His left, 'Depart from Me, accursed ones, into the eternal fire which has been prepared for the devil and his angels;</verse>
<verse>for I was hungry, and you gave Me nothing to eat; I was thirsty, and you gave Me nothing to drink;</verse>
<verse>I was a stranger, and you did not invite Me in; naked, and you did not clothe Me; sick, and in prison, and you did not visit Me.'</verse>
<verse>"Then they themselves also will answer, 'Lord, when did we see You hungry, or thirsty, or a stranger, or naked, or sick, or in prison, and did not take care of You?'</verse>
<verse>"Then He will answer them, 'Truly I say to you, to the extent that you did not do it to one of the least of these, you did not do it to Me.'</verse>
<verse>"These will go away into eternal punishment, but the righteous into eternal life."</verse>
</chapter>