<chapter translation="NASB" testament="New" book="Matthew" book-id="40" n="28">
<verse>Now after the Sabbath, as it began to dawn toward the first day of the week, Mary Magdalene and the other Mary came to look at the grave.</verse>
<verse>And behold, a severe earthquake had occurred, for an angel of the Lord descended from heaven and came and rolled away the stone and sat upon it.</verse>
<verse>And his appearance was like lightning, and his clothing as white as snow.</verse>
<verse>The guards shook for fear of him and became like dead men.</verse>
<verse>The angel said to the women, "Do not be afraid; for I know that you are looking for Jesus who has been crucified.</verse>
<verse>"He is not here, for He has risen, just as He said. Come, see the place where He was lying.</verse>
<verse>"Go quickly and tell His disciples that He has risen from the dead; and behold, He is going ahead of you into Galilee, there you will see Him; behold, I have told you."</verse>
<verse>And they left the tomb quickly with fear and great joy and ran to report it to His disciples.</verse>
<verse>And behold, Jesus met them and greeted them. And they came up and took hold of His feet and worshiped Him.</verse>
<verse>Then Jesus said to them, "Do not be afraid; go and take word to My brethren to leave for Galilee, and there they will see Me."</verse>
<verse>Now while they were on their way, some of the guard came into the city and reported to the chief priests all that had happened.</verse>
<verse>And when they had assembled with the elders and consulted together, they gave a large sum of money to the soldiers,</verse>
<verse>and said, "You are to say, 'His disciples came by night and stole Him away while we were asleep.'</verse>
<verse>"And if this should come to the governor's ears, we will win him over and keep you out of trouble."</verse>
<verse>And they took the money and did as they had been instructed; and this story was widely spread among the Jews, and is to this day.</verse>
<verse>But the eleven disciples proceeded to Galilee, to the mountain which Jesus had designated.</verse>
<verse>When they saw Him, they worshiped Him; but some were doubtful.</verse>
<verse>And Jesus came up and spoke to them, saying, "All authority has been given to Me in heaven and on earth.</verse>
<verse>"Go therefore and make disciples of all the nations, baptizing them in the name of the Father and the Son and the Holy Spirit,</verse>
<verse>teaching them to observe all that I commanded you; and lo, I am with you always, even to the end of the age."</verse>
</chapter>