<chapter translation="NIV" testament="New" book="1 Corinthians" book-id="46" n="11">
<verse>Follow my example, as I follow the example of Christ.</verse>
<verse>I praise you for remembering me in everything and for holding to the teachings, just as I passed them on to you.</verse>
<verse>Now I want you to realize that the head of every man is Christ, and the head of the woman is man, and the head of Christ is God.</verse>
<verse>Every man who prays or prophesies with his head covered dishonors his head.</verse>
<verse>And every woman who prays or prophesies with her head uncovered dishonors her head--it is just as though her head were shaved.</verse>
<verse>If a woman does not cover her head, she should have her hair cut off; and if it is a disgrace for a woman to have her hair cut or shaved off, she should cover her head.</verse>
<verse>A man ought not to cover his head, since he is the image and glory of God; but the woman is the glory of man.</verse>
<verse>For man did not come from woman, but woman from man;</verse>
<verse>neither was man created for woman, but woman for man.</verse>
<verse>For this reason, and because of the angels, the woman ought to have a sign of authority on her head.</verse>
<verse>In the Lord, however, woman is not independent of man, nor is man independent of woman.</verse>
<verse>For as woman came from man, so also man is born of woman. But everything comes from God.</verse>
<verse>Judge for yourselves: Is it proper for a woman to pray to God with her head uncovered?</verse>
<verse>Does not the very nature of things teach you that if a man has long hair, it is a disgrace to him,</verse>
<verse>but that if a woman has long hair, it is her glory? For long hair is given to her as a covering.</verse>
<verse>If anyone wants to be contentious about this, we have no other practice--nor do the churches of God.</verse>
<verse>In the following directives I have no praise for you, for your meetings do more harm than good.</verse>
<verse>In the first place, I hear that when you come together as a church, there are divisions among you, and to some extent I believe it.</verse>
<verse>No doubt there have to be differences among you to show which of you have God's approval.</verse>
<verse>When you come together, it is not the Lord's Supper you eat,</verse>
<verse>for as you eat, each of you goes ahead without waiting for anybody else. One remains hungry, another gets drunk.</verse>
<verse>Don't you have homes to eat and drink in? Or do you despise the church of God and humiliate those who have nothing? What shall I say to you? Shall I praise you for this? Certainly not!</verse>
<verse>For I received from the Lord what I also passed on to you: The Lord Jesus, on the night he was betrayed, took bread,</verse>
<verse>and when he had given thanks, he broke it and said, "This is my body, which is for you; do this in remembrance of me."</verse>
<verse>In the same way, after supper he took the cup, saying, "This cup is the new covenant in my blood; do this, whenever you drink it, in remembrance of me."</verse>
<verse>For whenever you eat this bread and drink this cup, you proclaim the Lord's death until he comes.</verse>
<verse>Therefore, whoever eats the bread or drinks the cup of the Lord in an unworthy manner will be guilty of sinning against the body and blood of the Lord.</verse>
<verse>A man ought to examine himself before he eats of the bread and drinks of the cup.</verse>
<verse>For anyone who eats and drinks without recognizing the body of the Lord eats and drinks judgment on himself.</verse>
<verse>That is why many among you are weak and sick, and a number of you have fallen asleep.</verse>
<verse>But if we judged ourselves, we would not come under judgment.</verse>
<verse>When we are judged by the Lord, we are being disciplined so that we will not be condemned with the world.</verse>
<verse>So then, my brothers, when you come together to eat, wait for each other.</verse>
<verse>If anyone is hungry, he should eat at home, so that when you meet together it may not result in judgment. And when I come I will give further directions.</verse>
</chapter>