<chapter translation="NIV" testament="New" book="1 Corinthians" book-id="46" n="16">
<verse>Now about the collection for God's people: Do what I told the Galatian churches to do.</verse>
<verse>On the first day of every week, each one of you should set aside a sum of money in keeping with his income, saving it up, so that when I come no collections will have to be made.</verse>
<verse>Then, when I arrive, I will give letters of introduction to the men you approve and send them with your gift to Jerusalem.</verse>
<verse>If it seems advisable for me to go also, they will accompany me.</verse>
<verse>After I go through Macedonia, I will come to you--for I will be going through Macedonia.</verse>
<verse>Perhaps I will stay with you awhile, or even spend the winter, so that you can help me on my journey, wherever I go.</verse>
<verse>I do not want to see you now and make only a passing visit; I hope to spend some time with you, if the Lord permits.</verse>
<verse>But I will stay on at Ephesus until Pentecost,</verse>
<verse>because a great door for effective work has opened to me, and there are many who oppose me.</verse>
<verse>If Timothy comes, see to it that he has nothing to fear while he is with you, for he is carrying on the work of the Lord, just as I am.</verse>
<verse>No one, then, should refuse to accept him. Send him on his way in peace so that he may return to me. I am expecting him along with the brothers.</verse>
<verse>Now about our brother Apollos: I strongly urged him to go to you with the brothers. He was quite unwilling to go now, but he will go when he has the opportunity.</verse>
<verse>Be on your guard; stand firm in the faith; be men of courage; be strong.</verse>
<verse>Do everything in love.</verse>
<verse>You know that the household of Stephanas were the first converts in Achaia, and they have devoted themselves to the service of the saints. I urge you, brothers,</verse>
<verse>to submit to such as these and to everyone who joins in the work, and labors at it.</verse>
<verse>I was glad when Stephanas, Fortunatus and Achaicus arrived, because they have supplied what was lacking from you.</verse>
<verse>For they refreshed my spirit and yours also. Such men deserve recognition.</verse>
<verse>The churches in the province of Asia send you greetings. Aquila and Priscilla greet you warmly in the Lord, and so does the church that meets at their house.</verse>
<verse>All the brothers here send you greetings. Greet one another with a holy kiss.</verse>
<verse>I, Paul, write this greeting in my own hand.</verse>
<verse>If anyone does not love the Lord--a curse be on him. Come, O Lord!</verse>
<verse>The grace of the Lord Jesus be with you.</verse>
<verse>My love to all of you in Christ Jesus. Amen.</verse>
</chapter>