<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Numbers" book_id="4" n="10">
<verse>GOD spoke to Moses:</verse>
<verse>"Make two bugles of hammered silver. Use them to call the congregation together and give marching orders to the camps.</verse>
<verse>When you blow them, the whole community will meet you at the entrance of the Tent of Meeting.</verse>
<verse>"When a bugle gives a single, short blast, that's the signal for the leaders, the heads of the clans, to assemble.</verse>
<verse>When it gives a long blast, that's the signal to march. At the first blast the tribes who were camped on the east set out.</verse>
<verse>At the second blast the camps on the south set out. The long blasts are the signals to march.</verse>
<verse>The bugle call that gathers the assembly is different from the signal to march.</verse>
<verse>"The sons of Aaron, the priests, are in charge of blowing the bugles; it's their assigned duty down through the generations.</verse>
<verse>When you go to war against an aggressor, blow a long blast on the bugle so that GOD will notice you and deliver you from your enemies.</verse>
<verse>Also at times of celebration, at the appointed feasts and New Moon festivals, blow the bugles over your Whole-Burnt-Offerings and Peace-Offerings: they will keep your attention on God. I am GOD, your God."</verse>
<verse>In the second year, on the twentieth day of the second month, the Cloud went up from over The Dwelling of The Testimony.</verse>
<verse>At that the People of Israel set out on their travels from the Wilderness of Sinai until the Cloud finally settled in the Wilderness of Paran.</verse>
<verse>They began their march at the command of GOD through Moses.</verse>
<verse>The flag of the camp of Judah led the way, rank after rank under the command of Nahshon son of Amminadab.</verse>
<verse>Nethanel son of Zuar commanded the forces of the tribe of Issachar,</verse>
<verse>and Eliab son of Helon commanded the forces of the tribe of Zebulun.</verse>
<verse>As soon as The Dwelling was taken down, the Gershonites and the Merarites set out, carrying The Dwelling.</verse>
<verse>The flag of the camp of Reuben was next with Elizur son of Shedeur in command.</verse>
<verse>Shelumiel son of Zurishaddai commanded the forces of the tribe of Simeon;</verse>
<verse>Eliasaph son of Deuel commanded the forces of the tribe of Gad.</verse>
<verse>Then the Kohathites left, carrying the holy things. By the time they arrived The Dwelling would be set up.</verse>
<verse>The flag of the tribe of Ephraim moved out next, commanded by Elishama son of Ammihud.</verse>
<verse>Gamaliel son of Pedahzur commanded the forces of the tribe of Manasseh;</verse>
<verse>Abidan son of Gideoni commanded the forces of the tribe of Benjamin.</verse>
<verse>Finally, under the flag of the tribe of Dan, the rear guard of all the camps marched out with Ahiezer son of Ammishaddai in command.</verse>
<verse>Pagiel son of Ocran commanded the forces of the tribe of Asher;</verse>
<verse>Ahira son of Enan commanded the forces of the tribe of Naphtali.</verse>
<verse>These were the marching units of the People of Israel. They were on their way.</verse>
<verse>Moses said to his brother-in-law Hobab son of Reuel the Midianite, Moses' father-in-law, "We're marching to the place about which GOD promised, "I'll give it to you.' Come with us; we'll treat you well. GOD has promised good things for Israel."</verse>
<verse>But Hobab said, "I'm not coming; I'm going back home to my own country, to my own family."</verse>
<verse>Moses countered, "Don't leave us. You know all the best places to camp in the wilderness. We need your eyes.</verse>
<verse>If you come with us, we'll make sure that you share in all the good things GOD will do for us."</verse>
<verse>And so off they marched. From the Mountain of GOD they marched three days with the Chest of the Covenant of GOD in the lead to scout out a campsite.</verse>
<verse>The Cloud of GOD was above them by day when they marched from the camp.</verse>
<verse>With the Chest leading the way, Moses would say, Get up, GOD! Put down your enemies! Chase those who hate you to the hills!</verse>
<verse>And when the Chest was set down, he would say, Rest with us, GOD, Stay with the many, Many thousands of Israel.</verse>
</chapter>