<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Numbers" book_id="4" n="15">
<verse>GOD spoke to Moses:</verse>
<verse>"Speak to the People of Israel. Tell them, When you enter your homeland that I am giving to you</verse>
<verse>and sacrifice a Fire-Gift to GOD, a Whole-Burnt-Offering or any sacrifice from the herd or flock for a Vow-Offering or Freewill-Offering at one of the appointed feasts, as a pleasing fragrance for GOD,</verse>
<verse>the one bringing the offering shall present to GOD a Grain-Offering of two quarts of fine flour mixed with a quart of oil.</verse>
<verse>With each lamb for the Whole-Burnt-Offering or other sacrifice, prepare a quart of oil and a quart of wine as a Drink-Offering.</verse>
<verse>"For a ram prepare a Grain-Offering of four quarts of fine flour mixed with one and a quarter quarts of oil</verse>
<verse>and one and a quarter quarts of wine as a Drink-Offering. Present it as a pleasing fragrance to GOD.</verse>
<verse>"When you prepare a young bull as a Whole-Burnt-Offering or sacrifice for a special vow or a Peace-Offering to GOD,</verse>
<verse>bring with the bull a Grain-Offering of six quarts of fine flour and two quarts of oil.</verse>
<verse>Also bring two quarts of wine as a Drink-Offering. It will be a Fire-Gift, a pleasing fragrance to GOD.</verse>
<verse>"Each bull or ram, each lamb or young goat, is to be prepared in this same way.</verse>
<verse>Carry out this procedure for each one, no matter how many you have to prepare.</verse>
<verse>"Every native-born Israelite is to follow this procedure when he brings a Fire-Gift as a pleasing fragrance to GOD.</verse>
<verse>In future generations, when a foreigner or visitor living at length among you presents a Fire-Gift as a pleasing fragrance to GOD, the same procedures must be followed.</verse>
<verse>The community has the same rules for you and the foreigner living among you. This is the regular rule for future generations. You and the foreigner are the same before GOD.</verse>
<verse>The same laws and regulations apply to both you and the foreigner who lives with you."</verse>
<verse>GOD spoke to Moses:</verse>
<verse>"Speak to the People of Israel. Tell them, When you enter the land into which I'm bringing you,</verse>
<verse>and you eat the food of that country, set some aside as an offering for GOD.</verse>
<verse>From the first batch of bread dough make a round loaf for an offering--an offering from the threshing floor.</verse>
<verse>Down through the future generations make this offering to GOD from each first batch of dough. [JC]</verse>
<verse>"But if you should get off the beaten track and not keep the commands which GOD spoke to Moses,</verse>
<verse>any of the things that GOD commanded you under the authority of Moses from the time that GOD first commanded you right up to this present time,</verse>
<verse>and if it happened more or less by mistake, with the congregation unaware of it, then the whole congregation is to sacrifice one young bull as a Whole-Burnt-Offering, a pleasing fragrance to GOD, accompanied by its Grain-Offering and Drink-Offering as stipulated in the rules, and a he-goat as an Absolution-Offering.</verse>
<verse>The priest is to atone for the entire community of the People of Israel and they will stand forgiven. The sin was not deliberate, and they offered to GOD the Fire-Gift and Absolution-Offering for their inadvertence.</verse>
<verse>The whole community of Israel including the foreigners living there will be absolved, because everyone was involved in the error.</verse>
<verse>"But if it's just one person who sins by mistake, not realizing what he's doing, he is to bring a yearling she-goat as an Absolution-Offering.</verse>
<verse>The priest then is to atone for the person who accidentally sinned, to make atonement before GOD so that it won't be held against him.</verse>
<verse>"The same standard holds for everyone who sins by mistake; the native-born Israelites and the foreigners go by the same rules.</verse>
<verse>"But the person, native or foreigner, who sins defiantly, deliberately blaspheming GOD, must be cut off from his people:</verse>
<verse>He has despised GOD's word, he has violated GOD's command; that person must be kicked out of the community, ostracized, left alone in his wrongdoing." [JC]</verse>
<verse>Once, during those wilderness years of the People of Israel, a man was caught gathering wood on the Sabbath.</verse>
<verse>The ones who caught him hauled him before Moses and Aaron and the entire congregation.</verse>
<verse>They put him in custody until it became clear what to do with him.</verse>
<verse>Then GOD spoke to Moses: "Give the man the death penalty. Yes, kill him, the whole community hurling stones at him outside the camp."</verse>
<verse>So the whole community took him outside the camp and threw stones at him, an execution commanded by GOD and given through Moses. [JC]</verse>
<verse>GOD spoke to Moses:</verse>
<verse>"Speak to the People of Israel. Tell them that from now on they are to make tassels on the corners of their garments and to mark each corner tassel with a blue thread.</verse>
<verse>When you look at these tassels you'll remember and keep all the commandments of GOD, and not get distracted by everything you feel or see that seduces you into infidelities.</verse>
<verse>The tassels will signal remembrance and observance of all my commandments, to live a holy life to GOD.</verse>
<verse>I am your GOD who rescued you from the land of Egypt to be your personal God. Yes, I am GOD, your God."</verse>
</chapter>