<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Numbers" book_id="4" n="28">
<verse>GOD spoke to Moses:</verse>
<verse>"Command the People of Israel. Tell them, You're in charge of presenting my food, my Fire-Gifts of pleasing fragrance, at the set times.</verse>
<verse>Tell them, This is the Fire-Gift that you are to present to GOD: two healthy yearling lambs each day as a regular Whole-Burnt-Offering.</verse>
<verse>Sacrifice one lamb in the morning, the other in the evening,</verse>
<verse>together with two quarts of fine flour mixed with a quart of olive oil for a Grain-Offering.</verse>
<verse>This is the standard Whole-Burnt-Offering instituted at Mount Sinai as a pleasing fragrance, a Fire-Gift to GOD.</verse>
<verse>The Drink-Offering that goes with it is a quart of strong beer with each lamb. Pour out the Drink-Offering before GOD in the Sanctuary.</verse>
<verse>Sacrifice the second lamb in the evening with the Grain-Offering and Drink-Offering the same as in the morning--a Fire-Gift of pleasing fragrance for GOD. [JC]</verse>
<verse>"On the Sabbath, sacrifice two healthy yearling lambs, together with the Drink-Offering and the Grain-Offering of four quarts of fine flour mixed with oil.</verse>
<verse>This is the regular Sabbath Whole-Burnt-Offering, in addition to the regular Whole-Burnt-Offering and its Drink-Offering. [JC]</verse>
<verse>"On the first of the month offer a Whole-Burnt-Offering to GOD: two young bulls, one ram, and seven male yearling lambs--all healthy.</verse>
<verse>"A Grain-Offering of six quarts of fine flour mixed with oil goes with each bull, four quarts of fine flour mixed with oil with the ram,</verse>
<verse>and two quarts of fine flour mixed with oil with each lamb. This is for a Whole-Burnt-Offering, a pleasing fragrance, a Fire-Gift to GOD.</verse>
<verse>Also, Drink-Offerings of two quarts of wine for each bull, one and a quarter quarts of wine for the ram, and a quart of wine for each lamb are to be poured out. "This is the first of the month Whole-Burnt-Offering to be made throughout the year.</verse>
<verse>In addition to the regular Whole-Burnt-Offering with its accompanying Drink-Offering, a he-goat is to be offered to GOD as an Absolution-Offering. [JC]</verse>
<verse>"GOD's Passover is to be held on the fourteenth day of the first month.</verse>
<verse>On the fifteenth day of this month hold a festival. "For seven days, eat only unraised bread:</verse>
<verse>Begin the first day in holy worship; don't do any regular work that day.</verse>
<verse>Bring a Fire-Gift to GOD, a Whole-Burnt-Offering: two young bulls, one ram, and seven male yearling lambs--all healthy.</verse>
<verse>Prepare a Grain-Offering of six quarts of fine flour mixed with oil for each bull, four quarts for the ram,</verse>
<verse>and two quarts for each lamb,</verse>
<verse>plus a goat as an Absolution-Offering to atone for you.</verse>
<verse>"Sacrifice these in addition to the regular morning Whole-Burnt-Offering.</verse>
<verse>Prepare the food this way for the Fire-Gift, a pleasing fragrance to GOD, every day for seven days. Prepare it in addition to the regular Whole-Burnt-Offering and Drink-Offering.</verse>
<verse>"Conclude the seventh day in holy worship; don't do any regular work on that day. [JC]</verse>
<verse>"On the Day of Firstfruits when you bring an offering of new grain to GOD on your Feast-of-Weeks, gather in holy worship and don't do any regular work.</verse>
<verse>Bring a Whole-Burnt-Offering of two young bulls, one ram, and seven male yearling lambs as a pleasing fragrance to GOD.</verse>
<verse>Prepare a Grain-Offering of six quarts of fine flour mixed with oil for each bull, four quarts for the ram,</verse>
<verse>and two quarts for each lamb,</verse>
<verse>plus a he-goat as an Absolution-Offering to atone for you.</verse>
<verse>"These are all over and above the daily Whole-Burnt-Offering and its Grain-Offering and the Drink-Offering. Remember, the animals must be healthy. [JC]</verse>
</chapter>