<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Numbers" book_id="4" n="29">
<verse>"On the first day of the seventh month, gather in holy worship and do no regular work. This is your Day-of-Trumpet-Blasts.</verse>
<verse>Sacrifice a Whole-Burnt-Offering: one young bull, one ram, and seven male yearling lambs--all healthy--as a pleasing fragrance to GOD.</verse>
<verse>Prepare a Grain-Offering of six quarts of fine flour mixed with oil for the bull, four quarts for the ram,</verse>
<verse>and two quarts for each lamb,</verse>
<verse>plus a he-goat as an Absolution-Offering to atone for you.</verse>
<verse>"These are all over and above the monthly and daily Whole-Burnt-Offerings with their Grain-Offerings and Drink-Offerings as prescribed, a pleasing fragrance, a Fire-Gift to GOD. [JC]</verse>
<verse>"On the tenth day of this seventh month, gather in holy worship, humble yourselves, and do no work.</verse>
<verse>"Bring a Whole-Burnt-Offering to GOD as a pleasing fragrance: one young bull, one ram, and seven yearling male lambs--all healthy.</verse>
<verse>Prepare a Grain-Offering of six quarts of fine flour mixed with oil for the bull, four quarts for the ram,</verse>
<verse>and two quarts for each of the seven lambs.</verse>
<verse>Also bring a he-goat as an Absolution-Offering to atone for you in addition to the regular Whole-Burnt-Offering with its Grain-Offering and Drink-Offering. [JC]</verse>
<verse>"Gather in holy worship on the fifteenth day of the seventh month; do no regular work. Celebrate a Festival to GOD for seven days.</verse>
<verse>Bring a Whole-Burnt-Offering, a Fire-Gift of pleasing fragrance to GOD: thirteen young bulls, two rams, and fourteen yearling male lambs--all healthy.</verse>
<verse>Prepare a Grain-Offering of six quarts of fine flour mixed with oil for each of the bulls, four quarts for each ram,</verse>
<verse>and two quarts for each of the fourteen lambs.</verse>
<verse>Also bring a he-goat as an Absolution-Offering in addition to the regular Whole-Burnt-Offering with its Grain-Offering and Drink-Offering.</verse>
<verse>"On the second day: twelve young bulls, two rams, and fourteen yearling male lambs--all healthy.</verse>
<verse>Prepare Grain-Offerings and Drink-Offerings to go with the bulls, rams, and lambs following the prescribed recipes.</verse>
<verse>And bring a he-goat as an Absolution-Offering in addition to the regular Whole-Burnt-Offering with its Grain-Offering and Drink-Offering.</verse>
<verse>"On the third day: eleven bulls, two rams, and fourteen male yearling lambs--all healthy.</verse>
<verse>Prepare Grain-Offerings and Drink-Offerings to go with the bulls, rams, and lambs following the prescribed recipes.</verse>
<verse>And bring a he-goat as an Absolution-Offering in addition to the regular Whole-Burnt-Offering with its Grain-Offering and Drink-Offering.</verse>
<verse>"On the fourth day: ten bulls, two rams, and fourteen male yearling lambs--all healthy.</verse>
<verse>Prepare Grain-Offerings and Drink-Offerings to go with the bulls, rams, and lambs following the prescribed recipes.</verse>
<verse>And bring a he-goat as an Absolution-Offering in addition to the regular Whole-Burnt-Offering with its Grain-Offering and Drink-Offering.</verse>
<verse>"On the fifth day: nine bulls, two rams, and fourteen male yearling lambs--all healthy.</verse>
<verse>Prepare Grain-Offerings and Drink-Offerings to go with the bulls, rams, and lambs following the prescribed recipes.</verse>
<verse>And bring a he-goat as an Absolution-Offering in addition to the regular Whole-Burnt-Offering with its Grain-Offering and Drink-Offering.</verse>
<verse>"On the sixth day: eight bulls, two rams, and fourteen male yearling lambs--all healthy.</verse>
<verse>Prepare Grain-Offerings and Drink-Offerings to go with the bulls, rams, and lambs following the prescribed recipes.</verse>
<verse>And bring a he-goat as an Absolution-Offering in addition to the regular Whole-Burnt-Offering with its Grain-Offering and Drink-Offering.</verse>
<verse>"On the seventh day: seven bulls, two rams, and fourteen male yearling lambs--all healthy.</verse>
<verse>Prepare Grain-Offerings and Drink-Offerings to go with the bulls, rams, and lambs following the prescribed recipes.</verse>
<verse>And bring a he-goat as an Absolution-Offering in addition to the regular Whole-Burnt-Offering with its Grain-Offering and Drink-Offering.</verse>
<verse>"On the eighth day: Gather in holy worship; do no regular work.</verse>
<verse>Bring a Fire-Gift of pleasing fragrance to GOD, a Whole-Burnt-Offering: one bull, one ram, and seven male yearling lambs--all healthy.</verse>
<verse>Prepare Grain-Offerings and Drink-Offerings to go with the bulls, rams, and lambs following the prescribed recipes.</verse>
<verse>And bring a he-goat as an Absolution-Offering in addition to the regular Whole-Burnt-Offering with its Grain-Offering and Drink-Offering.</verse>
<verse>"Sacrifice these to GOD as a congregation at your set feasts: your Whole-Burnt-Offerings, Grain-Offerings, Drink-Offerings, and Peace-Offerings. These are all over and above your personal Vow-Offerings and Freewill-Offerings."</verse>
<verse>Moses instructed the People of Israel in all that GOD commanded him.</verse>
</chapter>