<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Numbers" book-id="4" n="34">
<verse>GOD spoke to Moses:</verse>
<verse>"Command the People of Israel. Tell them: When you enter Canaan, these are the borders of the land you are getting as an inheritance:</verse>
<verse>"Your southern border will take in some of the Wilderness of Zin where it touches Edom. It starts in the east at the Dead Sea,</verse>
<verse>curves south of Scorpion Pass and on to Zin, continues south of Kadesh Barnea, then to Hazar Addar and on to Azmon,</verse>
<verse>where it takes a turn to the northwest to the Brook of Egypt and on to the Mediterranean Sea.</verse>
<verse>"Your western border will be the Mediterranean Sea.</verse>
<verse>"Your northern border runs on a line from the Mediterranean Sea to Mount Hor,</verse>
<verse>and from Mount Hor to Lebo Hamath, connects to Zedad,</verse>
<verse>continues to Ziphron, and ends at Hazar Enan. This is your northern border.</verse>
<verse>"Your eastern border runs on a line from Hazar Enan to Shepham.</verse>
<verse>The border goes south from Shepham to Riblah to the east of Ain, and continues along the slopes east of the Sea of Galilee.</verse>
<verse>The border then follows the Jordan River and ends at the Dead Sea. "This is your land with its four borders."</verse>
<verse>Moses then commanded the People of Israel: "This is the land: Divide up the inheritance by lot. GOD has ordered it to be given to the nine and a half tribes.</verse>
<verse>The tribe of Reuben, the tribe of Gad, and the half-tribe of Manasseh have already received their inheritance;</verse>
<verse>the two tribes and the half-tribe got their inheritance east of Jordan-Jericho, facing the sunrise." [JC]</verse>
<verse>GOD spoke to Moses:</verse>
<verse>"These are the men who will be in charge of distributing the inheritance of the land: Eleazar the priest and Joshua son of Nun.</verse>
<verse>Assign one leader from each tribe to help them in distributing the land.</verse>
<verse>Assign these: Caleb son of Jephunneh from the tribe of Judah;</verse>
<verse>Shemuel son of Ammihud from the tribe of Simeon;</verse>
<verse>Elidad son of Kislon from the tribe of Benjamin;</verse>
<verse>Bukki son of Jogli, leader from the tribe of Dan;</verse>
<verse>Hanniel son of Ephod, leader from the tribe of Manasseh son of Joseph;</verse>
<verse>Kemuel son of Shiphtan, leader from the tribe of Ephraim son of Joseph;</verse>
<verse>Elizaphan son of Parnach, leader from the tribe of Zebulun;</verse>
<verse>Paltiel son of Azzan, leader from the tribe of Issachar;</verse>
<verse>Ahihud son of Shelomi, leader from the tribe of Asher;</verse>
<verse>Pedahel son of Ammihud, leader from the tribe of Naphtali."</verse>
<verse>These are the men GOD commanded to hand out the assignments of land-inheritance to the People of Israel in the country of Canaan.</verse>
</chapter>