<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Numbers" book_id="4" n="36">
<verse>The heads of the ancestral clan of Gilead son of Makir, the son of Manasseh--they were from the clans of the descendants of Joseph--approached Moses and the leaders who were heads of the families in the People of Israel.</verse>
<verse>They said, "When GOD commanded my master to hand over the inheritance-lands by lot to the People of Israel, my master was also commanded by GOD to hand over the inheritance-land of Zelophehad our brother to his daughters.</verse>
<verse>But what happens if they marry into another tribe in the People of Israel? Their inheritance-land will be taken out of our ancestral tribe and get added into the tribe into which they married.</verse>
<verse>And then when the Year of Jubilee comes for the People of Israel their inheritance will be lumped in with the inheritance of the tribe into which they married--their land will be removed from our ancestors' inheritance!"</verse>
<verse>Moses, at GOD's command, issued this order to the People of Israel: "What the tribe of the sons of Joseph says is right.</verse>
<verse>This is GOD's command to Zelophehad's daughters: They are free to marry anyone they choose as long as they marry within their ancestral clan.</verse>
<verse>The inheritance-land of the People of Israel must not get passed around from tribe to tribe. No, keep the tribal inheritance-land in the family.</verse>
<verse>Every daughter who inherits land, regardless of the tribe she is in, must marry a man from within her father's tribal clan. Every Israelite is responsible for making sure the inheritance stays within the ancestral tribe.</verse>
<verse>No inheritance-land may be passed from tribe to tribe; each tribe of the People of Israel must hold tight to its own land."</verse>
<verse>Zelophehad's daughters did just as GOD commanded Moses.</verse>
<verse>Mahlah, Tirzah, Hoglah, Milcah, and Noah, Zelophehad's daughters, all married their cousins on their father's side.</verse>
<verse>They married within the families of Manasseh son of Joseph and their inheritance-lands stayed in their father's family.</verse>
<verse>These are the commands and regulations that GOD commanded through the authority of Moses to the People of Israel on the Plains of Moab at Jordan-Jericho.</verse>
</chapter>