<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Ezekiel" book-id="26" n="11">
<verse>Then the Spirit picked me up and took me to the gate of the Temple that faces east. There were twenty-five men standing at the gate. I recognized the leaders, Jaazaniah son of Azzur and Pelatiah son of Benaiah.</verse>
<verse>GOD said, "Son of man, these are the men who draw up blueprints for sin, who think up new programs for evil in this city.</verse>
<verse>They say, "We can make anything happen here. We're the best. We're the choice pieces of meat in the soup pot.'</verse>
<verse>"Oppose them, son of man. Preach against them."</verse>
<verse>Then the Spirit of GOD came upon me and told me what to say: "This is what GOD says: "That's a fine public speech, Israel, but I know what you are thinking.</verse>
<verse>You've murdered a lot of people in this city. The streets are piled high with corpses.'</verse>
<verse>"Therefore this is what GOD, the Master, says: "The corpses that you've piled in the streets are the meat and this city is the soup pot, and you're not even in the pot! I'm throwing you out!</verse>
<verse>You fear war, but war is what you're going to get. I'm bringing war against you.</verse>
<verse>I'm throwing you out of this city, giving you over to foreigners, and punishing you good.</verse>
<verse>You'll be killed in battle. I'll carry out judgment on you at the borders of Israel. Then you'll realize that I am GOD.</verse>
<verse>This city will not be your soup pot and you won't be the choice pieces of meat in it either. Hardly. I will carry out judgment on you at the borders of Israel</verse>
<verse>and you'll realize that I am GOD, for you haven't followed my statutes and ordinances. Instead of following my ways, you've sunk to the level of the laws of the nations around you.'"</verse>
<verse>Even while I was preaching, Pelatiah son of Benaiah died. I fell down, face to the ground, and prayed loudly, "O Master, GOD! Will you completely wipe out what's left of Israel?"</verse>
<verse>The answer from GOD came back:</verse>
<verse>"Son of man, your brothers--I mean the whole people of Israel who are in exile with you--are the people of whom the citizens of Jerusalem are saying, "They're in the far country, far from GOD. This land has been given to us to own.'</verse>
<verse>"Well, tell them this: "This is your Message from GOD, the Master. True, I sent you to the far country and scattered you through other lands. All the same, I've provided you a temporary sanctuary in the countries where you've gone.</verse>
<verse>I will gather you back from those countries and lands where you've been scattered and give you back the land of Israel.</verse>
<verse>You'll come back and clean house, throw out all the rotten images and obscene idols.</verse>
<verse>I'll give you a new heart. I'll put a new spirit in you. I'll cut out your stone heart and replace it with a red-blooded, firm-muscled heart.</verse>
<verse>Then you'll obey my statutes and be careful to obey my commands. You'll be my people! I'll be your God!</verse>
<verse>But not those who are self-willed and addicted to their rotten images and obscene idols! I'll see that they're paid in full for what they've done.' Decree of GOD, the Master."</verse>
<verse>Then the cherubim spread their wings, with the wheels beside them and the Glory of the God of Israel hovering over them.</verse>
<verse>The Glory of GOD ascended from within the city and rested on the mountain to the east of the city. [JC]</verse>
<verse>Then, still in the vision given me by the Spirit of God, the Spirit took me and carried me back to the exiles in Babylon. And then the vision left me.</verse>
<verse>I told the exiles everything that GOD had shown me.</verse>
</chapter>