<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Ezekiel" book-id="26" n="25">
<verse>GOD's Message came to me:</verse>
<verse>"Son of man, face Ammon and preach against the people:</verse>
<verse>Listen to the Message of GOD, the Master. This is what GOD has to say: Because you cheered when my Sanctuary was desecrated and the land of Judah was devastated and the people of Israel were taken into exile,</verse>
<verse>I'm giving you over to the people of the east. They'll move in and make themselves at home, eating the food right off your tables and drinking your milk.</verse>
<verse>I'll turn your capital, Rabbah, into pasture for camels and all your villages into corrals for flocks. Then you'll realize that I am GOD.</verse>
<verse>"GOD, the Master, says, Because you clapped and cheered, venting all your malicious contempt against the land of Israel,</verse>
<verse>I'll step in and hand you out as loot--first come, first served. I'll cross you off the roster of nations. There'll be nothing left of you. And you'll realize that I am GOD." [JC] 7</verse>
<verse>"GOD, the Master, says: Because Moab said, "Look, Judah's nothing special,'</verse>
<verse>I'll lay wide open the flank of Moab by exposing its lovely frontier villages to attack: Beth-jeshimoth, Baal-meon, and Kiriathaim.</verse>
<verse>I'll lump Moab in with Ammon and give them to the people of the east for the taking. Ammon won't be heard from again.</verse>
<verse>I'll punish Moab severely. And they'll realize that I am GOD." [JC]</verse>
<verse>"GOD, the Master, says: Because Edom reacted against the people of Judah in spiteful revenge and was so criminally vengeful against them,</verse>
<verse>therefore I, GOD, the Master, will oppose Edom and kill the lot of them, people and animals both. I'll waste it--corpses stretched from Teman to Dedan.</verse>
<verse>I'll use my people Israel to bring my vengeance down on Edom. My wrath will fuel their action. And they'll realize it's my vengeance. Decree of GOD the Master." [JC]</verse>
<verse>"GOD, the Master, says: Because the Philistines were so spitefully vengeful--all those centuries of stored-up malice!-and did their best to destroy Judah,</verse>
<verse>therefore I, GOD, the Master, will oppose the Philistines and cut down the Cretans and anybody else left along the seacoast.</verse>
<verse>Huge acts of vengeance, massive punishments! When I bring vengeance, they'll realize that I am GOD."</verse>
</chapter>