<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Ezekiel" book-id="26" n="26">
<verse>In the eleventh year, on the first day of the month, God's Message came to me:</verse>
<verse>"Son of man, Tyre cheered when they got the news of Jerusalem, exclaiming, Good! The gateway city is smashed! Now all her business comes my way. She's in ruins and I'm in clover.'</verse>
<verse>"Therefore, GOD, the Master, has this to say: I'm against you, Tyre, and I'll bring many nations surging against you, as the waves of the sea surging against the shore.</verse>
<verse>They'll smash the city walls of Tyre and break down her towers. I'll wash away the soil and leave nothing but bare rock.</verse>
<verse>She'll be an island of bare rock in the ocean, good for nothing but drying fishnets. Yes, I've said so.' Decree of GOD, the Master. "She'll be loot, free pickings for the nations!</verse>
<verse>Her surrounding villages will be butchered. Then they'll realize that I am GOD.'</verse>
<verse>"GOD, the Master, says: Look! Out of the north I'm bringing Nebuchadnezzar king of Babylon, a king's king, down on Tyre. He'll come with chariots and horses and riders--a huge army.</verse>
<verse>He'll massacre your surrounding villages and lay siege to you. He'll build siege ramps against your walls. A forest of shields will advance against you!</verse>
<verse>He'll pummel your walls with his battering rams and shatter your towers with his iron weapons.</verse>
<verse>You'll be covered with dust from his horde of horses--a thundering herd of war horses pouring through the breaches, pulling chariots. Oh, it will be an earthquake of an army and a city in shock!</verse>
<verse>Horses will stampede through the streets. Your people will be slaughtered and your huge pillars strewn like matchsticks.</verse>
<verse>The invaders will steal and loot--all that wealth, all that stuff! They'll knock down your fine houses and dump the stone and timber rubble into the sea.</verse>
<verse>And your parties, your famous good-time parties, will be no more. No more songs, no more lutes.</verse>
<verse>I'll reduce you to an island of bare rock, good for nothing but drying fishnets. You'll never be rebuilt. I, GOD, have said so. Decree of GOD, the Master.</verse>
<verse>"This is the Message of GOD, the Master, to Tyre: Won't the ocean islands shake at the crash of your collapse, at the groans of your wounded, at your mayhem and massacre?</verse>
<verse>"All up and down the coast, the princes will come down from their thrones, take off their royal robes and fancy clothes, and wrap themselves in sheer terror. They'll sit on the ground, shaken to the core, horrified at you.</verse>
<verse>Then they'll begin chanting a funeral song over you: Sunk! Sunk to the bottom of the sea, famous city on the sea! Power of the seas, you and your people, Intimidating everyone who lived in your shadows.</verse>
<verse>But now the islands are shaking at the sound of your crash, Ocean islands in tremors from the impact of your fall.'</verse>
<verse>"The Message of GOD, the Master: "When I turn you into a wasted city, a city empty of people, a ghost town, and when I bring up the great ocean deeps and cover you,</verse>
<verse>then I'll push you down among those who go to the grave, the long, long dead. I'll make you live there, in the grave in old ruins, with the buried dead. You'll never see the land of the living again.</verse>
<verse>I'll introduce you to the terrors of death and that'll be the end of you. They'll send out search parties for you, but you'll never be found. Decree of GOD, the Master.'"</verse>
</chapter>