<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Ezekiel" book-id="26" n="27">
<verse>GOD's Message came to me:</verse>
<verse>"You, son of man, raise a funeral song over Tyre.</verse>
<verse>Tell Tyre, gateway to the sea, merchant to the world, trader among the far-off islands, "This is what GOD, the Master, says: You boast, Tyre: "I'm the perfect ship--stately, handsome."</verse>
<verse>You ruled the high seas from a real beauty, crafted to perfection.</verse>
<verse>Your planking came from Mount Hermon junipers. A Lebanon cedar supplied your mast.</verse>
<verse>They made your oars from sturdy Bashan oaks. Cypress from Cyprus inlaid with ivory was used for the decks.</verse>
<verse>Your sail and flag were of colorful embroidered linen from Egypt. Your purple deck awnings also came from Cyprus.</verse>
<verse>Men of Sidon and Arvad pulled the oars. Your seasoned seamen, O Tyre, were the crew.</verse>
<verse>Ship's carpenters were old salts from Byblos. All the ships of the sea and their sailors clustered around you to barter for your goods.</verse>
<verse>Your army was composed of soldiers from Paras, Lud, and Put, Elite troops in uniformed splendor. They put you on the map!</verse>
<verse>Your city police were imported from Arvad, Helech, and Gammad. They hung their shields from the city walls, a final, perfect touch to your beauty.</verse>
<verse>Tarshish carried on business with you because of your great wealth. They worked for you, trading in silver, iron, tin, and lead for your products.</verse>
<verse>Greece, Tubal, and Meshech did business with you, trading slaves and bronze for your products.</verse>
<verse>Beth-togarmah traded work horses, war horses, and mules for your products.</verse>
<verse>The people of Rhodes did business with you. Many far-off islands traded with you in ivory and ebony.</verse>
<verse>Edom did business with you because of all your goods. They traded for your products with agate, purple textiles, embroidered cloth, fine linen, coral, and rubies.</verse>
<verse>Judah and Israel did business with you. They traded for your products with premium wheat, millet, honey, oil, and balm.</verse>
<verse>Damascus, attracted by your vast array of products and well-stocked warehouses, carried on business with you, trading in wine from Helbon and wool from Zahar.</verse>
<verse>Danites and Greeks from Uzal traded with you, using wrought iron, cinnamon, and spices.</verse>
<verse>Dedan traded with you for saddle blankets.</verse>
<verse>Arabia and all the Bedouin sheiks of Kedar traded lambs, rams, and goats with you.</verse>
<verse>Traders from Sheba and Raamah in South Arabia carried on business with you in premium spices, precious stones, and gold.</verse>
<verse>Haran, Canneh, and Eden from the east in Assyria and Media traded with you,</verse>
<verse>bringing elegant clothes, dyed textiles, and elaborate carpets to your bazaars.</verse>
<verse>The great Tarshish ships were your freighters, importing and exporting. Oh, it was big business for you, trafficking the seaways!</verse>
<verse>Your sailors row mightily, taking you into the high seas. Then a storm out of the east shatters your ship in the ocean deep.</verse>
<verse>Everything sinks--your rich goods and products, sailors and crew, ship's carpenters and soldiers, Sink to the bottom of the sea. Total shipwreck.</verse>
<verse>The cries of your sailors reverberate on shore.</verse>
<verse>Sailors everywhere abandon ship. Veteran seamen swim for dry land.</verse>
<verse>They cry out in grief, a choir of bitter lament over you. They smear their faces with ashes,</verse>
<verse>shave their heads, Wear rough burlap, wildly keening their loss.</verse>
<verse>They raise their funeral song: "Who on the high seas is like Tyre!"</verse>
<verse>As you crisscrossed the seas with your products, you satisfied many peoples. Your worldwide trade made earth's kings rich.</verse>
<verse>And now you're battered to bits by the waves, sunk to the bottom of the sea, And everything you've bought and sold has sunk to the bottom with you.</verse>
<verse>Everyone on shore looks on in terror. The hair of kings stands on end, their faces drawn and haggard!</verse>
<verse>The buyers and sellers of the world throw up their hands: This horror can't happen! Oh, this has happened!'"</verse>
</chapter>