<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Ezekiel" book-id="26" n="35">
<verse>GOD's Message came to me:</verse>
<verse>"Son of man, confront Mount Seir. Prophesy against it!</verse>
<verse>Tell them, "GOD, the Master, says: I'm coming down hard on you, Mount Seir. I'm stepping in and turning you to a pile of rubble.</verse>
<verse>I'll reduce your towns to piles of rocks. There'll be nothing left of you. Then you'll realize that I am GOD.</verse>
<verse>I'm doing this because you've kept this age-old grudge going against Israel: You viciously attacked them when they were already down, looking their final punishment in the face.</verse>
<verse>Therefore, as sure as I am the living God, I'm lining you up for a real bloodbath. Since you loved blood so much, you'll be chased by rivers of blood.</verse>
<verse>I'll reduce Mount Seir to a heap of rubble. No one will either come or go from that place!</verse>
<verse>I'll blanket your mountains with corpses. Massacred bodies will cover your hills and fill up your valleys and ditches.</verse>
<verse>I'll reduce you to ruins and all your towns will be ghost towns--population zero. Then you'll realize that I am GOD.</verse>
<verse>Because you said, "These two nations, these two countries, are mine. I'm taking over" (even though GOD is right there watching, right there listening),</verse>
<verse>I'll turn your hate-bloated anger and rage right back on you. You'll know I mean business when I bring judgment on you.</verse>
<verse>You'll realize then that I, GOD, have overheard all the vile abuse you've poured out against the mountains of Israel, saying, "They're roadkill and we're going to eat them up."</verse>
<verse>You've strutted around, talking so big, insolently pitting yourselves against me. And I've heard it all.</verse>
<verse>This is the verdict of GOD, the Master: With the whole earth applauding, I'll demolish you.</verse>
<verse>Since you danced in the streets, thinking it was so wonderful when Israel's inheritance was demolished, I'll give you the same treatment: demolition. Mount Seir demolished--yes, every square inch of Edom. Then they'll realize that I am GOD!'</verse>
</chapter>