<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Ezekiel" book_id="26" n="38">
<verse>GOD's Message came to me:</verse>
<verse>"Son of man, confront Gog from the country of Magog, head of Meshech and Tubal. Prophesy against him.</verse>
<verse>Say, "GOD, the Master, says: Be warned, Gog. I am against you, head of Meshech and Tubal.</verse>
<verse>I'm going to turn you around, put hooks in your jaws, and drag you off with your whole army, your horses and riders in full armor--all those shields and bucklers and swords--fighting men armed to the teeth!</verse>
<verse>Persia and Cush and Put will be in the ranks, also well-armed, as will</verse>
<verse>Gomer and its army and Beth-togarmah out of the north with its army. Many nations will be with you!</verse>
<verse>Get ready to fight, you and the whole company that's been called out. Take charge and wait for orders.</verse>
<verse>After a long time, you'll be given your orders. In the distant future you'll arrive at a country that has recovered from a devastating war. People from many nations will be gathered there on the mountains of Israel, for a long time now a wasteland. These people have been brought back from many countries and now live safe and secure.</verse>
<verse>You'll rise like a thunderstorm and roll in like clouds and cover the land, you and the massed troops with you.</verse>
<verse>Message of GOD, the Master: At that time you'll start thinking things over and cook up an evil plot.</verse>
<verse>You'll say, "I'm going to invade a country without defenses, attack an unsuspecting, carefree people going about their business--no gates to their cities, no locks on their doors.</verse>
<verse>And I'm going to plunder the place, march right in and clean them out, this rebuilt country risen from the ashes, these returned exiles and their booming economy centered down at the navel of the earth."</verse>
<verse>Sheba and Dedan and Tarshish, traders all out to make a fast buck, will say, "So! You've opened a new market for plunder! You've brought in your troops to get rich quick!"'</verse>
<verse>"Therefore, son of man, prophesy! Tell Gog, "A Message from GOD, the Master: When my people Israel are established securely, will you make your move?</verse>
<verse>Will you come down out of the far north, you and that mob of armies, charging out on your horses like a tidal wave across the land,</verse>
<verse>and invade my people Israel, covering the country like a cloud? When the time's ripe, I'll unleash you against my land in such a way that the nations will recognize me, realize that through you, Gog, in full view of the nations, I am putting my holiness on display.</verse>
<verse>A Message of GOD, the Master: Years ago when I spoke through my servants, the prophets of Israel, wasn't it you I was talking about? Year after year they prophesied that I would bring you against them.</verse>
<verse>And when the day comes, Gog, you will attack that land of Israel. Decree of GOD, the Master. My raging anger will erupt.</verse>
<verse>Fueled by blazing jealousy, I tell you that then there will be an earthquake that rocks the land of Israel.</verse>
<verse>Fish and birds and wild animals--even ants and beetles!-and every human being will tremble and shake before me. Mountains will disintegrate, terraces will crumble.</verse>
<verse>I'll order all-out war against you, Gog--Decree of GOD, the Master--Gog killing Gog on all the mountains of Israel.</verse>
<verse>I'll deluge Gog with judgment: disease and massacre, torrential rain and hail, volcanic lava pouring down on you and your mobs of troops and people.</verse>
<verse>I'll show you how great I am, how holy I am. I'll make myself known all over the world. Then you'll realize that I am GOD.'</verse>
</chapter>