<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Ezekiel" book-id="26" n="39">
<verse>"Son of man, prophesy against Gog. Say, "A Message of GOD, the Master: I'm against you, Gog, head of Meshech and Tubal.</verse>
<verse>I'm going to turn you around and drag you out, drag you out of the far north and down on the mountains of Israel.</verse>
<verse>Then I'll knock your bow out of your left hand and your arrows from your right hand.</verse>
<verse>On the mountains of Israel you'll be slaughtered, you and all your troops and the people with you. I'll serve you up as a meal to carrion birds and scavenging animals.</verse>
<verse>You'll be killed in the open field. I've given my word. Decree of GOD, the Master.'</verse>
<verse>"I'll set fire to Magog and the far-off islands, where people are so seemingly secure. And they'll realize that I am GOD.</verse>
<verse>"I'll reveal my holy name among my people Israel. Never again will I let my holy name be dragged in the mud. Then the nations will realize that I, GOD, am The Holy in Israel.</verse>
<verse>"It's coming! Yes, it will happen! This is the day I've been telling you about.</verse>
<verse>"People will come out of the cities of Israel and make a huge bonfire of the weapons of war, piling on shields large and small, bows and arrows, clubs and spears, a fire they'll keep going for seven years.</verse>
<verse>They won't need to go into the woods to get fuel for the fire. There'll be plenty of weapons to keep it going. They'll strip those who stripped them. They'll rob those who robbed them. Decree of GOD, the Master.</verse>
<verse>"At that time I'll set aside a burial ground for Gog in Israel at Traveler's Rest, just east of the sea. It will obstruct the route of travelers, blocking their way, the mass grave of Gog and his mob of an army. They'll call the place Gog's Mob.</verse>
<verse>"Israel will bury the corpses in order to clean up the land. It will take them seven months.</verse>
<verse>All the people will turn out to help with the burials. It will be a big day for the people when it's all done and I'm given my due.</verse>
<verse>Men will be hired full-time for the cleanup burial operation and will go through the country looking for defiling, decomposing corpses. At the end of seven months, there'll be an all-out final search.</verse>
<verse>Anyone who sees a bone will mark the place with a stick so the buriers can get it and bury it in the mass burial site, Gog's Mob.</verse>
<verse>(A town nearby is called Mobville, or Hamonah.) That's how they'll clean up the land.</verse>
<verse>"Son of man, GOD, the Master, says: Call the birds! Call the wild animals! Call out, "Gather and come, gather around my sacrificial meal that I'm preparing for you on the mountains of Israel. You'll eat meat and drink blood.</verse>
<verse>You'll eat off the bodies of great heroes and drink the blood of famous princes as if they were so many rams and lambs, goats and bulls, the choicest grain-fed animals of Bashan.</verse>
<verse>At the sacrificial meal I'm fixing for you, you'll eat fat till you're stuffed and drink blood till you're drunk.</verse>
<verse>At the table I set for you, you'll stuff yourselves with horses and riders, heroes and fighters of every kind.' Decree of GOD, the Master.</verse>
<verse>"I'll put my glory on display among the nations and they'll all see the judgment I execute, see me at work handing out judgment.</verse>
<verse>From that day on, Israel will realize that I am their GOD.</verse>
<verse>And the nations will get the message that it was because of their sins that Israel went into exile. They were disloyal to me and I turned away from them. I turned them over to their enemies and they were all killed.</verse>
<verse>I treated them as their polluted and sin-sated lives deserved. I turned away from them, refused to look at them.</verse>
<verse>"But now I will return Jacob back from exile, I'll be compassionate with all the people of Israel, and I'll be zealous for my holy name.</verse>
<verse>Eventually the memory will fade, the memory of their shame over their betrayals of me when they lived securely in their own land, safe and unafraid.</verse>
<verse>Once I've brought them back from foreign parts, gathered them in from enemy territories, I'll use them to demonstrate my holiness with all the nations watching.</verse>
<verse>Then they'll realize for sure that I am their GOD, for even though I sent them off into exile, I will gather them back to their own land, leaving not one soul behind.</verse>
<verse>After I've poured my Spirit on Israel, filled them with my life, I'll no longer turn away. I'll look them full in the face. Decree of GOD, the Master."</verse>
</chapter>