<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Ezekiel" book-id="26" n="47">
<verse>Now he brought me back to the entrance to the Temple. I saw water pouring out from under the Temple porch to the east (the Temple faced east). The water poured from the south side of the Temple, south of the altar.</verse>
<verse>He then took me out through the north gate and led me around the outside to the gate complex on the east. The water was gushing from under the south front of the Temple.</verse>
<verse>He walked to the east with a measuring tape and measured off fifteen hundred feet, leading me through water that was ankle-deep.</verse>
<verse>He measured off another fifteen hundred feet, leading me through water that was knee-deep. He measured off another fifteen hundred feet, leading me through water waist-deep.</verse>
<verse>He measured off another fifteen hundred feet. By now it was a river over my head, water to swim in, water no one could possibly walk through.</verse>
<verse>He said, "Son of man, have you had a good look?" Then he took me back to the riverbank.</verse>
<verse>While sitting on the bank, I noticed a lot of trees on both sides of the river.</verse>
<verse>He told me, "This water flows east, descends to the Arabah and then into the sea, the sea of stagnant waters. When it empties into those waters, the sea will become fresh.</verse>
<verse>Wherever the river flows, life will flourish--great schools of fish--because the river is turning the salt sea into fresh water. Where the river flows, life abounds.</verse>
<verse>Fishermen will stand shoulder to shoulder along the shore from En-gedi all the way north to En-eglaim, casting their nets. The sea will teem with fish of all kinds, like the fish of the Great Mediterranean.</verse>
<verse>"The swamps and marshes won't become fresh. They'll stay salty.</verse>
<verse>"But the river itself, on both banks, will grow fruit trees of all kinds. Their leaves won't wither, the fruit won't fail. Every month they'll bear fresh fruit because the river from the Sanctuary flows to them. Their fruit will be for food and their leaves for healing."</verse>
<verse>A Message from GOD, the Master: "These are the boundaries by which you are to divide up the inheritance of the land for the twelve tribes of Israel, with Joseph getting two parcels.</verse>
<verse>It is to be divided up equally. I swore in a solemn oath to give it to your ancestors, swore that this land would be your inheritance.</verse>
<verse>"These are the boundaries of the land: "The northern boundary runs from the Great Mediterranean Sea along the Hethlon road to where you turn off to the entrance of Hamath, Zedad,</verse>
<verse>Berothah, and Sibraim, which lies between the territory of Damascus and the territory of Hamath, and on to Hazor-hatticon on the border of Hauran.</verse>
<verse>The boundary runs from the Sea to Hazor-enon, with the territories of Damascus and Hamath to the north. That is the northern boundary.</verse>
<verse>"The eastern boundary runs between Damascus and Hauran, down along the Jordan between Gilead and the land of Israel to the Eastern Sea as far as Tamar. This is the eastern boundary.</verse>
<verse>"The southern boundary runs west from Tamar to the waters of Meribah-kadesh, along the Brook of Egypt, and out to the Great Mediterranean Sea. This is the southern boundary.</verse>
<verse>"The western boundary is formed by the Great Mediterranean Sea north to where the road turns east toward the entrance to Hamath. This is the western boundary.</verse>
<verse>"Divide up this land among the twelve tribes of Israel.</verse>
<verse>Divide it up as your inheritance, and include in it the resident aliens who have made themselves at home among you and now have children. Treat them as if they were born there, just like yourselves. They also get an inheritance among the tribes of Israel.</verse>
<verse>In whatever tribe the resident alien lives, there he gets his inheritance. Decree of GOD, the Master.</verse>
</chapter>