<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Proverbs" book-id="20" n="1">
<verse>The proverbs of Solomon the son of David, king of Israel:</verse>
<verse>To know wisdom and instruction, To discern the sayings of understanding,</verse>
<verse>To receive instruction in wise behavior, Righteousness, justice and equity;</verse>
<verse>To give prudence to the naive, To the youth knowledge and discretion,</verse>
<verse>A wise man will hear and increase in learning, And a man of understanding will acquire wise counsel,</verse>
<verse>To understand a proverb and a figure, The words of the wise and their riddles.</verse>
<verse>The fear of the LORD is the beginning of knowledge; Fools despise wisdom and instruction.</verse>
<verse>Hear, my son, your father's instruction And do not forsake your mother's teaching;</verse>
<verse>Indeed, they are a graceful wreath to your head And ornaments about your neck.</verse>
<verse>My son, if sinners entice you, Do not consent.</verse>
<verse>If they say, "Come with us, Let us lie in wait for blood, Let us ambush the innocent without cause;</verse>
<verse>Let us swallow them alive like Sheol, Even whole, as those who go down to the pit;</verse>
<verse>We will find all kinds of precious wealth, We will fill our houses with spoil;</verse>
<verse>Throw in your lot with us, We shall all have one purse,"</verse>
<verse>My son, do not walk in the way with them. Keep your feet from their path,</verse>
<verse>For their feet run to evil And they hasten to shed blood.</verse>
<verse>Indeed, it is useless to spread the baited net In the sight of any bird;</verse>
<verse>But they lie in wait for their own blood; They ambush their own lives.</verse>
<verse>So are the ways of everyone who gains by violence; It takes away the life of its possessors.</verse>
<verse>Wisdom shouts in the street, She lifts her voice in the square;</verse>
<verse>At the head of the noisy streets she cries out; At the entrance of the gates in the city she utters her sayings:</verse>
<verse>"How long, O naive ones, will you love being simple-minded? And scoffers delight themselves in scoffing And fools hate knowledge?</verse>
<verse>"Turn to my reproof, Behold, I will pour out my spirit on you; I will make my words known to you.</verse>
<verse>"Because I called and you refused, I stretched out my hand and no one paid attention;</verse>
<verse>And you neglected all my counsel And did not want my reproof;</verse>
<verse>I will also laugh at your calamity; I will mock when your dread comes,</verse>
<verse>When your dread comes like a storm And your calamity comes like a whirlwind, When distress and anguish come upon you.</verse>
<verse>"Then they will call on me, but I will not answer; They will seek me diligently but they will not find me,</verse>
<verse>Because they hated knowledge And did not choose the fear of the LORD.</verse>
<verse>"They would not accept my counsel, They spurned all my reproof.</verse>
<verse>"So they shall eat of the fruit of their own way And be satiated with their own devices.</verse>
<verse>"For the waywardness of the naive will kill them, And the complacency of fools will destroy them.</verse>
<verse>"But he who listens to me shall live securely And will be at ease from the dread of evil."</verse>
</chapter>