<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Proverbs" book-id="20" n="10">
<verse>The proverbs of Solomon. A wise son makes a father glad, But a foolish son is a grief to his mother.</verse>
<verse>Ill-gotten gains do not profit, But righteousness delivers from death.</verse>
<verse>The LORD will not allow the righteous to hunger, But He will reject the craving of the wicked.</verse>
<verse>Poor is he who works with a negligent hand, But the hand of the diligent makes rich.</verse>
<verse>He who gathers in summer is a son who acts wisely, But he who sleeps in harvest is a son who acts shamefully.</verse>
<verse>Blessings are on the head of the righteous, But the mouth of the wicked conceals violence.</verse>
<verse>The memory of the righteous is blessed, But the name of the wicked will rot.</verse>
<verse>The wise of heart will receive commands, But a babbling fool will be ruined.</verse>
<verse>He who walks in integrity walks securely, But he who perverts his ways will be found out.</verse>
<verse>He who winks the eye causes trouble, And a babbling fool will be ruined.</verse>
<verse>The mouth of the righteous is a fountain of life, But the mouth of the wicked conceals violence.</verse>
<verse>Hatred stirs up strife, But love covers all transgressions.</verse>
<verse>On the lips of the discerning, wisdom is found, But a rod is for the back of him who lacks understanding.</verse>
<verse>Wise men store up knowledge, But with the mouth of the foolish, ruin is at hand.</verse>
<verse>The rich man's wealth is his fortress, The ruin of the poor is their poverty.</verse>
<verse>The wages of the righteous is life, The income of the wicked, punishment.</verse>
<verse>He is on the path of life who heeds instruction, But he who ignores reproof goes astray.</verse>
<verse>He who conceals hatred has lying lips, And he who spreads slander is a fool.</verse>
<verse>When there are many words, transgression is unavoidable, But he who restrains his lips is wise.</verse>
<verse>The tongue of the righteous is as choice silver, The heart of the wicked is worth little.</verse>
<verse>The lips of the righteous feed many, But fools die for lack of understanding.</verse>
<verse>It is the blessing of the LORD that makes rich, And He adds no sorrow to it.</verse>
<verse>Doing wickedness is like sport to a fool, And so is wisdom to a man of understanding.</verse>
<verse>What the wicked fears will come upon him, But the desire of the righteous will be granted.</verse>
<verse>When the whirlwind passes, the wicked is no more, But the righteous has an everlasting foundation.</verse>
<verse>Like vinegar to the teeth and smoke to the eyes, So is the lazy one to those who send him.</verse>
<verse>The fear of the LORD prolongs life, But the years of the wicked will be shortened.</verse>
<verse>The hope of the righteous is gladness, But the expectation of the wicked perishes.</verse>
<verse>The way of the LORD is a stronghold to the upright, But ruin to the workers of iniquity.</verse>
<verse>The righteous will never be shaken, But the wicked will not dwell in the land.</verse>
<verse>The mouth of the righteous flows with wisdom, But the perverted tongue will be cut out.</verse>
<verse>The lips of the righteous bring forth what is acceptable, But the mouth of the wicked what is perverted.</verse>
</chapter>