<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Proverbs" book_id="20" n="11">
<verse>A false balance is an abomination to the LORD, But a just weight is His delight.</verse>
<verse>When pride comes, then comes dishonor, But with the humble is wisdom.</verse>
<verse>The integrity of the upright will guide them, But the crookedness of the treacherous will destroy them.</verse>
<verse>Riches do not profit in the day of wrath, But righteousness delivers from death.</verse>
<verse>The righteousness of the blameless will smooth his way, But the wicked will fall by his own wickedness.</verse>
<verse>The righteousness of the upright will deliver them, But the treacherous will be caught by their own greed.</verse>
<verse>When a wicked man dies, his expectation will perish, And the hope of strong men perishes.</verse>
<verse>The righteous is delivered from trouble, But the wicked takes his place.</verse>
<verse>With his mouth the godless man destroys his neighbor, But through knowledge the righteous will be delivered.</verse>
<verse>When it goes well with the righteous, the city rejoices, And when the wicked perish, there is joyful shouting.</verse>
<verse>By the blessing of the upright a city is exalted, But by the mouth of the wicked it is torn down.</verse>
<verse>He who despises his neighbor lacks sense, But a man of understanding keeps silent.</verse>
<verse>He who goes about as a talebearer reveals secrets, But he who is trustworthy conceals a matter.</verse>
<verse>Where there is no guidance the people fall, But in abundance of counselors there is victory.</verse>
<verse>He who is guarantor for a stranger will surely suffer for it, But he who hates being a guarantor is secure.</verse>
<verse>A gracious woman attains honor, And ruthless men attain riches.</verse>
<verse>The merciful man does himself good, But the cruel man does himself harm.</verse>
<verse>The wicked earns deceptive wages, But he who sows righteousness gets a true reward.</verse>
<verse>He who is steadfast in righteousness will attain to life, And he who pursues evil will bring about his own death.</verse>
<verse>The perverse in heart are an abomination to the LORD, But the blameless in their walk are His delight.</verse>
<verse>Assuredly, the evil man will not go unpunished, But the descendants of the righteous will be delivered.</verse>
<verse>As a ring of gold in a swine's snout So is a beautiful woman who lacks discretion.</verse>
<verse>The desire of the righteous is only good, But the expectation of the wicked is wrath.</verse>
<verse>There is one who scatters, and yet increases all the more, And there is one who withholds what is justly due, and yet it results only in want.</verse>
<verse>The generous man will be prosperous, And he who waters will himself be watered.</verse>
<verse>He who withholds grain, the people will curse him, But blessing will be on the head of him who sells it.</verse>
<verse>He who diligently seeks good seeks favor, But he who seeks evil, evil will come to him.</verse>
<verse>He who trusts in his riches will fall, But the righteous will flourish like the green leaf.</verse>
<verse>He who troubles his own house will inherit wind, And the foolish will be servant to the wisehearted.</verse>
<verse>The fruit of the righteous is a tree of life, And he who is wise wins souls.</verse>
<verse>If the righteous will be rewarded in the earth, How much more the wicked and the sinner!</verse>
</chapter>