<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Proverbs" book-id="20" n="12">
<verse>Whoever loves discipline loves knowledge, But he who hates reproof is stupid.</verse>
<verse>A good man will obtain favor from the LORD, But He will condemn a man who devises evil.</verse>
<verse>A man will not be established by wickedness, But the root of the righteous will not be moved.</verse>
<verse>An excellent wife is the crown of her husband, But she who shames him is like rottenness in his bones.</verse>
<verse>The thoughts of the righteous are just, But the counsels of the wicked are deceitful.</verse>
<verse>The words of the wicked lie in wait for blood, But the mouth of the upright will deliver them.</verse>
<verse>The wicked are overthrown and are no more, But the house of the righteous will stand.</verse>
<verse>A man will be praised according to his insight, But one of perverse mind will be despised.</verse>
<verse>Better is he who is lightly esteemed and has a servant Than he who honors himself and lacks bread.</verse>
<verse>A righteous man has regard for the life of his animal, But even the compassion of the wicked is cruel.</verse>
<verse>He who tills his land will have plenty of bread, But he who pursues worthless things lacks sense.</verse>
<verse>The wicked man desires the booty of evil men, But the root of the righteous yields fruit.</verse>
<verse>An evil man is ensnared by the transgression of his lips, But the righteous will escape from trouble.</verse>
<verse>A man will be satisfied with good by the fruit of his words, And the deeds of a man's hands will return to him.</verse>
<verse>The way of a fool is right in his own eyes, But a wise man is he who listens to counsel.</verse>
<verse>A fool's anger is known at once, But a prudent man conceals dishonor.</verse>
<verse>He who speaks truth tells what is right, But a false witness, deceit.</verse>
<verse>There is one who speaks rashly like the thrusts of a sword, But the tongue of the wise brings healing.</verse>
<verse>Truthful lips will be established forever, But a lying tongue is only for a moment.</verse>
<verse>Deceit is in the heart of those who devise evil, But counselors of peace have joy.</verse>
<verse>No harm befalls the righteous, But the wicked are filled with trouble.</verse>
<verse>Lying lips are an abomination to the LORD, But those who deal faithfully are His delight.</verse>
<verse>A prudent man conceals knowledge, But the heart of fools proclaims folly.</verse>
<verse>The hand of the diligent will rule, But the slack hand will be put to forced labor.</verse>
<verse>Anxiety in a man's heart weighs it down, But a good word makes it glad.</verse>
<verse>The righteous is a guide to his neighbor, But the way of the wicked leads them astray.</verse>
<verse>A lazy man does not roast his prey, But the precious possession of a man is diligence.</verse>
<verse>In the way of righteousness is life, And in its pathway there is no death.</verse>
</chapter>