<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Proverbs" book-id="20" n="13">
<verse>A wise son accepts his father's discipline, But a scoffer does not listen to rebuke.</verse>
<verse>From the fruit of a man's mouth he enjoys good, But the desire of the treacherous is violence.</verse>
<verse>The one who guards his mouth preserves his life; The one who opens wide his lips comes to ruin.</verse>
<verse>The soul of the sluggard craves and gets nothing, But the soul of the diligent is made fat.</verse>
<verse>A righteous man hates falsehood, But a wicked man acts disgustingly and shamefully.</verse>
<verse>Righteousness guards the one whose way is blameless, But wickedness subverts the sinner.</verse>
<verse>There is one who pretends to be rich, but has nothing; Another pretends to be poor, but has great wealth.</verse>
<verse>The ransom of a man's life is his wealth, But the poor hears no rebuke.</verse>
<verse>The light of the righteous rejoices, But the lamp of the wicked goes out.</verse>
<verse>Through insolence comes nothing but strife, But wisdom is with those who receive counsel.</verse>
<verse>Wealth obtained by fraud dwindles, But the one who gathers by labor increases it.</verse>
<verse>Hope deferred makes the heart sick, But desire fulfilled is a tree of life.</verse>
<verse>The one who despises the word will be in debt to it, But the one who fears the commandment will be rewarded.</verse>
<verse>The teaching of the wise is a fountain of life, To turn aside from the snares of death.</verse>
<verse>Good understanding produces favor, But the way of the treacherous is hard.</verse>
<verse>Every prudent man acts with knowledge, But a fool displays folly.</verse>
<verse>A wicked messenger falls into adversity, But a faithful envoy brings healing.</verse>
<verse>Poverty and shame will come to him who neglects discipline, But he who regards reproof will be honored.</verse>
<verse>Desire realized is sweet to the soul, But it is an abomination to fools to turn away from evil.</verse>
<verse>He who walks with wise men will be wise, But the companion of fools will suffer harm.</verse>
<verse>Adversity pursues sinners, But the righteous will be rewarded with prosperity.</verse>
<verse>A good man leaves an inheritance to his children's children, And the wealth of the sinner is stored up for the righteous.</verse>
<verse>Abundant food is in the fallow ground of the poor, But it is swept away by injustice.</verse>
<verse>He who withholds his rod hates his son, But he who loves him disciplines him diligently.</verse>
<verse>The righteous has enough to satisfy his appetite, But the stomach of the wicked is in need.</verse>
</chapter>