<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Proverbs" book-id="20" n="14">
<verse>The wise woman builds her house, But the foolish tears it down with her own hands.</verse>
<verse>He who walks in his uprightness fears the LORD, But he who is devious in his ways despises Him.</verse>
<verse>In the mouth of the foolish is a rod for his back, But the lips of the wise will protect them.</verse>
<verse>Where no oxen are, the manger is clean, But much revenue comes by the strength of the ox.</verse>
<verse>A trustworthy witness will not lie, But a false witness utters lies.</verse>
<verse>A scoffer seeks wisdom and finds none, But knowledge is easy to one who has understanding.</verse>
<verse>Leave the presence of a fool, Or you will not discern words of knowledge.</verse>
<verse>The wisdom of the sensible is to understand his way, But the foolishness of fools is deceit.</verse>
<verse>Fools mock at sin, But among the upright there is good will.</verse>
<verse>The heart knows its own bitterness, And a stranger does not share its joy.</verse>
<verse>The house of the wicked will be destroyed, But the tent of the upright will flourish.</verse>
<verse>There is a way which seems right to a man, But its end is the way of death.</verse>
<verse>Even in laughter the heart may be in pain, And the end of joy may be grief.</verse>
<verse>The backslider in heart will have his fill of his own ways, But a good man will be satisfied with his.</verse>
<verse>The naive believes everything, But the sensible man considers his steps.</verse>
<verse>A wise man is cautious and turns away from evil, But a fool is arrogant and careless.</verse>
<verse>A quick-tempered man acts foolishly, And a man of evil devices is hated.</verse>
<verse>The naive inherit foolishness, But the sensible are crowned with knowledge.</verse>
<verse>The evil will bow down before the good, And the wicked at the gates of the righteous.</verse>
<verse>The poor is hated even by his neighbor, But those who love the rich are many.</verse>
<verse>He who despises his neighbor sins, But happy is he who is gracious to the poor.</verse>
<verse>Will they not go astray who devise evil? But kindness and truth will be to those who devise good.</verse>
<verse>In all labor there is profit, But mere talk leads only to poverty.</verse>
<verse>The crown of the wise is their riches, But the folly of fools is foolishness.</verse>
<verse>A truthful witness saves lives, But he who utters lies is treacherous.</verse>
<verse>In the fear of the LORD there is strong confidence, And his children will have refuge.</verse>
<verse>The fear of the LORD is a fountain of life, That one may avoid the snares of death.</verse>
<verse>In a multitude of people is a king's glory, But in the dearth of people is a prince's ruin.</verse>
<verse>He who is slow to anger has great understanding, But he who is quick-tempered exalts folly.</verse>
<verse>A tranquil heart is life to the body, But passion is rottenness to the bones.</verse>
<verse>He who oppresses the poor taunts his Maker, But he who is gracious to the needy honors Him.</verse>
<verse>The wicked is thrust down by his wrongdoing, But the righteous has a refuge when he dies.</verse>
<verse>Wisdom rests in the heart of one who has understanding, But in the hearts of fools it is made known.</verse>
<verse>Righteousness exalts a nation, But sin is a disgrace to any people.</verse>
<verse>The king's favor is toward a servant who acts wisely, But his anger is toward him who acts shamefully.</verse>
</chapter>