<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Proverbs" book_id="20" n="15">
<verse>A gentle answer turns away wrath, But a harsh word stirs up anger.</verse>
<verse>The tongue of the wise makes knowledge acceptable, But the mouth of fools spouts folly.</verse>
<verse>The eyes of the LORD are in every place, Watching the evil and the good.</verse>
<verse>A soothing tongue is a tree of life, But perversion in it crushes the spirit.</verse>
<verse>A fool rejects his father's discipline, But he who regards reproof is sensible.</verse>
<verse>Great wealth is in the house of the righteous, But trouble is in the income of the wicked.</verse>
<verse>The lips of the wise spread knowledge, But the hearts of fools are not so.</verse>
<verse>The sacrifice of the wicked is an abomination to the LORD, But the prayer of the upright is His delight.</verse>
<verse>The way of the wicked is an abomination to the LORD, But He loves one who pursues righteousness.</verse>
<verse>Grievous punishment is for him who forsakes the way; He who hates reproof will die.</verse>
<verse>Sheol and Abaddon lie open before the LORD, How much more the hearts of men!</verse>
<verse>A scoffer does not love one who reproves him, He will not go to the wise.</verse>
<verse>A joyful heart makes a cheerful face, But when the heart is sad, the spirit is broken.</verse>
<verse>The mind of the intelligent seeks knowledge, But the mouth of fools feeds on folly.</verse>
<verse>All the days of the afflicted are bad, But a cheerful heart has a continual feast.</verse>
<verse>Better is a little with the fear of the LORD Than great treasure and turmoil with it.</verse>
<verse>Better is a dish of vegetables where love is Than a fattened ox served with hatred.</verse>
<verse>A hot-tempered man stirs up strife, But the slow to anger calms a dispute.</verse>
<verse>The way of the lazy is as a hedge of thorns, But the path of the upright is a highway.</verse>
<verse>A wise son makes a father glad, But a foolish man despises his mother.</verse>
<verse>Folly is joy to him who lacks sense, But a man of understanding walks straight.</verse>
<verse>Without consultation, plans are frustrated, But with many counselors they succeed.</verse>
<verse>A man has joy in an apt answer, And how delightful is a timely word!</verse>
<verse>The path of life leads upward for the wise That he may keep away from Sheol below.</verse>
<verse>The LORD will tear down the house of the proud, But He will establish the boundary of the widow.</verse>
<verse>Evil plans are an abomination to the LORD, But pleasant words are pure.</verse>
<verse>He who profits illicitly troubles his own house, But he who hates bribes will live.</verse>
<verse>The heart of the righteous ponders how to answer, But the mouth of the wicked pours out evil things.</verse>
<verse>The LORD is far from the wicked, But He hears the prayer of the righteous.</verse>
<verse>Bright eyes gladden the heart; Good news puts fat on the bones.</verse>
<verse>He whose ear listens to the life-giving reproof Will dwell among the wise.</verse>
<verse>He who neglects discipline despises himself, But he who listens to reproof acquires understanding.</verse>
<verse>The fear of the LORD is the instruction for wisdom, And before honor comes humility.</verse>
</chapter>