<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Proverbs" book_id="20" n="16">
<verse>The plans of the heart belong to man, But the answer of the tongue is from the LORD.</verse>
<verse>All the ways of a man are clean in his own sight, But the LORD weighs the motives.</verse>
<verse>Commit your works to the LORD And your plans will be established.</verse>
<verse>The LORD has made everything for its own purpose, Even the wicked for the day of evil.</verse>
<verse>Everyone who is proud in heart is an abomination to the LORD; Assuredly, he will not be unpunished.</verse>
<verse>By lovingkindness and truth iniquity is atoned for, And by the fear of the LORD one keeps away from evil.</verse>
<verse>When a man's ways are pleasing to the LORD, He makes even his enemies to be at peace with him.</verse>
<verse>Better is a little with righteousness Than great income with injustice.</verse>
<verse>The mind of man plans his way, But the LORD directs his steps.</verse>
<verse>A divine decision is in the lips of the king; His mouth should not err in judgment.</verse>
<verse>A just balance and scales belong to the LORD; All the weights of the bag are His concern.</verse>
<verse>It is an abomination for kings to commit wicked acts, For a throne is established on righteousness.</verse>
<verse>Righteous lips are the delight of kings, And he who speaks right is loved.</verse>
<verse>The fury of a king is like messengers of death, But a wise man will appease it.</verse>
<verse>In the light of a king's face is life, And his favor is like a cloud with the spring rain.</verse>
<verse>How much better it is to get wisdom than gold! And to get understanding is to be chosen above silver.</verse>
<verse>The highway of the upright is to depart from evil; He who watches his way preserves his life.</verse>
<verse>Pride goes before destruction, And a haughty spirit before stumbling.</verse>
<verse>It is better to be humble in spirit with the lowly Than to divide the spoil with the proud.</verse>
<verse>He who gives attention to the word will find good, And blessed is he who trusts in the LORD.</verse>
<verse>The wise in heart will be called understanding, And sweetness of speech increases persuasiveness.</verse>
<verse>Understanding is a fountain of life to one who has it, But the discipline of fools is folly.</verse>
<verse>The heart of the wise instructs his mouth And adds persuasiveness to his lips.</verse>
<verse>Pleasant words are a honeycomb, Sweet to the soul and healing to the bones.</verse>
<verse>There is a way which seems right to a man, But its end is the way of death.</verse>
<verse>A worker's appetite works for him, For his hunger urges him on.</verse>
<verse>A worthless man digs up evil, While his words are like scorching fire.</verse>
<verse>A perverse man spreads strife, And a slanderer separates intimate friends.</verse>
<verse>A man of violence entices his neighbor And leads him in a way that is not good.</verse>
<verse>He who winks his eyes does so to devise perverse things; He who compresses his lips brings evil to pass.</verse>
<verse>A gray head is a crown of glory; It is found in the way of righteousness.</verse>
<verse>He who is slow to anger is better than the mighty, And he who rules his spirit, than he who captures a city.</verse>
<verse>The lot is cast into the lap, But its every decision is from the LORD.</verse>
</chapter>