<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Proverbs" book-id="20" n="17">
<verse>Better is a dry morsel and quietness with it Than a house full of feasting with strife.</verse>
<verse>A servant who acts wisely will rule over a son who acts shamefully, And will share in the inheritance among brothers.</verse>
<verse>The refining pot is for silver and the furnace for gold, But the LORD tests hearts.</verse>
<verse>An evildoer listens to wicked lips; A liar pays attention to a destructive tongue.</verse>
<verse>He who mocks the poor taunts his Maker; He who rejoices at calamity will not go unpunished.</verse>
<verse>Grandchildren are the crown of old men, And the glory of sons is their fathers.</verse>
<verse>Excellent speech is not fitting for a fool, Much less are lying lips to a prince.</verse>
<verse>A bribe is a charm in the sight of its owner; Wherever he turns, he prospers.</verse>
<verse>He who conceals a transgression seeks love, But he who repeats a matter separates intimate friends.</verse>
<verse>A rebuke goes deeper into one who has understanding Than a hundred blows into a fool.</verse>
<verse>A rebellious man seeks only evil, So a cruel messenger will be sent against him.</verse>
<verse>Let a man meet a bear robbed of her cubs, Rather than a fool in his folly.</verse>
<verse>He who returns evil for good, Evil will not depart from his house.</verse>
<verse>The beginning of strife is like letting out water, So abandon the quarrel before it breaks out.</verse>
<verse>He who justifies the wicked and he who condemns the righteous, Both of them alike are an abomination to the LORD.</verse>
<verse>Why is there a price in the hand of a fool to buy wisdom, When he has no sense?</verse>
<verse>A friend loves at all times, And a brother is born for adversity.</verse>
<verse>A man lacking in sense pledges And becomes guarantor in the presence of his neighbor.</verse>
<verse>He who loves transgression loves strife; He who raises his door seeks destruction.</verse>
<verse>He who has a crooked mind finds no good, And he who is perverted in his language falls into evil.</verse>
<verse>He who sires a fool does so to his sorrow, And the father of a fool has no joy.</verse>
<verse>A joyful heart is good medicine, But a broken spirit dries up the bones.</verse>
<verse>A wicked man receives a bribe from the bosom To pervert the ways of justice.</verse>
<verse>Wisdom is in the presence of the one who has understanding, But the eyes of a fool are on the ends of the earth.</verse>
<verse>A foolish son is a grief to his father And bitterness to her who bore him.</verse>
<verse>It is also not good to fine the righteous, Nor to strike the noble for their uprightness.</verse>
<verse>He who restrains his words has knowledge, And he who has a cool spirit is a man of understanding.</verse>
<verse>Even a fool, when he keeps silent, is considered wise; When he closes his lips, he is considered prudent.</verse>
</chapter>