<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Proverbs" book_id="20" n="18">
<verse>He who separates himself seeks his own desire, He quarrels against all sound wisdom.</verse>
<verse>A fool does not delight in understanding, But only in revealing his own mind.</verse>
<verse>When a wicked man comes, contempt also comes, And with dishonor comes scorn.</verse>
<verse>The words of a man's mouth are deep waters; The fountain of wisdom is a bubbling brook.</verse>
<verse>To show partiality to the wicked is not good, Nor to thrust aside the righteous in judgment.</verse>
<verse>A fool's lips bring strife, And his mouth calls for blows.</verse>
<verse>A fool's mouth is his ruin, And his lips are the snare of his soul.</verse>
<verse>The words of a whisperer are like dainty morsels, And they go down into the innermost parts of the body.</verse>
<verse>He also who is slack in his work Is brother to him who destroys.</verse>
<verse>The name of the LORD is a strong tower; The righteous runs into it and is safe.</verse>
<verse>A rich man's wealth is his strong city, And like a high wall in his own imagination.</verse>
<verse>Before destruction the heart of man is haughty, But humility goes before honor.</verse>
<verse>He who gives an answer before he hears, It is folly and shame to him.</verse>
<verse>The spirit of a man can endure his sickness, But as for a broken spirit who can bear it?</verse>
<verse>The mind of the prudent acquires knowledge, And the ear of the wise seeks knowledge.</verse>
<verse>A man's gift makes room for him And brings him before great men.</verse>
<verse>The first to plead his case seems right, Until another comes and examines him.</verse>
<verse>The cast lot puts an end to strife And decides between the mighty ones.</verse>
<verse>A brother offended is harder to be won than a strong city, And contentions are like the bars of a citadel.</verse>
<verse>With the fruit of a man's mouth his stomach will be satisfied; He will be satisfied with the product of his lips.</verse>
<verse>Death and life are in the power of the tongue, And those who love it will eat its fruit.</verse>
<verse>He who finds a wife finds a good thing And obtains favor from the LORD.</verse>
<verse>The poor man utters supplications, But the rich man answers roughly.</verse>
<verse>A man of too many friends comes to ruin, But there is a friend who sticks closer than a brother.</verse>
</chapter>