<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Proverbs" book-id="20" n="19">
<verse>Better is a poor man who walks in his integrity Than he who is perverse in speech and is a fool.</verse>
<verse>Also it is not good for a person to be without knowledge, And he who hurries his footsteps errs.</verse>
<verse>The foolishness of man ruins his way, And his heart rages against the LORD.</verse>
<verse>Wealth adds many friends, But a poor man is separated from his friend.</verse>
<verse>A false witness will not go unpunished, And he who tells lies will not escape.</verse>
<verse>Many will seek the favor of a generous man, And every man is a friend to him who gives gifts.</verse>
<verse>All the brothers of a poor man hate him; How much more do his friends abandon him! He pursues them with words, but they are gone.</verse>
<verse>He who gets wisdom loves his own soul; He who keeps understanding will find good.</verse>
<verse>A false witness will not go unpunished, And he who tells lies will perish.</verse>
<verse>Luxury is not fitting for a fool; Much less for a slave to rule over princes.</verse>
<verse>A man's discretion makes him slow to anger, And it is his glory to overlook a transgression.</verse>
<verse>The king's wrath is like the roaring of a lion, But his favor is like dew on the grass.</verse>
<verse>A foolish son is destruction to his father, And the contentions of a wife are a constant dripping.</verse>
<verse>House and wealth are an inheritance from fathers, But a prudent wife is from the LORD.</verse>
<verse>Laziness casts into a deep sleep, And an idle man will suffer hunger.</verse>
<verse>He who keeps the commandment keeps his soul, But he who is careless of conduct will die.</verse>
<verse>One who is gracious to a poor man lends to the LORD, And He will repay him for his good deed.</verse>
<verse>Discipline your son while there is hope, And do not desire his death.</verse>
<verse>A man of great anger will bear the penalty, For if you rescue him, you will only have to do it again.</verse>
<verse>Listen to counsel and accept discipline, That you may be wise the rest of your days.</verse>
<verse>Many plans are in a man's heart, But the counsel of the LORD will stand.</verse>
<verse>What is desirable in a man is his kindness, And it is better to be a poor man than a liar.</verse>
<verse>The fear of the LORD leads to life, So that one may sleep satisfied, untouched by evil.</verse>
<verse>The sluggard buries his hand in the dish, But will not even bring it back to his mouth.</verse>
<verse>Strike a scoffer and the naive may become shrewd, But reprove one who has understanding and he will gain knowledge.</verse>
<verse>He who assaults his father and drives his mother away Is a shameful and disgraceful son.</verse>
<verse>Cease listening, my son, to discipline, And you will stray from the words of knowledge.</verse>
<verse>A rascally witness makes a mockery of justice, And the mouth of the wicked spreads iniquity.</verse>
<verse>Judgments are prepared for scoffers, And blows for the back of fools.</verse>
</chapter>