<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Proverbs" book_id="20" n="2">
<verse>My son, if you will receive my words And treasure my commandments within you,</verse>
<verse>Make your ear attentive to wisdom, Incline your heart to understanding;</verse>
<verse>For if you cry for discernment, Lift your voice for understanding;</verse>
<verse>If you seek her as silver And search for her as for hidden treasures;</verse>
<verse>Then you will discern the fear of the LORD And discover the knowledge of God.</verse>
<verse>For the LORD gives wisdom; From His mouth come knowledge and understanding.</verse>
<verse>He stores up sound wisdom for the upright; He is a shield to those who walk in integrity,</verse>
<verse>Guarding the paths of justice, And He preserves the way of His godly ones.</verse>
<verse>Then you will discern righteousness and justice And equity and every good course.</verse>
<verse>For wisdom will enter your heart And knowledge will be pleasant to your soul;</verse>
<verse>Discretion will guard you, Understanding will watch over you,</verse>
<verse>To deliver you from the way of evil, From the man who speaks perverse things;</verse>
<verse>From those who leave the paths of uprightness To walk in the ways of darkness;</verse>
<verse>Who delight in doing evil And rejoice in the perversity of evil;</verse>
<verse>Whose paths are crooked, And who are devious in their ways;</verse>
<verse>To deliver you from the strange woman, From the adulteress who flatters with her words;</verse>
<verse>That leaves the companion of her youth And forgets the covenant of her God;</verse>
<verse>For her house sinks down to death And her tracks lead to the dead;</verse>
<verse>None who go to her return again, Nor do they reach the paths of life.</verse>
<verse>So you will walk in the way of good men And keep to the paths of the righteous.</verse>
<verse>For the upright will live in the land And the blameless will remain in it;</verse>
<verse>But the wicked will be cut off from the land And the treacherous will be uprooted from it.</verse>
</chapter>