<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Proverbs" book-id="20" n="20">
<verse>Wine is a mocker, strong drink a brawler, And whoever is intoxicated by it is not wise.</verse>
<verse>The terror of a king is like the growling of a lion; He who provokes him to anger forfeits his own life.</verse>
<verse>Keeping away from strife is an honor for a man, But any fool will quarrel.</verse>
<verse>The sluggard does not plow after the autumn, So he begs during the harvest and has nothing.</verse>
<verse>A plan in the heart of a man is like deep water, But a man of understanding draws it out.</verse>
<verse>Many a man proclaims his own loyalty, But who can find a trustworthy man?</verse>
<verse>A righteous man who walks in his integrity--How blessed are his sons after him.</verse>
<verse>A king who sits on the throne of justice Disperses all evil with his eyes.</verse>
<verse>Who can say, "I have cleansed my heart, I am pure from my sin"?</verse>
<verse>Differing weights and differing measures, Both of them are abominable to the LORD.</verse>
<verse>It is by his deeds that a lad distinguishes himself If his conduct is pure and right.</verse>
<verse>The hearing ear and the seeing eye, The LORD has made both of them.</verse>
<verse>Do not love sleep, or you will become poor; Open your eyes, and you will be satisfied with food.</verse>
<verse>"Bad, bad," says the buyer, But when he goes his way, then he boasts.</verse>
<verse>There is gold, and an abundance of jewels; But the lips of knowledge are a more precious thing.</verse>
<verse>Take his garment when he becomes surety for a stranger; And for foreigners, hold him in pledge.</verse>
<verse>Bread obtained by falsehood is sweet to a man, But afterward his mouth will be filled with gravel.</verse>
<verse>Prepare plans by consultation, And make war by wise guidance.</verse>
<verse>He who goes about as a slanderer reveals secrets, Therefore do not associate with a gossip.</verse>
<verse>He who curses his father or his mother, His lamp will go out in time of darkness.</verse>
<verse>An inheritance gained hurriedly at the beginning Will not be blessed in the end.</verse>
<verse>Do not say, "I will repay evil"; Wait for the LORD, and He will save you.</verse>
<verse>Differing weights are an abomination to the LORD, And a false scale is not good.</verse>
<verse>Man's steps are ordained by the LORD, How then can man understand his way?</verse>
<verse>It is a trap for a man to say rashly, "It is holy!" And after the vows to make inquiry.</verse>
<verse>A wise king winnows the wicked, And drives the threshing wheel over them.</verse>
<verse>The spirit of man is the lamp of the LORD, Searching all the innermost parts of his being.</verse>
<verse>Loyalty and truth preserve the king, And he upholds his throne by righteousness.</verse>
<verse>The glory of young men is their strength, And the honor of old men is their gray hair.</verse>
<verse>Stripes that wound scour away evil, And strokes reach the innermost parts.</verse>
</chapter>