<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Proverbs" book_id="20" n="21">
<verse>The king's heart is like channels of water in the hand of the LORD; He turns it wherever He wishes.</verse>
<verse>Every man's way is right in his own eyes, But the LORD weighs the hearts.</verse>
<verse>To do righteousness and justice Is desired by the LORD more than sacrifice.</verse>
<verse>Haughty eyes and a proud heart, The lamp of the wicked, is sin.</verse>
<verse>The plans of the diligent lead surely to advantage, But everyone who is hasty comes surely to poverty.</verse>
<verse>The acquisition of treasures by a lying tongue Is a fleeting vapor, the pursuit of death.</verse>
<verse>The violence of the wicked will drag them away, Because they refuse to act with justice.</verse>
<verse>The way of a guilty man is crooked, But as for the pure, his conduct is upright.</verse>
<verse>It is better to live in a corner of a roof Than in a house shared with a contentious woman.</verse>
<verse>The soul of the wicked desires evil; His neighbor finds no favor in his eyes.</verse>
<verse>When the scoffer is punished, the naive becomes wise; But when the wise is instructed, he receives knowledge.</verse>
<verse>The righteous one considers the house of the wicked, Turning the wicked to ruin.</verse>
<verse>He who shuts his ear to the cry of the poor Will also cry himself and not be answered.</verse>
<verse>A gift in secret subdues anger, And a bribe in the bosom, strong wrath.</verse>
<verse>The exercise of justice is joy for the righteous, But is terror to the workers of iniquity.</verse>
<verse>A man who wanders from the way of understanding Will rest in the assembly of the dead.</verse>
<verse>He who loves pleasure will become a poor man; He who loves wine and oil will not become rich.</verse>
<verse>The wicked is a ransom for the righteous, And the treacherous is in the place of the upright.</verse>
<verse>It is better to live in a desert land Than with a contentious and vexing woman.</verse>
<verse>There is precious treasure and oil in the dwelling of the wise, But a foolish man swallows it up.</verse>
<verse>He who pursues righteousness and loyalty Finds life, righteousness and honor.</verse>
<verse>A wise man scales the city of the mighty And brings down the stronghold in which they trust.</verse>
<verse>He who guards his mouth and his tongue, Guards his soul from troubles.</verse>
<verse>"Proud,Haughty, Scoffer," are his names, Who acts with insolent pride.</verse>
<verse>The desire of the sluggard puts him to death, For his hands refuse to work;</verse>
<verse>All day long he is craving, While the righteous gives and does not hold back.</verse>
<verse>The sacrifice of the wicked is an abomination, How much more when he brings it with evil intent!</verse>
<verse>A false witness will perish, But the man who listens to the truth will speak forever.</verse>
<verse>A wicked man displays a bold face, But as for the upright, he makes his way sure.</verse>
<verse>There is no wisdom and no understanding And no counsel against the LORD.</verse>
<verse>The horse is prepared for the day of battle, But victory belongs to the LORD.</verse>
</chapter>