<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Proverbs" book_id="20" n="22">
<verse>A good name is to be more desired than great wealth, Favor is better than silver and gold.</verse>
<verse>The rich and the poor have a common bond, The LORD is the maker of them all.</verse>
<verse>The prudent sees the evil and hides himself, But the naive go on, and are punished for it.</verse>
<verse>The reward of humility and the fear of the LORD Are riches, honor and life.</verse>
<verse>Thorns and snares are in the way of the perverse; He who guards himself will be far from them.</verse>
<verse>Train up a child in the way he should go, Even when he is old he will not depart from it.</verse>
<verse>The rich rules over the poor, And the borrower becomes the lender's slave.</verse>
<verse>He who sows iniquity will reap vanity, And the rod of his fury will perish.</verse>
<verse>He who is generous will be blessed, For he gives some of his food to the poor.</verse>
<verse>Drive out the scoffer, and contention will go out, Even strife and dishonor will cease.</verse>
<verse>He who loves purity of heart And whose speech is gracious, the king is his friend.</verse>
<verse>The eyes of the LORD preserve knowledge, But He overthrows the words of the treacherous man.</verse>
<verse>The sluggard says, "There is a lion outside; I will be killed in the streets!"</verse>
<verse>The mouth of an adulteress is a deep pit; He who is cursed of the LORD will fall into it.</verse>
<verse>Foolishness is bound up in the heart of a child; The rod of discipline will remove it far from him.</verse>
<verse>He who oppresses the poor to make more for himself Or who gives to the rich, will only come to poverty.</verse>
<verse>Incline your ear and hear the words of the wise, And apply your mind to my knowledge;</verse>
<verse>For it will be pleasant if you keep them within you, That they may be ready on your lips.</verse>
<verse>So that your trust may be in the LORD, I have taught you today, even you.</verse>
<verse>Have I not written to you excellent things Of counsels and knowledge,</verse>
<verse>To make you know the certainty of the words of truth That you may correctly answer him who sent you?</verse>
<verse>Do not rob the poor because he is poor, Or crush the afflicted at the gate;</verse>
<verse>For the LORD will plead their case And take the life of those who rob them.</verse>
<verse>Do not associate with a man given to anger; Or go with a hot-tempered man,</verse>
<verse>Or you will learn his ways And find a snare for yourself.</verse>
<verse>Do not be among those who give pledges, Among those who become guarantors for debts.</verse>
<verse>If you have nothing with which to pay, Why should he take your bed from under you?</verse>
<verse>Do not move the ancient boundary Which your fathers have set.</verse>
<verse>Do you see a man skilled in his work? He will stand before kings; He will not stand before obscure men.</verse>
</chapter>