<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Proverbs" book_id="20" n="23">
<verse>When you sit down to dine with a ruler, Consider carefully what is before you,</verse>
<verse>And put a knife to your throat If you are a man of great appetite.</verse>
<verse>Do not desire his delicacies, For it is deceptive food.</verse>
<verse>Do not weary yourself to gain wealth, Cease from your consideration of it.</verse>
<verse>When you set your eyes on it, it is gone. For wealth certainly makes itself wings Like an eagle that flies toward the heavens.</verse>
<verse>Do not eat the bread of a selfish man, Or desire his delicacies;</verse>
<verse>For as he thinks within himself, so he is. He says to you, "Eat and drink!" But his heart is not with you.</verse>
<verse>You will vomit up the morsel you have eaten, And waste your compliments.</verse>
<verse>Do not speak in the hearing of a fool, For he will despise the wisdom of your words.</verse>
<verse>Do not move the ancient boundary Or go into the fields of the fatherless,</verse>
<verse>For their Redeemer is strong; He will plead their case against you.</verse>
<verse>Apply your heart to discipline And your ears to words of knowledge.</verse>
<verse>Do not hold back discipline from the child, Although you strike him with the rod, he will not die.</verse>
<verse>You shall strike him with the rod And rescue his soul from Sheol.</verse>
<verse>My son, if your heart is wise, My own heart also will be glad;</verse>
<verse>And my inmost being will rejoice When your lips speak what is right.</verse>
<verse>Do not let your heart envy sinners, But live in the fear of the LORD always.</verse>
<verse>Surely there is a future, And your hope will not be cut off.</verse>
<verse>Listen, my son, and be wise, And direct your heart in the way.</verse>
<verse>Do not be with heavy drinkers of wine, Or with gluttonous eaters of meat;</verse>
<verse>For the heavy drinker and the glutton will come to poverty, And drowsiness will clothe one with rags.</verse>
<verse>Listen to your father who begot you, And do not despise your mother when she is old.</verse>
<verse>Buy truth, and do not sell it, Get wisdom and instruction and understanding.</verse>
<verse>The father of the righteous will greatly rejoice, And he who sires a wise son will be glad in him.</verse>
<verse>Let your father and your mother be glad, And let her rejoice who gave birth to you.</verse>
<verse>Give me your heart, my son, And let your eyes delight in my ways.</verse>
<verse>For a harlot is a deep pit And an adulterous woman is a narrow well.</verse>
<verse>Surely she lurks as a robber, And increases the faithless among men.</verse>
<verse>Who has woe? Who has sorrow? Who has contentions? Who has complaining? Who has wounds without cause? Who has redness of eyes?</verse>
<verse>Those who linger long over wine, Those who go to taste mixed wine.</verse>
<verse>Do not look on the wine when it is red, When it sparkles in the cup, When it goes down smoothly;</verse>
<verse>At the last it bites like a serpent And stings like a viper.</verse>
<verse>Your eyes will see strange things And your mind will utter perverse things.</verse>
<verse>And you will be like one who lies down in the middle of the sea, Or like one who lies down on the top of a mast.</verse>
<verse>"They struck me, but I did not become ill; They beat me, but I did not know it. When shall I awake? I will seek another drink."</verse>
</chapter>