<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Proverbs" book-id="20" n="26">
<verse>Like snow in summer and like rain in harvest, So honor is not fitting for a fool.</verse>
<verse>Like a sparrow in its flitting, like a swallow in its flying, So a curse without cause does not alight.</verse>
<verse>A whip is for the horse, a bridle for the donkey, And a rod for the back of fools.</verse>
<verse>Do not answer a fool according to his folly, Or you will also be like him.</verse>
<verse>Answer a fool as his folly deserves, That he not be wise in his own eyes.</verse>
<verse>He cuts off his own feet and drinks violence Who sends a message by the hand of a fool.</verse>
<verse>Like the legs which are useless to the lame, So is a proverb in the mouth of fools.</verse>
<verse>Like one who binds a stone in a sling, So is he who gives honor to a fool.</verse>
<verse>Like a thorn which falls into the hand of a drunkard, So is a proverb in the mouth of fools.</verse>
<verse>Like an archer who wounds everyone, So is he who hires a fool or who hires those who pass by.</verse>
<verse>Like a dog that returns to its vomit Is a fool who repeats his folly.</verse>
<verse>Do you see a man wise in his own eyes? There is more hope for a fool than for him.</verse>
<verse>The sluggard says, "There is a lion in the road! A lion is in the open square!"</verse>
<verse>As the door turns on its hinges, So does the sluggard on his bed.</verse>
<verse>The sluggard buries his hand in the dish; He is weary of bringing it to his mouth again.</verse>
<verse>The sluggard is wiser in his own eyes Than seven men who can give a discreet answer.</verse>
<verse>Like one who takes a dog by the ears Is he who passes by and meddles with strife not belonging to him.</verse>
<verse>Like a madman who throws Firebrands, arrows and death,</verse>
<verse>So is the man who deceives his neighbor, And says, "Was I not joking?"</verse>
<verse>For lack of wood the fire goes out, And where there is no whisperer, contention quiets down.</verse>
<verse>Like charcoal to hot embers and wood to fire, So is a contentious man to kindle strife.</verse>
<verse>The words of a whisperer are like dainty morsels, And they go down into the innermost parts of the body.</verse>
<verse>Like an earthen vessel overlaid with silver dross Are burning lips and a wicked heart.</verse>
<verse>He who hates disguises it with his lips, But he lays up deceit in his heart.</verse>
<verse>When he speaks graciously, do not believe him, For there are seven abominations in his heart.</verse>
<verse>Though his hatred covers itself with guile, His wickedness will be revealed before the assembly.</verse>
<verse>He who digs a pit will fall into it, And he who rolls a stone, it will come back on him.</verse>
<verse>A lying tongue hates those it crushes, And a flattering mouth works ruin.</verse>
</chapter>