<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Proverbs" book-id="20" n="27">
<verse>Do not boast about tomorrow, For you do not know what a day may bring forth.</verse>
<verse>Let another praise you, and not your own mouth; A stranger, and not your own lips.</verse>
<verse>A stone is heavy and the sand weighty, But the provocation of a fool is heavier than both of them.</verse>
<verse>Wrath is fierce and anger is a flood, But who can stand before jealousy?</verse>
<verse>Better is open rebuke Than love that is concealed.</verse>
<verse>Faithful are the wounds of a friend, But deceitful are the kisses of an enemy.</verse>
<verse>A sated man loathes honey, But to a famished man any bitter thing is sweet.</verse>
<verse>Like a bird that wanders from her nest, So is a man who wanders from his home.</verse>
<verse>Oil and perfume make the heart glad, So a man's counsel is sweet to his friend.</verse>
<verse>Do not forsake your own friend or your father's friend, And do not go to your brother's house in the day of your calamity; Better is a neighbor who is near than a brother far away.</verse>
<verse>Be wise, my son, and make my heart glad, That I may reply to him who reproaches me.</verse>
<verse>A prudent man sees evil and hides himself, The naive proceed and pay the penalty.</verse>
<verse>Take his garment when he becomes surety for a stranger; And for an adulterous woman hold him in pledge.</verse>
<verse>He who blesses his friend with a loud voice early in the morning, It will be reckoned a curse to him.</verse>
<verse>A constant dripping on a day of steady rain And a contentious woman are alike;</verse>
<verse>He who would restrain her restrains the wind, And grasps oil with his right hand.</verse>
<verse>Iron sharpens iron, So one man sharpens another.</verse>
<verse>He who tends the fig tree will eat its fruit, And he who cares for his master will be honored.</verse>
<verse>As in water face reflects face, So the heart of man reflects man.</verse>
<verse>Sheol and Abaddon are never satisfied, Nor are the eyes of man ever satisfied.</verse>
<verse>The crucible is for silver and the furnace for gold, And each is tested by the praise accorded him.</verse>
<verse>Though you pound a fool in a mortar with a pestle along with crushed grain, Yet his foolishness will not depart from him.</verse>
<verse>Know well the condition of your flocks, And pay attention to your herds;</verse>
<verse>For riches are not forever, Nor does a crown endure to all generations.</verse>
<verse>When the grass disappears, the new growth is seen, And the herbs of the mountains are gathered in,</verse>
<verse>The lambs will be for your clothing, And the goats will bring the price of a field,</verse>
<verse>And there will be goats' milk enough for your food, For the food of your household, And sustenance for your maidens.</verse>
</chapter>