<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Proverbs" book-id="20" n="28">
<verse>The wicked flee when no one is pursuing, But the righteous are bold as a lion.</verse>
<verse>By the transgression of a land many are its princes, But by a man of understanding and knowledge, so it endures.</verse>
<verse>A poor man who oppresses the lowly Is like a driving rain which leaves no food.</verse>
<verse>Those who forsake the law praise the wicked, But those who keep the law strive with them.</verse>
<verse>Evil men do not understand justice, But those who seek the LORD understand all things.</verse>
<verse>Better is the poor who walks in his integrity Than he who is crooked though he be rich.</verse>
<verse>He who keeps the law is a discerning son, But he who is a companion of gluttons humiliates his father.</verse>
<verse>He who increases his wealth by interest and usury Gathers it for him who is gracious to the poor.</verse>
<verse>He who turns away his ear from listening to the law, Even his prayer is an abomination.</verse>
<verse>He who leads the upright astray in an evil way Will himself fall into his own pit, But the blameless will inherit good.</verse>
<verse>The rich man is wise in his own eyes, But the poor who has understanding sees through him.</verse>
<verse>When the righteous triumph, there is great glory, But when the wicked rise, men hide themselves.</verse>
<verse>He who conceals his transgressions will not prosper, But he who confesses and forsakes them will find compassion.</verse>
<verse>How blessed is the man who fears always, But he who hardens his heart will fall into calamity.</verse>
<verse>Like a roaring lion and a rushing bear Is a wicked ruler over a poor people.</verse>
<verse>A leader who is a great oppressor lacks understanding, But he who hates unjust gain will prolong his days.</verse>
<verse>A man who is laden with the guilt of human blood Will be a fugitive until death; let no one support him.</verse>
<verse>He who walks blamelessly will be delivered, But he who is crooked will fall all at once.</verse>
<verse>He who tills his land will have plenty of food, But he who follows empty pursuits will have poverty in plenty.</verse>
<verse>A faithful man will abound with blessings, But he who makes haste to be rich will not go unpunished.</verse>
<verse>To show partiality is not good, Because for a piece of bread a man will transgress.</verse>
<verse>A man with an evil eye hastens after wealth And does not know that want will come upon him.</verse>
<verse>He who rebukes a man will afterward find more favor Than he who flatters with the tongue.</verse>
<verse>He who robs his father or his mother And says, "It is not a transgression," Is the companion of a man who destroys.</verse>
<verse>An arrogant man stirs up strife, But he who trusts in the LORD will prosper.</verse>
<verse>He who trusts in his own heart is a fool, But he who walks wisely will be delivered.</verse>
<verse>He who gives to the poor will never want, But he who shuts his eyes will have many curses.</verse>
<verse>When the wicked rise, men hide themselves; But when they perish, the righteous increase.</verse>
</chapter>