<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Proverbs" book_id="20" n="29">
<verse>A man who hardens his neck after much reproof Will suddenly be broken beyond remedy.</verse>
<verse>When the righteous increase, the people rejoice, But when a wicked man rules, people groan.</verse>
<verse>A man who loves wisdom makes his father glad, But he who keeps company with harlots wastes his wealth.</verse>
<verse>The king gives stability to the land by justice, But a man who takes bribes overthrows it.</verse>
<verse>A man who flatters his neighbor Is spreading a net for his steps.</verse>
<verse>By transgression an evil man is ensnared, But the righteous sings and rejoices.</verse>
<verse>The righteous is concerned for the rights of the poor, The wicked does not understand such concern.</verse>
<verse>Scorners set a city aflame, But wise men turn away anger.</verse>
<verse>When a wise man has a controversy with a foolish man, The foolish man either rages or laughs, and there is no rest.</verse>
<verse>Men of bloodshed hate the blameless, But the upright are concerned for his life.</verse>
<verse>A fool always loses his temper, But a wise man holds it back.</verse>
<verse>If a ruler pays attention to falsehood, All his ministers become wicked.</verse>
<verse>The poor man and the oppressor have this in common: The LORD gives light to the eyes of both.</verse>
<verse>If a king judges the poor with truth, His throne will be established forever.</verse>
<verse>The rod and reproof give wisdom, But a child who gets his own way brings shame to his mother.</verse>
<verse>When the wicked increase, transgression increases; But the righteous will see their fall.</verse>
<verse>Correct your son, and he will give you comfort; He will also delight your soul.</verse>
<verse>Where there is no vision, the people are unrestrained, But happy is he who keeps the law.</verse>
<verse>A slave will not be instructed by words alone; For though he understands, there will be no response.</verse>
<verse>Do you see a man who is hasty in his words? There is more hope for a fool than for him.</verse>
<verse>He who pampers his slave from childhood Will in the end find him to be a son.</verse>
<verse>An angry man stirs up strife, And a hot-tempered man abounds in transgression.</verse>
<verse>A man's pride will bring him low, But a humble spirit will obtain honor.</verse>
<verse>He who is a partner with a thief hates his own life; He hears the oath but tells nothing.</verse>
<verse>The fear of man brings a snare, But he who trusts in the LORD will be exalted.</verse>
<verse>Many seek the ruler's favor, But justice for man comes from the LORD.</verse>
<verse>An unjust man is abominable to the righteous, And he who is upright in the way is abominable to the wicked.</verse>
</chapter>