<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Proverbs" book-id="20" n="3">
<verse>My son, do not forget my teaching, But let your heart keep my commandments;</verse>
<verse>For length of days and years of life And peace they will add to you.</verse>
<verse>Do not let kindness and truth leave you; Bind them around your neck, Write them on the tablet of your heart.</verse>
<verse>So you will find favor and good repute In the sight of God and man.</verse>
<verse>Trust in the LORD with all your heart And do not lean on your own understanding.</verse>
<verse>In all your ways acknowledge Him, And He will make your paths straight.</verse>
<verse>Do not be wise in your own eyes; Fear the LORD and turn away from evil.</verse>
<verse>It will be healing to your body And refreshment to your bones.</verse>
<verse>Honor the LORD from your wealth And from the first of all your produce;</verse>
<verse>So your barns will be filled with plenty And your vats will overflow with new wine.</verse>
<verse>My son, do not reject the discipline of the LORD Or loathe His reproof,</verse>
<verse>For whom the LORD loves He reproves, Even as a father corrects the son in whom he delights.</verse>
<verse>How blessed is the man who finds wisdom And the man who gains understanding.</verse>
<verse>For her profit is better than the profit of silver And her gain better than fine gold.</verse>
<verse>She is more precious than jewels; And nothing you desire compares with her.</verse>
<verse>Long life is in her right hand; In her left hand are riches and honor.</verse>
<verse>Her ways are pleasant ways And all her paths are peace.</verse>
<verse>She is a tree of life to those who take hold of her, And happy are all who hold her fast.</verse>
<verse>The LORD by wisdom founded the earth, By understanding He established the heavens.</verse>
<verse>By His knowledge the deeps were broken up And the skies drip with dew.</verse>
<verse>My son, let them not vanish from your sight; Keep sound wisdom and discretion,</verse>
<verse>So they will be life to your soul And adornment to your neck.</verse>
<verse>Then you will walk in your way securely And your foot will not stumble.</verse>
<verse>When you lie down, you will not be afraid; When you lie down, your sleep will be sweet.</verse>
<verse>Do not be afraid of sudden fear Nor of the onslaught of the wicked when it comes;</verse>
<verse>For the LORD will be your confidence And will keep your foot from being caught.</verse>
<verse>Do not withhold good from those to whom it is due, When it is in your power to do it.</verse>
<verse>Do not say to your neighbor, "Go, and come back, And tomorrow I will give it," When you have it with you.</verse>
<verse>Do not devise harm against your neighbor, While he lives securely beside you.</verse>
<verse>Do not contend with a man without cause, If he has done you no harm.</verse>
<verse>Do not envy a man of violence And do not choose any of his ways.</verse>
<verse>For the devious are an abomination to the LORD; But He is intimate with the upright.</verse>
<verse>The curse of the LORD is on the house of the wicked, But He blesses the dwelling of the righteous.</verse>
<verse>Though He scoffs at the scoffers, Yet He gives grace to the afflicted.</verse>
<verse>The wise will inherit honor, But fools display dishonor.</verse>
</chapter>