<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Proverbs" book-id="20" n="31">
<verse>The words of King Lemuel, the oracle which his mother taught him:</verse>
<verse>What, O my son? And what, O son of my womb? And what, O son of my vows?</verse>
<verse>Do not give your strength to women, Or your ways to that which destroys kings.</verse>
<verse>It is not for kings, O Lemuel, It is not for kings to drink wine, Or for rulers to desire strong drink,</verse>
<verse>For they will drink and forget what is decreed, And pervert the rights of all the afflicted.</verse>
<verse>Give strong drink to him who is perishing, And wine to him whose life is bitter.</verse>
<verse>Let him drink and forget his poverty And remember his trouble no more.</verse>
<verse>Open your mouth for the mute, For the rights of all the unfortunate.</verse>
<verse>Open your mouth, judge righteously, And defend the rights of the afflicted and needy.</verse>
<verse>An excellent wife, who can find? For her worth is far above jewels.</verse>
<verse>The heart of her husband trusts in her, And he will have no lack of gain.</verse>
<verse>She does him good and not evil All the days of her life.</verse>
<verse>She looks for wool and flax And works with her hands in delight.</verse>
<verse>She is like merchant ships; She brings her food from afar.</verse>
<verse>She rises also while it is still night And gives food to her household And portions to her maidens.</verse>
<verse>She considers a field and buys it; From her earnings she plants a vineyard.</verse>
<verse>She girds herself with strength And makes her arms strong.</verse>
<verse>She senses that her gain is good; Her lamp does not go out at night.</verse>
<verse>She stretches out her hands to the distaff, And her hands grasp the spindle.</verse>
<verse>She extends her hand to the poor, And she stretches out her hands to the needy.</verse>
<verse>She is not afraid of the snow for her household, For all her household are clothed with scarlet.</verse>
<verse>She makes coverings for herself; Her clothing is fine linen and purple.</verse>
<verse>Her husband is known in the gates, When he sits among the elders of the land.</verse>
<verse>She makes linen garments and sells them, And supplies belts to the tradesmen.</verse>
<verse>Strength and dignity are her clothing, And she smiles at the future.</verse>
<verse>She opens her mouth in wisdom, And the teaching of kindness is on her tongue.</verse>
<verse>She looks well to the ways of her household, And does not eat the bread of idleness.</verse>
<verse>Her children rise up and bless her; Her husband also, and he praises her, saying:</verse>
<verse>"Many daughters have done nobly, But you excel them all."</verse>
<verse>Charm is deceitful and beauty is vain, But a woman who fears the LORD, she shall be praised.</verse>
<verse>Give her the product of her hands, And let her works praise her in the gates.</verse>
</chapter>