<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Proverbs" book_id="20" n="5">
<verse>My son, give attention to my wisdom, Incline your ear to my understanding;</verse>
<verse>That you may observe discretion And your lips may reserve knowledge.</verse>
<verse>For the lips of an adulteress drip honey And smoother than oil is her speech;</verse>
<verse>But in the end she is bitter as wormwood, Sharp as a two-edged sword.</verse>
<verse>Her feet go down to death, Her steps take hold of Sheol.</verse>
<verse>She does not ponder the path of life; Her ways are unstable, she does not know it.</verse>
<verse>Now then, my sons, listen to me And do not depart from the words of my mouth.</verse>
<verse>Keep your way far from her And do not go near the door of her house,</verse>
<verse>Or you will give your vigor to others And your years to the cruel one;</verse>
<verse>And strangers will be filled with your strength And your hard-earned goods will go to the house of an alien;</verse>
<verse>And you groan at your final end, When your flesh and your body are consumed;</verse>
<verse>And you say, "How I have hated instruction! And my heart spurned reproof!</verse>
<verse>"I have not listened to the voice of my teachers, Nor inclined my ear to my instructors!</verse>
<verse>"I was almost in utter ruin In the midst of the assembly and congregation."</verse>
<verse>Drink water from your own cistern And fresh water from your own well.</verse>
<verse>Should your springs be dispersed abroad, Streams of water in the streets?</verse>
<verse>Let them be yours alone And not for strangers with you.</verse>
<verse>Let your fountain be blessed, And rejoice in the wife of your youth.</verse>
<verse>As a loving hind and a graceful doe, Let her breasts satisfy you at all times; Be exhilarated always with her love.</verse>
<verse>For why should you, my son, be exhilarated with an adulteress And embrace the bosom of a foreigner?</verse>
<verse>For the ways of a man are before the eyes of the LORD, And He watches all his paths.</verse>
<verse>His own iniquities will capture the wicked, And he will be held with the cords of his sin.</verse>
<verse>He will die for lack of instruction, And in the greatness of his folly he will go astray.</verse>
</chapter>