<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Proverbs" book-id="20" n="6">
<verse>My son, if you have become surety for your neighbor, Have given a pledge for a stranger,</verse>
<verse>If you have been snared with the words of your mouth, Have been caught with the words of your mouth,</verse>
<verse>Do this then, my son, and deliver yourself; Since you have come into the hand of your neighbor, Go, humble yourself, and importune your neighbor.</verse>
<verse>Give no sleep to your eyes, Nor slumber to your eyelids;</verse>
<verse>Deliver yourself like a gazelle from the hunter's hand And like a bird from the hand of the fowler.</verse>
<verse>Go to the ant, O sluggard, Observe her ways and be wise,</verse>
<verse>Which, having no chief, Officer or ruler,</verse>
<verse>Prepares her food in the summer And gathers her provision in the harvest.</verse>
<verse>How long will you lie down, O sluggard? When will you arise from your sleep?</verse>
<verse>"A little sleep, a little slumber, A little folding of the hands to rest"--</verse>
<verse>Your poverty will come in like a vagabond And your need like an armed man.</verse>
<verse>A worthless person, a wicked man, Is the one who walks with a perverse mouth,</verse>
<verse>Who winks with his eyes, who signals with his feet, Who points with his fingers;</verse>
<verse>Who with perversity in his heart continually devises evil, Who spreads strife.</verse>
<verse>Therefore his calamity will come suddenly; Instantly he will be broken and there will be no healing.</verse>
<verse>There are six things which the LORD hates, Yes, seven which are an abomination to Him:</verse>
<verse>Haughty eyes, a lying tongue, And hands that shed innocent blood,</verse>
<verse>A heart that devises wicked plans, Feet that run rapidly to evil,</verse>
<verse>A false witness who utters lies, And one who spreads strife among brothers.</verse>
<verse>My son, observe the commandment of your father And do not forsake the teaching of your mother;</verse>
<verse>Bind them continually on your heart; Tie them around your neck.</verse>
<verse>When you walk about, they will guide you; When you sleep, they will watch over you; And when you awake, they will talk to you.</verse>
<verse>For the commandment is a lamp and the teaching is light; And reproofs for discipline are the way of life</verse>
<verse>To keep you from the evil woman, From the smooth tongue of the adulteress.</verse>
<verse>Do not desire her beauty in your heart, Nor let her capture you with her eyelids.</verse>
<verse>For on account of a harlot one is reduced to a loaf of bread, And an adulteress hunts for the precious life.</verse>
<verse>Can a man take fire in his bosom And his clothes not be burned?</verse>
<verse>Or can a man walk on hot coals And his feet not be scorched?</verse>
<verse>So is the one who goes in to his neighbor's wife; Whoever touches her will not go unpunished.</verse>
<verse>Men do not despise a thief if he steals To satisfy himself when he is hungry;</verse>
<verse>But when he is found, he must repay sevenfold; He must give all the substance of his house.</verse>
<verse>The one who commits adultery with a woman is lacking sense; He who would destroy himself does it.</verse>
<verse>Wounds and disgrace he will find, And his reproach will not be blotted out.</verse>
<verse>For jealousy enrages a man, And he will not spare in the day of vengeance.</verse>
<verse>He will not accept any ransom, Nor will he be satisfied though you give many gifts.</verse>
</chapter>