<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Proverbs" book_id="20" n="7">
<verse>My son, keep my words And treasure my commandments within you.</verse>
<verse>Keep my commandments and live, And my teaching as the apple of your eye.</verse>
<verse>Bind them on your fingers; Write them on the tablet of your heart.</verse>
<verse>Say to wisdom, "You are my sister," And call understanding your intimate friend;</verse>
<verse>That they may keep you from an adulteress, From the foreigner who flatters with her words.</verse>
<verse>For at the window of my house I looked out through my lattice,</verse>
<verse>And I saw among the naive, And discerned among the youths A young man lacking sense,</verse>
<verse>Passing through the street near her corner; And he takes the way to her house,</verse>
<verse>In the twilight, in the evening, In the middle of the night and in the darkness.</verse>
<verse>And behold, a woman comes to meet him, Dressed as a harlot and cunning of heart.</verse>
<verse>She is boisterous and rebellious, Her feet do not remain at home;</verse>
<verse>She is now in the streets, now in the squares, And lurks by every corner.</verse>
<verse>So she seizes him and kisses him And with a brazen face she says to him:</verse>
<verse>"I was due to offer peace offerings; Today I have paid my vows.</verse>
<verse>"Therefore I have come out to meet you, To seek your presence earnestly, and I have found you.</verse>
<verse>"I have spread my couch with coverings, With colored linens of Egypt.</verse>
<verse>"I have sprinkled my bed With myrrh, aloes and cinnamon.</verse>
<verse>"Come, let us drink our fill of love until morning; Let us delight ourselves with caresses.</verse>
<verse>"For my husband is not at home, He has gone on a long journey;</verse>
<verse>He has taken a bag of money with him, At the full moon he will come home."</verse>
<verse>With her many persuasions she entices him; With her flattering lips she seduces him.</verse>
<verse>Suddenly he follows her As an ox goes to the slaughter, Or as one in fetters to the discipline of a fool,</verse>
<verse>Until an arrow pierces through his liver; As a bird hastens to the snare, So he does not know that it will cost him his life.</verse>
<verse>Now therefore, my sons, listen to me, And pay attention to the words of my mouth.</verse>
<verse>Do not let your heart turn aside to her ways, Do not stray into her paths.</verse>
<verse>For many are the victims she has cast down, And numerous are all her slain.</verse>
<verse>Her house is the way to Sheol, Descending to the chambers of death.</verse>
</chapter>