<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Proverbs" book_id="20" n="8">
<verse>Does not wisdom call, And understanding lift up her voice?</verse>
<verse>On top of the heights beside the way, Where the paths meet, she takes her stand;</verse>
<verse>Beside the gates, at the opening to the city, At the entrance of the doors, she cries out:</verse>
<verse>"To you, O men, I call, And my voice is to the sons of men.</verse>
<verse>"O naive ones, understand prudence; And, O fools, understand wisdom.</verse>
<verse>"Listen, for I will speak noble things; And the opening of my lips will reveal right things.</verse>
<verse>"For my mouth will utter truth; And wickedness is an abomination to my lips.</verse>
<verse>"All the utterances of my mouth are in righteousness; There is nothing crooked or perverted in them.</verse>
<verse>"They are all straightforward to him who understands, And right to those who find knowledge.</verse>
<verse>"Take my instruction and not silver, And knowledge rather than choicest gold.</verse>
<verse>"For wisdom is better than jewels; And all desirable things cannot compare with her.</verse>
<verse>"I, wisdom, dwell with prudence, And I find knowledge and discretion.</verse>
<verse>"The fear of the LORD is to hate evil; Pride and arrogance and the evil way And the perverted mouth, I hate.</verse>
<verse>"Counsel is mine and sound wisdom; I am understanding, power is mine.</verse>
<verse>"By me kings reign, And rulers decree justice.</verse>
<verse>"By me princes rule, and nobles, All who judge rightly.</verse>
<verse>"I love those who love me; And those who diligently seek me will find me.</verse>
<verse>"Riches and honor are with me, Enduring wealth and righteousness.</verse>
<verse>"My fruit is better than gold, even pure gold, And my yield better than choicest silver.</verse>
<verse>"I walk in the way of righteousness, In the midst of the paths of justice,</verse>
<verse>To endow those who love me with wealth, That I may fill their treasuries.</verse>
<verse>"The LORD possessed me at the beginning of His way, Before His works of old.</verse>
<verse>"From everlasting I was established, From the beginning, from the earliest times of the earth.</verse>
<verse>"When there were no depths I was brought forth, When there were no springs abounding with water.</verse>
<verse>"Before the mountains were settled, Before the hills I was brought forth;</verse>
<verse>While He had not yet made the earth and the fields, Nor the first dust of the world.</verse>
<verse>"When He established the heavens, I was there, When He inscribed a circle on the face of the deep,</verse>
<verse>When He made firm the skies above, When the springs of the deep became fixed,</verse>
<verse>When He set for the sea its boundary So that the water would not transgress His command, When He marked out the foundations of the earth;</verse>
<verse>Then I was beside Him, as a master workman; And I was daily His delight, Rejoicing always before Him,</verse>
<verse>Rejoicing in the world, His earth, And having my delight in the sons of men.</verse>
<verse>"Now therefore, O sons, listen to me, For blessed are they who keep my ways.</verse>
<verse>"Heed instruction and be wise, And do not neglect it.</verse>
<verse>"Blessed is the man who listens to me, Watching daily at my gates, Waiting at my doorposts.</verse>
<verse>"For he who finds me finds life And obtains favor from the LORD.</verse>
<verse>"But he who sins against me injures himself; All those who hate me love death."</verse>
</chapter>