<chapter translation="ESV" testament="New" book="1 Corinthians" book_id="46" n="16">
<verse>Now concerning the collection for the saints: as I directed the churches of Galatia, so you also are to do.</verse>
<verse>On the first day of every week, each of you is to put something aside and store it up, as he may prosper, so that there will be no collecting when I come.</verse>
<verse>And when I arrive, I will send those whom you accredit by letter to carry your gift to Jerusalem.</verse>
<verse>If it seems advisable that I should go also, they will accompany me.</verse>
<verse>I will visit you after passing through Macedonia, for I intend to pass through Macedonia,</verse>
<verse>and perhaps I will stay with you or even spend the winter, so that you may help me on my journey, wherever I go.</verse>
<verse>For I do not want to see you now just in passing. I hope to spend some time with you, if the Lord permits.</verse>
<verse>But I will stay in Ephesus until Pentecost,</verse>
<verse>for a wide door for effective work has opened to me, and there are many adversaries.</verse>
<verse>When Timothy comes, see that you put him at ease among you, for he is doing the work of the Lord, as I am.</verse>
<verse>So let no one despise him. Help him on his way in peace, that he may return to me, for I am expecting him with the brothers.</verse>
<verse>Now concerning our brother Apollos, I strongly urged him to visit you with the other brothers, but it was not at all his will to come now. He will come when he has opportunity.</verse>
<verse>Be watchful, stand firm in the faith, act like men, be strong.</verse>
<verse>Let all that you do be done in love.</verse>
<verse>Now I urge you, brothers--you know that the household of Stephanas were the first converts in Achaia, and that they have devoted themselves to the service of the saints--</verse>
<verse>be subject to such as these, and to every fellow worker and laborer.</verse>
<verse>I rejoice at the coming of Stephanas and Fortunatus and Achaicus, because they have made up for your absence,</verse>
<verse>for they refreshed my spirit as well as yours. Give recognition to such men.</verse>
<verse>The churches of Asia send you greetings. Aquila and Prisca, together with the church in their house, send you hearty greetings in the Lord.</verse>
<verse>All the brothers send you greetings. Greet one another with a holy kiss.</verse>
<verse>I, Paul, write this greeting with my own hand.</verse>
<verse>If anyone has no love for the Lord, let him be accursed. Our Lord, come!</verse>
<verse>The grace of the Lord Jesus be with you.</verse>
<verse>My love be with you all in Christ Jesus. Amen.</verse>
</chapter>