<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Song of Solomon" book_id="22" n="2">
<verse>I'm just a wildflower picked from the plains of Sharon, a lotus blossom from the valley pools.</verse>
<verse>A lotus blossoming in a swamp of weeds--that's my dear friend among the girls in the village.</verse>
<verse>As an apricot tree stands out in the forest, my lover stands above the young men in town. All I want is to sit in his shade, to taste and savor his delicious love.</verse>
<verse>He took me home with him for a festive meal, but his eyes feasted on me!</verse>
<verse>Oh! Give me something refreshing to eat--and quickly! Apricots, raisins--anything. I'm about to faint with love!</verse>
<verse>His left hand cradles my head, and his right arm encircles my waist!</verse>
<verse>Oh, let me warn you, sisters in Jerusalem, by the gazelles, yes, by all the wild deer: Don't excite love, don't stir it up, until the time is ripe--and you're ready.</verse>
<verse>Look! Listen! There's my lover! Do you see him coming? Vaulting the mountains, leaping the hills.</verse>
<verse>My lover is like a gazelle, graceful; like a young stag, virile. Look at him there, on tiptoe at the gate, all ears, all eyes--ready!</verse>
<verse>My lover has arrived and he's speaking to me! Get up, my dear friend, fair and beautiful lover--come to me!</verse>
<verse>Look around you: Winter is over; the winter rains are over, gone!</verse>
<verse>Spring flowers are in blossom all over. The whole world's a choir--and singing! Spring warblers are filling the forest with sweet arpeggios.</verse>
<verse>Lilacs are exuberantly purple and perfumed, and cherry trees fragrant with blossoms. Oh, get up, dear friend, my fair and beautiful lover--come to me!</verse>
<verse>Come, my shy and modest dove--leave your seclusion, come out in the open. Let me see your face, let me hear your voice. For your voice is soothing and your face is ravishing.</verse>
<verse>Then you must protect me from the foxes, foxes on the prowl, Foxes who would like nothing better than to get into our flowering garden.</verse>
<verse>My lover is mine, and I am his. Nightly he strolls in our garden, Delighting in the flowers</verse>
<verse>until dawn breathes its light and night slips away. Turn to me, dear lover. Come like a gazelle. Leap like a wild stag on delectable mountains!</verse>
</chapter>