<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Ruth" book_id="8" n="1">
<verse>Now it came about in the days when the judges governed, that there was a famine in the land. And a certain man of Bethlehem in Judah went to sojourn in the land of Moab with his wife and his two sons.</verse>
<verse>The name of the man was Elimelech, and the name of his wife, Naomi; and the names of his two sons were Mahlon and Chilion, Ephrathites of Bethlehem in Judah. Now they entered the land of Moab and remained there.</verse>
<verse>Then Elimelech, Naomi's husband, died; and she was left with her two sons.</verse>
<verse>They took for themselves Moabite women as wives; the name of the one was Orpah and the name of the other Ruth. And they lived there about ten years.</verse>
<verse>Then both Mahlon and Chilion also died, and the woman was bereft of her two children and her husband.</verse>
<verse>Then she arose with her daughters-in-law that she might return from the land of Moab, for she had heard in the land of Moab that the LORD had visited His people in giving them food.</verse>
<verse>So she departed from the place where she was, and her two daughters-in-law with her; and they went on the way to return to the land of Judah.</verse>
<verse>And Naomi said to her two daughters-in-law, "Go, return each of you to her mother's house. May the LORD deal kindly with you as you have dealt with the dead and with me.</verse>
<verse>"May the LORD grant that you may find rest, each in the house of her husband." Then she kissed them, and they lifted up their voices and wept.</verse>
<verse>And they said to her, "No, but we will surely return with you to your people."</verse>
<verse>But Naomi said, "Return, my daughters. Why should you go with me? Have I yet sons in my womb, that they may be your husbands?</verse>
<verse>"Return, my daughters! Go, for I am too old to have a husband. If I said I have hope, if I should even have a husband tonight and also bear sons,</verse>
<verse>would you therefore wait until they were grown? Would you therefore refrain from marrying? No, my daughters; for it is harder for me than for you, for the hand of the LORD has gone forth against me."</verse>
<verse>And they lifted up their voices and wept again; and Orpah kissed her mother-in-law, but Ruth clung to her.</verse>
<verse>Then she said, "Behold, your sister-in-law has gone back to her people and her gods; return after your sister-in-law."</verse>
<verse>But Ruth said, "Do not urge me to leave you or turn back from following you; for where you go, I will go, and where you lodge, I will lodge. Your people shall be my people, and your God, my God.</verse>
<verse>"Where you die, I will die, and there I will be buried. Thus may the LORD do to me, and worse, if anything but death parts you and me."</verse>
<verse>When she saw that she was determined to go with her, she said no more to her.</verse>
<verse>So they both went until they came to Bethlehem. And when they had come to Bethlehem, all the city was stirred because of them, and the women said, "Is this Naomi?"</verse>
<verse>She said to them, "Do not call me Naomi; call me Mara, for the Almighty has dealt very bitterly with me.</verse>
<verse>"I went out full, but the LORD has brought me back empty. Why do you call me Naomi, since the LORD has witnessed against me and the Almighty has afflicted me?"</verse>
<verse>So Naomi returned, and with her Ruth the Moabitess, her daughter-in-law, who returned from the land of Moab. And they came to Bethlehem at the beginning of barley harvest.</verse>
</chapter>