<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Exodus" book_id="2" n="1">
<verse>These are the names of the Israelites who went to Egypt with Jacob, each bringing his family members:</verse>
<verse>Reuben, Simeon, Levi, and Judah,</verse>
<verse>Issachar, Zebulun, and Benjamin,</verse>
<verse>Dan and Naphtali, Gad and Asher.</verse>
<verse>Seventy persons in all generated by Jacob's seed. Joseph was already in Egypt.</verse>
<verse>Then Joseph died, and all his brothers-that whole generation.</verse>
<verse>But the children of Israel kept on reproducing. They were very prolific--a population explosion in their own right--and the land was filled with them.</verse>
<verse>A new king came to power in Egypt who didn't know Joseph.</verse>
<verse>He spoke to his people in alarm, "There are way too many of these Israelites for us to handle.</verse>
<verse>We've got to do something: Let's devise a plan to contain them, lest if there's a war they should join our enemies, or just walk off and leave us."</verse>
<verse>So they organized them into work-gangs and put them to hard labor under gang-foremen. They built the storage cities Pithom and Rameses for Pharaoh.</verse>
<verse>But the harder the Egyptians worked them the more children the Israelites had--children everywhere! The Egyptians got so they couldn't stand the Israelites</verse>
<verse>and treated them worse than ever, crushing them with slave labor.</verse>
<verse>They made them miserable with hard labor--making bricks and mortar and back-breaking work in the fields. They piled on the work, crushing them under the cruel workload.</verse>
<verse>The king of Egypt had a talk with the two Hebrew midwives; one was named Shiphrah and the other Puah.</verse>
<verse>He said, "When you deliver the Hebrew women, look at the sex of the baby. If it's a boy, kill him; if it's a girl, let her live."</verse>
<verse>But the midwives had far too much respect for God and didn't do what the king of Egypt ordered; they let the boy babies live.</verse>
<verse>The king of Egypt called in the midwives. "Why didn't you obey my orders? You've let those babies live!"</verse>
<verse>The midwives answered Pharaoh, "The Hebrew women aren't like the Egyptian women; they're vigorous. Before the midwife can get there, they've already had the baby."</verse>
<verse>God was pleased with the midwives. The people continued to increase in number--a very strong people.</verse>
<verse>And because the midwives honored God, God gave them families of their own.</verse>
<verse>So Pharaoh issued a general order to all his people: "Every boy that is born, drown him in the Nile. But let the girls live."</verse>
</chapter>