<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Exodus" book-id="2" n="2">
<verse>A man from the family of Levi married a Levite woman.</verse>
<verse>The woman became pregnant and had a son. She saw there was something special about him and hid him. She hid him for three months.</verse>
<verse>When she couldn't hide him any longer she got a little basket-boat made of papyrus, waterproofed it with tar and pitch, and placed the child in it. Then she set it afloat in the reeds at the edge of the Nile.</verse>
<verse>The baby's older sister found herself a vantage point a little way off and watched to see what would happen to him.</verse>
<verse>Pharaoh's daughter came down to the Nile to bathe; her maidens strolled on the bank. She saw the basket-boat floating in the reeds and sent her maid to get it.</verse>
<verse>She opened it and saw the child--a baby crying! Her heart went out to him. She said, "This must be one of the Hebrew babies."</verse>
<verse>Then his sister was before her: "Do you want me to go and get a nursing mother from the Hebrews so she can nurse the baby for you?"</verse>
<verse>Pharaoh's daughter said, "Yes. Go." The girl went and called the child's mother.</verse>
<verse>Pharaoh's daughter told her, "Take this baby and nurse him for me. I'll pay you." The woman took the child and nursed him.</verse>
<verse>After the child was weaned, she presented him to Pharaoh's daughter who adopted him as her son. She named him Moses (Pulled-Out), saying, "I pulled him out of the water."</verse>
<verse>Time passed. Moses grew up. One day he went and saw his brothers, saw all that hard labor. Then he saw an Egyptian hit a Hebrew--one of his relatives!</verse>
<verse>He looked this way and then that; when he realized there was no one in sight, he killed the Egyptian and buried him in the sand.</verse>
<verse>The next day he went out there again. Two Hebrew men were fighting. He spoke to the man who started it: "Why are you hitting your neighbor?"</verse>
<verse>The man shot back: "Who do you think you are, telling us what to do? Are you going to kill me the way you killed that Egyptian?" Then Moses panicked: "Word's gotten out--people know about this." [JC]</verse>
<verse>Pharaoh heard about it and tried to kill Moses, but Moses got away to the land of Midian. He sat down by a well.</verse>
<verse>The priest of Midian had seven daughters. They came and drew water, filling the troughs and watering their father's sheep.</verse>
<verse>When some shepherds came and chased the girls off, Moses came to their rescue and helped them water their sheep.</verse>
<verse>When they got home to their father, Reuel, he said, "That didn't take long. Why are you back so soon?"</verse>
<verse>"An Egyptian," they said, "rescued us from a bunch of shepherds. Why, he even drew water for us and watered the sheep."</verse>
<verse>He said, "So where is he? Why did you leave him behind? Invite him so he can have something to eat with us."</verse>
<verse>Moses agreed to settle down there with the man, who then gave his daughter Zipporah (Bird) to him for his wife.</verse>
<verse>She had a son, and Moses named him Gershom (Sojourner), saying, "I'm a sojourner in a foreign country." [JC]</verse>
<verse>Many years later the king of Egypt died. The Israelites groaned under their slavery and cried out. Their cries for relief from their hard labor ascended to God:</verse>
<verse>God listened to their groanings. God remembered his covenant with Abraham, with Isaac, and with Jacob.</verse>
<verse>God saw what was going on with Israel. God understood. [JC]</verse>
</chapter>