<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Exodus" book_id="2" n="20">
<verse>GOD spoke all these words:</verse>
<verse>I am GOD, your God, who brought you out of the land of Egypt, out of a life of slavery.</verse>
<verse>No other gods, only me.</verse>
<verse>No carved gods of any size, shape, or form of anything whatever, whether of things that fly or walk or swim.</verse>
<verse>Don't bow down to them and don't serve them because I am GOD your God, and I'm a most jealous God, punishing the children for any sins their parents pass on to them to the third, and yes, even to the fourth generation of those who hate me.</verse>
<verse>But I'm unswervingly loyal to the thousands who love me and keep my commandments.</verse>
<verse>No using the name of GOD your God, in curses or silly banter; GOD won't put up with the irreverant use of his name.</verse>
<verse>Observe the Sabbath day, to keep it holy.</verse>
<verse>Work six days and do everything you need to do.</verse>
<verse>But the seventh day is a Sabbath to GOD your God. Don't do any work--not you, nor your son, nor your daughter, nor your servant, nor your maid, nor your animals, not even the foreign guest visiting in your town.</verse>
<verse>For in six days GOD made Heaven, Earth, and sea, and everything in them; he rested on the seventh day. Therefore GOD blessed the Sabbath day; he set it apart as a holy day.</verse>
<verse>Honor your father and mother so that you'll live a long time in the land that GOD your God, is giving you.</verse>
<verse>No murder.</verse>
<verse>No adultery.</verse>
<verse>No stealing.</verse>
<verse>No lies about your neighbor.</verse>
<verse>No lusting after your neighbor's house--or wife or servant or maid or ox or donkey. Don't set your heart on anything that is your neighbor's. [JC]</verse>
<verse>All the people, experiencing the thunder and lightning, the trumpet blast and the smoking mountain, were afraid--they pulled back and stood at a distance.</verse>
<verse>They said to Moses, "You speak to us and we'll listen, but don't have God speak to us or we'll die."</verse>
<verse>Moses spoke to the people: "Don't be afraid. God has come to test you and instill a deep and reverent awe within you so that you won't sin."</verse>
<verse>The people kept their distance while Moses approached the thick cloud where God was.</verse>
<verse>GOD said to Moses, "Give this Message to the People of Israel: "You've experienced firsthand how I spoke with you from Heaven.</verse>
<verse>Don't make gods of silver and gods of gold and then set them alongside me.</verse>
<verse>Make me an earthen Altar. Sacrifice your Whole-Burnt-Offerings, your Peace-Offerings, your sheep, and your cattle on it. Every place where I cause my name to be honored in your worship, I'll be there myself and bless you.</verse>
<verse>If you use stones to make my Altar, don't use dressed stones. If you use a chisel on the stones you'll profane the Altar.</verse>
<verse>Don't use steps to climb to my Altar because that will expose your nakedness.' [JC]</verse>
</chapter>