<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Exodus" book-id="2" n="21">
<verse>"These are the laws that you are to place before them:</verse>
<verse>"When you buy a Hebrew slave, he will serve six years. The seventh year he goes free, for nothing.</verse>
<verse>If he came in single he leaves single. If he came in married he leaves with his wife.</verse>
<verse>If the master gives him a wife and she gave him sons and daughters, the wife and children stay with the master and he leaves by himself.</verse>
<verse>But suppose the slave should say, "I love my master and my wife and children--I don't want my freedom,'</verse>
<verse>then his master is to bring him before God and to a door or doorpost and pierce his ear with an awl, a sign that he is a slave for life.</verse>
<verse>"When a man sells his daughter to be a handmaid, she doesn't go free after six years like the men.</verse>
<verse>If she doesn't please her master, her family must buy her back; her master doesn't have the right to sell her to foreigners since he broke his word to her.</verse>
<verse>If he turns her over to his son, he has to treat her like a daughter.</verse>
<verse>If he marries another woman, she retains all her full rights to meals, clothing, and marital relations.</verse>
<verse>If he won't do any of these three things for her, she goes free, for nothing.</verse>
<verse>"If someone hits another and death results, the penalty is death.</verse>
<verse>But if there was no intent to kill--if it was an accident, an "act of God'--I'll set aside a place to which the killer can flee for refuge.</verse>
<verse>But if the murder was premeditated, cunningly plotted, then drag the killer away, even if it's from my Altar, to be put to death.</verse>
<verse>"If someone hits father or mother, the penalty is death.</verse>
<verse>"If someone kidnaps a person, the penalty is death, regardless of whether the person has been sold or is still held in possession.</verse>
<verse>"If someone curses father or mother, the penalty is death.</verse>
<verse>"If a quarrel breaks out and one hits the other with a rock or a fist and the injured one doesn't die but is confined to bed</verse>
<verse>and then later gets better and can get about on a crutch, the one who hit him is in the clear, except to pay for the loss of time and make sure of complete recovery.</verse>
<verse>"If a slave owner hits a slave, male or female, with a stick and the slave dies on the spot, the slave must be avenged.</verse>
<verse>But if the slave survives a day or two, he's not to be avenged--the slave is the owner's property.</verse>
<verse>"When there's a fight and in the fight a pregnant woman is hit so that she miscarries but is not otherwise hurt, the one responsible has to pay whatever the husband demands in compensation.</verse>
<verse>But if there is further damage, then you must give life for life</verse>
<verse>-eye for eye, tooth for tooth, hand for hand, foot for foot,</verse>
<verse>burn for burn, wound for wound, bruise for bruise.</verse>
<verse>"If a slave owner hits the eye of a slave or handmaid and ruins it, the owner must let the slave go free because of the eye.</verse>
<verse>If the owner knocks out the tooth of the male or female slave, the slave must be released and go free because of the tooth.</verse>
<verse>"If an ox gores a man or a woman to death, the ox must be stoned. The meat cannot be eaten but the owner of the ox is in the clear.</verse>
<verse>But if the ox has a history of goring and the owner knew it and did nothing to guard against it, then if the ox kills a man or a woman, the ox is to be stoned and the owner given the death penalty.</verse>
<verse>If a ransom is agreed upon instead of death, he must pay it in full as a redemption for his life.</verse>
<verse>If a son or daughter is gored, the same judgment holds.</verse>
<verse>If it is a slave or a handmaid the ox gores, thirty shekels of silver is to be paid to the owner and the ox stoned.</verse>
<verse>"If someone uncovers a cistern or digs a pit and leaves it open and an ox or donkey falls into it,</verse>
<verse>the owner of the pit must pay whatever the animal is worth to its owner but can keep the dead animal.</verse>
<verse>"If someone's ox injures a neighbor's ox and the ox dies, they must sell the live ox and split the price; they must also split the dead animal.</verse>
<verse>But if the ox had a history of goring and the owner knew it and did nothing to guard against it, the owner must pay an ox for an ox but can keep the dead animal.</verse>
</chapter>