<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Exodus" book-id="2" n="25">
<verse>GOD spoke to Moses:</verse>
<verse>"Tell the Israelites that they are to set aside offerings for me. Receive the offerings from everyone who is willing to give.</verse>
<verse>These are the offerings I want you to receive from them: gold, silver, bronze;</verse>
<verse>blue, purple, and scarlet material; fine linen; goats' hair;</verse>
<verse>tanned rams' skins; dolphin skins; acacia wood;</verse>
<verse>lamp oil; spices for anointing oils and for fragrant incense;</verse>
<verse>onyx stones and other stones for setting in the Ephod and the Breastpiece.</verse>
<verse>Let them construct a Sanctuary for me so that I can live among them.</verse>
<verse>You are to construct it following the plans I've given you, the design for The Dwelling and the design for all its furnishings.</verse>
<verse>"First let them make a Chest using acacia wood: make it three and three-quarters feet long and two and one-quarter feet wide and deep</verse>
<verse>. Cover it with a veneer of pure gold inside and out and make a molding of gold all around it.</verse>
<verse>Cast four gold rings and attach them to its four feet, two rings on one side and two rings on the other.</verse>
<verse>Make poles from acacia wood and cover them with a veneer of gold</verse>
<verse>and insert them into the rings on the sides of the Chest for carrying the Chest.</verse>
<verse>The poles are to stay in the rings; they must not be removed.</verse>
<verse>"Place The Testimony that I give you in the Chest.</verse>
<verse>"Now make a lid of pure gold for the Chest, an Atonement-Cover, three and three-quarters feet long and two and one-quarter feet wide.</verse>
<verse>"Sculpt two winged angels out of hammered gold for either end of the Atonement-Cover,</verse>
<verse>one angel at one end, one angel at the other. Make them of one piece with the Atonement-Cover.</verse>
<verse>Make the angels with their wings spread, hovering over the Atonement-Cover, facing one another but looking down on it.</verse>
<verse>Set the Atonement-Cover as a lid over the Chest and place in the Chest The Testimony that I will give you.</verse>
<verse>I will meet you there at set times and speak with you from above the Atonement-Cover and from between the angel-figures that are on it, speaking the commands that I have for the Israelites.</verse>
<verse>"Next make a Table from acacia wood. Make it three feet long, one and one-half feet wide and two and one-quarter feet high.</verse>
<verse>Cover it with a veneer of pure gold. Make a molding all around it of gold.</verse>
<verse>Make the border a handbreadth wide all around it and a rim of gold for the border.</verse>
<verse>Make four rings of gold and attach the rings to the four legs</verse>
<verse>parallel to the table top. They will serve as holders for the poles used to carry the Table.</verse>
<verse>Make the poles of acacia wood and cover them with a veneer of gold. They will be used to carry the Table.</verse>
<verse>"Make plates, bowls, jars, and jugs for pouring out offerings. Make them of pure gold.</verse>
<verse>"Always keep fresh Bread of the Presence on the Table before me.</verse>
<verse>"Make a Lampstand of pure hammered gold. Make its stem and branches, cups, calyxes, and petals all of one piece.</verse>
<verse>Give it six branches, three from one side and three from the other;</verse>
<verse>put three cups shaped like almond blossoms, each with calyx and petals, on one branch, three on the next, and so on--the same for all six branches.</verse>
<verse>On the main stem of the Lampstand, make four cups shaped like almonds, with calyx and petals,</verse>
<verse>a calyx extending from under each pair of the six branches,</verse>
<verse>the entire Lampstand fashioned from one piece of hammered pure gold.</verse>
<verse>"Make seven of these lamps for the Table. Arrange the lamps so they throw their light out in front.</verse>
<verse>Make the candle snuffers and trays out of pure gold.</verse>
<verse>"Use a seventy-five-pound brick of pure gold to make the Lampstand and its accessories.</verse>
<verse>Study the design you were given on the mountain and make everything accordingly.</verse>
</chapter>