<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Exodus" book_id="2" n="26">
<verse>"Make The Dwelling itself from ten panels of tapestry woven from fine twisted linen, blue and purple and scarlet material, with an angel-cherubim design. A skilled craftsman should do it.</verse>
<verse>The panels of tapestry are each to be forty-six feet long and six feet wide.</verse>
<verse>Join five of the panels together, and then the other five together.</verse>
<verse>Make loops of blue along the edge of the outside panel of the first set and the same on the outside panel of the second set.</verse>
<verse>Make fifty loops on each panel.</verse>
<verse>Then make fifty gold clasps and join the tapestries together so that The Dwelling is one whole.</verse>
<verse>"Next make tapestries of goat hair for a tent that will cover The Dwelling. Make eleven panels of these tapestries.</verse>
<verse>The length of each panel will be forty-five feet long and six feet wide.</verse>
<verse>Join five of the panels together, and then the other six. Fold the sixth panel double at the front of the tent.</verse>
<verse>Now make fifty loops along the edge of the end panel and fifty loops along the edge of the joining panel.</verse>
<verse>Make fifty clasps of bronze and connect the clasps with the loops, bringing the tent together.</verse>
<verse>"Hang half of the overlap of the tapestry panels over the rear of The Dwelling.</verse>
<verse>The eighteen inches of overlap on either side will cover the sides of the tent.</verse>
<verse>Finally, make a covering for the tapestries of tanned rams' skins dyed red and over that a covering of dolphin skins.</verse>
<verse>"Frame The Dwelling with planks of acacia wood,</verse>
<verse>each section of frame fifteen feet long and two and one-quarter feet wide,</verse>
<verse>with two pegs for securing them. Make all the frames identical:</verse>
<verse>twenty frames for the south side</verse>
<verse>with forty silver sockets to receive the two pegs from each of the twenty frames;</verse>
<verse>the same construction on the north side of The Dwelling;</verse>
<verse>for the rear of The Dwelling, which faces west, make six frames</verse>
<verse>with two additional frames for the rear corners.</verse>
<verse>Both of the two corner frames need to be double in thickness from top to bottom and fit into a single ring</verse>
<verse>-eight frames altogether with sixteen sockets of silver, two under each frame.</verse>
<verse>"Now make crossbars of acacia wood, five for the frames on one side of The Dwelling,</verse>
<verse>five for the other side, and five for the back side facing west.</verse>
<verse>The center crossbar runs from end to end halfway up the frames.</verse>
<verse>Cover the frames with a veneer of gold and make gold rings to hold the crossbars. And cover the crossbars with a veneer of gold.</verse>
<verse>Then put The Dwelling together, following the design you were shown on the mountain.</verse>
<verse>"Make a curtain of blue, purple, and scarlet material and fine twisted linen. Have a design of angel-cherubim woven into it by a skilled craftsman.</verse>
<verse>Fasten it with gold hooks to four posts of acacia wood covered with a veneer of gold, set on four silver bases.</verse>
<verse>After hanging the curtain from the clasps, bring the Chest of The Testimony in behind the curtain. The curtain will separate the Holy Place from the Holy-of-Holies.</verse>
<verse>Now place the Atonement-Cover lid on the Chest of The Testimony in the Holy-of-Holies.</verse>
<verse>Place the Table and the Lampstand outside the curtain, the Lampstand on the south side of The Dwelling and the Table opposite it on the north side.</verse>
<verse>"Make a screen for the door of the tent. Weave it from blue, purple, and scarlet material and fine twisted linen.</verse>
<verse>Frame the weaving with five poles of acacia wood covered with a veneer of gold and make gold hooks to hang the weaving. Cast five bronze bases for the poles.</verse>
</chapter>