<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Exodus" book_id="2" n="28">
<verse>"Get your brother Aaron and his sons from among the Israelites to serve me as priests: Aaron and his sons Nadab, Abihu, Eleazar, Ithamar.</verse>
<verse>Make sacred vestments for your brother Aaron to symbolize glory and beauty.</verse>
<verse>Consult with the skilled craftsmen, those whom I have gifted in this work, and arrange for them to make Aaron's vestments, to set him apart as holy, to act as priest for me.</verse>
<verse>These are the articles of clothing they are to make: Breastpiece, Ephod, robe, woven tunic, turban, sash. They are making holy vestments for your brother Aaron and his sons as they work as priests for me.</verse>
<verse>They will need gold; blue, purple, and scarlet material; and fine linen.</verse>
<verse>"Have the Ephod made from gold; blue, purple, and scarlet material; and fine twisted linen by a skilled craftsman.</verse>
<verse>Give it two shoulder pieces at two of the corners so it can be fastened.</verse>
<verse>The decorated band on it is to be just like it and of one piece with it: made of gold; blue, purple, and scarlet material; and of fine twisted linen.</verse>
<verse>Next take two onyx stones and engrave the names of the sons of Israel on them in the order of their birth,</verse>
<verse>six names on one stone and the remaining six on the other.</verse>
<verse>Engrave the names of the sons of Israel on the two stones the way a jeweler engraves a seal. Then mount the stones in settings of filigreed gold.</verse>
<verse>Fasten the two stones on the shoulder pieces of the Ephod--they are memorial stones for the Israelites. Aaron will wear these names on his shoulders as a memorial before GOD.</verse>
<verse>Make the settings of gold filigree.</verse>
<verse>Make two chains of pure gold and braid them like cords, then attach the corded chains to the settings.</verse>
<verse>"Now make a Breastpiece of Judgment, using skilled craftsmen, the same as with the Ephod. Use gold; blue, purple, and scarlet material; and fine twisted linen.</verse>
<verse>Make it nine inches square and folded double.</verse>
<verse>Mount four rows of precious gemstones on it. First row: carnelian, topaz, emerald.</verse>
<verse>Second row: ruby, sapphire, crystal.</verse>
<verse>Third row: jacinth, agate, amethyst.</verse>
<verse>Fourth row: beryl, onyx, jasper. "Set them in gold filigree.</verse>
<verse>The twelve stones correspond to the names of the Israelites, with twelve names engraved, one on each, as on a seal for the twelve tribes.</verse>
<verse>"Then make braided chains of pure gold for the Breastpiece, like cords.</verse>
<verse>Make two rings of gold for the Breastpiece and fasten them to the two ends.</verse>
<verse>Fasten the two golden cords to the rings at the ends of the Breastpiece.</verse>
<verse>Then fasten the other ends of the two cords to the two settings of filigree, attaching them to the shoulder pieces of the Ephod in front.</verse>
<verse>Then make two rings of gold and fasten them to the two ends of the Breastpiece on its inside edge facing the Ephod.</verse>
<verse>Then make two more rings of gold and fasten them in the front of the Ephod to the lower part of the two shoulder pieces, near the seam above the decorated band.</verse>
<verse>Fasten the Breastpiece in place by running a cord of blue through its rings to the rings of the Ephod so that it rests secure on the decorated band of the Ephod and won't come loose.</verse>
<verse>"Aaron will regularly carry the names of the sons of Israel on the Breastpiece of Judgment over his heart as he enters the Sanctuary into the presence of GOD for remembrance.</verse>
<verse>Place the Urim and Thummim in the Breastpiece of Judgment. They will be over Aaron's heart when he enters the presence of GOD. In this way Aaron will regularly carry the Breastpiece of Judgment into the presence of GOD.</verse>
<verse>"Make the robe for the Ephod entirely of blue,</verse>
<verse>with an opening for the head at the center and a hem on the edge so that it won't tear.</verse>
<verse>For the edge of the skirts make pomegranates of blue, purple, and scarlet material all around and alternate them with bells of gold</verse>
<verse>-gold bell and pomegranate, gold bell and pomegranate--all around the hem of the robe.</verse>
<verse>Aaron has to wear it when he does his priestly work. The bells will be heard when he enters the Holy Place and comes into the presence of GOD, and again when he comes out so that he won't die.</verse>
<verse>"Make a plate of pure gold. Engrave on it as on a seal: "Holy to GOD.'</verse>
<verse>Tie it with a blue cord to the front of the turban.</verse>
<verse>It is to rest there on Aaron's forehead. He'll take on any guilt involved in the sacred offerings that the Israelites consecrate, no matter what they bring. It will always be on Aaron's forehead so that the offerings will be acceptable before GOD.</verse>
<verse>"Weave the tunic of fine linen. Make the turban of fine linen. The sash will be the work of an embroiderer.</verse>
<verse>Make tunics, sashes, and hats for Aaron's sons to express glory and beauty.</verse>
<verse>Dress your brother Aaron and his sons in them. Anoint, ordain, and consecrate them to serve me as priests.</verse>
<verse>"Make linen underwear to cover their nakedness from waist to thigh.</verse>
<verse>Aaron and his sons must wear it whenever they enter the Tent of Meeting or approach the Altar to minister in the Holy Place so that they won't incur guilt and die. This is a permanent rule for Aaron and all his priest-descendants.</verse>
</chapter>