<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Exodus" book-id="2" n="30">
<verse>"Make an Altar for burning incense. Construct it from acacia wood,</verse>
<verse>one and one-half feet square and three feet high with its horns of one piece with it.</verse>
<verse>Cover it with a veneer of pure gold, its top, sides, and horns, and make a gold molding around it</verse>
<verse>with two rings of gold beneath the molding. Place the rings on the two opposing sides to serve as holders for poles by which it will be carried.</verse>
<verse>Make the poles of acacia wood and cover them with a veneer of gold.</verse>
<verse>"Place the Altar in front of the curtain that hides the Chest of The Testimony, in front of the Atonement-Cover that is over The Testimony where I will meet you.</verse>
<verse>Aaron will burn fragrant incense on it every morning when he polishes the lamps,</verse>
<verse>and again in the evening as he prepares the lamps for lighting, so that there will always be incense burning before GOD, generation after generation.</verse>
<verse>But don't burn on this Altar any unholy incense or Whole-Burnt-Offering or Grain-Offering. And don't pour out Drink-Offerings on it.</verse>
<verse>Once a year Aaron is to purify the Altar horns. Using the blood of the Absolution-Offering of atonement, he is to make this atonement every year down through the generations. It is most holy to GOD."</verse>
<verse>GOD spoke to Moses:</verse>
<verse>"When you take a head count of the Israelites to keep track of them, all must pay an atonement-tax to GOD for their life at the time of being registered so that nothing bad will happen because of the registration.</verse>
<verse>Everyone who gets counted is to give a half-shekel (using the standard Sanctuary shekel of a fifth of an ounce to the shekel)-a half-shekel offering to GOD.</verse>
<verse>Everyone counted, age twenty and up, is to make the offering to GOD.</verse>
<verse>The rich are not to pay more nor the poor less than the half-shekel offering to GOD, the atonement-tax for your lives.</verse>
<verse>Take the atonement-tax money from the Israelites and put it to the maintenance of the Tent of Meeting. It will be a memorial fund for the Israelites in honor of GOD, making atonement for your lives."</verse>
<verse>GOD spoke to Moses:</verse>
<verse>"Make a bronze Washbasin; make it with a bronze base. Place it between the Tent of Meeting and the Altar. Put water in it.</verse>
<verse>Aaron and his sons will wash their hands and feet in it.</verse>
<verse>When they enter the Tent of Meeting or approach the Altar to serve there or offer gift offerings to GOD, they are to wash so they will not die.</verse>
<verse>They are to wash their hands and their feet so they will not die. This is the rule forever, for Aaron and his sons down through the generations."</verse>
<verse>GOD spoke to Moses:</verse>
<verse>"Take the best spices: twelve and a half pounds of liquid myrrh; half that much, six and a quarter pounds, of fragrant cinnamon; six and a quarter pounds of fragrant cane;</verse>
<verse>twelve and a half pounds of cassia--using the standard Sanctuary weight for all of them--and a gallon of olive oil.</verse>
<verse>Make these into a holy anointing oil, a perfumer's skillful blend.</verse>
<verse>"Use it to anoint the Tent of Meeting, the Chest of The Testimony,</verse>
<verse>the Table and all its utensils, the Lampstand and its utensils, the Altar of Incense,</verse>
<verse>the Altar of Whole-Burnt-Offerings and all its utensils, and the Washbasin and its base.</verse>
<verse>Consecrate them so they'll be soaked in holiness, so that anyone who so much as touches them will become holy.</verse>
<verse>"Then anoint Aaron and his sons. Consecrate them as priests to me.</verse>
<verse>Tell the Israelites, "This will be my holy anointing oil throughout your generations.'</verse>
<verse>Don't pour it on ordinary men. Don't copy this mixture to use for yourselves. It's holy; keep it holy.</verse>
<verse>Whoever mixes up anything like it, or puts it on an ordinary person, will be expelled."</verse>
<verse>GOD spoke to Moses: "Take fragrant spices--gum resin, onycha, galbanum--and add pure frankincense. Mix the spices in equal proportions</verse>
<verse>to make an aromatic incense, the art of a perfumer, salted and pure--holy.</verse>
<verse>Now crush some of it into powder and place some of it before The Testimony in the Tent of Meeting where I will meet with you; it will be for you the holiest of holy places.</verse>
<verse>When you make this incense, you are not to copy the mixture for your own use. It's holy to GOD; keep it that way.</verse>
<verse>Whoever copies it for personal use will be excommunicated."</verse>
</chapter>