<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Exodus" book-id="2" n="31">
<verse>GOD spoke to Moses:</verse>
<verse>"See what I've done; I've personally chosen Bezalel son of Uri, son of Hur of the tribe of Judah.</verse>
<verse>I've filled him with the Spirit of God, giving him skill and know-how and expertise in every kind of craft</verse>
<verse>to create designs and work in gold, silver, and bronze;</verse>
<verse>to cut and set gemstones; to carve wood--he's an all-around craftsman.</verse>
<verse>"Not only that, but I've given him Oholiab, son of Ahisamach of the tribe of Dan, to work with him. And to all who have an aptitude for crafts I've given the skills to make all the things I've commanded you:</verse>
<verse>the Tent of Meeting, the Chest of The Testimony and its Atonement-Cover, all the implements for the Tent,</verse>
<verse>the Table and its implements, the pure Lampstand and all its implements, the Altar of Incense,</verse>
<verse>the Altar of Whole-Burnt-Offering and all its implements, the Washbasin and its base,</verse>
<verse>the official vestments, the holy vestments for Aaron the priest and his sons in their priestly duties,</verse>
<verse>the anointing oil, and the aromatic incense for the Holy Place--they'll make everything just the way I've commanded you."</verse>
<verse>GOD spoke to Moses:</verse>
<verse>"Tell the Israelites, "Above all, keep my Sabbaths, the sign between me and you, generation after generation, to keep the knowledge alive that I am the GOD who makes you holy.</verse>
<verse>Keep the Sabbath; it's holy to you. Whoever profanes it will most certainly be put to death. Whoever works on it will be excommunicated from the people.</verse>
<verse>There are six days for work but the seventh day is Sabbath, pure rest, holy to GOD. Anyone who works on the Sabbath will most certainly be put to death.</verse>
<verse>The Israelites will keep the Sabbath, observe Sabbath-keeping down through the generations, as a standing covenant.</verse>
<verse>It's a fixed sign between me and the Israelites. Yes, because in six days GOD made the Heavens and the Earth and on the seventh day he stopped and took a long, deep breath.'"</verse>
<verse>When he finished speaking with him on Mount Sinai, he gave Moses two tablets of Testimony, slabs of stone, written with the finger of God.</verse>
</chapter>