<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Exodus" book-id="2" n="39">
<verse>Vestments. Using the blue, purple, and scarlet fabrics, they made the woven vestments for ministering in the Sanctuary. Also they made the sacred vestments for Aaron, as GOD had commanded Moses.</verse>
<verse>Ephod. They made the Ephod using gold and blue, purple, and scarlet fabrics and finely twisted linen.</verse>
<verse>They hammered out gold leaf and sliced it into threads that were then worked into designs in the blue, purple, and scarlet fabric and fine linen.</verse>
<verse>They made shoulder pieces fastened at the two ends.</verse>
<verse>The decorated band was made of the same material--gold, blue, purple, and scarlet material, and of fine twisted linen--and of one piece with it, just as GOD had commanded Moses.</verse>
<verse>They mounted the onyx stones in a setting of filigreed gold and engraved the names of the sons of Israel on them,</verse>
<verse>then fastened them on the shoulder pieces of the Ephod as memorial stones for the Israelites, just as GOD had commanded Moses.</verse>
<verse>Breastpiece. They made a Breastpiece designed like the Ephod from gold, blue, purple, and scarlet material and fine twisted linen.</verse>
<verse>Doubled, the Breastpiece was nine inches square.</verse>
<verse>They mounted four rows of precious gemstones on it. First row: carnelian, topaz, emerald.</verse>
<verse>Second row: ruby, sapphire, crystal.</verse>
<verse>Third row: jacinth, agate, amethyst.</verse>
<verse>Fourth row: beryl, onyx, jasper. The stones were mounted in a gold filigree.</verse>
<verse>The twelve stones corresponded to the names of the sons of Israel, twelve names engraved as on a seal, one for each of the twelve tribes.</verse>
<verse>They made braided chains of pure gold for the Breastpiece, like cords.</verse>
<verse>They made two settings of gold filigree and two rings of gold, put the two rings at the two ends of the Breastpiece,</verse>
<verse>and fastened the two ends of the cords to the two rings at the end of the Breastpiece.</verse>
<verse>Then they fastened the cords to the settings of filigree, attaching them to the shoulder pieces of the Ephod in front.</verse>
<verse>Then they made two rings of gold and fastened them to the two ends of the Breastpiece on its inside edge facing the Ephod.</verse>
<verse>They made two more rings of gold and fastened them in the front of the Ephod to the lower part of the two shoulder pieces, near the seam above the decorated band of the Ephod.</verse>
<verse>The Breastpiece was fastened by running a cord of blue through its rings to the rings of the Ephod so that it rested secure on the decorated band of the Ephod and wouldn't come loose, just as GOD had commanded Moses.</verse>
<verse>Robe. They made the robe for the Ephod entirely of blue.</verse>
<verse>The opening of the robe at the center was like a collar, the edge hemmed so that it wouldn't tear.</verse>
<verse>On the hem of the robe they made pomegranates of blue, purple, and scarlet material and fine twisted linen.</verse>
<verse>They also made bells of pure gold and alternated the bells and pomegranates</verse>
<verse>-a bell and a pomegranate, a bell and a pomegranate--all around the hem of the robe that was worn for ministering, just as GOD had commanded Moses.</verse>
<verse>They also made the tunics of fine linen, the work of a weaver, for Aaron and his sons,</verse>
<verse>the turban of fine linen, the linen hats, the linen underwear made of fine twisted linen,</verse>
<verse>and sashes of fine twisted linen, blue, purple, and scarlet material and embroidered, just as GOD had commanded Moses.</verse>
<verse>They made the plate, the sacred crown, of pure gold and engraved on it as on a seal: "Holy to GOD."</verse>
<verse>They attached a blue cord to it and fastened it to the turban, just as GOD had commanded Moses.</verse>
<verse>That completed the work of The Dwelling, the Tent of Meeting. The People of Israel did what GOD had commanded Moses. They did it all.</verse>
<verse>They presented The Dwelling to Moses, the Tent and all its furnishings: fastening hooks frames crossbars posts bases</verse>
<verse>tenting of tanned ram skins tenting of dolphin skins veil of the screen</verse>
<verse>Chest of The Testimony with its poles and Atonement-Cover</verse>
<verse>Table with its utensils and the Bread of the Presence</verse>
<verse>Lampstand of pure gold and its lamps all fitted out and all its utensils and the oil for the light</verse>
<verse>Gold Altar anointing oil fragrant incense screen for the entrance to the Tent</verse>
<verse>Bronze Altar with its bronze grate its poles and all its utensils Washbasin and its base</verse>
<verse>hangings for the Courtyard its posts and bases screen for the gate of the Courtyard its cords and its pegs utensils for ministry in The Dwelling, the Tent of Meeting</verse>
<verse>woven vestments for ministering in the Sanctuary sacred vestments for Aaron the priest, and his sons when serving as priests</verse>
<verse>The Israelites completed all the work, just as GOD had commanded.</verse>
<verse>Moses saw that they had done all the work and done it exactly as GOD had commanded. Moses blessed them.</verse>
</chapter>