<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Exodus" book-id="2" n="40">
<verse>GOD spoke to Moses:</verse>
<verse>"On the first day of the first month, set up The Dwelling, the Tent of Meeting.</verse>
<verse>Place the Chest of The Testimony in it and screen the Chest with the curtain.</verse>
<verse>"Bring in the Table and set it, arranging its Lampstand and lamps.</verse>
<verse>"Place the Gold Altar of Incense before the Chest of The Testimony and hang the curtain at the door of The Dwelling.</verse>
<verse>"Place the Altar of Whole-Burnt-Offering at the door of The Dwelling, the Tent of Meeting.</verse>
<verse>"Place the Washbasin between the Tent of Meeting and the Altar and fill it with water.</verse>
<verse>"Set up the Courtyard on all sides and hang the curtain at the entrance to the Courtyard.</verse>
<verse>"Then take the anointing oil and anoint The Dwelling and everything in it; consecrate it and all its furnishings so that it becomes holy.</verse>
<verse>Anoint the Altar of Whole-Burnt-Offering and all its utensils, consecrating the Altar so that it is completely holy.</verse>
<verse>Anoint the Washbasin and its base: consecrate it.</verse>
<verse>"Finally, bring Aaron and his sons to the entrance of the Tent of Meeting and wash them with water.</verse>
<verse>Dress Aaron in the sacred vestments. Anoint him. Consecrate him to serve me as priest.</verse>
<verse>Bring his sons and put tunics on them.</verse>
<verse>Anoint them, just as you anointed their father, to serve me as priests. Their anointing will bring them into a perpetual priesthood, down through the generations."</verse>
<verse>Moses did everything GOD commanded. He did it all.</verse>
<verse>On the first day of the first month of the second year, The Dwelling was set up.</verse>
<verse>Moses set it up: He laid its bases, erected the frames, placed the crossbars, set the posts,</verse>
<verse>spread the tent over The Dwelling, and put the covering over the tent, just as GOD had commanded Moses.</verse>
<verse>He placed The Testimony in the Chest, inserted the poles for carrying the Chest, and placed the lid, the Atonement-Cover, on it.</verse>
<verse>He brought the Chest into The Dwelling and set up the curtain, screening off the Chest of The Testimony, just as GOD had commanded Moses.</verse>
<verse>He placed the Table in the Tent of Meeting on the north side of The Dwelling, outside the curtain,</verse>
<verse>and arranged the Bread there before GOD, just as GOD had commanded him.</verse>
<verse>He placed the Lampstand in the Tent of Meeting opposite the Table on the south side of The Dwelling</verse>
<verse>and set up the lamps before GOD, just as GOD had commanded him.</verse>
<verse>Moses placed the Gold Altar in the Tent of Meeting in front of the curtain</verse>
<verse>and burned fragrant incense on it, just as GOD had commanded him.</verse>
<verse>He placed the screen at the entrance to The Dwelling.</verse>
<verse>He set the Altar of Whole-Burnt-Offering at the door of The Dwelling, the Tent of Meeting, and offered up the Whole-Burnt-Offerings and the Grain-Offerings, just as GOD had commanded Moses.</verse>
<verse>He placed the Washbasin between the Tent of Meeting and the Altar, and filled it with water for washing.</verse>
<verse>Moses and Aaron and his sons washed their hands and feet there.</verse>
<verse>When they entered the Tent of Meeting and when they served at the Altar, they washed, just as GOD had commanded Moses.</verse>
<verse>Finally, he erected the Courtyard all around The Dwelling and the Altar, and put up the screen for the Courtyard entrance. Moses finished the work.</verse>
<verse>The Cloud covered the Tent of Meeting, and the Glory of GOD filled The Dwelling.</verse>
<verse>Moses couldn't enter the Tent of Meeting because the Cloud was upon it, and the Glory of GOD filled The Dwelling.</verse>
<verse>Whenever the Cloud lifted from The Dwelling, the People of Israel set out on their travels,</verse>
<verse>but if the Cloud did not lift, they wouldn't set out until it did lift.</verse>
<verse>The Cloud of GOD was over The Dwelling during the day and the fire was in it at night, visible to all the Israelites in all their travels.</verse>
</chapter>