<?xml version="1.0"?>
<chapter translation="KJV" testament="Old" book="Genesis" n="12">
      <verse>Now the LORD had said unto Abram, Get thee out of thy country, and from thy kindred, and from thy father&#x2019;s house, unto a land that I will shew thee:
</verse><verse>And I will make of thee a great nation, and I will bless thee, and make thy name great; and thou shalt be a blessing:
</verse><verse>And I will bless them that bless thee, and curse him that curseth thee: and in thee shall all families of the earth be blessed.
</verse><verse>So Abram departed, as the LORD had spoken unto him; and Lot went with him: and Abram <supplied>was</supplied> seventy and five years old when he departed out of Haran.
</verse><verse>And Abram took Sarai his wife, and Lot his brother&#x2019;s son, and all their substance that they had gathered, and the souls that they had gotten in Haran; and they went forth to go into the land of Canaan; and into the land of Canaan they came.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>And Abram passed through the land unto the place of Sichem, unto the plain of Moreh. And the Canaanite <supplied>was</supplied> then in the land.
</verse><verse>And the LORD appeared unto Abram, and said, Unto thy seed will I give this land: and there builded he an altar unto the LORD, who appeared unto him.
</verse><verse>And he removed from thence unto a mountain on the east of Bethel, and pitched his tent, <supplied>having</supplied> Bethel on the west, and Hai on the east: and there he builded an altar unto the LORD, and called upon the name of the LORD.
</verse><verse>And Abram journeyed, going on still toward the south.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>And there was a famine in the land: and Abram went down into Egypt to sojourn there; for the famine <supplied>was</supplied> grievous in the land.
</verse><verse>And it came to pass, when he was come near to enter into Egypt, that he said unto Sarai his wife, Behold now, I know that thou <supplied>art</supplied> a fair woman to look upon:
</verse><verse>Therefore it shall come to pass, when the Egyptians shall see thee, that they shall say, This <supplied>is</supplied> his wife: and they will kill me, but they will save thee alive.
</verse><verse>Say, I pray thee, thou <supplied>art</supplied> my sister: that it may be well with me for thy sake; and my soul shall live because of thee.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>And it came to pass, that, when Abram was come into Egypt, the Egyptians beheld the woman that she <supplied>was</supplied> very fair.
</verse><verse>The princes also of Pharaoh saw her, and commended her before Pharaoh: and the woman was taken into Pharaoh&#x2019;s house.
</verse><verse>And he entreated Abram well for her sake: and he had sheep, and oxen, and he asses, and menservants, and maidservants, and she asses, and camels.
</verse><verse>And the LORD plagued Pharaoh and his house with great plagues because of Sarai Abram&#x2019;s wife.
</verse><verse>And Pharaoh called Abram, and said, What <supplied>is</supplied> this <supplied>that</supplied> thou hast done unto me? why didst thou not tell me that she <supplied>was</supplied> thy wife?
</verse><verse>Why saidst thou, She <supplied>is</supplied> my sister? so I might have taken her to me to wife: now therefore behold thy wife, take <supplied>her,</supplied> and go thy way.
</verse><verse>And Pharaoh commanded <supplied>his</supplied> men concerning him: and they sent him away, and his wife, and all that he had.
     
      </verse>
      </chapter>
