<?xml version="1.0"?>
<chapter translation="KJV" testament="Old" book="Genesis" n="2" chapters="50">
      <verse>Thus the heavens and the earth were finished, and all the host of them.
</verse><verse>And on the seventh day God ended his work which he had made; and he rested on the seventh day from all his work which he had made.
</verse><verse>And God blessed the seventh day, and sanctified it: because that in it he had rested from all his work which God created and made.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>These <supplied>are</supplied> the generations of the heavens and of the earth when they were created, in the day that the LORD God made the earth and the heavens,
</verse><verse>And every plant of the field before it was in the earth, and every herb of the field before it grew: for the LORD God had not caused it to rain upon the earth, and <supplied>there was</supplied> not a man to till the ground.
</verse><verse>But there went up a mist from the earth, and watered the whole face of the ground.
</verse><verse>And the LORD God formed man <supplied>of</supplied> the dust of the ground, and breathed into his nostrils the breath of life; and man became a living soul.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>And the LORD God planted a garden eastward in Eden; and there he put the man whom he had formed.
</verse><verse>And out of the ground made the LORD God to grow every tree that is pleasant to the sight, and good for food; the tree of life also in the midst of the garden, and the tree of knowledge of good and evil.
</verse><verse>And a river went out of Eden to water the garden; and from thence it was parted, and became into four heads.
</verse><verse>The name of the first <supplied>is</supplied> Pison: that <supplied>is</supplied> it which compasseth the whole land of Havilah, where <supplied>there is</supplied> gold;
</verse><verse>And the gold of that land <supplied>is</supplied> good: there <supplied>is</supplied> bdellium and the onyx stone.
</verse><verse>And the name of the second river <supplied>is</supplied> Gihon: the same <supplied>is</supplied> it that compasseth the whole land of Ethiopia.
</verse><verse>And the name of the third river <supplied>is</supplied> Hiddekel: that <supplied>is</supplied> it which goeth toward the east of Assyria. And the fourth river <supplied>is</supplied> Euphrates.
</verse><verse>And the LORD God took the man, and put him into the garden of Eden to dress it and to keep it.
</verse><verse>And the LORD God commanded the man, saying, Of every tree of the garden thou mayest freely eat:
</verse><verse>But of the tree of the knowledge of good and evil, thou shalt not eat of it: for in the day that thou eatest thereof thou shalt surely die.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>And the LORD God said, <supplied>It is</supplied> not good that the man should be alone; I will make him an help meet for him.
</verse><verse>And out of the ground the LORD God formed every beast of the field, and every fowl of the air; and brought <supplied>them</supplied> unto Adam to see what he would call them: and whatsoever Adam called every living creature, that <supplied>was</supplied> the name
thereof.
</verse><verse>And Adam gave names to all cattle, and to the fowl of the air, and to every beast of the field; but for Adam there was not found an help meet for him.
</verse><verse>And the LORD God caused a deep sleep to fall upon Adam and he slept: and he took one of his ribs, and closed up the flesh instead thereof;
</verse><verse>And the rib, which the LORD God had taken from man, made he a woman, and brought her unto the man.
</verse><verse>And Adam said, This <supplied>is</supplied> now bone of my bones, and flesh of my flesh: she shall be called Woman, because she was taken out of Man.
</verse><verse>Therefore shall a man leave his father and his mother, and shall cleave unto his wife: and they shall be one flesh.
</verse><verse>And they were both naked, the man and his wife, and were not ashamed.
     
      </verse>
      </chapter>
