<chapter translation="KJV" testament="Old" book="GEN" n="44">
      <verse>And he commanded the steward of his house, saying, Fill the men’s sacks <supplied>with</supplied> food, as much as they can carry, and put every man’s money in his sack’s mouth.
</verse><verse>And put my cup, the silver cup, in the sack’s mouth of the youngest, and his corn money. And he did according to the word that Joseph had spoken.
</verse><verse>As soon as the morning was light, the men were sent away, they and their asses.
</verse><verse><supplied>And</supplied> when they were gone out of the city, <supplied>and</supplied> not <supplied>yet</supplied> far off, Joseph said unto his steward, Up, follow after the men; and when thou dost overtake them, say unto them, Wherefore have ye rewarded evil for good?
</verse><verse><supplied>Is</supplied> not this <supplied>it</supplied> in which my lord drinketh, and whereby indeed he divineth? ye have done evil in so doing.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>And he overtook them, and he spake unto them these same words.
</verse><verse>And they said unto him, Wherefore saith my lord these words? God forbid that thy servants should do according to this thing:
</verse><verse>Behold, the money, which we found in our sacks’ mouths, we brought again unto thee out of the land of Canaan: how then should we steal out of thy lord’s house silver or gold?
</verse><verse>With whomsoever of thy servants it be found, both let him die, and we also will be my lord’s bondmen.
</verse><verse>And he said, Now also <supplied>let</supplied> it <supplied>be</supplied> according unto your words; he with whom it is found shall be my servant; and ye shall be blameless.
</verse><verse>Then they speedily took down every man his sack to the ground, and opened every man his sack.
</verse><verse>And he searched, <supplied>and</supplied> began at the eldest, and left at the youngest: and the cup was found in Benjamin’s sack.
</verse><verse>Then they rent their clothes, and laded every man his ass, and returned to the city.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>And Judah and his brethren came to Joseph’s house; for he <supplied>was</supplied> yet there: and they fell before him on the ground.
</verse><verse>And Joseph said unto them, What deed <supplied>is</supplied> this that ye have done? wot ye not that such a man as I can certainly divine?
</verse><verse>And Judah said, What shall we say unto my lord? what shall we speak? or how shall we clear ourselves? God hath found out the iniquity of thy servants: behold, we <supplied>are</supplied> my lord’s servants, both we, and <supplied>he</supplied> also with whom the cup is
found.
</verse><verse>And he said, God forbid that I should do so: <supplied>but</supplied> the man in whose hand the cup is found, he shall be my servant; and as for you, get you up in peace unto your father.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>Then Judah came near unto him, and said, Oh my lord, let thy servant, I pray thee, speak a word in my lord’s ears, and let not thine anger burn against thy servant: for thou <supplied>art</supplied> even as Pharaoh.
</verse><verse>My lord asked his servants, saying, Have ye a father, or a brother?
</verse><verse>And we said unto my lord, We have a father, an old man, and a child of his old age, a little one; and his brother is dead, and he alone is left of his mother, and his father loveth him.
</verse><verse>And thou saidst unto thy servants, Bring him down unto me, that I may set mine eyes upon him.
</verse><verse>And we said unto my lord, The lad cannot leave his father: for <supplied>if</supplied> he should leave his father, <supplied>his father</supplied> would die.
</verse><verse>And thou saidst unto thy servants, Except your youngest brother come down with you, ye shall see my face no more.
</verse><verse>And it came to pass when we came up unto thy servant my father, we told him the words of my lord.
</verse><verse>And our father said, Go again, <supplied>and</supplied> buy us a little food.
</verse><verse>And we said, We cannot go down: if our youngest brother be with us, then will we go down: for we may not see the man’s face, except our youngest brother <supplied>be</supplied> with us.
</verse><verse>And thy servant my father said unto us, Ye know that my wife bare me two <supplied>sons: </supplied></verse><verse>And the one went out from me, and I said, Surely he is torn in pieces; and I saw him not since:
</verse><verse>And if ye take this also from me, and mischief befall him, ye shall bring down my gray hairs with sorrow to the grave.
</verse><verse>Now therefore when I come to thy servant my father, and the lad <supplied>be</supplied> not with us; seeing that his life is bound up in the lad’s life;
</verse><verse>It shall come to pass, when he seeth that the lad <supplied>is</supplied> not <supplied>with us,</supplied> that he will die: and thy servants shall bring down the gray hairs of thy servant our father with sorrow to the grave.
</verse><verse>For thy servant became surety for the lad unto my father, saying, If I bring him not unto thee, then I shall bear the blame to my father for ever.
</verse><verse>Now therefore, I pray thee, let thy servant abide instead of the lad a bondman to my lord; and let the lad go up with his brethren.
</verse><verse>For how shall I go up to my father, and the lad <supplied>be</supplied> not with me? lest peradventure I see the evil that shall come on my father.
     
      </verse>
      </chapter>