<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Micah" book-id="33" n="2">
<verse>Woe to those who plan iniquity, to those who plot evil on their beds! At morning's light they carry it out because it is in their power to do it.</verse>
<verse>They covet fields and seize them, and houses, and take them. They defraud a man of his home, a fellowman of his inheritance.</verse>
<verse>Therefore, the LORD says: "I am planning disaster against this people, from which you cannot save yourselves. You will no longer walk proudly, for it will be a time of calamity.</verse>
<verse>In that day men will ridicule you; they will taunt you with this mournful song: 'We are utterly ruined; my people's possession is divided up. He takes it from me! He assigns our fields to traitors.'"</verse>
<verse>Therefore you will have no one in the assembly of the LORD to divide the land by lot.</verse>
<verse>"Do not prophesy," their prophets say. "Do not prophesy about these things; disgrace will not overtake us."</verse>
<verse>Should it be said, O house of Jacob: "Is the Spirit of the LORD angry? Does he do such things?Do not my words do good to him whose ways are upright?</verse>
<verse>Lately my people have risen up like an enemy. You strip off the rich robe from those who pass by without a care, like men returning from battle.</verse>
<verse>You drive the women of my people from their pleasant homes. You take away my blessing from their children forever.</verse>
<verse>Get up, go away! For this is not your resting place, because it is defiled, it is ruined, beyond all remedy.</verse>
<verse>If a liar and deceiver comes and says, 'I will prophesy for you plenty of wine and beer,' he would be just the prophet for this people!</verse>
<verse>"I will surely gather all of you, O Jacob; I will surely bring together the remnant of Israel. I will bring them together like sheep in a pen, like a flock in its pasture; the place will throng with people.</verse>
<verse>One who breaks open the way will go up before them; they will break through the gate and go out. Their king will pass through before them, the LORD at their head."</verse>
</chapter>