<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="1 Chronicles" book_id="13" n="18">
<verse>Now after this it came about that David defeated the Philistines and subdued them and took Gath and its towns from the hand of the Philistines.</verse>
<verse>He defeated Moab, and the Moabites became servants to David, bringing tribute.</verse>
<verse>David also defeated Hadadezer king of Zobah as far as Hamath, as he went to establish his rule to the Euphrates River.</verse>
<verse>David took from him 1,000 chariots and 7,000 horsemen and 20,000 foot soldiers, and David hamstrung all the chariot horses, but reserved enough of them for 100 chariots.</verse>
<verse>When the Arameans of Damascus came to help Hadadezer king of Zobah, David killed 22,000 men of the Arameans.</verse>
<verse>Then David put garrisons among the Arameans of Damascus; and the Arameans became servants to David, bringing tribute. And the LORD helped David wherever he went.</verse>
<verse>David took the shields of gold which were carried by the servants of Hadadezer and brought them to Jerusalem.</verse>
<verse>Also from Tibhath and from Cun, cities of Hadadezer, David took a very large amount of bronze, with which Solomon made the bronze sea and the pillars and the bronze utensils.</verse>
<verse>Now when Tou king of Hamath heard that David had defeated all the army of Hadadezer king of Zobah,</verse>
<verse>he sent Hadoram his son to King David to greet him and to bless him, because he had fought against Hadadezer and had defeated him; for Hadadezer had been at war with Tou. And Hadoram brought all kinds of articles of gold and silver and bronze.</verse>
<verse>King David also dedicated these to the LORD with the silver and the gold which he had carried away from all the nations: from Edom, Moab, the sons of Ammon, the Philistines, and from Amalek.</verse>
<verse>Moreover Abishai the son of Zeruiah defeated 18,000 Edomites in the Valley of Salt.</verse>
<verse>Then he put garrisons in Edom, and all the Edomites became servants to David. And the LORD helped David wherever he went.</verse>
<verse>So David reigned over all Israel; and he administered justice and righteousness for all his people.</verse>
<verse>Joab the son of Zeruiah was over the army, and Jehoshaphat the son of Ahilud was recorder;</verse>
<verse>and Zadok the son of Ahitub and Abimelech the son of Abiathar were priests, and Shavsha was secretary;</verse>
<verse>and Benaiah the son of Jehoiada was over the Cherethites and the Pelethites, and the sons of David were chiefs at the king's side.</verse>
</chapter>