<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="1 Chronicles" book_id="13" n="8">
<verse>And Benjamin became the father of Bela his firstborn, Ashbel the second, Aharah the third,</verse>
<verse>Nohah the fourth and Rapha the fifth.</verse>
<verse>Bela had sons: Addar, Gera, Abihud,</verse>
<verse>Abishua, Naaman, Ahoah,</verse>
<verse>Gera, Shephuphan and Huram.</verse>
<verse>These are the sons of Ehud: these are the heads of fathers' households of the inhabitants of Geba, and they carried them into exile to Manahath,</verse>
<verse>namely, Naaman, Ahijah and Gera--he carried them into exile; and he became the father of Uzza and Ahihud.</verse>
<verse>Shaharaim became the father of children in the country of Moab after he had sent away Hushim and Baara his wives.</verse>
<verse>By Hodesh his wife he became the father of Jobab, Zibia, Mesha, Malcam,</verse>
<verse>Jeuz, Sachia, Mirmah. These were his sons, heads of fathers' households.</verse>
<verse>By Hushim he became the father of Abitub and Elpaal.</verse>
<verse>The sons of Elpaal were Eber, Misham, and Shemed, who built Ono and Lod, with its towns;</verse>
<verse>and Beriah and Shema, who were heads of fathers' households of the inhabitants of Aijalon, who put to flight the inhabitants of Gath;</verse>
<verse>and Ahio, Shashak and Jeremoth.</verse>
<verse>Zebadiah, Arad, Eder,</verse>
<verse>Michael, Ishpah and Joha were the sons of Beriah.</verse>
<verse>Zebadiah, Meshullam, Hizki, Heber,</verse>
<verse>Ishmerai, Izliah and Jobab were the sons of Elpaal.</verse>
<verse>Jakim, Zichri, Zabdi,</verse>
<verse>Elienai, Zillethai, Eliel,</verse>
<verse>Adaiah, Beraiah and Shimrath were the sons of Shimei.</verse>
<verse>Ishpan, Eber, Eliel,</verse>
<verse>Abdon, Zichri, Hanan,</verse>
<verse>Hananiah, Elam, Anthothijah,</verse>
<verse>Iphdeiah and Penuel were the sons of Shashak.</verse>
<verse>Shamsherai, Shehariah, Athaliah,</verse>
<verse>Jaareshiah, Elijah and Zichri were the sons of Jeroham.</verse>
<verse>These were heads of the fathers' households according to their generations, chief men who lived in Jerusalem.</verse>
<verse>Now in Gibeon, Jeiel, the father of Gibeon lived, and his wife's name was Maacah;</verse>
<verse>and his firstborn son was Abdon, then Zur, Kish, Baal, Nadab,</verse>
<verse>Gedor, Ahio and Zecher.</verse>
<verse>Mikloth became the father of Shimeah. And they also lived with their relatives in Jerusalem opposite their other relatives.</verse>
<verse>Ner became the father of Kish, and Kish became the father of Saul, and Saul became the father of Jonathan, Malchi-shua, Abinadab and Eshbaal.</verse>
<verse>The son of Jonathan was Merib-baal, and Merib-baal became the father of Micah.</verse>
<verse>The sons of Micah were Pithon, Melech, Tarea and Ahaz.</verse>
<verse>Ahaz became the father of Jehoaddah, and Jehoaddah became the father of Alemeth, Azmaveth and Zimri; and Zimri became the father of Moza.</verse>
<verse>Moza became the father of Binea; Raphah was his son, Eleasah his son, Azel his son.</verse>
<verse>Azel had six sons, and these were their names: Azrikam, Bocheru, Ishmael, Sheariah, Obadiah and Hanan. All these were the sons of Azel.</verse>
<verse>The sons of Eshek his brother were Ulam his firstborn, Jeush the second and Eliphelet the third.</verse>
<verse>The sons of Ulam were mighty men of valor, archers, and had many sons and grandsons, 150 of them. All these were of the sons of Benjamin.</verse>
</chapter>