<chapter translation="NIV" testament="New" book="John" book-id="43" n="5">
<verse>Some time later, Jesus went up to Jerusalem for a feast of the Jews.</verse>
<verse>Now there is in Jerusalem near the Sheep Gate a pool, which in Aramaic is called Bethesda and which is surrounded by five covered colonnades.</verse>
<verse>Here a great number of disabled people used to lie--the blind, the lame, the paralyzed.</verse>
<verse>See Footnote</verse>
<verse>One who was there had been an invalid for thirty-eight years.</verse>
<verse>When Jesus saw him lying there and learned that he had been in this condition for a long time, he asked him, "Do you want to get well?"</verse>
<verse>"Sir," the invalid replied, "I have no one to help me into the pool when the water is stirred. While I am trying to get in, someone else goes down ahead of me."</verse>
<verse>Then Jesus said to him, "Get up! Pick up your mat and walk."</verse>
<verse>At once the man was cured; he picked up his mat and walked. The day on which this took place was a Sabbath,</verse>
<verse>and so the Jews said to the man who had been healed, "It is the Sabbath; the law forbids you to carry your mat."</verse>
<verse>But he replied, "The man who made me well said to me, 'Pick up your mat and walk.'"</verse>
<verse>So they asked him, "Who is this fellow who told you to pick it up and walk?"</verse>
<verse>The man who was healed had no idea who it was, for Jesus had slipped away into the crowd that was there.</verse>
<verse>Later Jesus found him at the temple and said to him, "See, you are well again. Stop sinning or something worse may happen to you."</verse>
<verse>The man went away and told the Jews that it was Jesus who had made him well.</verse>
<verse>So, because Jesus was doing these things on the Sabbath, the Jews persecuted him.</verse>
<verse>Jesus said to them, "My Father is always at his work to this very day, and I, too, am working."</verse>
<verse>For this reason the Jews tried all the harder to kill him; not only was he breaking the Sabbath, but he was even calling God his own Father, making himself equal with God.</verse>
<verse>Jesus gave them this answer: "I tell you the truth, the Son can do nothing by himself; he can do only what he sees his Father doing, because whatever the Father does the Son also does.</verse>
<verse>For the Father loves the Son and shows him all he does. Yes, to your amazement he will show him even greater things than these.</verse>
<verse>For just as the Father raises the dead and gives them life, even so the Son gives life to whom he is pleased to give it.</verse>
<verse>Moreover, the Father judges no one, but has entrusted all judgment to the Son,</verse>
<verse>that all may honor the Son just as they honor the Father. He who does not honor the Son does not honor the Father, who sent him.</verse>
<verse>"I tell you the truth, whoever hears my word and believes him who sent me has eternal life and will not be condemned; he has crossed over from death to life.</verse>
<verse>I tell you the truth, a time is coming and has now come when the dead will hear the voice of the Son of God and those who hear will live.</verse>
<verse>For as the Father has life in himself, so he has granted the Son to have life in himself.</verse>
<verse>And he has given him authority to judge because he is the Son of Man.</verse>
<verse>"Do not be amazed at this, for a time is coming when all who are in their graves will hear his voice</verse>
<verse>and come out--those who have done good will rise to live, and those who have done evil will rise to be condemned.</verse>
<verse>By myself I can do nothing; I judge only as I hear, and my judgment is just, for I seek not to please myself but him who sent me.</verse>
<verse>"If I testify about myself, my testimony is not valid.</verse>
<verse>There is another who testifies in my favor, and I know that his testimony about me is valid.</verse>
<verse>"You have sent to John and he has testified to the truth.</verse>
<verse>Not that I accept human testimony; but I mention it that you may be saved.</verse>
<verse>John was a lamp that burned and gave light, and you chose for a time to enjoy his light.</verse>
<verse>"I have testimony weightier than that of John. For the very work that the Father has given me to finish, and which I am doing, testifies that the Father has sent me.</verse>
<verse>And the Father who sent me has himself testified concerning me. You have never heard his voice nor seen his form,</verse>
<verse>nor does his word dwell in you, for you do not believe the one he sent.</verse>
<verse>You diligently study the Scriptures because you think that by them you possess eternal life. These are the Scriptures that testify about me,</verse>
<verse>yet you refuse to come to me to have life.</verse>
<verse>"I do not accept praise from men,</verse>
<verse>but I know you. I know that you do not have the love of God in your hearts.</verse>
<verse>I have come in my Father's name, and you do not accept me; but if someone else comes in his own name, you will accept him.</verse>
<verse>How can you believe if you accept praise from one another, yet make no effort to obtain the praise that comes from the only God?</verse>
<verse>"But do not think I will accuse you before the Father. Your accuser is Moses, on whom your hopes are set.</verse>
<verse>If you believed Moses, you would believe me, for he wrote about me.</verse>
<verse>But since you do not believe what he wrote, how are you going to believe what I say?"</verse>
</chapter>