<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Job" book_id="18" n="10">
<verse>"I loathe my very life; therefore I will give free rein to my complaint and speak out in the bitterness of my soul.</verse>
<verse>I will say to God: Do not condemn me, but tell me what charges you have against me.</verse>
<verse>Does it please you to oppress me, to spurn the work of your hands, while you smile on the schemes of the wicked?</verse>
<verse>Do you have eyes of flesh? Do you see as a mortal sees?</verse>
<verse>Are your days like those of a mortal or your years like those of a man,</verse>
<verse>that you must search out my faults and probe after my sin-</verse>
<verse>though you know that I am not guilty and that no one can rescue me from your hand?</verse>
<verse>"Your hands shaped me and made me. Will you now turn and destroy me?</verse>
<verse>Remember that you molded me like clay. Will you now turn me to dust again?</verse>
<verse>Did you not pour me out like milk and curdle me like cheese,</verse>
<verse>clothe me with skin and flesh and knit me together with bones and sinews?</verse>
<verse>You gave me life and showed me kindness, and in your providence watched over my spirit.</verse>
<verse>"But this is what you concealed in your heart, and I know that this was in your mind:</verse>
<verse>If I sinned, you would be watching me and would not let my offense go unpunished.</verse>
<verse>If I am guilty-woe to me! Even if I am innocent, I cannot lift my head, for I am full of shame and drowned in my affliction.</verse>
<verse>If I hold my head high, you stalk me like a lion and again display your awesome power against me.</verse>
<verse>You bring new witnesses against me and increase your anger toward me; your forces come against me wave upon wave.</verse>
<verse>"Why then did you bring me out of the womb? I wish I had died before any eye saw me.</verse>
<verse>If only I had never come into being, or had been carried straight from the womb to the grave!</verse>
<verse>Are not my few days almost over? Turn away from me so I can have a moment's joy</verse>
<verse>before I go to the place of no return, to the land of gloom and deep shadow,</verse>
<verse>to the land of deepest night, of deep shadow and disorder, where even the light is like darkness."</verse>
</chapter>