<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Job" book_id="18" n="11">
<verse>Then Zophar the Naamathite replied:</verse>
<verse>"Are all these words to go unanswered? Is this talker to be vindicated?</verse>
<verse>Will your idle talk reduce men to silence? Will no one rebuke you when you mock?</verse>
<verse>You say to God, 'My beliefs are flawless and I am pure in your sight.'</verse>
<verse>Oh, how I wish that God would speak, that he would open his lips against you</verse>
<verse>and disclose to you the secrets of wisdom, for true wisdom has two sides. Know this: God has even forgotten some of your sin.</verse>
<verse>"Can you fathom the mysteries of God? Can you probe the limits of the Almighty?</verse>
<verse>They are higher than the heavens-what can you do? They are deeper than the depths of the grave -what can you know?</verse>
<verse>Their measure is longer than the earth and wider than the sea.</verse>
<verse>"If he comes along and confines you in prison and convenes a court, who can oppose him?</verse>
<verse>Surely he recognizes deceitful men; and when he sees evil, does he not take note?</verse>
<verse>But a witless man can no more become wise than a wild donkey's colt can be born a man.</verse>
<verse>"Yet if you devote your heart to him and stretch out your hands to him,</verse>
<verse>if you put away the sin that is in your hand and allow no evil to dwell in your tent,</verse>
<verse>then you will lift up your face without shame; you will stand firm and without fear.</verse>
<verse>You will surely forget your trouble, recalling it only as waters gone by.</verse>
<verse>Life will be brighter than noonday, and darkness will become like morning.</verse>
<verse>You will be secure, because there is hope; you will look about you and take your rest in safety.</verse>
<verse>You will lie down, with no one to make you afraid, and many will court your favor.</verse>
<verse>But the eyes of the wicked will fail, and escape will elude them; their hope will become a dying gasp."</verse>
</chapter>