<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Job" book-id="18" n="13">
<verse>"My eyes have seen all this, my ears have heard and understood it.</verse>
<verse>What you know, I also know; I am not inferior to you.</verse>
<verse>But I desire to speak to the Almighty and to argue my case with God.</verse>
<verse>You, however, smear me with lies; you are worthless physicians, all of you!</verse>
<verse>If only you would be altogether silent! For you, that would be wisdom.</verse>
<verse>Hear now my argument; listen to the plea of my lips.</verse>
<verse>Will you speak wickedly on God's behalf? Will you speak deceitfully for him?</verse>
<verse>Will you show him partiality? Will you argue the case for God?</verse>
<verse>Would it turn out well if he examined you? Could you deceive him as you might deceive men?</verse>
<verse>He would surely rebuke you if you secretly showed partiality.</verse>
<verse>Would not his splendor terrify you? Would not the dread of him fall on you?</verse>
<verse>Your maxims are proverbs of ashes; your defenses are defenses of clay.</verse>
<verse>"Keep silent and let me speak; then let come to me what may.</verse>
<verse>Why do I put myself in jeopardy and take my life in my hands?</verse>
<verse>Though he slay me, yet will I hope in him; I will surely defend my ways to his face.</verse>
<verse>Indeed, this will turn out for my deliverance, for no godless man would dare come before him!</verse>
<verse>Listen carefully to my words; let your ears take in what I say.</verse>
<verse>Now that I have prepared my case, I know I will be vindicated.</verse>
<verse>Can anyone bring charges against me? If so, I will be silent and die.</verse>
<verse>"Only grant me these two things, O God, and then I will not hide from you:</verse>
<verse>Withdraw your hand far from me, and stop frightening me with your terrors.</verse>
<verse>Then summon me and I will answer, or let me speak, and you reply.</verse>
<verse>How many wrongs and sins have I committed? Show me my offense and my sin.</verse>
<verse>Why do you hide your face and consider me your enemy?</verse>
<verse>Will you torment a windblown leaf? Will you chase after dry chaff?</verse>
<verse>For you write down bitter things against me and make me inherit the sins of my youth.</verse>
<verse>You fasten my feet in shackles; you keep close watch on all my paths by putting marks on the soles of my feet.</verse>
<verse>"So man wastes away like something rotten, like a garment eaten by moths.</verse>
</chapter>