<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Job" book-id="18" n="14">
<verse>"Man born of woman is of few days and full of trouble.</verse>
<verse>He springs up like a flower and withers away; like a fleeting shadow, he does not endure.</verse>
<verse>Do you fix your eye on such a one? Will you bring him before you for judgment?</verse>
<verse>Who can bring what is pure from the impure? No one!</verse>
<verse>Man's days are determined; you have decreed the number of his months and have set limits he cannot exceed.</verse>
<verse>So look away from him and let him alone, till he has put in his time like a hired man.</verse>
<verse>"At least there is hope for a tree: If it is cut down, it will sprout again, and its new shoots will not fail.</verse>
<verse>Its roots may grow old in the ground and its stump die in the soil,</verse>
<verse>yet at the scent of water it will bud and put forth shoots like a plant.</verse>
<verse>But man dies and is laid low; he breathes his last and is no more.</verse>
<verse>As water disappears from the sea or a riverbed becomes parched and dry,</verse>
<verse>so man lies down and does not rise; till the heavens are no more, men will not awake or be roused from their sleep.</verse>
<verse>"If only you would hide me in the grave and conceal me till your anger has passed! If only you would set me a time and then remember me!</verse>
<verse>If a man dies, will he live again? All the days of my hard service I will wait for my renewal to come.</verse>
<verse>You will call and I will answer you; you will long for the creature your hands have made.</verse>
<verse>Surely then you will count my steps but not keep track of my sin.</verse>
<verse>My offenses will be sealed up in a bag; you will cover over my sin.</verse>
<verse>"But as a mountain erodes and crumbles and as a rock is moved from its place,</verse>
<verse>as water wears away stones and torrents wash away the soil, so you destroy man's hope.</verse>
<verse>You overpower him once for all, and he is gone; you change his countenance and send him away.</verse>
<verse>If his sons are honored, he does not know it; if they are brought low, he does not see it.</verse>
<verse>He feels but the pain of his own body and mourns only for himself."</verse>
</chapter>