<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Job" book_id="18" n="16">
<verse>Then Job replied:</verse>
<verse>"I have heard many things like these; miserable comforters are you all!</verse>
<verse>Will your long-winded speeches never end? What ails you that you keep on arguing?</verse>
<verse>I also could speak like you, if you were in my place; I could make fine speeches against you and shake my head at you.</verse>
<verse>But my mouth would encourage you; comfort from my lips would bring you relief.</verse>
<verse>"Yet if I speak, my pain is not relieved; and if I refrain, it does not go away.</verse>
<verse>Surely, O God, you have worn me out; you have devastated my entire household.</verse>
<verse>You have bound me-and it has become a witness; my gauntness rises up and testifies against me.</verse>
<verse>God assails me and tears me in his anger and gnashes his teeth at me; my opponent fastens on me his piercing eyes.</verse>
<verse>Men open their mouths to jeer at me; they strike my cheek in scorn and unite together against me.</verse>
<verse>God has turned me over to evil men and thrown me into the clutches of the wicked.</verse>
<verse>All was well with me, but he shattered me; he seized me by the neck and crushed me. He has made me his target;</verse>
<verse>his archers surround me. Without pity, he pierces my kidneys and spills my gall on the ground.</verse>
<verse>Again and again he bursts upon me; he rushes at me like a warrior.</verse>
<verse>"I have sewed sackcloth over my skin and buried my brow in the dust.</verse>
<verse>My face is red with weeping, deep shadows ring my eyes;</verse>
<verse>yet my hands have been free of violence and my prayer is pure.</verse>
<verse>"O earth, do not cover my blood; may my cry never be laid to rest!</verse>
<verse>Even now my witness is in heaven; my advocate is on high.</verse>
<verse>My intercessor is my friend as my eyes pour out tears to God;</verse>
<verse>on behalf of a man he pleads with God as a man pleads for his friend.</verse>
<verse>"Only a few years will pass before I go on the journey of no return.</verse>
</chapter>