<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Job" book-id="18" n="19">
<verse>Then Job replied:</verse>
<verse>"How long will you torment me and crush me with words?</verse>
<verse>Ten times now you have reproached me; shamelessly you attack me.</verse>
<verse>If it is true that I have gone astray, my error remains my concern alone.</verse>
<verse>If indeed you would exalt yourselves above me and use my humiliation against me,</verse>
<verse>then know that God has wronged me and drawn his net around me.</verse>
<verse>"Though I cry, 'I've been wronged!' I get no response; though I call for help, there is no justice.</verse>
<verse>He has blocked my way so I cannot pass; he has shrouded my paths in darkness.</verse>
<verse>He has stripped me of my honor and removed the crown from my head.</verse>
<verse>He tears me down on every side till I am gone; he uproots my hope like a tree.</verse>
<verse>His anger burns against me; he counts me among his enemies.</verse>
<verse>His troops advance in force; they build a siege ramp against me and encamp around my tent.</verse>
<verse>"He has alienated my brothers from me; my acquaintances are completely estranged from me.</verse>
<verse>My kinsmen have gone away; my friends have forgotten me.</verse>
<verse>My guests and my maidservants count me a stranger; they look upon me as an alien.</verse>
<verse>I summon my servant, but he does not answer, though I beg him with my own mouth.</verse>
<verse>My breath is offensive to my wife; I am loathsome to my own brothers.</verse>
<verse>Even the little boys scorn me; when I appear, they ridicule me.</verse>
<verse>All my intimate friends detest me; those I love have turned against me.</verse>
<verse>I am nothing but skin and bones; I have escaped with only the skin of my teeth.</verse>
<verse>"Have pity on me, my friends, have pity, for the hand of God has struck me.</verse>
<verse>Why do you pursue me as God does? Will you never get enough of my flesh?</verse>
<verse>"Oh, that my words were recorded, that they were written on a scroll,</verse>
<verse>that they were inscribed with an iron tool on lead, or engraved in rock forever!</verse>
<verse>I know that my Redeemer lives, and that in the end he will stand upon the earth.</verse>
<verse>And after my skin has been destroyed, yet in my flesh I will see God;</verse>
<verse>I myself will see him with my own eyes-I, and not another. How my heart yearns within me!</verse>
<verse>"If you say, 'How we will hound him, since the root of the trouble lies in him, '</verse>
<verse>you should fear the sword yourselves; for wrath will bring punishment by the sword, and then you will know that there is judgment. "</verse>
</chapter>