<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Job" book-id="18" n="21">
<verse>Then Job replied:</verse>
<verse>"Listen carefully to my words; let this be the consolation you give me.</verse>
<verse>Bear with me while I speak, and after I have spoken, mock on.</verse>
<verse>"Is my complaint directed to man? Why should I not be impatient?</verse>
<verse>Look at me and be astonished; clap your hand over your mouth.</verse>
<verse>When I think about this, I am terrified; trembling seizes my body.</verse>
<verse>Why do the wicked live on, growing old and increasing in power?</verse>
<verse>They see their children established around them, their offspring before their eyes.</verse>
<verse>Their homes are safe and free from fear; the rod of God is not upon them.</verse>
<verse>Their bulls never fail to breed; their cows calve and do not miscarry.</verse>
<verse>They send forth their children as a flock; their little ones dance about.</verse>
<verse>They sing to the music of tambourine and harp; they make merry to the sound of the flute.</verse>
<verse>They spend their years in prosperity and go down to the grave in peace.</verse>
<verse>Yet they say to God, 'Leave us alone! We have no desire to know your ways.</verse>
<verse>Who is the Almighty, that we should serve him? What would we gain by praying to him?'</verse>
<verse>But their prosperity is not in their own hands, so I stand aloof from the counsel of the wicked.</verse>
<verse>"Yet how often is the lamp of the wicked snuffed out? How often does calamity come upon them, the fate God allots in his anger?</verse>
<verse>How often are they like straw before the wind, like chaff swept away by a gale?</verse>
<verse>It is said, 'God stores up a man's punishment for his sons.' Let him repay the man himself, so that he will know it!</verse>
<verse>Let his own eyes see his destruction; let him drink of the wrath of the Almighty.</verse>
<verse>For what does he care about the family he leaves behind when his allotted months come to an end?</verse>
<verse>"Can anyone teach knowledge to God, since he judges even the highest?</verse>
<verse>One man dies in full vigor, completely secure and at ease,</verse>
<verse>his body well nourished, his bones rich with marrow.</verse>
<verse>Another man dies in bitterness of soul, never having enjoyed anything good.</verse>
<verse>Side by side they lie in the dust, and worms cover them both.</verse>
<verse>"I know full well what you are thinking, the schemes by which you would wrong me.</verse>
<verse>You say, 'Where now is the great man's house, the tents where wicked men lived?'</verse>
<verse>Have you never questioned those who travel? Have you paid no regard to their accounts-</verse>
<verse>that the evil man is spared from the day of calamity, that he is delivered from the day of wrath?</verse>
<verse>Who denounces his conduct to his face? Who repays him for what he has done?</verse>
<verse>He is carried to the grave, and watch is kept over his tomb.</verse>
<verse>The soil in the valley is sweet to him; all men follow after him, and a countless throng goes before him.</verse>
<verse>"So how can you console me with your nonsense? Nothing is left of your answers but falsehood!"</verse>
</chapter>