<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Job" book_id="18" n="22">
<verse>Then Eliphaz the Temanite replied:</verse>
<verse>"Can a man be of benefit to God? Can even a wise man benefit him?</verse>
<verse>What pleasure would it give the Almighty if you were righteous? What would he gain if your ways were blameless?</verse>
<verse>"Is it for your piety that he rebukes you and brings charges against you?</verse>
<verse>Is not your wickedness great? Are not your sins endless?</verse>
<verse>You demanded security from your brothers for no reason; you stripped men of their clothing, leaving them naked.</verse>
<verse>You gave no water to the weary and you withheld food from the hungry,</verse>
<verse>though you were a powerful man, owning land- an honored man, living on it.</verse>
<verse>And you sent widows away empty-handed and broke the strength of the fatherless.</verse>
<verse>That is why snares are all around you, why sudden peril terrifies you,</verse>
<verse>why it is so dark you cannot see, and why a flood of water covers you.</verse>
<verse>"Is not God in the heights of heaven? And see how lofty are the highest stars!</verse>
<verse>Yet you say, 'What does God know? Does he judge through such darkness?</verse>
<verse>Thick clouds veil him, so he does not see us as he goes about in the vaulted heavens.'</verse>
<verse>Will you keep to the old path that evil men have trod?</verse>
<verse>They were carried off before their time, their foundations washed away by a flood.</verse>
<verse>They said to God, 'Leave us alone! What can the Almighty do to us?'</verse>
<verse>Yet it was he who filled their houses with good things, so I stand aloof from the counsel of the wicked.</verse>
<verse>"The righteous see their ruin and rejoice; the innocent mock them, saying,</verse>
<verse>'Surely our foes are destroyed, and fire devours their wealth.'</verse>
<verse>"Submit to God and be at peace with him; in this way prosperity will come to you.</verse>
<verse>Accept instruction from his mouth and lay up his words in your heart.</verse>
<verse>If you return to the Almighty, you will be restored: If you remove wickedness far from your tent</verse>
<verse>and assign your nuggets to the dust, your gold of Ophir to the rocks in the ravines,</verse>
<verse>then the Almighty will be your gold, the choicest silver for you.</verse>
<verse>Surely then you will find delight in the Almighty and will lift up your face to God.</verse>
<verse>You will pray to him, and he will hear you, and you will fulfill your vows.</verse>
<verse>What you decide on will be done, and light will shine on your ways.</verse>
<verse>When men are brought low and you say, 'Lift them up!' then he will save the downcast.</verse>
<verse>He will deliver even one who is not innocent, who will be delivered through the cleanness of your hands."</verse>
</chapter>