<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Job" book_id="18" n="24">
<verse>"Why does the Almighty not set times for judgment? Why must those who know him look in vain for such days?</verse>
<verse>Men move boundary stones; they pasture flocks they have stolen.</verse>
<verse>They drive away the orphan's donkey and take the widow's ox in pledge.</verse>
<verse>They thrust the needy from the path and force all the poor of the land into hiding.</verse>
<verse>Like wild donkeys in the desert, the poor go about their labor of foraging food; the wasteland provides food for their children.</verse>
<verse>They gather fodder in the fields and glean in the vineyards of the wicked.</verse>
<verse>Lacking clothes, they spend the night naked; they have nothing to cover themselves in the cold.</verse>
<verse>They are drenched by mountain rains and hug the rocks for lack of shelter.</verse>
<verse>The fatherless child is snatched from the breast; the infant of the poor is seized for a debt.</verse>
<verse>Lacking clothes, they go about naked; they carry the sheaves, but still go hungry.</verse>
<verse>They crush olives among the terraces; they tread the winepresses, yet suffer thirst.</verse>
<verse>The groans of the dying rise from the city, and the souls of the wounded cry out for help. But God charges no one with wrongdoing.</verse>
<verse>"There are those who rebel against the light, who do not know its ways or stay in its paths.</verse>
<verse>When daylight is gone, the murderer rises up and kills the poor and needy; in the night he steals forth like a thief.</verse>
<verse>The eye of the adulterer watches for dusk; he thinks, 'No eye will see me,' and he keeps his face concealed.</verse>
<verse>In the dark, men break into houses, but by day they shut themselves in; they want nothing to do with the light.</verse>
<verse>For all of them, deep darkness is their morning; they make friends with the terrors of darkness.</verse>
<verse>"Yet they are foam on the surface of the water; their portion of the land is cursed, so that no one goes to the vineyards.</verse>
<verse>As heat and drought snatch away the melted snow, so the grave snatches away those who have sinned.</verse>
<verse>The womb forgets them, the worm feasts on them; evil men are no longer remembered but are broken like a tree.</verse>
<verse>They prey on the barren and childless woman, and to the widow show no kindness.</verse>
<verse>But God drags away the mighty by his power; though they become established, they have no assurance of life.</verse>
<verse>He may let them rest in a feeling of security, but his eyes are on their ways.</verse>
<verse>For a little while they are exalted, and then they are gone; they are brought low and gathered up like all others; they are cut off like heads of grain.</verse>
<verse>"If this is not so, who can prove me false and reduce my words to nothing?"</verse>
</chapter>