<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Job" book_id="18" n="27">
<verse>And Job continued his discourse:</verse>
<verse>"As surely as God lives, who has denied me justice, the Almighty, who has made me taste bitterness of soul,</verse>
<verse>as long as I have life within me, the breath of God in my nostrils,</verse>
<verse>my lips will not speak wickedness, and my tongue will utter no deceit.</verse>
<verse>I will never admit you are in the right; till I die, I will not deny my integrity.</verse>
<verse>I will maintain my righteousness and never let go of it; my conscience will not reproach me as long as I live.</verse>
<verse>"May my enemies be like the wicked, my adversaries like the unjust!</verse>
<verse>For what hope has the godless when he is cut off, when God takes away his life?</verse>
<verse>Does God listen to his cry when distress comes upon him?</verse>
<verse>Will he find delight in the Almighty? Will he call upon God at all times?</verse>
<verse>"I will teach you about the power of God; the ways of the Almighty I will not conceal.</verse>
<verse>You have all seen this yourselves. Why then this meaningless talk?</verse>
<verse>"Here is the fate God allots to the wicked, the heritage a ruthless man receives from the Almighty:</verse>
<verse>However many his children, their fate is the sword; his offspring will never have enough to eat.</verse>
<verse>The plague will bury those who survive him, and their widows will not weep for them.</verse>
<verse>Though he heaps up silver like dust and clothes like piles of clay,</verse>
<verse>what he lays up the righteous will wear, and the innocent will divide his silver.</verse>
<verse>The house he builds is like a moth's cocoon, like a hut made by a watchman.</verse>
<verse>He lies down wealthy, but will do so no more; when he opens his eyes, all is gone.</verse>
<verse>Terrors overtake him like a flood; a tempest snatches him away in the night.</verse>
<verse>The east wind carries him off, and he is gone; it sweeps him out of his place.</verse>
<verse>It hurls itself against him without mercy as he flees headlong from its power.</verse>
<verse>It claps its hands in derision and hisses him out of his place.</verse>
</chapter>