<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Job" book_id="18" n="28">
<verse>"There is a mine for silver and a place where gold is refined.</verse>
<verse>Iron is taken from the earth, and copper is smelted from ore.</verse>
<verse>Man puts an end to the darkness; he searches the farthest recesses for ore in the blackest darkness.</verse>
<verse>Far from where people dwell he cuts a shaft, in places forgotten by the foot of man; far from men he dangles and sways.</verse>
<verse>The earth, from which food comes, is transformed below as by fire;</verse>
<verse>sapphires come from its rocks, and its dust contains nuggets of gold.</verse>
<verse>No bird of prey knows that hidden path, no falcon's eye has seen it.</verse>
<verse>Proud beasts do not set foot on it, and no lion prowls there.</verse>
<verse>Man's hand assaults the flinty rock and lays bare the roots of the mountains.</verse>
<verse>He tunnels through the rock; his eyes see all its treasures.</verse>
<verse>He searches the sources of the rivers and brings hidden things to light.</verse>
<verse>"But where can wisdom be found? Where does understanding dwell?</verse>
<verse>Man does not comprehend its worth; it cannot be found in the land of the living.</verse>
<verse>The deep says, 'It is not in me'; the sea says, 'It is not with me.'</verse>
<verse>It cannot be bought with the finest gold, nor can its price be weighed in silver.</verse>
<verse>It cannot be bought with the gold of Ophir, with precious onyx or sapphires.</verse>
<verse>Neither gold nor crystal can compare with it, nor can it be had for jewels of gold.</verse>
<verse>Coral and jasper are not worthy of mention; the price of wisdom is beyond rubies.</verse>
<verse>The topaz of Cush cannot compare with it; it cannot be bought with pure gold.</verse>
<verse>"Where then does wisdom come from? Where does understanding dwell?</verse>
<verse>It is hidden from the eyes of every living thing, concealed even from the birds of the air.</verse>
<verse>Destruction and Death say, 'Only a rumor of it has reached our ears.'</verse>
<verse>God understands the way to it and he alone knows where it dwells,</verse>
<verse>for he views the ends of the earth and sees everything under the heavens.</verse>
<verse>When he established the force of the wind and measured out the waters,</verse>
<verse>when he made a decree for the rain and a path for the thunderstorm,</verse>
<verse>then he looked at wisdom and appraised it; he confirmed it and tested it.</verse>
<verse>And he said to man, 'The fear of the Lord-that is wisdom, and to shun evil is understanding.'"</verse>
</chapter>