<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Job" book-id="18" n="29">
<verse>Job continued his discourse:</verse>
<verse>"How I long for the months gone by, for the days when God watched over me,</verse>
<verse>when his lamp shone upon my head and by his light I walked through darkness!</verse>
<verse>Oh, for the days when I was in my prime, when God's intimate friendship blessed my house,</verse>
<verse>when the Almighty was still with me and my children were around me,</verse>
<verse>when my path was drenched with cream and the rock poured out for me streams of olive oil.</verse>
<verse>"When I went to the gate of the city and took my seat in the public square,</verse>
<verse>the young men saw me and stepped aside and the old men rose to their feet;</verse>
<verse>the chief men refrained from speaking and covered their mouths with their hands;</verse>
<verse>the voices of the nobles were hushed, and their tongues stuck to the roof of their mouths.</verse>
<verse>Whoever heard me spoke well of me, and those who saw me commended me,</verse>
<verse>because I rescued the poor who cried for help, and the fatherless who had none to assist him.</verse>
<verse>The man who was dying blessed me; I made the widow's heart sing.</verse>
<verse>I put on righteousness as my clothing; justice was my robe and my turban.</verse>
<verse>I was eyes to the blind and feet to the lame.</verse>
<verse>I was a father to the needy; I took up the case of the stranger.</verse>
<verse>I broke the fangs of the wicked and snatched the victims from their teeth.</verse>
<verse>"I thought, 'I will die in my own house, my days as numerous as the grains of sand.</verse>
<verse>My roots will reach to the water, and the dew will lie all night on my branches.</verse>
<verse>My glory will remain fresh in me, the bow ever new in my hand.'</verse>
<verse>"Men listened to me expectantly, waiting in silence for my counsel.</verse>
<verse>After I had spoken, they spoke no more; my words fell gently on their ears.</verse>
<verse>They waited for me as for showers and drank in my words as the spring rain.</verse>
<verse>When I smiled at them, they scarcely believed it; the light of my face was precious to them.</verse>
<verse>I chose the way for them and sat as their chief; I dwelt as a king among his troops; I was like one who comforts mourners.</verse>
</chapter>