<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Job" book-id="18" n="3">
<verse>After this, Job opened his mouth and cursed the day of his birth.</verse>
<verse>He said:</verse>
<verse>"May the day of my birth perish, and the night it was said, 'A boy is born!'</verse>
<verse>That day-may it turn to darkness; may God above not care about it; may no light shine upon it.</verse>
<verse>May darkness and deep shadow claim it once more; may a cloud settle over it; may blackness overwhelm its light.</verse>
<verse>That night-may thick darkness seize it; may it not be included among the days of the year nor be entered in any of the months.</verse>
<verse>May that night be barren; may no shout of joy be heard in it.</verse>
<verse>May those who curse days curse that day, those who are ready to rouse Leviathan.</verse>
<verse>May its morning stars become dark; may it wait for daylight in vain and not see the first rays of dawn,</verse>
<verse>for it did not shut the doors of the womb on me to hide trouble from my eyes.</verse>
<verse>"Why did I not perish at birth, and die as I came from the womb?</verse>
<verse>Why were there knees to receive me and breasts that I might be nursed?</verse>
<verse>For now I would be lying down in peace; I would be asleep and at rest</verse>
<verse>with kings and counselors of the earth, who built for themselves places now lying in ruins,</verse>
<verse>with rulers who had gold, who filled their houses with silver.</verse>
<verse>Or why was I not hidden in the ground like a stillborn child, like an infant who never saw the light of day?</verse>
<verse>There the wicked cease from turmoil, and there the weary are at rest.</verse>
<verse>Captives also enjoy their ease; they no longer hear the slave driver's shout.</verse>
<verse>The small and the great are there, and the slave is freed from his master.</verse>
<verse>"Why is light given to those in misery, and life to the bitter of soul,</verse>
<verse>to those who long for death that does not come, who search for it more than for hidden treasure,</verse>
<verse>who are filled with gladness and rejoice when they reach the grave?</verse>
<verse>Why is life given to a man whose way is hidden, whom God has hedged in?</verse>
<verse>For sighing comes to me instead of food; my groans pour out like water.</verse>
<verse>What I feared has come upon me; what I dreaded has happened to me.</verse>
<verse>I have no peace, no quietness; I have no rest, but only turmoil."</verse>
</chapter>