<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Job" book_id="18" n="30">
<verse>"But now they mock me, men younger than I, whose fathers I would have disdained to put with my sheep dogs.</verse>
<verse>Of what use was the strength of their hands to me, since their vigor had gone from them?</verse>
<verse>Haggard from want and hunger, they roamed the parched land in desolate wastelands at night.</verse>
<verse>In the brush they gathered salt herbs, and their food was the root of the broom tree.</verse>
<verse>They were banished from their fellow men, shouted at as if they were thieves.</verse>
<verse>They were forced to live in the dry stream beds, among the rocks and in holes in the ground.</verse>
<verse>They brayed among the bushes and huddled in the undergrowth.</verse>
<verse>A base and nameless brood, they were driven out of the land.</verse>
<verse>"And now their sons mock me in song; I have become a byword among them.</verse>
<verse>They detest me and keep their distance; they do not hesitate to spit in my face.</verse>
<verse>Now that God has unstrung my bow and afflicted me, they throw off restraint in my presence.</verse>
<verse>On my right the tribe attacks; they lay snares for my feet, they build their siege ramps against me.</verse>
<verse>They break up my road; they succeed in destroying me- without anyone's helping them.</verse>
<verse>They advance as through a gaping breach; amid the ruins they come rolling in.</verse>
<verse>Terrors overwhelm me; my dignity is driven away as by the wind, my safety vanishes like a cloud.</verse>
<verse>"And now my life ebbs away; days of suffering grip me.</verse>
<verse>Night pierces my bones; my gnawing pains never rest.</verse>
<verse>In his great power God becomes like clothing to me; he binds me like the neck of my garment.</verse>
<verse>He throws me into the mud, and I am reduced to dust and ashes.</verse>
<verse>"I cry out to you, O God, but you do not answer; I stand up, but you merely look at me.</verse>
<verse>You turn on me ruthlessly; with the might of your hand you attack me.</verse>
<verse>You snatch me up and drive me before the wind; you toss me about in the storm.</verse>
<verse>I know you will bring me down to death, to the place appointed for all the living.</verse>
<verse>"Surely no one lays a hand on a broken man when he cries for help in his distress.</verse>
<verse>Have I not wept for those in trouble? Has not my soul grieved for the poor?</verse>
<verse>Yet when I hoped for good, evil came; when I looked for light, then came darkness.</verse>
<verse>The churning inside me never stops; days of suffering confront me.</verse>
<verse>I go about blackened, but not by the sun; I stand up in the assembly and cry for help.</verse>
<verse>I have become a brother of jackals, a companion of owls.</verse>
<verse>My skin grows black and peels; my body burns with fever.</verse>
<verse>My harp is tuned to mourning, and my flute to the sound of wailing.</verse>
</chapter>