<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Job" book_id="18" n="31">
<verse>"I made a covenant with my eyes not to look lustfully at a girl.</verse>
<verse>For what is man's lot from God above, his heritage from the Almighty on high?</verse>
<verse>Is it not ruin for the wicked, disaster for those who do wrong?</verse>
<verse>Does he not see my ways and count my every step?</verse>
<verse>"If I have walked in falsehood or my foot has hurried after deceit-</verse>
<verse>let God weigh me in honest scales and he will know that I am blameless-</verse>
<verse>if my steps have turned from the path, if my heart has been led by my eyes, or if my hands have been defiled,</verse>
<verse>then may others eat what I have sown, and may my crops be uprooted.</verse>
<verse>"If my heart has been enticed by a woman, or if I have lurked at my neighbor's door,</verse>
<verse>then may my wife grind another man's grain, and may other men sleep with her.</verse>
<verse>For that would have been shameful, a sin to be judged.</verse>
<verse>It is a fire that burns to Destruction; it would have uprooted my harvest.</verse>
<verse>"If I have denied justice to my menservants and maidservants when they had a grievance against me,</verse>
<verse>what will I do when God confronts me? What will I answer when called to account?</verse>
<verse>Did not he who made me in the womb make them? Did not the same one form us both within our mothers?</verse>
<verse>"If I have denied the desires of the poor or let the eyes of the widow grow weary,</verse>
<verse>if I have kept my bread to myself, not sharing it with the fatherless-</verse>
<verse>but from my youth I reared him as would a father, and from my birth I guided the widow-</verse>
<verse>if I have seen anyone perishing for lack of clothing, or a needy man without a garment,</verse>
<verse>and his heart did not bless me for warming him with the fleece from my sheep,</verse>
<verse>if I have raised my hand against the fatherless, knowing that I had influence in court,</verse>
<verse>then let my arm fall from the shoulder, let it be broken off at the joint.</verse>
<verse>For I dreaded destruction from God, and for fear of his splendor I could not do such things.</verse>
<verse>"If I have put my trust in gold or said to pure gold, 'You are my security,'</verse>
<verse>if I have rejoiced over my great wealth, the fortune my hands had gained,</verse>
<verse>if I have regarded the sun in its radiance or the moon moving in splendor,</verse>
<verse>so that my heart was secretly enticed and my hand offered them a kiss of homage,</verse>
<verse>then these also would be sins to be judged, for I would have been unfaithful to God on high.</verse>
<verse>"If I have rejoiced at my enemy's misfortune or gloated over the trouble that came to him-</verse>
<verse>I have not allowed my mouth to sin by invoking a curse against his life-</verse>
<verse>if the men of my household have never said, 'Who has not had his fill of Job's meat?'-</verse>
<verse>but no stranger had to spend the night in the street, for my door was always open to the traveler-</verse>
<verse>if I have concealed my sin as men do, by hiding my guilt in my heart</verse>
<verse>because I so feared the crowd and so dreaded the contempt of the clans that I kept silent and would not go outside</verse>
<verse>("Oh, that I had someone to hear me! I sign now my defense-let the Almighty answer me; let my accuser put his indictment in writing.</verse>
<verse>Surely I would wear it on my shoulder, I would put it on like a crown.</verse>
<verse>I would give him an account of my every step; like a prince I would approach him.)-</verse>
<verse>"if my land cries out against me and all its furrows are wet with tears,</verse>
<verse>if I have devoured its yield without payment or broken the spirit of its tenants,</verse>
<verse>then let briers come up instead of wheat and weeds instead of barley." The words of Job are ended.</verse>
</chapter>