<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Job" book-id="18" n="32">
<verse>So these three men stopped answering Job, because he was righteous in his own eyes.</verse>
<verse>But Elihu son of Barakel the Buzite, of the family of Ram, became very angry with Job for justifying himself rather than God.</verse>
<verse>He was also angry with the three friends, because they had found no way to refute Job, and yet had condemned him.</verse>
<verse>Now Elihu had waited before speaking to Job because they were older than he.</verse>
<verse>But when he saw that the three men had nothing more to say, his anger was aroused.</verse>
<verse>So Elihu son of Barakel the Buzite said: "I am young in years, and you are old; that is why I was fearful, not daring to tell you what I know.</verse>
<verse>I thought, 'Age should speak; advanced years should teach wisdom.'</verse>
<verse>But it is the spirit in a man, the breath of the Almighty, that gives him understanding.</verse>
<verse>It is not only the old who are wise, not only the aged who understand what is right.</verse>
<verse>"Therefore I say: Listen to me; I too will tell you what I know.</verse>
<verse>I waited while you spoke, I listened to your reasoning; while you were searching for words,</verse>
<verse>I gave you my full attention. But not one of you has proved Job wrong; none of you has answered his arguments.</verse>
<verse>Do not say, 'We have found wisdom; let God refute him, not man.'</verse>
<verse>But Job has not marshaled his words against me, and I will not answer him with your arguments.</verse>
<verse>"They are dismayed and have no more to say; words have failed them.</verse>
<verse>Must I wait, now that they are silent, now that they stand there with no reply?</verse>
<verse>I too will have my say; I too will tell what I know.</verse>
<verse>For I am full of words, and the spirit within me compels me;</verse>
<verse>inside I am like bottled-up wine, like new wineskins ready to burst.</verse>
<verse>I must speak and find relief; I must open my lips and reply.</verse>
<verse>I will show partiality to no one, nor will I flatter any man;</verse>
<verse>for if I were skilled in flattery, my Maker would soon take me away.</verse>
</chapter>