<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Job" book-id="18" n="33">
<verse>"But now, Job, listen to my words; pay attention to everything I say.</verse>
<verse>I am about to open my mouth; my words are on the tip of my tongue.</verse>
<verse>My words come from an upright heart; my lips sincerely speak what I know.</verse>
<verse>The Spirit of God has made me; the breath of the Almighty gives me life.</verse>
<verse>Answer me then, if you can; prepare yourself and confront me.</verse>
<verse>I am just like you before God; I too have been taken from clay.</verse>
<verse>No fear of me should alarm you, nor should my hand be heavy upon you.</verse>
<verse>"But you have said in my hearing- I heard the very words-</verse>
<verse>'I am pure and without sin; I am clean and free from guilt.</verse>
<verse>Yet God has found fault with me; he considers me his enemy.</verse>
<verse>He fastens my feet in shackles; he keeps close watch on all my paths.'</verse>
<verse>"But I tell you, in this you are not right, for God is greater than man.</verse>
<verse>Why do you complain to him that he answers none of man's words?</verse>
<verse>For God does speak-now one way, now another- though man may not perceive it.</verse>
<verse>In a dream, in a vision of the night, when deep sleep falls on men as they slumber in their beds,</verse>
<verse>he may speak in their ears and terrify them with warnings,</verse>
<verse>to turn man from wrongdoing and keep him from pride,</verse>
<verse>to preserve his soul from the pit, his life from perishing by the sword.</verse>
<verse>Or a man may be chastened on a bed of pain with constant distress in his bones,</verse>
<verse>so that his very being finds food repulsive and his soul loathes the choicest meal.</verse>
<verse>His flesh wastes away to nothing, and his bones, once hidden, now stick out.</verse>
<verse>His soul draws near to the pit, and his life to the messengers of death.</verse>
<verse>"Yet if there is an angel on his side as a mediator, one out of a thousand, to tell a man what is right for him,</verse>
<verse>to be gracious to him and say, 'Spare him from going down to the pit; I have found a ransom for him'-</verse>
<verse>then his flesh is renewed like a child's; it is restored as in the days of his youth.</verse>
<verse>He prays to God and finds favor with him, he sees God's face and shouts for joy; he is restored by God to his righteous state.</verse>
<verse>Then he comes to men and says, 'I sinned, and perverted what was right, but I did not get what I deserved.</verse>
<verse>He redeemed my soul from going down to the pit, and I will live to enjoy the light.'</verse>
<verse>"God does all these things to a man- twice, even three times-</verse>
<verse>to turn back his soul from the pit, that the light of life may shine on him.</verse>
<verse>"Pay attention, Job, and listen to me; be silent, and I will speak.</verse>
<verse>If you have anything to say, answer me; speak up, for I want you to be cleared.</verse>
<verse>But if not, then listen to me; be silent, and I will teach you wisdom."</verse>
</chapter>