<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Job" book-id="18" n="34">
<verse>Then Elihu said:</verse>
<verse>"Hear my words, you wise men; listen to me, you men of learning.</verse>
<verse>For the ear tests words as the tongue tastes food.</verse>
<verse>Let us discern for ourselves what is right; let us learn together what is good.</verse>
<verse>"Job says, 'I am innocent, but God denies me justice.</verse>
<verse>Although I am right, I am considered a liar; although I am guiltless, his arrow inflicts an incurable wound.'</verse>
<verse>What man is like Job, who drinks scorn like water?</verse>
<verse>He keeps company with evildoers; he associates with wicked men.</verse>
<verse>For he says, 'It profits a man nothing when he tries to please God.'</verse>
<verse>"So listen to me, you men of understanding. Far be it from God to do evil, from the Almighty to do wrong.</verse>
<verse>He repays a man for what he has done; he brings upon him what his conduct deserves.</verse>
<verse>It is unthinkable that God would do wrong, that the Almighty would pervert justice.</verse>
<verse>Who appointed him over the earth? Who put him in charge of the whole world?</verse>
<verse>If it were his intention and he withdrew his spirit and breath,</verse>
<verse>all mankind would perish together and man would return to the dust.</verse>
<verse>"If you have understanding, hear this; listen to what I say.</verse>
<verse>Can he who hates justice govern? Will you condemn the just and mighty One?</verse>
<verse>Is he not the One who says to kings, 'You are worthless,' and to nobles, 'You are wicked,'</verse>
<verse>who shows no partiality to princes and does not favor the rich over the poor, for they are all the work of his hands?</verse>
<verse>They die in an instant, in the middle of the night; the people are shaken and they pass away; the mighty are removed without human hand.</verse>
<verse>"His eyes are on the ways of men; he sees their every step.</verse>
<verse>There is no dark place, no deep shadow, where evildoers can hide.</verse>
<verse>God has no need to examine men further, that they should come before him for judgment.</verse>
<verse>Without inquiry he shatters the mighty and sets up others in their place.</verse>
<verse>Because he takes note of their deeds, he overthrows them in the night and they are crushed.</verse>
<verse>He punishes them for their wickedness where everyone can see them,</verse>
<verse>because they turned from following him and had no regard for any of his ways.</verse>
<verse>They caused the cry of the poor to come before him, so that he heard the cry of the needy.</verse>
<verse>But if he remains silent, who can condemn him? If he hides his face, who can see him? Yet he is over man and nation alike,</verse>
<verse>to keep a godless man from ruling, from laying snares for the people.</verse>
<verse>"Suppose a man says to God, 'I am guilty but will offend no more.</verse>
<verse>Teach me what I cannot see; if I have done wrong, I will not do so again.'</verse>
<verse>Should God then reward you on your terms, when you refuse to repent? You must decide, not I; so tell me what you know.</verse>
<verse>"Men of understanding declare, wise men who hear me say to me,</verse>
<verse>'Job speaks without knowledge; his words lack insight.'</verse>
<verse>Oh, that Job might be tested to the utmost for answering like a wicked man!</verse>
<verse>To his sin he adds rebellion; scornfully he claps his hands among us and multiplies his words against God."</verse>
</chapter>