<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Job" book-id="18" n="36">
<verse>Elihu continued:</verse>
<verse>"Bear with me a little longer and I will show you that there is more to be said in God's behalf.</verse>
<verse>I get my knowledge from afar; I will ascribe justice to my Maker.</verse>
<verse>Be assured that my words are not false; one perfect in knowledge is with you.</verse>
<verse>"God is mighty, but does not despise men; he is mighty, and firm in his purpose.</verse>
<verse>He does not keep the wicked alive but gives the afflicted their rights.</verse>
<verse>He does not take his eyes off the righteous; he enthrones them with kings and exalts them forever.</verse>
<verse>But if men are bound in chains, held fast by cords of affliction,</verse>
<verse>he tells them what they have done- that they have sinned arrogantly.</verse>
<verse>He makes them listen to correction and commands them to repent of their evil.</verse>
<verse>If they obey and serve him, they will spend the rest of their days in prosperity and their years in contentment.</verse>
<verse>But if they do not listen, they will perish by the sword and die without knowledge.</verse>
<verse>"The godless in heart harbor resentment; even when he fetters them, they do not cry for help.</verse>
<verse>They die in their youth, among male prostitutes of the shrines.</verse>
<verse>But those who suffer he delivers in their suffering; he speaks to them in their affliction.</verse>
<verse>"He is wooing you from the jaws of distress to a spacious place free from restriction, to the comfort of your table laden with choice food.</verse>
<verse>But now you are laden with the judgment due the wicked; judgment and justice have taken hold of you.</verse>
<verse>Be careful that no one entices you by riches; do not let a large bribe turn you aside.</verse>
<verse>Would your wealth or even all your mighty efforts sustain you so you would not be in distress?</verse>
<verse>Do not long for the night, to drag people away from their homes.</verse>
<verse>Beware of turning to evil, which you seem to prefer to affliction.</verse>
<verse>"God is exalted in his power. Who is a teacher like him?</verse>
<verse>Who has prescribed his ways for him, or said to him, 'You have done wrong'?</verse>
<verse>Remember to extol his work, which men have praised in song.</verse>
<verse>All mankind has seen it; men gaze on it from afar.</verse>
<verse>How great is God-beyond our understanding! The number of his years is past finding out.</verse>
<verse>"He draws up the drops of water, which distill as rain to the streams;</verse>
<verse>the clouds pour down their moisture and abundant showers fall on mankind.</verse>
<verse>Who can understand how he spreads out the clouds, how he thunders from his pavilion?</verse>
<verse>See how he scatters his lightning about him, bathing the depths of the sea.</verse>
<verse>This is the way he governs the nations and provides food in abundance.</verse>
<verse>He fills his hands with lightning and commands it to strike its mark.</verse>
<verse>His thunder announces the coming storm; even the cattle make known its approach.</verse>
</chapter>