<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Job" book_id="18" n="39">
<verse>"Do you know when the mountain goats give birth? Do you watch when the doe bears her fawn?</verse>
<verse>Do you count the months till they bear? Do you know the time they give birth?</verse>
<verse>They crouch down and bring forth their young; their labor pains are ended.</verse>
<verse>Their young thrive and grow strong in the wilds; they leave and do not return.</verse>
<verse>"Who let the wild donkey go free? Who untied his ropes?</verse>
<verse>I gave him the wasteland as his home, the salt flats as his habitat.</verse>
<verse>He laughs at the commotion in the town; he does not hear a driver's shout.</verse>
<verse>He ranges the hills for his pasture and searches for any green thing.</verse>
<verse>"Will the wild ox consent to serve you? Will he stay by your manger at night?</verse>
<verse>Can you hold him to the furrow with a harness? Will he till the valleys behind you?</verse>
<verse>Will you rely on him for his great strength? Will you leave your heavy work to him?</verse>
<verse>Can you trust him to bring in your grain and gather it to your threshing floor?</verse>
<verse>"The wings of the ostrich flap joyfully, but they cannot compare with the pinions and feathers of the stork.</verse>
<verse>She lays her eggs on the ground and lets them warm in the sand,</verse>
<verse>unmindful that a foot may crush them, that some wild animal may trample them.</verse>
<verse>She treats her young harshly, as if they were not hers; she cares not that her labor was in vain,</verse>
<verse>for God did not endow her with wisdom or give her a share of good sense.</verse>
<verse>Yet when she spreads her feathers to run, she laughs at horse and rider.</verse>
<verse>"Do you give the horse his strength or clothe his neck with a flowing mane?</verse>
<verse>Do you make him leap like a locust, striking terror with his proud snorting?</verse>
<verse>He paws fiercely, rejoicing in his strength, and charges into the fray.</verse>
<verse>He laughs at fear, afraid of nothing; he does not shy away from the sword.</verse>
<verse>The quiver rattles against his side, along with the flashing spear and lance.</verse>
<verse>In frenzied excitement he eats up the ground; he cannot stand still when the trumpet sounds.</verse>
<verse>At the blast of the trumpet he snorts, 'Aha!' He catches the scent of battle from afar, the shout of commanders and the battle cry.</verse>
<verse>"Does the hawk take flight by your wisdom and spread his wings toward the south?</verse>
<verse>Does the eagle soar at your command and build his nest on high?</verse>
<verse>He dwells on a cliff and stays there at night; a rocky crag is his stronghold.</verse>
<verse>From there he seeks out his food; his eyes detect it from afar.</verse>
<verse>His young ones feast on blood, and where the slain are, there is he."</verse>
</chapter>