<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Job" book_id="18" n="4">
<verse>Then Eliphaz the Temanite replied:</verse>
<verse>"If someone ventures a word with you, will you be impatient? But who can keep from speaking?</verse>
<verse>Think how you have instructed many, how you have strengthened feeble hands.</verse>
<verse>Your words have supported those who stumbled; you have strengthened faltering knees.</verse>
<verse>But now trouble comes to you, and you are discouraged; it strikes you, and you are dismayed.</verse>
<verse>Should not your piety be your confidence and your blameless ways your hope?</verse>
<verse>"Consider now: Who, being innocent, has ever perished? Where were the upright ever destroyed?</verse>
<verse>As I have observed, those who plow evil and those who sow trouble reap it.</verse>
<verse>At the breath of God they are destroyed; at the blast of his anger they perish.</verse>
<verse>The lions may roar and growl, yet the teeth of the great lions are broken.</verse>
<verse>The lion perishes for lack of prey, and the cubs of the lioness are scattered.</verse>
<verse>"A word was secretly brought to me, my ears caught a whisper of it.</verse>
<verse>Amid disquieting dreams in the night, when deep sleep falls on men,</verse>
<verse>fear and trembling seized me and made all my bones shake.</verse>
<verse>A spirit glided past my face, and the hair on my body stood on end.</verse>
<verse>It stopped, but I could not tell what it was. A form stood before my eyes, and I heard a hushed voice:</verse>
<verse>'Can a mortal be more righteous than God? Can a man be more pure than his Maker?</verse>
<verse>If God places no trust in his servants, if he charges his angels with error,</verse>
<verse>how much more those who live in houses of clay, whose foundations are in the dust, who are crushed more readily than a moth!</verse>
<verse>Between dawn and dusk they are broken to pieces; unnoticed, they perish forever.</verse>
<verse>Are not the cords of their tent pulled up, so that they die without wisdom?'</verse>
</chapter>