<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Job" book-id="18" n="41">
<verse>"Can you pull in the leviathan with a fishhook or tie down his tongue with a rope?</verse>
<verse>Can you put a cord through his nose or pierce his jaw with a hook?</verse>
<verse>Will he keep begging you for mercy? Will he speak to you with gentle words?</verse>
<verse>Will he make an agreement with you for you to take him as your slave for life?</verse>
<verse>Can you make a pet of him like a bird or put him on a leash for your girls?</verse>
<verse>Will traders barter for him? Will they divide him up among the merchants?</verse>
<verse>Can you fill his hide with harpoons or his head with fishing spears?</verse>
<verse>If you lay a hand on him, you will remember the struggle and never do it again!</verse>
<verse>Any hope of subduing him is false; the mere sight of him is overpowering.</verse>
<verse>No one is fierce enough to rouse him. Who then is able to stand against me?</verse>
<verse>Who has a claim against me that I must pay? Everything under heaven belongs to me.</verse>
<verse>"I will not fail to speak of his limbs, his strength and his graceful form.</verse>
<verse>Who can strip off his outer coat? Who would approach him with a bridle?</verse>
<verse>Who dares open the doors of his mouth, ringed about with his fearsome teeth?</verse>
<verse>His back has rows of shields tightly sealed together;</verse>
<verse>each is so close to the next that no air can pass between.</verse>
<verse>They are joined fast to one another; they cling together and cannot be parted.</verse>
<verse>His snorting throws out flashes of light; his eyes are like the rays of dawn.</verse>
<verse>Firebrands stream from his mouth; sparks of fire shoot out.</verse>
<verse>Smoke pours from his nostrils as from a boiling pot over a fire of reeds.</verse>
<verse>His breath sets coals ablaze, and flames dart from his mouth.</verse>
<verse>Strength resides in his neck; dismay goes before him.</verse>
<verse>The folds of his flesh are tightly joined; they are firm and immovable.</verse>
<verse>His chest is hard as rock, hard as a lower millstone.</verse>
<verse>When he rises up, the mighty are terrified; they retreat before his thrashing.</verse>
<verse>The sword that reaches him has no effect, nor does the spear or the dart or the javelin.</verse>
<verse>Iron he treats like straw and bronze like rotten wood.</verse>
<verse>Arrows do not make him flee; slingstones are like chaff to him.</verse>
<verse>A club seems to him but a piece of straw; he laughs at the rattling of the lance.</verse>
<verse>His undersides are jagged potsherds, leaving a trail in the mud like a threshing sledge.</verse>
<verse>He makes the depths churn like a boiling caldron and stirs up the sea like a pot of ointment.</verse>
<verse>Behind him he leaves a glistening wake; one would think the deep had white hair.</verse>
<verse>Nothing on earth is his equal- a creature without fear.</verse>
<verse>He looks down on all that are haughty; he is king over all that are proud."</verse>
</chapter>