<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Job" book_id="18" n="5">
<verse>"Call if you will, but who will answer you? To which of the holy ones will you turn?</verse>
<verse>Resentment kills a fool, and envy slays the simple.</verse>
<verse>I myself have seen a fool taking root, but suddenly his house was cursed.</verse>
<verse>His children are far from safety, crushed in court without a defender.</verse>
<verse>The hungry consume his harvest, taking it even from among thorns, and the thirsty pant after his wealth.</verse>
<verse>For hardship does not spring from the soil, nor does trouble sprout from the ground.</verse>
<verse>Yet man is born to trouble as surely as sparks fly upward.</verse>
<verse>"But if it were I, I would appeal to God; I would lay my cause before him.</verse>
<verse>He performs wonders that cannot be fathomed, miracles that cannot be counted.</verse>
<verse>He bestows rain on the earth; he sends water upon the countryside.</verse>
<verse>The lowly he sets on high, and those who mourn are lifted to safety.</verse>
<verse>He thwarts the plans of the crafty, so that their hands achieve no success.</verse>
<verse>He catches the wise in their craftiness, and the schemes of the wily are swept away.</verse>
<verse>Darkness comes upon them in the daytime; at noon they grope as in the night.</verse>
<verse>He saves the needy from the sword in their mouth; he saves them from the clutches of the powerful.</verse>
<verse>So the poor have hope, and injustice shuts its mouth.</verse>
<verse>"Blessed is the man whom God corrects; so do not despise the discipline of the Almighty.</verse>
<verse>For he wounds, but he also binds up; he injures, but his hands also heal.</verse>
<verse>From six calamities he will rescue you; in seven no harm will befall you.</verse>
<verse>In famine he will ransom you from death, and in battle from the stroke of the sword.</verse>
<verse>You will be protected from the lash of the tongue, and need not fear when destruction comes.</verse>
<verse>You will laugh at destruction and famine, and need not fear the beasts of the earth.</verse>
<verse>For you will have a covenant with the stones of the field, and the wild animals will be at peace with you.</verse>
<verse>You will know that your tent is secure; you will take stock of your property and find nothing missing.</verse>
<verse>You will know that your children will be many, and your descendants like the grass of the earth.</verse>
<verse>You will come to the grave in full vigor, like sheaves gathered in season.</verse>
<verse>"We have examined this, and it is true. So hear it and apply it to yourself."</verse>
</chapter>