<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Job" book_id="18" n="6">
<verse>Then Job replied:</verse>
<verse>"If only my anguish could be weighed and all my misery be placed on the scales!</verse>
<verse>It would surely outweigh the sand of the seas- no wonder my words have been impetuous.</verse>
<verse>The arrows of the Almighty are in me, my spirit drinks in their poison; God's terrors are marshaled against me.</verse>
<verse>Does a wild donkey bray when it has grass, or an ox bellow when it has fodder?</verse>
<verse>Is tasteless food eaten without salt, or is there flavor in the white of an egg?</verse>
<verse>I refuse to touch it; such food makes me ill.</verse>
<verse>"Oh, that I might have my request, that God would grant what I hope for,</verse>
<verse>that God would be willing to crush me, to let loose his hand and cut me off!</verse>
<verse>Then I would still have this consolation- my joy in unrelenting pain- that I had not denied the words of the Holy One.</verse>
<verse>"What strength do I have, that I should still hope? What prospects, that I should be patient?</verse>
<verse>Do I have the strength of stone? Is my flesh bronze?</verse>
<verse>Do I have any power to help myself, now that success has been driven from me?</verse>
<verse>"A despairing man should have the devotion of his friends, even though he forsakes the fear of the Almighty.</verse>
<verse>But my brothers are as undependable as intermittent streams, as the streams that overflow</verse>
<verse>when darkened by thawing ice and swollen with melting snow,</verse>
<verse>but that cease to flow in the dry season, and in the heat vanish from their channels.</verse>
<verse>Caravans turn aside from their routes; they go up into the wasteland and perish.</verse>
<verse>The caravans of Tema look for water, the traveling merchants of Sheba look in hope.</verse>
<verse>They are distressed, because they had been confident; they arrive there, only to be disappointed.</verse>
<verse>Now you too have proved to be of no help; you see something dreadful and are afraid.</verse>
<verse>Have I ever said, 'Give something on my behalf, pay a ransom for me from your wealth,</verse>
<verse>deliver me from the hand of the enemy, ransom me from the clutches of the ruthless'?</verse>
<verse>"Teach me, and I will be quiet; show me where I have been wrong.</verse>
<verse>How painful are honest words! But what do your arguments prove?</verse>
<verse>Do you mean to correct what I say, and treat the words of a despairing man as wind?</verse>
<verse>You would even cast lots for the fatherless and barter away your friend.</verse>
<verse>"But now be so kind as to look at me. Would I lie to your face?</verse>
<verse>Relent, do not be unjust; reconsider, for my integrity is at stake.</verse>
<verse>Is there any wickedness on my lips? Can my mouth not discern malice?</verse>
</chapter>