<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Job" book_id="18" n="7">
<verse>"Does not man have hard service on earth? Are not his days like those of a hired man?</verse>
<verse>Like a slave longing for the evening shadows, or a hired man waiting eagerly for his wages,</verse>
<verse>so I have been allotted months of futility, and nights of misery have been assigned to me.</verse>
<verse>When I lie down I think, 'How long before I get up?' The night drags on, and I toss till dawn.</verse>
<verse>My body is clothed with worms and scabs, my skin is broken and festering.</verse>
<verse>"My days are swifter than a weaver's shuttle, and they come to an end without hope.</verse>
<verse>Remember, O God, that my life is but a breath; my eyes will never see happiness again.</verse>
<verse>The eye that now sees me will see me no longer; you will look for me, but I will be no more.</verse>
<verse>As a cloud vanishes and is gone, so he who goes down to the grave does not return.</verse>
<verse>He will never come to his house again; his place will know him no more.</verse>
<verse>"Therefore I will not keep silent; I will speak out in the anguish of my spirit, I will complain in the bitterness of my soul.</verse>
<verse>Am I the sea, or the monster of the deep, that you put me under guard?</verse>
<verse>When I think my bed will comfort me and my couch will ease my complaint,</verse>
<verse>even then you frighten me with dreams and terrify me with visions,</verse>
<verse>so that I prefer strangling and death, rather than this body of mine.</verse>
<verse>I despise my life; I would not live forever. Let me alone; my days have no meaning.</verse>
<verse>"What is man that you make so much of him, that you give him so much attention,</verse>
<verse>that you examine him every morning and test him every moment?</verse>
<verse>Will you never look away from me, or let me alone even for an instant?</verse>
<verse>If I have sinned, what have I done to you, O watcher of men? Why have you made me your target? Have I become a burden to you?</verse>
<verse>Why do you not pardon my offenses and forgive my sins? For I will soon lie down in the dust; you will search for me, but I will be no more."</verse>
</chapter>