<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Job" book-id="18" n="8">
<verse>Then Bildad the Shuhite replied:</verse>
<verse>"How long will you say such things? Your words are a blustering wind.</verse>
<verse>Does God pervert justice? Does the Almighty pervert what is right?</verse>
<verse>When your children sinned against him, he gave them over to the penalty of their sin.</verse>
<verse>But if you will look to God and plead with the Almighty,</verse>
<verse>if you are pure and upright, even now he will rouse himself on your behalf and restore you to your rightful place.</verse>
<verse>Your beginnings will seem humble, so prosperous will your future be.</verse>
<verse>"Ask the former generations and find out what their fathers learned,</verse>
<verse>for we were born only yesterday and know nothing, and our days on earth are but a shadow.</verse>
<verse>Will they not instruct you and tell you? Will they not bring forth words from their understanding?</verse>
<verse>Can papyrus grow tall where there is no marsh? Can reeds thrive without water?</verse>
<verse>While still growing and uncut, they wither more quickly than grass.</verse>
<verse>Such is the destiny of all who forget God; so perishes the hope of the godless.</verse>
<verse>What he trusts in is fragile; what he relies on is a spider's web.</verse>
<verse>He leans on his web, but it gives way; he clings to it, but it does not hold.</verse>
<verse>He is like a well-watered plant in the sunshine, spreading its shoots over the garden;</verse>
<verse>it entwines its roots around a pile of rocks and looks for a place among the stones.</verse>
<verse>But when it is torn from its spot, that place disowns it and says, 'I never saw you.'</verse>
<verse>Surely its life withers away, and from the soil other plants grow.</verse>
<verse>"Surely God does not reject a blameless man or strengthen the hands of evildoers.</verse>
<verse>He will yet fill your mouth with laughter and your lips with shouts of joy.</verse>
<verse>Your enemies will be clothed in shame, and the tents of the wicked will be no more."</verse>
</chapter>