<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Job" book-id="18" n="9">
<verse>Then Job replied:</verse>
<verse>"Indeed, I know that this is true. But how can a mortal be righteous before God?</verse>
<verse>Though one wished to dispute with him, he could not answer him one time out of a thousand.</verse>
<verse>His wisdom is profound, his power is vast. Who has resisted him and come out unscathed?</verse>
<verse>He moves mountains without their knowing it and overturns them in his anger.</verse>
<verse>He shakes the earth from its place and makes its pillars tremble.</verse>
<verse>He speaks to the sun and it does not shine; he seals off the light of the stars.</verse>
<verse>He alone stretches out the heavens and treads on the waves of the sea.</verse>
<verse>He is the Maker of the Bear and Orion, the Pleiades and the constellations of the south.</verse>
<verse>He performs wonders that cannot be fathomed, miracles that cannot be counted.</verse>
<verse>When he passes me, I cannot see him; when he goes by, I cannot perceive him.</verse>
<verse>If he snatches away, who can stop him? Who can say to him, 'What are you doing?'</verse>
<verse>God does not restrain his anger; even the cohorts of Rahab cowered at his feet.</verse>
<verse>"How then can I dispute with him? How can I find words to argue with him?</verse>
<verse>Though I were innocent, I could not answer him; I could only plead with my Judge for mercy.</verse>
<verse>Even if I summoned him and he responded, I do not believe he would give me a hearing.</verse>
<verse>He would crush me with a storm and multiply my wounds for no reason.</verse>
<verse>He would not let me regain my breath but would overwhelm me with misery.</verse>
<verse>If it is a matter of strength, he is mighty! And if it is a matter of justice, who will summon him?</verse>
<verse>Even if I were innocent, my mouth would condemn me; if I were blameless, it would pronounce me guilty.</verse>
<verse>"Although I am blameless, I have no concern for myself; I despise my own life.</verse>
<verse>It is all the same; that is why I say, 'He destroys both the blameless and the wicked.'</verse>
<verse>When a scourge brings sudden death, he mocks the despair of the innocent.</verse>
<verse>When a land falls into the hands of the wicked, he blindfolds its judges. If it is not he, then who is it?</verse>
<verse>"My days are swifter than a runner; they fly away without a glimpse of joy.</verse>
<verse>They skim past like boats of papyrus, like eagles swooping down on their prey.</verse>
<verse>If I say, 'I will forget my complaint, I will change my expression, and smile,'</verse>
<verse>I still dread all my sufferings, for I know you will not hold me innocent.</verse>
<verse>Since I am already found guilty, why should I struggle in vain?</verse>
<verse>Even if I washed myself with soap and my hands with washing soda,</verse>
<verse>you would plunge me into a slime pit so that even my clothes would detest me.</verse>
<verse>"He is not a man like me that I might answer him, that we might confront each other in court.</verse>
<verse>If only there were someone to arbitrate between us, to lay his hand upon us both,</verse>
<verse>someone to remove God's rod from me, so that his terror would frighten me no more.</verse>
<verse>Then I would speak up without fear of him, but as it now stands with me, I cannot.</verse>
</chapter>