<?xml version="1.0"?>
<chapter translation="KJV" testament="New" book="Romans" n="14" book_id="45">
      <verse>Him that is weak in the faith receive ye, <supplied>but</supplied> not to doubtful disputations.
</verse><verse>For one believeth that he may eat all things: another, who is weak, eateth herbs.
</verse><verse>Let not him that eateth despise him that eateth not; and let not him which eateth not judge him that eateth: for God hath received him.
</verse><verse>Who art thou that judgest another man&#x2019;s servant? to his own master he standeth or falleth. Yea, he shall be holden up: for God is able to make him stand.
</verse><verse>One man esteemeth one day above another: another esteemeth every day <supplied>alike.</supplied> Let every man be fully persuaded in his own mind.
</verse><verse>He that regardeth the day, regardeth <supplied>it</supplied> unto the Lord; and he that regardeth not the day, to the Lord he doth not regard <supplied>it.</supplied> He that eateth, eateth to the Lord, for he giveth God thanks; and he that eateth not, to the Lord he
eateth not, and giveth God thanks.
</verse><verse>For none of us liveth to himself, and no man dieth to himself.
</verse><verse>For whether we live, we live unto the Lord; and whether we die, we die unto the Lord: whether we live therefore, or die, we are the Lord&#x2019;s.
</verse><verse>For to this end Christ both died, and rose, and revived, that he might be Lord both of the dead and living.
</verse><verse>But why dost thou judge thy brother? or why dost thou set at nought thy brother? for we shall all stand before the judgment seat of Christ.
</verse><verse>For it is written, <supplied>As</supplied> I live, saith the Lord, every knee shall bow to me, and every tongue shall confess to God.
</verse><verse>So then every one of us shall give account of himself to God.
</verse><verse>Let us not therefore judge one another any more: but judge this rather, that no man put a stumblingblock or an occasion to fall in <supplied>his</supplied> brother&#x2019;s way.
</verse><verse>I know, and am persuaded by the Lord Jesus, that <supplied>there is</supplied> nothing unclean of itself: but to him that esteemeth any thing to be unclean, to him <supplied>it is</supplied> unclean.
</verse><verse>But if thy brother be grieved with <supplied>thy</supplied> meat, now walkest thou not charitably. Destroy not him with thy meat, for whom Christ died.
</verse><verse>Let not then your good be evil spoken of:
</verse><verse>For the kingdom of God is not meat and drink; but righteousness, and peace, and joy in the Holy Ghost.
</verse><verse>For he that in these things serveth Christ <supplied>is</supplied> acceptable to God, and approved of men.
</verse><verse>Let us therefore follow after the things which make for peace, and things wherewith one may edify another.
</verse><verse>For meat destroy not the work of God. All things indeed <supplied>are</supplied> pure; but <supplied>it is</supplied> evil for that man who eateth with offence.
</verse><verse><supplied>It is</supplied> good neither to eat flesh, nor to drink wine, nor <supplied>any thing</supplied> whereby thy brother stumbleth, or is offended, or is made weak.
</verse><verse>Hast thou faith? have <supplied>it</supplied> to thyself before God. Happy <supplied>is</supplied> he that condemneth not himself in that thing which he alloweth.
</verse><verse>And he that doubteth is damned if he eat, because <supplied>he eateth</supplied> not of faith: for whatsoever <supplied>is</supplied> not of faith is sin.
     
      </verse>
      </chapter>
