<chapter translation="NASB" testament="New" book="Romans" book-id="45" n="10">
<verse>Brethren, my heart's desire and my prayer to God for them is for their salvation.</verse>
<verse>For I testify about them that they have a zeal for God, but not in accordance with knowledge.</verse>
<verse>For not knowing about God's righteousness and seeking to establish their own, they did not subject themselves to the righteousness of God.</verse>
<verse>For Christ is the end of the law for righteousness to everyone who believes.</verse>
<verse>For Moses writes that the man who practices the righteousness which is based on law shall live by that righteousness.</verse>
<verse>But the righteousness based on faith speaks as follows: "DO NOT SAY IN YOUR HEART, 'WHO WILL ASCEND INTO HEAVEN?' (that is, to bring Christ down),</verse>
<verse>or 'WHO WILL DESCEND INTO THE ABYSS?' (that is, to bring Christ up from the dead)."</verse>
<verse>But what does it say? "THE WORD IS NEAR YOU, IN YOUR MOUTH AND IN YOUR HEART"--that is, the word of faith which we are preaching,</verse>
<verse>that if you confess with your mouth Jesus as Lord, and believe in your heart that God raised Him from the dead, you will be saved;</verse>
<verse>for with the heart a person believes, resulting in righteousness, and with the mouth he confesses, resulting in salvation.</verse>
<verse>For the Scripture says, "WHOEVER BELIEVES IN HIM WILL NOT BE DISAPPOINTED."</verse>
<verse>For there is no distinction between Jew and Greek; for the same Lord is Lord of all, abounding in riches for all who call on Him;</verse>
<verse>for "WHOEVER WILL CALL ON THE NAME OF THE LORD WILL BE SAVED."</verse>
<verse>How then will they call on Him in whom they have not believed? How will they believe in Him whom they have not heard? And how will they hear without a preacher?</verse>
<verse>How will they preach unless they are sent? Just as it is written, "HOW BEAUTIFUL ARE THE FEET OF THOSE WHO BRING GOOD NEWS OF GOOD THINGS!"</verse>
<verse>However, they did not all heed the good news; for Isaiah says, "LORD, WHO HAS BELIEVED OUR REPORT?"</verse>
<verse>So faith comes from hearing, and hearing by the word of Christ.</verse>
<verse>But I say, surely they have never heard, have they? Indeed they have; "THEIR VOICE HAS GONE OUT INTO ALL THE EARTH, AND THEIR WORDS TO THE ENDS OF THE WORLD."</verse>
<verse>But I say, surely Israel did not know, did they? First Moses says, "I WILL MAKE YOU JEALOUS BY THAT WHICH IS NOT A NATION, BY A NATION WITHOUT UNDERSTANDING WILL I ANGER YOU."</verse>
<verse>And Isaiah is very bold and says, "I WAS FOUND BY THOSE WHO DID NOT SEEK ME, I BECAME MANIFEST TO THOSE WHO DID NOT ASK FOR ME."</verse>
<verse>But as for Israel He says, "ALL THE DAY LONG I HAVE STRETCHED OUT MY HANDS TO A DISOBEDIENT AND OBSTINATE PEOPLE."</verse>
</chapter>