<chapter translation="NASB" testament="New" book="Romans" book_id="45" n="11">
<verse>I say then, God has not rejected His people, has He? May it never be! For I too am an Israelite, a descendant of Abraham, of the tribe of Benjamin.</verse>
<verse>God has not rejected His people whom He foreknew. Or do you not know what the Scripture says in the passage about Elijah, how he pleads with God against Israel?</verse>
<verse>"Lord, THEY HAVE KILLED YOUR PROPHETS, THEY HAVE TORN DOWN YOUR ALTARS, AND I ALONE AM LEFT, AND THEY ARE SEEKING MY LIFE."</verse>
<verse>But what is the divine response to him? "I HAVE KEPT for Myself SEVEN THOUSAND MEN WHO HAVE NOT BOWED THE KNEE TO BAAL."</verse>
<verse>In the same way then, there has also come to be at the present time a remnant according to God's gracious choice.</verse>
<verse>But if it is by grace, it is no longer on the basis of works, otherwise grace is no longer grace.</verse>
<verse>What then? What Israel is seeking, it has not obtained, but those who were chosen obtained it, and the rest were hardened;</verse>
<verse>just as it is written, "GOD GAVE THEM A SPIRIT OF STUPOR, EYES TO SEE NOT AND EARS TO HEAR NOT, DOWN TO THIS VERY DAY."</verse>
<verse>And David says, "LET THEIR TABLE BECOME A SNARE AND A TRAP, AND A STUMBLING BLOCK AND A RETRIBUTION TO THEM.</verse>
<verse>"LET THEIR EYES BE DARKENED TO SEE NOT, AND BEND THEIR BACKS FOREVER."</verse>
<verse>I say then, they did not stumble so as to fall, did they? May it never be! But by their transgression salvation has come to the Gentiles, to make them jealous.</verse>
<verse>Now if their transgression is riches for the world and their failure is riches for the Gentiles, how much more will their fulfillment be!</verse>
<verse>But I am speaking to you who are Gentiles. Inasmuch then as I am an apostle of Gentiles, I magnify my ministry,</verse>
<verse>if somehow I might move to jealousy my fellow countrymen and save some of them.</verse>
<verse>For if their rejection is the reconciliation of the world, what will their acceptance be but life from the dead?</verse>
<verse>If the first piece of dough is holy, the lump is also; and if the root is holy, the branches are too.</verse>
<verse>But if some of the branches were broken off, and you, being a wild olive, were grafted in among them and became partaker with them of the rich root of the olive tree,</verse>
<verse>do not be arrogant toward the branches; but if you are arrogant, remember that it is not you who supports the root, but the root supports you.</verse>
<verse>You will say then, "Branches were broken off so that I might be grafted in."</verse>
<verse>Quite right, they were broken off for their unbelief, but you stand by your faith. Do not be conceited, but fear;</verse>
<verse>for if God did not spare the natural branches, He will not spare you, either.</verse>
<verse>Behold then the kindness and severity of God; to those who fell, severity, but to you, God's kindness, if you continue in His kindness; otherwise you also will be cut off.</verse>
<verse>And they also, if they do not continue in their unbelief, will be grafted in, for God is able to graft them in again.</verse>
<verse>For if you were cut off from what is by nature a wild olive tree, and were grafted contrary to nature into a cultivated olive tree, how much more will these who are the natural branches be grafted into their own olive tree?</verse>
<verse>For I do not want you, brethren, to be uninformed of this mystery--so that you will not be wise in your own estimation--that a partial hardening has happened to Israel until the fullness of the Gentiles has come in;</verse>
<verse>and so all Israel will be saved; just as it is written, "THE DELIVERER WILL COME FROM ZION, HE WILL REMOVE UNGODLINESS FROM JACOB."</verse>
<verse>"THIS IS MY COVENANT WITH THEM, WHEN I TAKE AWAY THEIR SINS."</verse>
<verse>From the standpoint of the gospel they are enemies for your sake, but from the standpoint of God's choice they are beloved for the sake of the fathers;</verse>
<verse>for the gifts and the calling of God are irrevocable.</verse>
<verse>For just as you once were disobedient to God, but now have been shown mercy because of their disobedience,</verse>
<verse>so these also now have been disobedient, that because of the mercy shown to you they also may now be shown mercy.</verse>
<verse>For God has shut up all in disobedience so that He may show mercy to all.</verse>
<verse>Oh, the depth of the riches both of the wisdom and knowledge of God! How unsearchable are His judgments and unfathomable His ways!</verse>
<verse>For WHO HAS KNOWN THE MIND OF THE LORD, OR WHO BECAME HIS COUNSELOR?</verse>
<verse>Or WHO HAS FIRST GIVEN TO HIM THAT IT MIGHT BE PAID BACK TO HIM AGAIN?</verse>
<verse>For from Him and through Him and to Him are all things. To Him be the glory forever. Amen.</verse>
</chapter>