<chapter translation="NASB" testament="New" book="Romans" book-id="45" n="2">
<verse>Therefore you have no excuse, everyone of you who passes judgment, for in that which you judge another, you condemn yourself; for you who judge practice the same things.</verse>
<verse>And we know that the judgment of God rightly falls upon those who practice such things.</verse>
<verse>But do you suppose this, O man, when you pass judgment on those who practice such things and do the same yourself, that you will escape the judgment of God?</verse>
<verse>Or do you think lightly of the riches of His kindness and tolerance and patience, not knowing that the kindness of God leads you to repentance?</verse>
<verse>But because of your stubbornness and unrepentant heart you are storing up wrath for yourself in the day of wrath and revelation of the righteous judgment of God,</verse>
<verse>who WILL RENDER TO EACH PERSON ACCORDING TO HIS DEEDS:</verse>
<verse>to those who by perseverance in doing good seek for glory and honor and immortality, eternal life;</verse>
<verse>but to those who are selfishly ambitious and do not obey the truth, but obey unrighteousness, wrath and indignation.</verse>
<verse>There will be tribulation and distress for every soul of man who does evil, of the Jew first and also of the Greek,</verse>
<verse>but glory and honor and peace to everyone who does good, to the Jew first and also to the Greek.</verse>
<verse>For there is no partiality with God.</verse>
<verse>For all who have sinned without the Law will also perish without the Law, and all who have sinned under the Law will be judged by the Law;</verse>
<verse>for it is not the hearers of the Law who are just before God, but the doers of the Law will be justified.</verse>
<verse>For when Gentiles who do not have the Law do instinctively the things of the Law, these, not having the Law, are a law to themselves,</verse>
<verse>in that they show the work of the Law written in their hearts, their conscience bearing witness and their thoughts alternately accusing or else defending them,</verse>
<verse>on the day when, according to my gospel, God will judge the secrets of men through Christ Jesus.</verse>
<verse>But if you bear the name "Jew" and rely upon the Law and boast in God,</verse>
<verse>and know His will and approve the things that are essential, being instructed out of the Law,</verse>
<verse>and are confident that you yourself are a guide to the blind, a light to those who are in darkness,</verse>
<verse>a corrector of the foolish, a teacher of the immature, having in the Law the embodiment of knowledge and of the truth,</verse>
<verse>you, therefore, who teach another, do you not teach yourself? You who preach that one shall not steal, do you steal?</verse>
<verse>You who say that one should not commit adultery, do you commit adultery? You who abhor idols, do you rob temples?</verse>
<verse>You who boast in the Law, through your breaking the Law, do you dishonor God?</verse>
<verse>For "THE NAME OF GOD IS BLASPHEMED AMONG THE GENTILES BECAUSE OF YOU," just as it is written.</verse>
<verse>For indeed circumcision is of value if you practice the Law; but if you are a transgressor of the Law, your circumcision has become uncircumcision.</verse>
<verse>So if the uncircumcised man keeps the requirements of the Law, will not his uncircumcision be regarded as circumcision?</verse>
<verse>And he who is physically uncircumcised, if he keeps the Law, will he not judge you who though having the letter of the Law and circumcision are a transgressor of the Law?</verse>
<verse>For he is not a Jew who is one outwardly, nor is circumcision that which is outward in the flesh.</verse>
<verse>But he is a Jew who is one inwardly; and circumcision is that which is of the heart, by the Spirit, not by the letter; and his praise is not from men, but from God.</verse>
</chapter>