<?xml version="1.0"?>
<chapter translation="KJV" testament="Old" book="Zechariah" n="4">
      <verse>And the angel that talked with me came again, and waked me, as a man that is wakened out of his sleep,
</verse><verse>And said unto me, What seest thou? And I said, I have looked, and behold a candlestick all <supplied>of</supplied> gold, with a bowl upon the top of it, and his seven lamps thereon, and seven pipes to the seven lamps, which <supplied>are</supplied> upon the top thereof:
</verse><verse>And two olive trees by it, one upon the right <supplied>side</supplied> of the bowl, and the other upon the left <supplied>side</supplied> thereof.
</verse><verse>So I answered and spake to the angel that talked with me, saying, What <supplied>are</supplied> these, my lord?
</verse><verse>Then the angel that talked with me answered and said unto me, Knowest thou not what these be? And I said, No, my lord.
</verse><verse>Then he answered and spake unto me, saying, This <supplied>is</supplied> the word of the LORD unto Zerubbabel, saying, Not by might, nor by power, but by my spirit, saith the LORD of hosts.
</verse><verse>Who <supplied>art</supplied> thou, O great mountain? before Zerubbabel <supplied>thou shalt become</supplied> a plain: and he shall bring forth the headstone <supplied>thereof with</supplied> shoutings, <supplied>crying,</supplied> Grace, grace unto it.
</verse><verse>Moreover the word of the LORD came unto me, saying,
</verse><verse>The hands of Zerubbabel have laid the foundation of this house; his hands shall also finish it; and thou shalt know that the LORD of hosts hath sent me unto you.
</verse><verse>For who hath despised the day of small things? for they shall rejoice, and shall see the plummet in the hand of Zerubbabel <supplied>with</supplied> those seven; they <supplied>are</supplied> the eyes of the LORD, which run to and fro through the whole earth.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>Then answered I, and said unto him, What <supplied>are</supplied> these two olive trees upon the right <supplied>side</supplied> of the candlestick and upon the left <supplied>side</supplied> thereof?
</verse><verse>And I answered again, and said unto him, What <supplied>be these</supplied> two olive branches which through the two golden pipes empty the golden <supplied>oil</supplied> out of themselves?
</verse><verse>And he answered me and said, Knowest thou not what these <supplied>be?</supplied> And I said, No, my lord.
</verse><verse>Then said he, These <supplied>are</supplied> the two anointed ones, that stand by the LORD of the whole earth.
     
      </verse>
      </chapter>
