<?xml version="1.0"?>
<chapter translation="KJV" testament="Old" book="Zechariah" n="6" book-chapters="14">
      <verse>And I turned, and lifted up mine eyes, and looked, and, behold, there came four chariots out from between two mountains; and the mountains <supplied>were</supplied> mountains of brass.
</verse><verse>In the first chariot <supplied>were</supplied> red horses; and in the second chariot black horses;
</verse><verse>And in the third chariot white horses; and in the fourth chariot grisled and bay horses.
</verse><verse>Then I answered and said unto the angel that talked with me, What <supplied>are</supplied> these, my lord?
</verse><verse>And the angel answered and said unto me, These <supplied>are</supplied> the four spirits of the heavens, which go forth from standing before the Lord of all the earth.
</verse><verse>The black horses which <supplied>are</supplied> therein go forth into the north country; and the white go forth after them; and the grisled go forth toward the south country.
</verse><verse>And the bay went forth, and sought to go that they might walk to and fro through the earth: and he said, Get you hence, walk to and fro through the earth. So they walked to and fro through the earth.
</verse><verse>Then cried he upon me, and spake unto me, saying, Behold, these that go toward the north country have quieted my spirit in the north country.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>And the word of the LORD came unto me, saying,
</verse><verse>Take of <supplied>them of</supplied> the captivity, <supplied>even</supplied> of Heldai, of Tobijah, and of Jedaiah, which are come from Babylon, and come thou the same day, and go into the house of Josiah the son of Zephaniah;
</verse><verse>Then take silver and gold, and make crowns, and set <supplied>them</supplied> upon the head of Joshua the son of Josedech, the high priest;
</verse><verse>And speak unto him, saying, Thus speaketh the LORD of hosts, saying, Behold the man whose name <supplied>is</supplied> The BRANCH; and he shall grow up out of his place, and he shall build the temple of the LORD:
</verse><verse>Even he shall build the temple of the LORD; and he shall bear the glory, and shall sit and rule upon his throne; and he shall be a priest upon his throne: and the counsel of peace shall be between them both.
</verse><verse>And the crowns shall be to Helem, and to Tobijah, and to Jedaiah, and to Hen the son of Zephaniah, for a memorial in the temple of the LORD.
</verse><verse>And they <supplied>that are</supplied> far off shall come and build in the temple of the LORD, and ye shall know that the LORD of hosts hath sent me unto you. And <supplied>this</supplied> shall come to pass, if ye will diligently obey the voice of the LORD your
God.
     
      </verse>
      </chapter>
