<?xml version="1.0"?>
<chapter translation="KJV" testament="Old" book="Zechariah" n="9" chapters="14">
      <verse>The burden of the word of the LORD in the land of Hadrach, and Damascus <supplied>shall be</supplied> the rest thereof: when the eyes of man, as of all the tribes of Israel, <supplied>shall be</supplied> toward the LORD.
</verse><verse>And Hamath also shall border thereby; Tyrus, and Zidon, though it be very wise.
</verse><verse>And Tyrus did build herself a strong hold, and heaped up silver as the dust, and fine gold as the mire of the streets.
</verse><verse>Behold, the Lord will cast her out, and he will smite her power in the sea; and she shall be devoured with fire.
</verse><verse>Ashkelon shall see <supplied>it,</supplied> and fear; Gaza also <supplied>shall see it,</supplied> and be very sorrowful, and Ekron; for her expectation shall be ashamed; and the king shall perish from Gaza, and Ashkelon shall not be inhabited.
</verse><verse>And a bastard shall dwell in Ashdod, and I will cut off the pride of the Philistines.
</verse><verse>And I will take away his blood out of his mouth, and his abominations from between his teeth: but he that remaineth, even he, <supplied>shall be</supplied> for our God, and he shall be as a governor in Judah, and Ekron as a Jebusite.
</verse><verse>And I will encamp about mine house because of the army, because of him that passeth by, and because of him that returneth: and no oppressor shall pass through them any more: for now have I seen with mine eyes.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>Rejoice greatly, O daughter of Zion; shout, O daughter of Jerusalem: behold, thy King cometh unto thee: he <supplied>is</supplied> just, and having salvation; lowly, and riding upon an ass, and upon a colt the foal of an ass.
</verse><verse>And I will cut off the chariot from Ephraim, and the horse from Jerusalem, and the battle bow shall be cut off: and he shall speak peace unto the heathen: and his dominion <supplied>shall be</supplied> from sea <supplied>even</supplied> to sea, and from river
<supplied>even</supplied> to the ends of the earth.
</verse><verse>As for thee also, by the blood of thy covenant I have sent forth thy prisoners out of the pit wherein <supplied>is</supplied> no water.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>Turn you to the strong hold, ye prisoners of hope: even to day do I declare <supplied>that</supplied> I will render double unto thee;
</verse><verse>When I have bent Judah for me, filled the bow with Ephraim, and raised up thy sons, O Zion, against thy sons, O Greece, and made thee as the sword of a mighty man.
</verse><verse>And the LORD shall be seen over them, and his arrow shall go forth as the lightning: and the LORD GOD shall blow the trumpet, and shall go with whirlwinds of the south.
</verse><verse>The LORD of hosts shall defend them; and they shall devour, and subdue with sling stones; and they shall drink, <supplied>and</supplied> make a noise as through wine; and they shall be filled like bowls, <supplied>and</supplied> as the corners of the altar.
</verse><verse>And the LORD their God shall save them in that day as the flock of his people: for they <supplied>shall be as</supplied> the stones of a crown, lifted up as an ensign upon his land.
</verse><verse>For how great <supplied>is</supplied> his goodness, and how great <supplied>is</supplied> his beauty! corn shall make the young men cheerful, and new wine the maids.
     
      </verse>
      </chapter>
