<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Proverbs" book_id="20" n="1">
<verse>These are the wise sayings of Solomon, David's son, Israel's king--</verse>
<verse>Written down so we'll know how to live well and right, to understand what life means and where it's going;</verse>
<verse>A manual for living, for learning what's right and just and fair;</verse>
<verse>To teach the inexperienced the ropes and give our young people a grasp on reality.</verse>
<verse>There's something here also for seasoned men and women,</verse>
<verse>still a thing or two for the experienced to learn--Fresh wisdom to probe and penetrate, the rhymes and reasons of wise men and women.</verse>
<verse>Start with GOD-the first step in learning is bowing down to GOD; only fools thumb their noses at such wisdom and learning.</verse>
<verse>Pay close attention, friend, to what your father tells you; never forget what you learned at your mother's knee.</verse>
<verse>Wear their counsel like flowers in your hair, like rings on your fingers.</verse>
<verse>Dear friend, if bad companions tempt you, don't go along with them.</verse>
<verse>If they say--"Let's go out and raise some hell. Let's beat up some old man, mug some old woman.</verse>
<verse>Let's pick them clean and get them ready for their funerals.</verse>
<verse>We'll load up on top-quality loot. We'll haul it home by the truckload.</verse>
<verse>Join us for the time of your life! With us, it's share and share alike!"-</verse>
<verse>Oh, friend, don't give them a second look; don't listen to them for a minute.</verse>
<verse>They're racing to a very bad end, hurrying to ruin everything they lay hands on.</verse>
<verse>Nobody robs a bank with everyone watching,</verse>
<verse>Yet that's what these people are doing--they're doing themselves in.</verse>
<verse>When you grab all you can get, that's what happens: the more you get, the less you are.</verse>
<verse>Lady Wisdom goes out in the street and shouts. At the town center she makes her speech.</verse>
<verse>In the middle of the traffic she takes her stand. At the busiest corner she calls out:</verse>
<verse>"Simpletons! How long will you wallow in ignorance? Cynics! How long will you feed your cynicism? Idiots! How long will you refuse to learn?</verse>
<verse>About face! I can revise your life. Look, I'm ready to pour out my spirit on you; I'm ready to tell you all I know.</verse>
<verse>As it is, I've called, but you've turned a deaf ear; I've reached out to you, but you've ignored me.</verse>
<verse>"Since you laugh at my counsel and make a joke of my advice,</verse>
<verse>How can I take you seriously? I'll turn the tables and joke about your troubles!</verse>
<verse>What if the roof falls in, and your whole life goes to pieces? What if catastrophe strikes and there's nothing to show for your life but rubble and ashes?</verse>
<verse>You'll need me then. You'll call for me, but don't expect 	an answer. No matter how hard you look, you won't find me.</verse>
<verse>"Because you hated Knowledge and had nothing to do with the Fear-of-GOD,</verse>
<verse>Because you wouldn't take my advice and brushed aside all my offers to train you,</verse>
<verse>Well, you've made your bed--now lie in it; you wanted your own way--now, how do you like it?</verse>
<verse>Don't you see what happens, you simpletons, you idiots? Carelessness kills; complacency is murder.</verse>
<verse>First pay attention to me, and then relax. Now you can take it easy--you're in good hands."</verse>
</chapter>