<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Proverbs" book_id="20" n="10">
<verse>Wise son, glad father; stupid son, sad mother.</verse>
<verse>Ill-gotten gain gets you nowhere; an honest life is immortal.</verse>
<verse>GOD won't starve an honest soul, but he frustrates the appetites of the wicked.</verse>
<verse>Sloth makes you poor; diligence brings wealth.</verse>
<verse>Make hay while the sun shines--that's smart; go fishing during harvest--that's stupid.</verse>
<verse>Blessings accrue on a good and honest life, but the mouth of the wicked is a dark cave of abuse.</verse>
<verse>A good and honest life is a blessed memorial; a wicked life leaves a rotten stench.</verse>
<verse>A wise heart takes orders; an empty head will come unglued.</verse>
<verse>Honesty lives confident and carefree, but Shifty is sure to be exposed.</verse>
<verse>An evasive eye is a sign of trouble ahead, but an open, face-to-face meeting results in peace.</verse>
<verse>The mouth of a good person is a deep, life--giving well, but the mouth of the wicked is a dark cave of abuse.</verse>
<verse>Hatred starts fights, but love pulls a quilt over the bickering.</verse>
<verse>You'll find wisdom on the lips of a person of insight, but the shortsighted needs a slap in the face.</verse>
<verse>The wise accumulate knowledge--a true treasure; know--it--alls talk too much--a sheer waste.</verse>
<verse>The wealth of the rich is their bastion; the poverty of the indigent is their ruin.</verse>
<verse>The wage of a good person is exuberant life; an evil person ends up with nothing but sin.</verse>
<verse>The road to life is a disciplined life; ignore correction and you're lost for good.</verse>
<verse>Liars secretly hoard hatred; fools openly spread slander.</verse>
<verse>The more talk, the less truth; the wise measure their words.</verse>
<verse>The speech of a good person is worth waiting for; the blabber of the wicked is worthless.</verse>
<verse>The talk of a good person is rich fare for many, but chatterboxes die of an empty heart.</verse>
<verse>GOD's blessing makes life rich; nothing we do can improve on God.</verse>
<verse>An empty-head thinks mischief is fun, but a mindful person relishes wisdom.</verse>
<verse>The nightmares of the wicked come true; what the good people desire, they get.</verse>
<verse>When the storm is over, there's nothing left of the wicked; good people, firm on their rock foundation, aren't even fazed.</verse>
<verse>A lazy employee will give you nothing but trouble; it's vinegar in the mouth, smoke in the eyes.</verse>
<verse>The Fear-of-GOD expands your life; a wicked life is a puny life.</verse>
<verse>The aspirations of good people end in celebration; the ambitions of bad people crash.</verse>
<verse>GOD is solid backing to a well-lived life, but he calls into question a shabby performance.</verse>
<verse>Good people last--they can't be moved; the wicked are here today, gone tomorrow.</verse>
<verse>A good person's mouth is a clear fountain of wisdom; a foul mouth is a stagnant swamp.</verse>
<verse>The speech of a good person clears the air; the words of the wicked pollute it.</verse>
</chapter>