<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Proverbs" book_id="20" n="11">
<verse>GOD hates cheating in the marketplace; he loves it when business is aboveboard.</verse>
<verse>The stuck-up fall flat on their faces, but down-to-earth people stand firm.</verse>
<verse>The integrity of the honest keeps them on track; the deviousness of crooks brings them to ruin.</verse>
<verse>A thick bankroll is no help when life falls apart, but a principled life can stand up to the worst.</verse>
<verse>Moral character makes for smooth traveling; an evil life is a hard life.</verse>
<verse>Good character is the best insurance; crooks get trapped in their sinful lust.</verse>
<verse>When the wicked die, that's it--the story's over, end of hope.</verse>
<verse>A good person is saved from much trouble; a bad person runs straight into it.</verse>
<verse>The loose tongue of the godless spreads destruction; the common sense of the godly preserves them.</verse>
<verse>When it goes well for good people, the whole town cheers; when it goes badly for bad people, the town celebrates.</verse>
<verse>When right-living people bless the city, it flourishes; evil talk turns it into a ghost town in no time.</verse>
<verse>Mean-spirited slander is heartless; quiet discretion accompanies good sense.</verse>
<verse>A gadabout gossip can't be trusted with a secret, but someone of integrity won't violate a confidence.</verse>
<verse>Without good direction, people lose their way; the more wise counsel you follow, the better your chances.</verse>
<verse>Whoever makes deals with strangers is sure to get burned; if you keep a cool head, you'll avoid rash bargains.</verse>
<verse>A woman of gentle grace gets respect, but men of rough violence grab for loot.</verse>
<verse>When you're kind to others, you help yourself; when you're cruel to others, you hurt yourself.</verse>
<verse>Bad work gets paid with a bad check; good work gets solid pay.</verse>
<verse>Take your stand with God's loyal community and live, or chase after phantoms of evil and die.</verse>
<verse>GOD can't stand deceivers, but oh how he relishes integrity.</verse>
<verse>Count on this: The wicked won't get off scot-free, and God's loyal people will triumph.</verse>
<verse>Like a gold ring in a pig's snout is a beautiful face on an empty head.</verse>
<verse>The desires of good people lead straight to the best, but wicked ambition ends in angry frustration.</verse>
<verse>The world of the generous gets larger and larger; the world of the stingy gets smaller and smaller.</verse>
<verse>The one who blesses others is abundantly blessed; those who help others are helped.</verse>
<verse>Curses on those who drive a hard bargain! Blessings on all who play fair and square!</verse>
<verse>The one who seeks good finds delight; the student of evil becomes evil.</verse>
<verse>A life devoted to things is a dead life, a stump; a God-shaped life is a flourishing tree.</verse>
<verse>Exploit or abuse your family, and end up with a fistful of air; common sense tells you it's a stupid way to live.</verse>
<verse>A good life is a fruit--bearing tree; a violent life destroys souls.</verse>
<verse>If good people barely make it, what's in store for the bad!</verse>
</chapter>