<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Proverbs" book_id="20" n="12">
<verse>If you love learning, you love the discipline that goes with it--how shortsighted to refuse correction!</verse>
<verse>A good person basks in the delight of GOD, and he wants nothing to do with devious schemers.</verse>
<verse>You can't find firm footing in a swamp, but life rooted in God stands firm.</verse>
<verse>A hearty wife invigorates her husband, but a frigid woman is cancer in the bones.</verse>
<verse>The thinking of principled people makes for justice; the plots of degenerates corrupt.</verse>
<verse>The words of the wicked kill; the speech of the upright saves.</verse>
<verse>Wicked people fall to pieces--there's nothing to them; the homes of good people hold together.</verse>
<verse>A person who talks sense is honored; airheads are held in contempt.</verse>
<verse>Better to be ordinary and work for a living than act important and starve in the process.</verse>
<verse>Good people are good to their animals; the "good-hearted" bad people kick and abuse them.</verse>
<verse>The one who stays on the job has food on the table; the witless chase whims and fancies.</verse>
<verse>What the wicked construct finally falls into ruin, while the roots of the righteous give life, and more life.</verse>
<verse>The gossip of bad people gets them in trouble; the conversation of good people keeps them out of it.</verse>
<verse>Well-spoken words bring satisfaction; well-done work has its own reward.</verse>
<verse>Fools are headstrong and do what they like; wise people take advice.</verse>
<verse>Fools have short fuses and explode all too quickly; the prudent quietly shrug off insults.</verse>
<verse>Truthful witness by a good person clears the air, but liars lay down a smoke screen of deceit.</verse>
<verse>Rash language cuts and maims, but there is healing in the words of the wise.</verse>
<verse>Truth lasts; lies are here today, gone tomorrow.</verse>
<verse>Evil scheming distorts the schemer; peace-planning brings joy to the planner.</verse>
<verse>No evil can overwhelm a good person, but the wicked have their hands full of it.</verse>
<verse>God can't stomach liars; he loves the company of those who keep their word.</verse>
<verse>Prudent people don't flaunt their knowledge; talkative fools broadcast their silliness.</verse>
<verse>The diligent find freedom in their work; the lazy are oppressed by work.</verse>
<verse>Worry weighs us down; a cheerful word picks us up.</verse>
<verse>A good person survives misfortune, but a wicked life invites disaster.</verse>
<verse>A lazy life is an empty life, but "early to rise" gets the job done.</verse>
<verse>Good men and women travel right into life; sin's detours take you straight to hell.</verse>
</chapter>