<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Proverbs" book-id="20" n="13">
<verse>Intelligent children listen to their parents; foolish children do their own thing.</verse>
<verse>The good acquire a taste for helpful conversation; bullies push and shove their way through life.</verse>
<verse>Careful words make for a careful life; careless talk may ruin everything.</verse>
<verse>Indolence wants it all and gets nothing; the energetic have something to show for their lives.</verse>
<verse>A good person hates false talk; a bad person wallows in gibberish.</verse>
<verse>A God-loyal life keeps you on track; sin dumps the wicked in the ditch.</verse>
<verse>A pretentious, showy life is an empty life; a plain and simple life is a full life.</verse>
<verse>The rich can be sued for everything they have, but the poor are free of such threats.</verse>
<verse>The lives of good people are brightly lit streets; the lives of the wicked are dark alleys.</verse>
<verse>Arrogant know--it--alls stir up discord, but wise men and women listen to each other's counsel.</verse>
<verse>Easy come, easy go, but steady diligence pays off.</verse>
<verse>Unrelenting disappointment leaves you heartsick, but a sudden good break can turn life around.</verse>
<verse>Ignore the Word and suffer; honor God's commands and grow rich.</verse>
<verse>The teaching of the wise is a fountain of life, so, no more drinking from death-tainted wells!</verse>
<verse>Sound thinking makes for gracious living, but liars walk a rough road.</verse>
<verse>A commonsense person lives good sense; fools litter the country with silliness.</verse>
<verse>Irresponsible talk makes a real mess of things, but a reliable reporter is a healing presence.</verse>
<verse>Refuse discipline and end up homeless; embrace correction and live an honored life.</verse>
<verse>Souls who follow their hearts thrive; fools bent on evil despise matters of soul.</verse>
<verse>Become wise by walking with the wise; hang out with fools and watch your life fall to pieces.</verse>
<verse>Disaster entraps sinners, but God-loyal people get a good life.</verse>
<verse>A good life gets passed on to the grandchildren; ill-gotten wealth ends up with good people.</verse>
<verse>Banks foreclose on the farms of the poor, or else the poor lose their shirts to crooked lawyers.</verse>
<verse>A refusal to correct is a refusal to love; love your children by disciplining them.</verse>
<verse>An appetite for good brings much satisfaction, but the belly of the wicked always wants more.</verse>
</chapter>