<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Proverbs" book_id="20" n="14">
<verse>Lady Wisdom builds a lovely home; Sir Fool comes along and tears it down brick by brick.</verse>
<verse>An honest life shows respect for GOD; a degenerate life is a slap in his face.</verse>
<verse>Frivolous talk provokes a derisive smile; wise speech evokes nothing but respect.</verse>
<verse>No cattle, no crops; a good harvest requires a strong ox for the plow.</verse>
<verse>A true witness never lies; a false witness makes a business of it.</verse>
<verse>Cynics look high and low for wisdom--and never find it; the open-minded find it right on their doorstep!</verse>
<verse>Escape quickly from the company of fools; they're a waste of your time, a waste of your words.</verse>
<verse>The wisdom of the wise keeps life on track; the foolishness of fools lands them in the ditch.</verse>
<verse>The stupid ridicule right and wrong, but a moral life is a favored life.</verse>
<verse>The person who shuns the bitter moments of friends will be an outsider at their celebrations.</verse>
<verse>Lives of careless wrongdoing are tumbledown shacks; holy living builds soaring cathedrals.</verse>
<verse>There's a way of life that looks harmless enough; look again--it leads straight to hell.</verse>
<verse>Sure, those people appear to be having a good time, but all that laughter will end in heartbreak.</verse>
<verse>A mean person gets paid back in meanness, a gracious person in grace.</verse>
<verse>The gullible believe anything they're told; the prudent sift and weigh every word.</verse>
<verse>The wise watch their steps and avoid evil; fools are headstrong and reckless.</verse>
<verse>The hotheaded do things they'll later regret; the coldhearted get the cold shoulder.</verse>
<verse>Foolish dreamers live in a world of illusion; wise realists plant their feet on the ground.</verse>
<verse>Eventually, evil will pay tribute to good; the wicked will respect God-loyal people.</verse>
<verse>An unlucky loser is shunned by all, but everyone loves a winner.</verse>
<verse>It's criminal to ignore a neighbor in need, but compassion for the poor--what a blessing!</verse>
<verse>Isn't it obvious that conspirators lose out, while the thoughtful win love and trust?</verse>
<verse>Hard work always pays off; mere talk puts no bread on the table.</verse>
<verse>The wise accumulate wisdom; fools get stupider by the day.</verse>
<verse>Souls are saved by truthful witness and betrayed by the spread of lies.</verse>
<verse>The Fear-of-GOD builds up confidence, and makes a world safe for your children.</verse>
<verse>The Fear-of-GOD is a spring of living water so you won't go off drinking from poisoned wells.</verse>
<verse>The mark of a good leader is loyal followers; leadership is nothing without a following.</verse>
<verse>Slowness to anger makes for deep understanding; a quick-tempered person stockpiles stupidity.</verse>
<verse>A sound mind makes for a robust body, but runaway emotions corrode the bones.</verse>
<verse>You insult your Maker when you exploit the powerless; when you're kind to the poor, you honor God.</verse>
<verse>The evil of bad people leaves them out in the cold; the integrity of good people creates a safe place for living.</verse>
<verse>Lady Wisdom is at home in an understanding heart--fools never even get to say hello.</verse>
<verse>God-devotion makes a country strong; God-avoidance leaves people weak.</verse>
<verse>Diligent work gets a warm commendation; shiftless work earns an angry rebuke.</verse>
</chapter>