<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Proverbs" book-id="20" n="15">
<verse>A gentle response defuses anger, but a sharp tongue kindles a temper-fire.</verse>
<verse>Knowledge flows like spring water from the wise; fools are leaky faucets, dripping nonsense.</verse>
<verse>GOD doesn't miss a thing--he's alert to good and evil alike.</verse>
<verse>Kind words heal and help; cutting words wound and maim.</verse>
<verse>Moral dropouts won't listen to their elders; welcoming correction is a mark of good sense.</verse>
<verse>The lives of God-loyal people flourish; a misspent life is soon bankrupt.</verse>
<verse>Perceptive words spread knowledge; fools are hollow--there's nothing to them.</verse>
<verse>GOD can't stand pious poses, but he delights in genuine prayers.</verse>
<verse>A life frittered away disgusts GOD; he loves those who run straight for the finish line.</verse>
<verse>It's a school of hard knocks for those who leave God's path, a dead-end street for those who hate God's rules.</verse>
<verse>Even hell holds no secrets from GOD- do you think he can't read human hearts?</verse>
<verse>Know-it--alls don't like being told what to do; they avoid the company of wise men and women.</verse>
<verse>A cheerful heart brings a smile to your face; a sad heart makes it hard to get through the day.</verse>
<verse>An intelligent person is always eager to take in more truth; fools feed on fast-food fads and fancies.</verse>
<verse>A miserable heart means a miserable life; a cheerful heart fills the day with song.</verse>
<verse>A simple life in the Fear-of-GOD is better than a rich life with a ton of headaches.</verse>
<verse>Better a bread crust shared in love than a slab of prime rib served in hate.</verse>
<verse>Hot tempers start fights; a calm, cool spirit keeps the peace.</verse>
<verse>The path of lazy people is overgrown with briers; the diligent walk down a smooth road.</verse>
<verse>Intelligent children make their parents proud; lazy students embarrass their parents.</verse>
<verse>The empty-headed treat life as a plaything; the perceptive grasp its meaning and make a go of it.</verse>
<verse>Refuse good advice and watch your plans fail; take good counsel and watch them succeed.</verse>
<verse>Congenial conversation--what a pleasure! The right word at the right time--beautiful!</verse>
<verse>Life ascends to the heights for the thoughtful--it's a clean about-face from descent into hell.</verse>
<verse>GOD smashes the pretensions of the arrogant; he stands with those who have no standing.</verse>
<verse>GOD can't stand evil scheming, but he puts words of grace and beauty on display.</verse>
<verse>A greedy and grasping person destroys community; those who refuse to exploit live and let live.</verse>
<verse>Prayerful answers come from God-loyal people; the wicked are sewers of abuse.</verse>
<verse>GOD keeps his distance from the wicked; he closely attends to the prayers of God-loyal people.</verse>
<verse>A twinkle in the eye means joy in the heart, and good news makes you feel fit as a fiddle.</verse>
<verse>Listen to good advice if you want to live well, an honored guest among wise men and women.</verse>
<verse>An undisciplined, self-willed life is puny; an obedient, God-willed life is spacious.</verse>
<verse>Fear-of-GOD is a school in skilled living--first you learn humility, then you experience glory.</verse>
</chapter>