<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Proverbs" book-id="20" n="16">
<verse>Mortals make elaborate plans, but GOD has the last word.</verse>
<verse>Humans are satisfied with whatever looks good; GOD probes for what is good.</verse>
<verse>Put GOD in charge of your work, then what you've planned will take place.</verse>
<verse>GOD made everything with a place and purpose; even the wicked are included--but for judgment.</verse>
<verse>GOD can't stomach arrogance or pretense; believe me, he'll put those upstarts in their place.</verse>
<verse>Guilt is banished through love and truth; Fear-of-GOD deflects evil.</verse>
<verse>When GOD approves of your life, even your enemies will end up shaking your hand.</verse>
<verse>Far better to be right and poor than to be wrong and rich.</verse>
<verse>We plan the way we want to live, but only GOD makes us able to live it.</verse>
<verse>A good leader motivates, doesn't mislead, doesn't exploit.</verse>
<verse>GOD cares about honesty in the workplace; your business is his business.</verse>
<verse>Good leaders abhor wrongdoing of all kinds; sound leadership has a moral foundation.</verse>
<verse>Good leaders cultivate honest speech; they love advisors who tell them the truth.</verse>
<verse>An intemperate leader wreaks havoc in lives; you're smart to stay clear of someone like that.</verse>
<verse>Good-tempered leaders invigorate lives; they're like spring rain and sunshine.</verse>
<verse>Get wisdom--it's worth more than money; choose insight over income every time.</verse>
<verse>The road of right living bypasses evil; watch your step and save your life.</verse>
<verse>First pride, then the crash--the bigger the ego, the harder the fall.</verse>
<verse>It's better to live humbly among the poor than to live it up among the rich and famous.</verse>
<verse>It pays to take life seriously; things work out when you trust in GOD.</verse>
<verse>A wise person gets known for insight; gracious words add to one's reputation.</verse>
<verse>True intelligence is a spring of fresh water, while fools sweat it out the hard way.</verse>
<verse>They make a lot of sense, these wise folks; whenever they speak, their reputation increases.</verse>
<verse>Gracious speech is like clover honey--good taste to the soul, quick energy for the body.</verse>
<verse>There's a way that looks harmless enough; look again--it leads straight to hell.</verse>
<verse>Appetite is an incentive to work; hunger makes you work all the harder.</verse>
<verse>Mean people spread mean gossip; their words smart and burn.</verse>
<verse>Troublemakers start fights; gossips break up friendships.</verse>
<verse>Calloused climbers betray their very own friends; they'd stab their own grandmothers in the back.</verse>
<verse>A shifty eye betrays an evil intention; a clenched jaw signals trouble ahead.</verse>
<verse>Gray hair is a mark of distinction, the award for a God-loyal life.</verse>
<verse>Moderation is better than muscle, self-control better than political power.</verse>
<verse>Make your motions and cast your votes, but GOD has the final say.</verse>
</chapter>