<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Proverbs" book-id="20" n="17">
<verse>A meal of bread and water in contented peace is better than a banquet spiced with quarrels.</verse>
<verse>A wise servant takes charge of an unruly child and is honored as one of the family.</verse>
<verse>As silver in a crucible and gold in a pan, so our lives are assayed by GOD.</verse>
<verse>Evil people relish malicious conversation; the ears of liars itch for dirty gossip.</verse>
<verse>Whoever mocks poor people, insults their Creator; gloating over misfortune is a punishable crime.</verse>
<verse>Old people are distinguished by grandchildren; children take pride in their parents.</verse>
<verse>We don't expect eloquence from fools, nor do we expect lies from our leaders.</verse>
<verse>Receiving a gift is like getting a rare gemstone; any way you look at it, you see beauty refracted.</verse>
<verse>Overlook an offense and bond a friendship; fasten on to a slight and--good-bye, friend!</verse>
<verse>A quiet rebuke to a person of good sense does more than a whack on the head of a fool.</verse>
<verse>Criminals out looking for nothing but trouble won't have to wait long--they'll meet it coming and going!</verse>
<verse>Better to meet a grizzly robbed of her cubs than a fool hellbent on folly.</verse>
<verse>Those who return evil for good will meet their own evil returning.</verse>
<verse>The start of a quarrel is like a leak in a dam, so stop it before it bursts.</verse>
<verse>Whitewashing bad people and throwing mud on good people are equally abhorrent to GOD.</verse>
<verse>What's this? Fools out shopping for wisdom! They wouldn't recognize it if they saw it!</verse>
<verse>Friends love through all kinds of weather, and families stick together in all kinds of trouble.</verse>
<verse>It's stupid to try to get something for nothing, or run up huge bills you can never pay.</verse>
<verse>The person who courts sin, marries trouble; build a wall, invite a burglar.</verse>
<verse>A bad motive can't achieve a good end; double-talk brings you double trouble.</verse>
<verse>Having a fool for a child is misery; it's no fun being the parent of a dolt.</verse>
<verse>A cheerful disposition is good for your health; gloom and doom leave you bone-tired.</verse>
<verse>The wicked take bribes under the table; they show nothing but contempt for justice.</verse>
<verse>The perceptive find wisdom in their own front yard; fools look for it everywhere but right here.</verse>
<verse>A surly, stupid child is sheer pain to a father, a bitter pill for a mother to swallow.</verse>
<verse>It's wrong to penalize good behavior, or make good citizens pay for the crimes of others.</verse>
<verse>The one who knows much says little; an understanding person remains calm.</verse>
<verse>Even dunces who keep quiet are thought to be wise; as long as they keep their mouths shut, they're smart.</verse>
</chapter>