<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Proverbs" book-id="20" n="18">
<verse>Loners who care only for themselves spit on the common good.</verse>
<verse>Fools care nothing for thoughtful discourse; all they do is run off at the mouth.</verse>
<verse>When wickedness arrives, shame's not far behind; contempt for life is contemptible.</verse>
<verse>Many words rush along like rivers in flood, but deep wisdom flows up from artesian springs.</verse>
<verse>It's not right to go easy on the guilty, or come down hard on the innocent.</verse>
<verse>The words of a fool start fights; do him a favor and gag him.</verse>
<verse>Fools are undone by their big mouths; their souls are crushed by their words.</verse>
<verse>Listening to gossip is like eating cheap candy; do you really want junk like that in your belly?</verse>
<verse>Slack habits and sloppy work are as bad as vandalism.</verse>
<verse>GOD's name is a place of protection--good people can run there and be safe.</verse>
<verse>The rich think their wealth protects them; they imagine themselves safe behind it.</verse>
<verse>Pride first, then the crash, but humility is precursor to honor.</verse>
<verse>Answering before listening is both stupid and rude.</verse>
<verse>A healthy spirit conquers adversity, but what can you do when the spirit is crushed?</verse>
<verse>Wise men and women are always learning, always listening for fresh insights.</verse>
<verse>A gift gets attention; it buys the attention of eminent people.</verse>
<verse>The first speech in a court case is always convincing--until the cross-examination starts!</verse>
<verse>You may have to draw straws when faced with a tough decision.</verse>
<verse>Do a favor and win a friend forever; nothing can untie that bond.</verse>
<verse>Words satisfy the mind as much as fruit does the stomach; good talk is as gratifying as a good harvest.</verse>
<verse>Words kill, words give life; they're either poison or fruit--you choose.</verse>
<verse>Find a good spouse, you find a good life--and even more: the favor of GOD!</verse>
<verse>The poor speak in soft supplications; the rich bark out answers.</verse>
<verse>Friends come and friends go, but a true friend sticks by you like family.</verse>
</chapter>