<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Proverbs" book-id="20" n="19">
<verse>Better to be poor and honest than a rich person no one can trust.</verse>
<verse>Ignorant zeal is worthless; haste makes waste.</verse>
<verse>People ruin their lives by their own stupidity, so why does GOD always get blamed?</verse>
<verse>Wealth attracts friends as honey draws flies, but poor people are avoided like a plague.</verse>
<verse>Perjury won't go unpunished. Would you let a liar go free?</verse>
<verse>Lots of people flock around a generous person; everyone's a friend to the philanthropist.</verse>
<verse>When you're down on your luck, even your family avoids you--yes, even your best friends wish you'd get lost. If they see you coming, they look the other way--out of sight, out of mind.</verse>
<verse>Grow a wise heart--you'll do yourself a favor; keep a clear head--you'll find a good life.</verse>
<verse>The person who tells lies gets caught; the person who spreads rumors is ruined.</verse>
<verse>Blockheads shouldn't live on easy street any more than workers should give orders to their boss.</verse>
<verse>Smart people know how to hold their tongue; their grandeur is to forgive and forget.</verse>
<verse>Mean-tempered leaders are like mad dogs; the good-natured are like fresh morning dew.</verse>
<verse>A parent is worn to a frazzle by a stupid child; a nagging spouse is a leaky faucet.</verse>
<verse>House and land are handed down from parents, but a congenial spouse comes straight from GOD.</verse>
<verse>Life collapses on loafers; lazybones go hungry.</verse>
<verse>Keep the rules and keep your life; careless living kills.</verse>
<verse>Mercy to the needy is a loan to GOD, and GOD pays back those loans in full.</verse>
<verse>Discipline your children while you still have the chance; indulging them destroys them.</verse>
<verse>Let angry people endure the backlash of their own anger; if you try to make it better, you'll only make it worse.</verse>
<verse>Take good counsel and accept correction--that's the way to live wisely and well.</verse>
<verse>We humans keep brainstorming options and plans, but GOD's purpose prevails.</verse>
<verse>It's only human to want to make a buck, but it's better to be poor than a liar.</verse>
<verse>Fear-of-GOD is life itself, a full life, and serene--no nasty surprises.</verse>
<verse>Some people dig a fork into the pie but are too lazy to raise it to their mouth.</verse>
<verse>Punish the insolent--make an example of them. Who knows? Somebody might learn a good lesson.</verse>
<verse>Kids who lash out against their parents are an embarrassment and disgrace.</verse>
<verse>If you quit listening, dear child, and strike off on your own, you'll soon be out of your depth.</verse>
<verse>An unprincipled witness desecrates justice; the mouths of the wicked spew malice.</verse>
<verse>The irreverent have to learn reverence the hard way; only a slap in the face brings fools to attention.</verse>
</chapter>