<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Proverbs" book_id="20" n="2">
<verse>Good friend, take to heart what I'm telling you; collect my counsels and guard them with your life.</verse>
<verse>Tune your ears to the world of Wisdom; set your heart on a life of Understanding.</verse>
<verse>That's right--if you make Insight your priority, and won't take no for an answer,</verse>
<verse>Searching for it like a prospector panning for gold, like an adventurer on a treasure hunt,</verse>
<verse>Believe me, before you know it Fear-of-GOD will be yours; you'll have come upon the Knowledge of God.</verse>
<verse>And here's why: GOD gives out Wisdom free, is plainspoken in Knowledge and Understanding.</verse>
<verse>He's a rich mine of Common Sense for those who live well, a personal bodyguard to the candid and sincere.</verse>
<verse>He keeps his eye on all who live honestly, and pays special attention to his loyally committed ones.</verse>
<verse>So now you can pick out what's true and fair, find all the good trails!</verse>
<verse>Lady Wisdom will be your close friend, and Brother Knowledge your pleasant companion.</verse>
<verse>Good Sense will scout ahead for danger, Insight will keep an eye out for you.</verse>
<verse>They'll keep you from making wrong turns, or following the bad directions</verse>
<verse>Of those who are lost themselves and can't tell a trail from a tumbleweed,</verse>
<verse>These losers who make a game of evil and throw parties to celebrate perversity,</verse>
<verse>Traveling paths that go nowhere, wandering in a maze of detours and dead ends.</verse>
<verse>Wise friends will rescue you from the Temptress--that smooth-talking Seductress</verse>
<verse>Who's faithless to the husband she married years ago, never gave a second thought to her promises before God.</verse>
<verse>Her whole way of life is doomed; every step she takes brings her closer to hell.</verse>
<verse>No one who joins her company ever comes back, ever sets foot on the path to real living.</verse>
<verse>So--join the company of good men and women, keep your feet on the tried and true paths.</verse>
<verse>It's the men who walk straight who will settle this land, the women with integrity who will last here.</verse>
<verse>The corrupt will lose their lives; the dishonest will be gone for good.</verse>
</chapter>