<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Proverbs" book_id="20" n="20">
<verse>Wine makes you mean, beer makes you quarrelsome--a staggering drunk is not much fun.</verse>
<verse>Quick-tempered leaders are like mad dogs--cross them and they bite your head off.</verse>
<verse>It's a mark of good character to avert quarrels, but fools love to pick fights.</verse>
<verse>A farmer too lazy to plant in the spring has nothing to harvest in the fall.</verse>
<verse>Knowing what is right is like deep water in the heart; a wise person draws from the well within.</verse>
<verse>Lots of people claim to be loyal and loving, but where on earth can you find one?</verse>
<verse>God-loyal people, living honest lives, make it much easier for their children.</verse>
<verse>Leaders who know their business and care keep a sharp eye out for the shoddy and cheap,</verse>
<verse>For who among us can be trusted to be always diligent and honest?</verse>
<verse>Switching price tags and padding the expense account are two things GOD hates.</verse>
<verse>Young people eventually reveal by their actions if their motives are on the up and up.</verse>
<verse>Ears that hear and eyes that see--we get our basic equipment from GOD!</verse>
<verse>Don't be too fond of sleep; you'll end up in the poorhouse. Wake up and get up; then there'll be food on the table.</verse>
<verse>The shopper says, "That's junk--I'll take it off your hands," then goes off boasting of the bargain.</verse>
<verse>Drinking from the beautiful chalice of knowledge is better than adorning oneself with gold and rare gems.</verse>
<verse>Hold tight to collateral on any loan to a stranger; beware of accepting what a transient has pawned.</verse>
<verse>Stolen bread tastes sweet, but soon your mouth is full of gravel.</verse>
<verse>Form your purpose by asking for counsel, then carry it out using all the help you can get.</verse>
<verse>Gossips can't keep secrets, so never confide in blabbermouths.</verse>
<verse>Anyone who curses father and mother extinguishes light and exists benighted.</verse>
<verse>A bonanza at the beginning is no guarantee of blessing at the end.</verse>
<verse>Don't ever say, "I'll get you for that!" Wait for GOD; he'll settle the score.</verse>
<verse>GOD hates cheating in the marketplace; rigged scales are an outrage.</verse>
<verse>The very steps we take come from GOD; otherwise how would we know where we're going?</verse>
<verse>An impulsive vow is a trap; later you'll wish you could get out of it.</verse>
<verse>After careful scrutiny, a wise leader makes a clean sweep of rebels and dolts.</verse>
<verse>GOD is in charge of human life, watching and examining us inside and out.</verse>
<verse>Love and truth form a good leader; sound leadership is founded on loving integrity.</verse>
<verse>Youth may be admired for vigor, but gray hair gives prestige to old age.</verse>
<verse>A good thrashing purges evil; punishment goes deep within us.</verse>
</chapter>