<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Proverbs" book-id="20" n="21">
<verse>Good leadership is a channel of water controlled by God; he directs it to whatever ends he chooses.</verse>
<verse>We justify our actions by appearances; GOD examines our motives.</verse>
<verse>Clean living before God and justice with our neighbors mean far more to GOD than religious performance.</verse>
<verse>Arrogance and pride--distinguishing marks in the wicked--are just plain sin.</verse>
<verse>Careful planning puts you ahead in the long run; hurry and scurry puts you further behind.</verse>
<verse>Make it to the top by lying and cheating; get paid with smoke and a promotion--to death!</verse>
<verse>The wicked get buried alive by their loot because they refuse to use it to help others.</verse>
<verse>Mixed motives twist life into tangles; pure motives take you straight down the road.</verse>
<verse>Better to live alone in a tumbledown shack than share a mansion with a nagging spouse.</verse>
<verse>Wicked souls love to make trouble; they feel nothing for friends and neighbors.</verse>
<verse>Simpletons only learn the hard way, but the wise learn by listening.</verse>
<verse>A God-loyal person will see right through the wicked and undo the evil they've planned.</verse>
<verse>If you stop your ears to the cries of the poor, your cries will go unheard, unanswered.</verse>
<verse>A quietly given gift soothes an irritable person; a heartfelt present cools a hot temper.</verse>
<verse>Good people celebrate when justice triumphs, but for the workers of evil it's a bad day.</verse>
<verse>Whoever wanders off the straight and narrow ends up in a congregation of ghosts.</verse>
<verse>You're addicted to thrills? What an empty life! The pursuit of pleasure is never satisfied.</verse>
<verse>What a bad person plots against the good, boomerangs; the plotter gets it in the end.</verse>
<verse>Better to live in a tent in the wild than with a cross and petulant spouse.</verse>
<verse>Valuables are safe in a wise person's home; fools put it all out for yard sales.</verse>
<verse>Whoever goes hunting for what is right and kind bfinds life itself--glorious life!</verse>
<verse>One sage entered a whole city of armed soldiers--their trusted defenses fell to pieces!</verse>
<verse>Watch your words and hold your tongue; you'll save yourself a lot of grief.</verse>
<verse>You know their names--Brash, Impudent, Blasphemer--intemperate hotheads, every one.</verse>
<verse>Lazy people finally die of hunger because they won't get up and go to work.</verse>
<verse>Sinners are always wanting what they don't have; the God-loyal are always giving what they do have.</verse>
<verse>Religious performance by the wicked stinks; it's even worse when they use it to get ahead.</verse>
<verse>A lying witness is unconvincing; a person who speaks truth is respected.</verse>
<verse>Unscrupulous people fake it a lot; honest people are sure of their steps.</verse>
<verse>Nothing clever, nothing conceived, nothing contrived, can get the better of GOD.</verse>
<verse>Do your best, prepare for the worst--then trust GOD to bring victory.</verse>
</chapter>