<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Proverbs" book_id="20" n="22">
<verse>A sterling reputation is better than striking it rich; a gracious spirit is better than money in the bank.</verse>
<verse>The rich and the poor shake hands as equals--GOD made them both!</verse>
<verse>A prudent person sees trouble coming and ducks; a simpleton walks in blindly and is clobbered.</verse>
<verse>The payoff for meekness and Fear-of-GOD is plenty and honor and a satisfying life.</verse>
<verse>The perverse travel a dangerous road, potholed and mud-slick; if you know what's good for you, stay clear of it.</verse>
<verse>Point your kids in the right direction--when they're old they won't be lost.</verse>
<verse>The poor are always ruled over by the rich, so don't borrow and put yourself under their power.</verse>
<verse>Whoever sows sin reaps weeds, and bullying anger sputters into nothing.</verse>
<verse>Generous hands are blessed hands because they give bread to the poor.</verse>
<verse>Kick out the troublemakers and things will quiet down; you need a break from bickering and griping!</verse>
<verse>GOD loves the pure-hearted and well-spoken; good leaders also delight in their friendship.</verse>
<verse>GOD guards knowledge with a passion, but he'll have nothing to do with deception.</verse>
<verse>The loafer says, "There's a lion on the loose! If I go out I'll be eaten alive!"</verse>
<verse>The mouth of a whore is a bottomless pit; you'll fall in that pit if you're on the outs with GOD.</verse>
<verse>Young people are prone to foolishness and fads; the cure comes through tough-minded discipline.</verse>
<verse>Exploit the poor or glad-hand the rich--whichever, you'll end up the poorer for it. The Thirty Precepts of the Sages Don't Move Back the Boundary Lines</verse>
<verse>Listen carefully to my wisdom; take to heart what I can teach you. You'll treasure its sweetness deep within;</verse>
<verse>you'll give it bold expression in your speech.</verse>
<verse>To make sure your foundation is trust in GOD, I'm laying it all out right now just for you.</verse>
<verse>I'm giving you thirty sterling principles--tested guidelines to live by.</verse>
<verse>Believe me--these are truths that work, and will keep you accountable to those who sent you.</verse>
<verse>Don't walk on the poor just because they're poor, and don't use your position to crush the weak,</verse>
<verse>Because GOD will come to their defense; the life you took, he'll take from you and give back to them.</verse>
<verse>Don't hang out with angry people; don't keep company with hotheads.</verse>
<verse>Bad temper is contagious--don't get infected.</verse>
<verse>Don't gamble on the pot of gold at the end of the rainbow, hocking your house against a lucky chance.</verse>
<verse>The time will come when you have to pay up; you'll be left with nothing but the shirt on your back.</verse>
<verse>Don't stealthily move back the boundary lines staked out long ago by your ancestors.</verse>
<verse>Observe people who are good at their work--skilled workers are always in demand and admired; they don't take a back seat to anyone.</verse>
</chapter>