<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Proverbs" book-id="20" n="23">
<verse>When you go out to dinner with an influential person, mind your manners:</verse>
<verse>Don't gobble your food, don't talk with your mouth full.</verse>
<verse>And don't stuff yourself; bridle your appetite.</verse>
<verse>Don't wear yourself out trying to get rich; restrain yourself!</verse>
<verse>Riches disappear in the blink of an eye; wealth sprouts wings and flies off into the wild blue yonder.</verse>
<verse>Don't accept a meal from a tightwad; don't expect anything special.</verse>
<verse>He'll be as stingy with you as he is with himself; he'll say, "Eat! Drink!" but won't mean a word of it.</verse>
<verse>His miserly serving will turn your stomach when you realize the meal's a sham.</verse>
<verse>Don't bother talking sense to fools; they'll only poke fun at your words.</verse>
<verse>Don't stealthily move back the boundary lines or cheat orphans out of their property,</verse>
<verse>For they have a powerful Advocate who will go to bat for them.</verse>
<verse>Give yourselves to disciplined instruction; open your ears to tested knowledge.</verse>
<verse>Don't be afraid to correct your young ones; a spanking won't kill them.</verse>
<verse>A good spanking, in fact, might save them from something worse than death.</verse>
<verse>Dear child, if you become wise, I'll be one happy parent.</verse>
<verse>My heart will dance and sing to the tuneful truth you'll speak.</verse>
<verse>Don't for a minute envy careless rebels; soak yourself in the Fear-of-GOD-</verse>
<verse>That's where your future lies. Then you won't be left with an armload of nothing.</verse>
<verse>Oh listen, dear child--become wise; point your life in the right direction.</verse>
<verse>Don't drink too much wine and get drunk; don't eat too much food and get fat.</verse>
<verse>Drunks and gluttons will end up on skid row, in a stupor and dressed in rags.</verse>
<verse>Listen with respect to the father who raised you, and when your mother grows old, don't neglect her.</verse>
<verse>Buy truth--don't sell it for love or money; buy wisdom, buy education, buy insight.</verse>
<verse>Parents rejoice when their children turn out well; wise children become proud parents.</verse>
<verse>So make your father happy! Make your mother proud!</verse>
<verse>Dear child, I want your full attention; please do what I show you.</verse>
<verse>A whore is a bottomless pit; a loose woman can get you in deep trouble fast.</verse>
<verse>She'll take you for all you've got; she's worse than a pack of thieves.</verse>
<verse>Who are the people who are always crying the blues? Who do you know who reeks of self-pity? Who keeps getting beat up for no reason at all? Whose eyes are bleary and bloodshot?</verse>
<verse>It's those who spend the night with a bottle, for whom drinking is serious business.</verse>
<verse>Don't judge wine by its label, or its bouquet, or its full-bodied flavor.</verse>
<verse>Judge it rather by the hangover it leaves you with--the splitting headache, the queasy stomach.</verse>
<verse>Do you really prefer seeing double, with your speech all slurred,</verse>
<verse>Reeling and seasick, drunk as a sailor?</verse>
<verse>"They hit me," you'll say, "but it didn't hurt; they beat on me, but I didn't feel a thing. When I'm sober enough to manage it, bring me another drink!"</verse>
</chapter>