<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Proverbs" book-id="20" n="24">
<verse>Don't envy bad people; don't even want to be around them.</verse>
<verse>All they think about is causing a disturbance; all they talk about is making trouble.</verse>
<verse>It takes wisdom to build a house, and understanding to set it on a firm foundation;</verse>
<verse>It takes knowledge to furnish its rooms with fine furniture and beautiful draperies.</verse>
<verse>It's better to be wise than strong; intelligence outranks muscle any day.</verse>
<verse>Strategic planning is the key to warfare; to win, you need a lot of good counsel.</verse>
<verse>Wise conversation is way over the head of fools; in a serious discussion they haven't a clue.</verse>
<verse>The person who's always cooking up some evil soon gets a reputation as prince of rogues.</verse>
<verse>Fools incubate sin; cynics desecrate beauty.</verse>
<verse>If you fall to pieces in a crisis, there wasn't much to you in the first place.</verse>
<verse>Rescue the perishing; don't hesitate to step in and help.</verse>
<verse>If you say, "Hey, that's none of my business," will that get you off the hook? Someone is watching you closely, you know--Someone not impressed with weak excuses.</verse>
<verse>Eat honey, dear child--it's good for you--and delicacies that melt in your mouth.</verse>
<verse>Likewise knowledge, and wisdom for your soul--Get that and your future's secured, your hope is on solid rock.</verse>
<verse>Don't interfere with good people's lives; don't try to get the best of them.</verse>
<verse>No matter how many times you trip them up, God-loyal people don't stay down long; Soon they're up on their feet, while the wicked end up flat on their faces.</verse>
<verse>Don't laugh when your enemy falls; don't crow over his collapse.</verse>
<verse>GOD might see, and become very provoked, and then take pity on his plight.</verse>
<verse>Don't bother your head with braggarts or wish you could succeed like the wicked.</verse>
<verse>Those people have no future at all; they're headed down a dead-end street.</verse>
<verse>Fear GOD, dear child--respect your leaders; don't be defiant or mutinous.</verse>
<verse>Without warning your life can turn upside-down, and who knows how or when it might happen? More Sayings of the Wise</verse>
<verse>It's wrong, very wrong, to go along with injustice.</verse>
<verse>Whoever whitewashes the wicked gets a black mark in the history books,</verse>
<verse>But whoever exposes the wicked will be thanked and rewarded.</verse>
<verse>An honest answer is like a warm hug.</verse>
<verse>First plant your fields; then build your barn.</verse>
<verse>Don't talk about your neighbors behind their backs--no slander or gossip, please.</verse>
<verse>Don't say to anyone, "I'll get back at you for what you did to me. I'll make you pay for what you did!"</verse>
<verse>One day I walked by the field of an old lazybones, and then passed the vineyard of a lout;</verse>
<verse>They were overgrown with weeds, thick with thistles, all the fences broken down.</verse>
<verse>I took a long look and pondered what I saw; the fields preached me a sermon and I listened:</verse>
<verse>"A nap here, a nap there, a day off here, a day off there, sit back, take it easy--do you know what comes next?</verse>
<verse>Just this: You can look forward to a dirt-poor life, with poverty as your permanent houseguest!" Further Wise Sayings of Solomon The Right Word at the Right Time</verse>
</chapter>