<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Proverbs" book-id="20" n="25">
<verse>There are also these proverbs of Solomon, collected by scribes of Hezekiah, king of Judah.</verse>
<verse>God delights in concealing things; scientists delight in discovering things.</verse>
<verse>Like the horizons for breadth and the ocean for depth, the understanding of a good leader is broad and deep.</verse>
<verse>Remove impurities from the silver and the silversmith can craft a fine chalice;</verse>
<verse>Remove the wicked from leadership and authority will be credible and God-honoring.</verse>
<verse>Don't work yourself into the spotlight; don't push your way into the place of prominence.</verse>
<verse>It's better to be promoted to a place of honor than face humiliation by being demoted.</verse>
<verse>Don't jump to conclusions--there may be a perfectly good explanation for what you just saw.</verse>
<verse>In the heat of an argument, don't betray confidences;</verse>
<verse>Word is sure to get around, and no one will trust you.</verse>
<verse>The right word at the right time is like a custom-made piece of jewelry,</verse>
<verse>And a wise friend's timely reprimand is like a gold ring slipped on your finger.</verse>
<verse>Reliable friends who do what they say are like cool drinks in sweltering heat--refreshing!</verse>
<verse>Like billowing clouds that bring no rain is the person who talks big but never produces.</verse>
<verse>Patient persistence pierces through indifference; gentle speech breaks down rigid defenses.</verse>
<verse>When you're given a box of candy, don't gulp it all down; eat too much chocolate and you'll make yourself sick;</verse>
<verse>And when you find a friend, don't outwear your welcome; show up at all hours and he'll soon get fed up.</verse>
<verse>Anyone who tells lies against the neighbors in court or on the street is a loose cannon.</verse>
<verse>Trusting a double-crosser when you're in trouble is like biting down on an abscessed tooth.</verse>
<verse>Singing light songs to the heavyhearted is like pouring salt in their wounds.</verse>
<verse>If you see your enemy hungry, go buy him lunch; if he's thirsty, bring him a drink.</verse>
<verse>Your generosity will surprise him with goodness, and GOD will look after you.</verse>
<verse>A north wind brings stormy weather, and a gossipy tongue stormy looks.</verse>
<verse>Better to live alone in a tumbledown shack than share a mansion with a nagging spouse.</verse>
<verse>Like a cool drink of water when you're worn out and weary is a letter from a long-lost friend.</verse>
<verse>A good person who gives in to a bad person is a muddied spring, a polluted well.</verse>
<verse>It's not smart to stuff yourself with sweets, nor is glory piled on glory good for you.</verse>
<verse>A person without self-control is like a house with its doors and windows knocked out.</verse>
</chapter>