<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Proverbs" book-id="20" n="26">
<verse>We no more give honors to fools than pray for snow in summer or rain during harvest.</verse>
<verse>You have as little to fear from an undeserved curse as from the dart of a wren or the swoop of a swallow.</verse>
<verse>A whip for the racehorse, a tiller for the sailboat--and a stick for the back of fools!</verse>
<verse>Don't respond to the stupidity of a fool; you'll only look foolish yourself.</verse>
<verse>Answer a fool in simple terms so he doesn't get a swelled head.</verse>
<verse>You're only asking for trouble when you send a message by a fool.</verse>
<verse>A proverb quoted by fools is limp as a wet noodle.</verse>
<verse>Putting a fool in a place of honor is like setting a mud brick on a marble column.</verse>
<verse>To ask a moron to quote a proverb is like putting a scalpel in the hands of a drunk.</verse>
<verse>Hire a fool or a drunk and you shoot yourself in the foot.</verse>
<verse>As a dog eats its own vomit, so fools recycle silliness.</verse>
<verse>See that man who thinks he's so smart? You can expect far more from a fool than from him.</verse>
<verse>Loafers say, "It's dangerous out there! Tigers are prowling the streets!" and then pull the covers back over their heads.</verse>
<verse>Just as a door turns on its hinges, so a lazybones turns back over in bed.</verse>
<verse>A shiftless sluggard puts his fork in the pie, but is too lazy to lift it to his mouth.</verse>
<verse>Dreamers fantasize their self-importance; they think they are smarter than a whole college faculty.</verse>
<verse>You grab a mad dog by the ears when you butt into a quarrel that's none of your business.</verse>
<verse>People who shrug off deliberate deceptions, saying, "I didn't mean it, I was only joking,"</verse>
<verse>Are worse than careless campers who walk away from smoldering campfires.</verse>
<verse>When you run out of wood, the fire goes out; when the gossip ends, the quarrel dies down.</verse>
<verse>A quarrelsome person in a dispute is like kerosene thrown on a fire.</verse>
<verse>Listening to gossip is like eating cheap candy; do you want junk like that in your belly?</verse>
<verse>Smooth talk from an evil heart is like glaze on cracked pottery.</verse>
<verse>Your enemy shakes hands and greets you like an old friend, all the while conniving against you.</verse>
<verse>When he speaks warmly to you, don't believe him for a minute; he's just waiting for the chance to rip you off.</verse>
<verse>No matter how cunningly he conceals his malice, eventually his evil will be exposed in public.</verse>
<verse>Malice backfires; spite boomerangs.</verse>
<verse>Liars hate their victims; flatterers sabotage trust.</verse>
</chapter>