<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Proverbs" book-id="20" n="27">
<verse>Don't brashly announce what you're going to do tomorrow; you don't know the first thing about tomorrow.</verse>
<verse>Don't call attention to yourself; let others do that for you.</verse>
<verse>Carrying a log across your shoulders while you're hefting a boulder with your arms Is nothing compared to the burden of putting up with a fool.</verse>
<verse>We're blasted by anger and swamped by rage, but who can survive jealousy?</verse>
<verse>A spoken reprimand is better than approval that's never expressed.</verse>
<verse>The wounds from a lover are worth it; kisses from an enemy do you in.</verse>
<verse>When you've stuffed yourself, you refuse dessert; when you're starved, you could eat a horse.</verse>
<verse>People who won't settle down, wandering hither and yon, are like restless birds, flitting to and fro.</verse>
<verse>Just as lotions and fragrance give sensual delight, a sweet friendship refreshes the soul.</verse>
<verse>Don't leave your friends or your parents' friends and run home to your family when things get rough; Better a nearby friend than a distant family.</verse>
<verse>Become wise, dear child, and make me happy; then nothing the world throws my way will upset me.</verse>
<verse>A prudent person sees trouble coming and ducks; a simpleton walks in blindly and is clobbered.</verse>
<verse>Hold tight to collateral on any loan to a stranger; be wary of accepting what a transient has pawned.</verse>
<verse>If you wake your friend in the early morning by shouting "Rise and shine!" It will sound to him more like a curse than a blessing.</verse>
<verse>A nagging spouse is like the drip, drip, drip of a leaky faucet;</verse>
<verse>You can't turn it off, and you can't get away from it.</verse>
<verse>You use steel to sharpen steel, and one friend sharpens another.</verse>
<verse>If you care for your orchard, you'll enjoy its fruit; if you honor your boss, you'll be honored.</verse>
<verse>Just as water mirrors your face, so your face mirrors your heart.</verse>
<verse>Hell has a voracious appetite, and lust just never quits.</verse>
<verse>The purity of silver and gold is tested by putting them in the fire; The purity of human hearts is tested by giving them a little fame.</verse>
<verse>Pound on a fool all you like--you can't pound out foolishness.</verse>
<verse>Know your sheep by name; carefully attend to your flocks;</verse>
<verse>(Don't take them for granted; possessions don't last forever, you know.)</verse>
<verse>And then, when the crops are in and the harvest is stored in the barns,</verse>
<verse>You can knit sweaters from lambs' wool, and sell your goats for a profit;</verse>
<verse>There will be plenty of milk and meat to last your family through the winter.</verse>
</chapter>