<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Proverbs" book_id="20" n="28">
<verse>The wicked are edgy with guilt, ready to run off even when no one's after them; Honest people are relaxed and confident, bold as lions.</verse>
<verse>When the country is in chaos, everybody has a plan to fix it--But it takes a leader of real understanding to straighten things out.</verse>
<verse>The wicked who oppress the poor are like a hailstorm that beats down the harvest.</verse>
<verse>If you desert God's law, you're free to embrace depravity; if you love God's law, you fight for it tooth and nail.</verse>
<verse>Justice makes no sense to the evilminded; those who seek GOD know it inside and out.</verse>
<verse>It's better to be poor and direct than rich and crooked.</verse>
<verse>Practice God's law--get a reputation for wisdom; hang out with a loose crowd--embarrass your family.</verse>
<verse>Get as rich as you want through cheating and extortion, But eventually some friend of the poor is going to give it all back to them.</verse>
<verse>God has no use for the prayers of the people who won't listen to him.</verse>
<verse>Lead good people down a wrong path and you'll come to a bad end; do good and you'll be rewarded for it.</verse>
<verse>The rich think they know it all, but the poor can see right through them.</verse>
<verse>When good people are promoted, everything is great, but when the bad are in charge, watch out!</verse>
<verse>You can't whitewash your sins and get by with it; you find mercy by admitting and leaving them.</verse>
<verse>A tenderhearted person lives a blessed life; a hardhearted person lives a hard life.</verse>
<verse>Lions roar and bears charge--and the wicked lord it over the poor.</verse>
<verse>Among leaders who lack insight, abuse abounds, but for one who hates corruption, the future is bright.</verse>
<verse>A murderer haunted by guilt is doomed--there's no helping him.</verse>
<verse>Walk straight--live well and be saved; a devious life is a doomed life.</verse>
<verse>Work your garden--you'll end up with plenty of food; play and party--you'll end up with an empty plate.</verse>
<verse>Committed and persistent work pays off; get-rich-quick schemes are ripoffs.</verse>
<verse>Playing favorites is always a bad thing; you can do great harm in seemingly harmless ways.</verse>
<verse>A miser in a hurry to get rich doesn't know that he'll end up broke.</verse>
<verse>In the end, serious reprimand is appreciated far more than bootlicking flattery.</verse>
<verse>Anyone who robs father and mother and says, "So, what's wrong with that?" is worse than a pirate.</verse>
<verse>A grasping person stirs up trouble, but trust in GOD brings a sense of well-being.</verse>
<verse>If you think you know it all, you're a fool for sure; real survivors learn wisdom from others.</verse>
<verse>Be generous to the poor--you'll never go hungry; shut your eyes to their needs, and run a gauntlet of curses.</verse>
<verse>When corruption takes over, good people go underground, but when the crooks are thrown out, it's safe to come out.</verse>
</chapter>