<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Proverbs" book-id="20" n="29">
<verse>For people who hate discipline and only get more stubborn, There'll come a day when life tumbles in and they break, but by then it'll be too late to help them.</verse>
<verse>When good people run things, everyone is glad, but when the ruler is bad, everyone groans.</verse>
<verse>If you love wisdom, you'll delight your parents, but you'll destroy their trust if you run with whores.</verse>
<verse>A leader of good judgment gives stability; an exploiting leader leaves a trail of waste.</verse>
<verse>A flattering neighbor is up to no good; he's probably planning to take advantage of you.</verse>
<verse>Evil people fall into their own traps; good people run the other way, glad to escape.</verse>
<verse>The good-hearted understand what it's like to be poor; the hardhearted haven't the faintest idea.</verse>
<verse>A gang of cynics can upset a whole city; a group of sages can calm everyone down.</verse>
<verse>A sage trying to work things out with a fool gets only scorn and sarcasm for his trouble.</verse>
<verse>Murderers hate honest people; moral folks encourage them.</verse>
<verse>A fool lets it all hang out; a sage quietly mulls it over.</verse>
<verse>When a leader listens to malicious gossip, all the workers get infected with evil.</verse>
<verse>The poor and their abusers have at least something in common: they can both see--their sight, GOD's gift!</verse>
<verse>Leadership gains authority and respect when the voiceless poor are treated fairly.</verse>
<verse>Wise discipline imparts wisdom; spoiled adolescents embarrass their parents.</verse>
<verse>When degenerates take charge, crime runs wild, but the righteous will eventually observe their collapse.</verse>
<verse>Discipline your children; you'll be glad you did--they'll turn out delightful to live with.</verse>
<verse>If people can't see what God is doing, they stumble all over themselves; But when they attend to what he reveals, they are most blessed.</verse>
<verse>It takes more than talk to keep workers in line; mere words go in one ear and out the other.</verse>
<verse>Observe the people who always talk before they think--even simpletons are better off than they are.</verse>
<verse>If you let people treat you like a doormat, you'll be quite forgotten in the end.</verse>
<verse>Angry people stir up a lot of discord; the intemperate stir up trouble.</verse>
<verse>Pride lands you flat on your face; humility prepares you for honors.</verse>
<verse>Befriend an outlaw and become an enemy to yourself. When the victims cry out, you'll be included in their curses if you're a coward to their cause in court.</verse>
<verse>The fear of human opinion disables; trusting in GOD protects you from that.</verse>
<verse>Everyone tries to get help from the leader, but only GOD will give us justice.</verse>
<verse>Good people can't stand the sight of deliberate evil; the wicked can't stand the sight of well-chosen goodness. The Words of Agur Ben Yakeh God? Who Needs Him?</verse>
</chapter>