<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Proverbs" book-id="20" n="3">
<verse>Good friend, don't forget all I've taught you; take to heart my commands.</verse>
<verse>They'll help you live a long, long time, a long life lived full and well.</verse>
<verse>Don't lose your grip on Love and Loyalty. Tie them around your neck; carve their initials on your heart.</verse>
<verse>Earn a reputation for living well in God's eyes and the eyes of the people.</verse>
<verse>Trust GOD from the bottom of your heart; don't try to figure out everything on your own.</verse>
<verse>Listen for GOD's voice in everything you do, everywhere you go; he's the one who will keep you on track.</verse>
<verse>Don't assume that you know it all. Run to GOD! Run from evil!</verse>
<verse>Your body will glow with health, your very bones will vibrate with life!</verse>
<verse>Honor GOD with everything you own; give him the first and the best.</verse>
<verse>Your barns will burst, your wine vats will brim over.</verse>
<verse>But don't, dear friend, resent GOD's discipline; don't sulk under his loving correction.</verse>
<verse>It's the child he loves that GOD corrects; a father's delight is behind all this.</verse>
<verse>You're blessed when you meet Lady Wisdom, when you make friends with Madame Insight.</verse>
<verse>She's worth far more than money in the bank; her friendship is better than a big salary.</verse>
<verse>Her value exceeds all the trappings of wealth; nothing you could wish for holds a candle to her.</verse>
<verse>With one hand she gives long life, with the other she confers recognition.</verse>
<verse>Her manner is beautiful, her life wonderfully complete.</verse>
<verse>She's the very Tree of Life to those who embrace her. Hold her tight--and be blessed!</verse>
<verse>With Lady Wisdom, GOD formed Earth; with Madame Insight, he raised Heaven.</verse>
<verse>They knew when to signal rivers and springs to the surface, and dew to descend from the night skies.</verse>
<verse>Dear friend, guard Clear Thinking and Common Sense with your life; don't for a minute lose sight of them.</verse>
<verse>They'll keep your soul alive and well, they'll keep you fit and attractive.</verse>
<verse>You'll travel safely, you'll neither tire nor trip.</verse>
<verse>You'll take afternoon naps without a worry, you'll enjoy a good night's sleep.</verse>
<verse>No need to panic over alarms or surprises, or predictions that doomsday's just around the corner,</verse>
<verse>Because GOD will be right there with you; he'll keep you safe and sound.</verse>
<verse>Never walk away from someone who deserves help; your hand is God's hand for that person.</verse>
<verse>Don't tell your neighbor, "Maybe some other time," or, "Try me tomorrow," when the money's right there in your pocket.</verse>
<verse>Don't figure ways of taking advantage of your neighbor when he's sitting there trusting and unsuspecting.</verse>
<verse>Don't walk around with a chip on your shoulder, always spoiling for a fight.</verse>
<verse>Don't try to be like those who shoulder their way through life. Why be a bully?</verse>
<verse>"Why not?" you say. Because GOD can't stand twisted souls. It's the straightforward who get his respect.</verse>
<verse>GOD's curse blights the house of the wicked, but he blesses the home of the righteous.</verse>
<verse>He gives proud skeptics a cold shoulder, but if you're down on your luck, he's right there to help.</verse>
<verse>Wise living gets rewarded with honor; stupid living gets the booby prize.</verse>
</chapter>