<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Proverbs" book_id="20" n="31">
<verse>The words of King Lemuel, the strong advice his mother gave him:</verse>
<verse>"Oh, son of mine, what can you be thinking of! Child whom I bore! The son I dedicated to God!</verse>
<verse>Don't dissipate your virility on fortune-hunting women, promiscuous women who shipwreck leaders.</verse>
<verse>"Leaders can't afford to make fools of themselves, gulping wine and swilling beer,</verse>
<verse>Lest, hung over, they don't know right from wrong, and the people who depend on them are hurt.</verse>
<verse>Use wine and beer only as sedatives, to kill the pain and dull the ache</verse>
<verse>Of the terminally ill, for whom life is a living death.</verse>
<verse>"Speak up for the people who have no voice, for the rights of all the down-and-outers.</verse>
<verse>Speak out for justice! Stand up for the poor and destitute!"</verse>
<verse>A good woman is hard to find, and worth far more than diamonds.</verse>
<verse>Her husband trusts her without reserve, and never has reason to regret it.</verse>
<verse>Never spiteful, she treats him generously all her life long.</verse>
<verse>She shops around for the best yarns and cottons, and enjoys knitting and sewing.</verse>
<verse>She's like a trading ship that sails to faraway places and brings back exotic surprises.</verse>
<verse>She's up before dawn, preparing breakfast for her family and organizing her day.</verse>
<verse>She looks over a field and buys it, then, with money she's put aside, plants a garden.</verse>
<verse>First thing in the morning, she dresses for work, rolls up her sleeves, eager to get started.</verse>
<verse>She senses the worth of her work, is in no hurry to call it quits for the day.</verse>
<verse>She's skilled in the crafts of home and hearth, diligent in homemaking.</verse>
<verse>She's quick to assist anyone in need, reaches out to help the poor.</verse>
<verse>She doesn't worry about her family when it snows; their winter clothes are all mended and ready to wear.</verse>
<verse>She makes her own clothing, and dresses in colorful linens and silks.</verse>
<verse>Her husband is greatly respected when he deliberates with the city fathers.</verse>
<verse>She designs gowns and sells them, brings the sweaters she knits to the dress shops.</verse>
<verse>Her clothes are well-made and elegant, and she always faces tomorrow with a smile.</verse>
<verse>When she speaks she has something worthwhile to say, and she always says it kindly.</verse>
<verse>She keeps an eye on everyone in her household, and keeps them all busy and productive.</verse>
<verse>Her children respect and bless her; her husband joins in with words of praise:</verse>
<verse>"Many women have done wonderful things, but you've outclassed them all!"</verse>
<verse>Charm can mislead and beauty soon fades. The woman to be admired and praised is the woman who lives in the Fear-of-GOD.</verse>
<verse>Give her everything she deserves! Festoon her life with praises!</verse>
</chapter>