<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Proverbs" book-id="20" n="4">
<verse>Listen, friends, to some fatherly advice; sit up and take notice so you'll know how to live.</verse>
<verse>I'm giving you good counsel; don't let it go in one ear and out the other.</verse>
<verse>When I was a boy at my father's knee, the pride and joy of my mother,</verse>
<verse>He would sit me down and drill me: "Take this to heart. Do what I tell you--live!</verse>
<verse>Sell everything and buy Wisdom! Forage for Understanding! Don't forget one word! Don't deviate an inch!</verse>
<verse>Never walk away from Wisdom--she guards your life; love her--she keeps her eye on you.</verse>
<verse>Above all and before all, do this: Get Wisdom! Write this at the top of your list: Get Understanding!</verse>
<verse>Throw your arms around her--believe me, you won't regret it; never let her go--she'll make your life glorious.</verse>
<verse>She'll garland your life with grace, she'll festoon your days with beauty."</verse>
<verse>Dear friend, take my advice; it will add years to your life.</verse>
<verse>I'm writing out clear directions to Wisdom Way, I'm drawing a map to Righteous Road.</verse>
<verse>I don't want you ending up in blind alleys, or wasting time making wrong turns.</verse>
<verse>Hold tight to good advice; don't relax your grip. Guard it well--your life is at stake!</verse>
<verse>Don't take Wicked Bypass; don't so much as set foot on that road.</verse>
<verse>Stay clear of it; give it a wide berth. Make a detour and be on your way.</verse>
<verse>Evil people are restless unless they're making trouble; They can't get a good night's sleep unless they've made life miserable for somebody.</verse>
<verse>Perversity is their food and drink, violence their drug of choice.</verse>
<verse>The ways of right-living people glow with light; the longer they live, the brighter they shine.</verse>
<verse>But the road of wrongdoing gets darker and darker--travelers can't see a thing; they fall flat on their faces.</verse>
<verse>Dear friend, listen well to my words; tune your ears to my voice.</verse>
<verse>Keep my message in plain view at all times. Concentrate! Learn it by heart!</verse>
<verse>Those who discover these words live, really live; body and soul, they're bursting with health.</verse>
<verse>Keep vigilant watch over your heart; that's where life starts.</verse>
<verse>Don't talk out of both sides of your mouth; avoid careless banter, white lies, and gossip.</verse>
<verse>Keep your eyes straight ahead; ignore all sideshow distractions.</verse>
<verse>Watch your step, and the road will stretch out smooth before you.</verse>
<verse>Look neither right nor left; leave evil in the dust.</verse>
</chapter>