<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Proverbs" book-id="20" n="5">
<verse>Dear friend, pay close attention to this, my wisdom; listen very closely to the way I see it.</verse>
<verse>Then you'll acquire a taste for good sense; what I tell you will keep you out of trouble.</verse>
<verse>The lips of a seductive woman are oh so sweet, her soft words are oh so smooth.</verse>
<verse>But it won't be long before she's gravel in your mouth, a pain in your gut, a wound in your heart.</verse>
<verse>She's dancing down the primrose path to Death; she's headed straight for Hell and taking you with her.</verse>
<verse>She hasn't a clue about Real Life, about who she is or where she's going.</verse>
<verse>So, my friend, listen closely; don't treat my words casually.</verse>
<verse>Keep your distance from such a woman; absolutely stay out of her neighborhood.</verse>
<verse>You don't want to squander your wonderful life, to waste your precious life among the hardhearted.</verse>
<verse>Why should you allow strangers to take advantage of you? Why be exploited by those who care nothing for you?</verse>
<verse>You don't want to end your life full of regrets, nothing but sin and bones,</verse>
<verse>Saying, "Oh, why didn't I do what they told me? Why did I reject a disciplined life?</verse>
<verse>Why didn't I listen to my mentors, or take my teachers seriously?</verse>
<verse>My life is ruined! I haven't one blessed thing to show for my life!"</verse>
<verse>Do you know the saying, "Drink from your own rain barrel, draw water from your own spring-fed well"?</verse>
<verse>It's true. Otherwise, you may one day come home and find your barrel empty and your well polluted.</verse>
<verse>Your spring water is for you and you only, not to be passed around among strangers.</verse>
<verse>Bless your fresh-flowing fountain! Enjoy the wife you married as a young man!</verse>
<verse>Lovely as an angel, beautiful as a rose--don't ever quit taking delight in her body. Never take her love for granted!</verse>
<verse>Why would you trade enduring intimacies for cheap thrills with a whore? for dalliance with a promiscuous stranger?</verse>
<verse>Mark well that GOD doesn't miss a move you make; he's aware of every step you take.</verse>
<verse>The shadow of your sin will overtake you; you'll find yourself stumbling all over yourself in the dark.</verse>
<verse>Death is the reward of an undisciplined life; your foolish decisions trap you in a dead end.</verse>
</chapter>