<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Proverbs" book_id="20" n="6">
<verse>Dear friend, if you've gone into hock with your neighbor or locked yourself into a deal with a stranger,</verse>
<verse>If you've impulsively promised the shirt off your back and now find yourself shivering out in the cold,</verse>
<verse>Friend, don't waste a minute, get yourself out of that mess. You're in that man's clutches! Go, put on a long face; act desperate.</verse>
<verse>Don't procrastinate--there's no time to lose.</verse>
<verse>Run like a deer from the hunter, fly like a bird from the trapper!</verse>
<verse>You lazy fool, look at an ant. Watch it closely; let it teach you a thing or two.</verse>
<verse>Nobody has to tell it what to do.</verse>
<verse>All summer it stores up food; at harvest it stockpiles provisions.</verse>
<verse>So how long are you going to laze around doing nothing? How long before you get out of bed?</verse>
<verse>A nap here, a nap there, a day off here, a day off there, sit back, take it easy--do you know what comes next?</verse>
<verse>Just this: You can look forward to a dirt-poor life, poverty your permanent houseguest!</verse>
<verse>Riffraff and rascals talk out of both sides of their mouths.</verse>
<verse>They wink at each other, they shuffle their feet, they cross their fingers behind their backs.</verse>
<verse>Their perverse minds are always cooking up something nasty, always stirring up trouble.</verse>
<verse>Catastrophe is just around the corner for them, a total smash-up, their lives ruined beyond repair.</verse>
<verse>Here are six things GOD hates, and one more that he loathes with a passion:</verse>
<verse>eyes that are arrogant, a tongue that lies, hands that murder the innocent,</verse>
<verse>a heart that hatches evil plots, feet that race down a wicked track,</verse>
<verse>a mouth that lies under oath, a troublemaker in the family.</verse>
<verse>Good friend, follow your father's good advice; don't wander off from your mother's teachings.</verse>
<verse>Wrap yourself in them from head to foot; wear them like a scarf around your neck.</verse>
<verse>Wherever you walk, they'll guide you; whenever you rest, they'll guard you; when you wake up, they'll tell you what's next.</verse>
<verse>For sound advice is a beacon, good teaching is a light, moral discipline is a life path.</verse>
<verse>They'll protect you from wanton women, from the seductive talk of some temptress.</verse>
<verse>Don't lustfully fantasize on her beauty, nor be taken in by her bedroom eyes.</verse>
<verse>You can buy an hour with a whore for a loaf of bread, but a wanton woman may well eat you alive.</verse>
<verse>Can you build a fire in your lap and not burn your pants?</verse>
<verse>Can you walk barefoot on hot coals and not get blisters?</verse>
<verse>It's the same when you have sex with your neighbor's wife: Touch her and you'll pay for it. No excuses.</verse>
<verse>Hunger is no excuse for a thief to steal;</verse>
<verse>When he's caught he has to pay it back, even if he has to put his whole house in hock.</verse>
<verse>Adultery is a brainless act, soul--destroying, self-destructive;</verse>
<verse>Expect a bloody nose, a black eye, and a reputation ruined for good.</verse>
<verse>For jealousy detonates rage in a cheated husband; wild for revenge, he won't make allowances.</verse>
<verse>Nothing you say or pay will make it all right; neither bribes nor reason will satisfy him.</verse>
</chapter>