<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Proverbs" book_id="20" n="7">
<verse>Dear friend, do what I tell you; treasure my careful instructions.</verse>
<verse>Do what I say and you'll live well. My teaching is as precious as your eyesight--guard it!</verse>
<verse>Write it out on the back of your hands; etch it on the chambers of your heart.</verse>
<verse>Talk to Wisdom as to a sister. Treat Insight as your companion.</verse>
<verse>They'll be with you to fend off the Temptress--that smooth-talking, honey--tongued Seductress.</verse>
<verse>As I stood at the window of my house looking out through the shutters,</verse>
<verse>Watching the mindless crowd stroll by, I spotted a young man without any sense</verse>
<verse>Arriving at the corner of the street where she lived, then turning up the path to her house.</verse>
<verse>It was dusk, the evening coming on, the darkness thickening into night.</verse>
<verse>Just then, a woman met him--she'd been lying in wait for him, dressed to seduce him.</verse>
<verse>Brazen and brash she was, restless and roaming, never at home,</verse>
<verse>Walking the streets, loitering in the mall, hanging out at every corner in town.</verse>
<verse>She threw her arms around him and kissed him, boldly took his arm and said,</verse>
<verse>"I've got all the makings for a feast--today I made my offerings, my vows are all paid,</verse>
<verse>So now I've come to find you, hoping to catch sight of your face--and here you are!</verse>
<verse>I've spread fresh, clean sheets on my bed, colorful imported linens.</verse>
<verse>My bed is aromatic with spices and exotic fragrances.</verse>
<verse>Come, let's make love all night, spend the night in ecstatic lovemaking!</verse>
<verse>My husband's not home; he's away on business, and he won't be back for a month."</verse>
<verse>Soon she has him eating out of her hand, bewitched by her honeyed speech.</verse>
<verse>Before you know it, he's trotting behind her, like a calf led to the butcher shop, Like a stag lured into ambush</verse>
<verse>and then shot with an arrow, Like a bird flying into a net not knowing that its flying life is over.</verse>
<verse>So, friends, listen to me, take these words of mine most seriously.</verse>
<verse>Don't fool around with a woman like that; don't even stroll through her neighborhood.</verse>
<verse>Countless victims come under her spell; she's the death of many a poor man.</verse>
<verse>She runs a halfway house to hell, fits you out with a shroud and a coffin.</verse>
</chapter>