<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Proverbs" book-id="20" n="8">
<verse>Do you hear Lady Wisdom calling? Can you hear Madame Insight raising her voice?</verse>
<verse>She's taken her stand at First and Main, at the busiest intersection.</verse>
<verse>Right in the city square where the traffic is thickest, she shouts,</verse>
<verse>"You--I'm talking to all of you, everyone out here on the streets!</verse>
<verse>Listen, you idiots--learn good sense! You blockheads--shape up!</verse>
<verse>Don't miss a word of this--I'm telling you how to live well, I'm telling you how to live at your best.</verse>
<verse>My mouth chews and savors and relishes truth--I can't stand the taste of evil!</verse>
<verse>You'll only hear true and right words from my mouth; not one syllable will be twisted or skewed.</verse>
<verse>You'll recognize this as true--you with open minds; truth--ready minds will see it at once.</verse>
<verse>Prefer my life--disciplines over chasing after money, and God-knowledge over a lucrative career.</verse>
<verse>For Wisdom is better than all the trappings of wealth; nothing you could wish for holds a candle to her.</verse>
<verse>"I am Lady Wisdom, and I live next to Sanity; Knowledge and Discretion live just down the street.</verse>
<verse>The Fear-of-GOD means hating Evil, whose ways I hate with a passion--pride and arrogance and crooked talk.</verse>
<verse>Good counsel and common sense are my characteristics; I am both Insight and the Virtue to live it out.</verse>
<verse>With my help, leaders rule, and lawmakers legislate fairly;</verse>
<verse>With my help, governors govern, along with all in legitimate authority.</verse>
<verse>I love those who love me; those who look for me find me.</verse>
<verse>Wealth and Glory accompany me--also substantial Honor and a Good Name.</verse>
<verse>My benefits are worth more than a big salary, even a very big salary; the returns on me exceed any imaginable bonus.</verse>
<verse>You can find me on Righteous Road--that's where I walk--at the intersection of Justice Avenue,</verse>
<verse>Handing out life to those who love me, filling their arms with life--armloads of life!</verse>
<verse>"GOD sovereignly made me--the first, the basic--before he did anything else.</verse>
<verse>I was brought into being a long time ago, well before Earth got its start.</verse>
<verse>I arrived on the scene before Ocean, yes, even before Springs and Rivers and Lakes.</verse>
<verse>Before Mountains were sculpted and Hills took shape, I was already there, newborn;</verse>
<verse>Long before GOD stretched out Earth's Horizons, and tended to the minute details of Soil and Weather,</verse>
<verse>And set Sky firmly in place, I was there. When he mapped and gave borders to wild Ocean,</verse>
<verse>built the vast vault of Heaven, and installed the fountains that fed Ocean,</verse>
<verse>When he drew a boundary for Sea, posted a sign that said, NO TRESPASSING, And then staked out Earth's foundations,</verse>
<verse>I was right there with him, making sure everything fit. Day after day I was there, with my joyful applause, always enjoying his company,</verse>
<verse>Delighted with the world of things and creatures, happily celebrating the human family.</verse>
<verse>"So, my dear friends, listen carefully; those who embrace these my ways are most blessed.</verse>
<verse>Mark a life of discipline and live wisely; don't squander your precious life.</verse>
<verse>Blessed the man, blessed the woman, who listens to me, awake and ready for me each morning, alert and responsive as I start my day's work.</verse>
<verse>When you find me, you find life, real life, to say nothing of GOD's good pleasure.</verse>
<verse>But if you wrong me, you damage your very soul; when you reject me, you're flirting with death."</verse>
</chapter>