<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Proverbs" book_id="20" n="9">
<verse>Lady Wisdom has built and furnished her home; it's supported by seven hewn timbers.</verse>
<verse>The banquet meal is ready to be served: lamb roasted, wine poured out, table set with silver and flowers.</verse>
<verse>Having dismissed her serving maids, Lady Wisdom goes to town, stands in a prominent place, and invites everyone within sound of her voice:</verse>
<verse>"Are you confused about life, don't know what's going on? Come with me, oh come, have dinner with me!</verse>
<verse>I've prepared a wonderful spread--fresh-baked bread, roast lamb, carefully selected wines.</verse>
<verse>Leave your impoverished confusion and live! Walk up the street to a life with meaning." [JC]</verse>
<verse>If you reason with an arrogant cynic, you'll get slapped in the face; confront bad behavior and get a kick in the shins.</verse>
<verse>So don't waste your time on a scoffer; all you'll get for your pains is abuse. But if you correct those who care about life, that's different--they'll love you for it!</verse>
<verse>Save your breath for the wise--they'll be wiser for it; tell good people what you know--they'll profit from it.</verse>
<verse>Skilled living gets its start in the Fear-of-GOD, insight into life from knowing a Holy God.</verse>
<verse>It's through me, Lady Wisdom, that your life deepens, and the years of your life ripen.</verse>
<verse>Live wisely and wisdom will permeate your life; mock life and life will mock you.</verse>
<verse>Then there's this other woman, Madame Whore--brazen, empty-headed, frivolous.</verse>
<verse>She sits on the front porch of her house on Main Street,</verse>
<verse>And as people walk by minding their own business, calls out,</verse>
<verse>"Are you confused about life, don't know what's going on?</verse>
<verse>Steal off with me, I'll show you a good time! No one will ever know--I'll give you the time of your life."</verse>
<verse>But they don't know about all the skeletons in her closet, that all her guests end up in hell. The Wise Sayings of Solomon An Honest Life Is Immortal</verse>
</chapter>