<chapter translation="NIV" testament="New" book="Philippians" book-id="50" n="1">
<verse>Paul and Timothy, servants of Christ Jesus, To all the saints in Christ Jesus at Philippi, together with the overseers and deacons:</verse>
<verse>Grace and peace to you from God our Father and the Lord Jesus Christ.</verse>
<verse>I thank my God every time I remember you.</verse>
<verse>In all my prayers for all of you, I always pray with joy</verse>
<verse>because of your partnership in the gospel from the first day until now,</verse>
<verse>being confident of this, that he who began a good work in you will carry it on to completion until the day of Christ Jesus.</verse>
<verse>It is right for me to feel this way about all of you, since I have you in my heart; for whether I am in chains or defending and confirming the gospel, all of you share in God's grace with me.</verse>
<verse>God can testify how I long for all of you with the affection of Christ Jesus.</verse>
<verse>And this is my prayer: that your love may abound more and more in knowledge and depth of insight,</verse>
<verse>so that you may be able to discern what is best and may be pure and blameless until the day of Christ,</verse>
<verse>filled with the fruit of righteousness that comes through Jesus Christ--to the glory and praise of God.</verse>
<verse>Now I want you to know, brothers, that what has happened to me has really served to advance the gospel.</verse>
<verse>As a result, it has become clear throughout the whole palace guard and to everyone else that I am in chains for Christ.</verse>
<verse>Because of my chains, most of the brothers in the Lord have been encouraged to speak the word of God more courageously and fearlessly.</verse>
<verse>It is true that some preach Christ out of envy and rivalry, but others out of goodwill.</verse>
<verse>The latter do so in love, knowing that I am put here for the defense of the gospel.</verse>
<verse>The former preach Christ out of selfish ambition, not sincerely, supposing that they can stir up trouble for me while I am in chains.</verse>
<verse>But what does it matter? The important thing is that in every way, whether from false motives or true, Christ is preached. And because of this I rejoice.</verse>
<verse>Yes, and I will continue to rejoice, for I know that through your prayers and the help given by the Spirit of Jesus Christ, what has happened to me will turn out for my deliverance.</verse>
<verse>I eagerly expect and hope that I will in no way be ashamed, but will have sufficient courage so that now as always Christ will be exalted in my body, whether by life or by death.</verse>
<verse>For to me, to live is Christ and to die is gain.</verse>
<verse>If I am to go on living in the body, this will mean fruitful labor for me. Yet what shall I choose? I do not know!</verse>
<verse>I am torn between the two: I desire to depart and be with Christ, which is better by far;</verse>
<verse>but it is more necessary for you that I remain in the body.</verse>
<verse>Convinced of this, I know that I will remain, and I will continue with all of you for your progress and joy in the faith,</verse>
<verse>so that through my being with you again your joy in Christ Jesus will overflow on account of me.</verse>
<verse>Whatever happens, conduct yourselves in a manner worthy of the gospel of Christ. Then, whether I come and see you or only hear about you in my absence, I will know that you stand firm in one spirit, contending as one man for the faith of the gospel</verse>
<verse>without being frightened in any way by those who oppose you. This is a sign to them that they will be destroyed, but that you will be saved--and that by God.</verse>
<verse>For it has been granted to you on behalf of Christ not only to believe on him, but also to suffer for him,</verse>
<verse>since you are going through the same struggle you saw I had, and now hear that I still have.</verse>
</chapter>