<chapter translation="NIV" testament="New" book="Philippians" book-id="50" n="3">
<verse>Finally, my brothers, rejoice in the Lord! It is no trouble for me to write the same things to you again, and it is a safeguard for you.</verse>
<verse>Watch out for those dogs, those men who do evil, those mutilators of the flesh.</verse>
<verse>For it is we who are the circumcision, we who worship by the Spirit of God, who glory in Christ Jesus, and who put no confidence in the flesh--</verse>
<verse>though I myself have reasons for such confidence. If anyone else thinks he has reasons to put confidence in the flesh, I have more:</verse>
<verse>circumcised on the eighth day, of the people of Israel, of the tribe of Benjamin, a Hebrew of Hebrews; in regard to the law, a Pharisee;</verse>
<verse>as for zeal, persecuting the church; as for legalistic righteousness, faultless.</verse>
<verse>But whatever was to my profit I now consider loss for the sake of Christ.</verse>
<verse>What is more, I consider everything a loss compared to the surpassing greatness of knowing Christ Jesus my Lord, for whose sake I have lost all things. I consider them rubbish, that I may gain Christ</verse>
<verse>and be found in him, not having a righteousness of my own that comes from the law, but that which is through faith in Christ--the righteousness that comes from God and is by faith.</verse>
<verse>I want to know Christ and the power of his resurrection and the fellowship of sharing in his sufferings, becoming like him in his death,</verse>
<verse>and so, somehow, to attain to the resurrection from the dead.</verse>
<verse>Not that I have already obtained all this, or have already been made perfect, but I press on to take hold of that for which Christ Jesus took hold of me.</verse>
<verse>Brothers, I do not consider myself yet to have taken hold of it. But one thing I do: Forgetting what is behind and straining toward what is ahead,</verse>
<verse>I press on toward the goal to win the prize for which God has called me heavenward in Christ Jesus.</verse>
<verse>All of us who are mature should take such a view of things. And if on some point you think differently, that too God will make clear to you.</verse>
<verse>Only let us live up to what we have already attained.</verse>
<verse>Join with others in following my example, brothers, and take note of those who live according to the pattern we gave you.</verse>
<verse>For, as I have often told you before and now say again even with tears, many live as enemies of the cross of Christ.</verse>
<verse>Their destiny is destruction, their god is their stomach, and their glory is in their shame. Their mind is on earthly things.</verse>
<verse>But our citizenship is in heaven. And we eagerly await a Savior from there, the Lord Jesus Christ,</verse>
<verse>who, by the power that enables him to bring everything under his control, will transform our lowly bodies so that they will be like his glorious body.</verse>
</chapter>