<chapter translation="NASB" testament="New" book="Philemon" book-id="57" n="1">
<verse>Paul, a prisoner of Christ Jesus, and Timothy our brother, To Philemon our beloved brother and fellow worker,</verse>
<verse>and to Apphia our sister, and to Archippus our fellow soldier, and to the church in your house:</verse>
<verse>Grace to you and peace from God our Father and the Lord Jesus Christ.</verse>
<verse>I thank my God always, making mention of you in my prayers,</verse>
<verse>because I hear of your love and of the faith which you have toward the Lord Jesus and toward all the saints;</verse>
<verse>and I pray that the fellowship of your faith may become effective through the knowledge of every good thing which is in you for Christ's sake.</verse>
<verse>For I have come to have much joy and comfort in your love, because the hearts of the saints have been refreshed through you, brother.</verse>
<verse>Therefore, though I have enough confidence in Christ to order you to do what is proper,</verse>
<verse>yet for love's sake I rather appeal to you--since I am such a person as Paul, the aged, and now also a prisoner of Christ Jesus--</verse>
<verse>I appeal to you for my child Onesimus, whom I have begotten in my imprisonment,</verse>
<verse>who formerly was useless to you, but now is useful both to you and to me.</verse>
<verse>I have sent him back to you in person, that is, sending my very heart,</verse>
<verse>whom I wished to keep with me, so that on your behalf he might minister to me in my imprisonment for the gospel;</verse>
<verse>but without your consent I did not want to do anything, so that your goodness would not be, in effect, by compulsion but of your own free will.</verse>
<verse>For perhaps he was for this reason separated from you for a while, that you would have him back forever,</verse>
<verse>no longer as a slave, but more than a slave, a beloved brother, especially to me, but how much more to you, both in the flesh and in the Lord.</verse>
<verse>If then you regard me a partner, accept him as you would me.</verse>
<verse>But if he has wronged you in any way or owes you anything, charge that to my account;</verse>
<verse>I, Paul, am writing this with my own hand, I will repay it ( not to mention to you that you owe to me even your own self as well).</verse>
<verse>Yes, brother, let me benefit from you in the Lord; refresh my heart in Christ.</verse>
<verse>Having confidence in your obedience, I write to you, since I know that you will do even more than what I say.</verse>
<verse>At the same time also prepare me a lodging, for I hope that through your prayers I will be given to you.</verse>
<verse>Epaphras, my fellow prisoner in Christ Jesus, greets you,</verse>
<verse>as do Mark, Aristarchus, Demas, Luke, my fellow workers.</verse>
<verse>The grace of the Lord Jesus Christ be with your spirit.</verse>
</chapter>