<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Ecclesiastes" book-id="21" n="10">
<verse>Dead flies make a perfumer's oil stink, so a little foolishness is weightier than wisdom and honor.</verse>
<verse>A wise man's heart directs him toward the right, but the foolish man's heart directs him toward the left.</verse>
<verse>Even when the fool walks along the road, his sense is lacking and he demonstrates to everyone that he is a fool.</verse>
<verse>If the ruler's temper rises against you, do not abandon your position, because composure allays great offenses.</verse>
<verse>There is an evil I have seen under the sun, like an error which goes forth from the ruler--</verse>
<verse>folly is set in many exalted places while rich men sit in humble places.</verse>
<verse>I have seen slaves riding on horses and princes walking like slaves on the land.</verse>
<verse>He who digs a pit may fall into it, and a serpent may bite him who breaks through a wall.</verse>
<verse>He who quarries stones may be hurt by them, and he who splits logs may be endangered by them.</verse>
<verse>If the axe is dull and he does not sharpen its edge, then he must exert more strength. Wisdom has the advantage of giving success.</verse>
<verse>If the serpent bites before being charmed, there is no profit for the charmer.</verse>
<verse>Words from the mouth of a wise man are gracious, while the lips of a fool consume him;</verse>
<verse>the beginning of his talking is folly and the end of it is wicked madness.</verse>
<verse>Yet the fool multiplies words. No man knows what will happen, and who can tell him what will come after him?</verse>
<verse>The toil of a fool so wearies him that he does not even know how to go to a city.</verse>
<verse>Woe to you, O land, whose king is a lad and whose princes feast in the morning.</verse>
<verse>Blessed are you, O land, whose king is of nobility and whose princes eat at the appropriate time--for strength and not for drunkenness.</verse>
<verse>Through indolence the rafters sag, and through slackness the house leaks.</verse>
<verse>Men prepare a meal for enjoyment, and wine makes life merry, and money is the answer to everything.</verse>
<verse>Furthermore, in your bedchamber do not curse a king, and in your sleeping rooms do not curse a rich man, for a bird of the heavens will carry the sound and the winged creature will make the matter known.</verse>
</chapter>