<chapter translation="NASB" testament="New" book="2 Corinthians" book-id="47" n="12">
<verse>Boasting is necessary, though it is not profitable; but I will go on to visions and revelations of the Lord.</verse>
<verse>I know a man in Christ who fourteen years ago--whether in the body I do not know, or out of the body I do not know, God knows--such a man was caught up to the third heaven.</verse>
<verse>And I know how such a man--whether in the body or apart from the body I do not know, God knows--</verse>
<verse>was caught up into Paradise and heard inexpressible words, which a man is not permitted to speak.</verse>
<verse>On behalf of such a man I will boast; but on my own behalf I will not boast, except in regard to my weaknesses.</verse>
<verse>For if I do wish to boast I will not be foolish, for I will be speaking the truth; but I refrain from this, so that no one will credit me with more than he sees in me or hears from me.</verse>
<verse>Because of the surpassing greatness of the revelations, for this reason, to keep me from exalting myself, there was given me a thorn in the flesh, a messenger of Satan to torment me--to keep me from exalting myself!</verse>
<verse>Concerning this I implored the Lord three times that it might leave me.</verse>
<verse>And He has said to me, "My grace is sufficient for you, for power is perfected in weakness." Most gladly, therefore, I will rather boast about my weaknesses, so that the power of Christ may dwell in me.</verse>
<verse>Therefore I am well content with weaknesses, with insults, with distresses, with persecutions, with difficulties, for Christ's sake; for when I am weak, then I am strong.</verse>
<verse>I have become foolish; you yourselves compelled me. Actually I should have been commended by you, for in no respect was I inferior to the most eminent apostles, even though I am a nobody.</verse>
<verse>The signs of a true apostle were performed among you with all perseverance, by signs and wonders and miracles.</verse>
<verse>For in what respect were you treated as inferior to the rest of the churches, except that I myself did not become a burden to you? Forgive me this wrong!</verse>
<verse>Here for this third time I am ready to come to you, and I will not be a burden to you; for I do not seek what is yours, but you; for children are not responsible to save up for their parents, but parents for their children.</verse>
<verse>I will most gladly spend and be expended for your souls. If I love you more, am I to be loved less?</verse>
<verse>But be that as it may, I did not burden you myself; nevertheless, crafty fellow that I am, I took you in by deceit.</verse>
<verse>Certainly I have not taken advantage of you through any of those whom I have sent to you, have I?</verse>
<verse>I urged Titus to go, and I sent the brother with him. Titus did not take any advantage of you, did he? Did we not conduct ourselves in the same spirit and walk in the same steps?</verse>
<verse>All this time you have been thinking that we are defending ourselves to you. Actually, it is in the sight of God that we have been speaking in Christ; and all for your upbuilding, beloved.</verse>
<verse>For I am afraid that perhaps when I come I may find you to be not what I wish and may be found by you to be not what you wish; that perhaps there will be strife, jealousy, angry tempers, disputes, slanders, gossip, arrogance, disturbances;</verse>
<verse>I am afraid that when I come again my God may humiliate me before you, and I may mourn over many of those who have sinned in the past and not repented of the impurity, immorality and sensuality which they have practiced.</verse>
</chapter>