<chapter translation="NASB" testament="New" book="2 Corinthians" book-id="47" n="6">
<verse>And working together with Him, we also urge you not to receive the grace of God in vain--</verse>
<verse>for He says, "AT THE ACCEPTABLE TIME I LISTENED TO YOU, AND ON THE DAY OF SALVATION I HELPED YOU." Behold, now is "THE ACCEPTABLE TIME," behold, now is "THE DAY OF SALVATION"--</verse>
<verse>giving no cause for offense in anything, so that the ministry will not be discredited,</verse>
<verse>but in everything commending ourselves as servants of God, in much endurance, in afflictions, in hardships, in distresses,</verse>
<verse>in beatings, in imprisonments, in tumults, in labors, in sleeplessness, in hunger,</verse>
<verse>in purity, in knowledge, in patience, in kindness, in the Holy Spirit, in genuine love,</verse>
<verse>in the word of truth, in the power of God; by the weapons of righteousness for the right hand and the left,</verse>
<verse>by glory and dishonor, by evil report and good report; regarded as deceivers and yet true;</verse>
<verse>as unknown yet well-known, as dying yet behold, we live; as punished yet not put to death,</verse>
<verse>as sorrowful yet always rejoicing, as poor yet making many rich, as having nothing yet possessing all things.</verse>
<verse>Our mouth has spoken freely to you, O Corinthians, our heart is opened wide.</verse>
<verse>You are not restrained by us, but you are restrained in your own affections.</verse>
<verse>Now in a like exchange--I speak as to children--open wide to us also.</verse>
<verse>Do not be bound together with unbelievers; for what partnership have righteousness and lawlessness, or what fellowship has light with darkness?</verse>
<verse>Or what harmony has Christ with Belial, or what has a believer in common with an unbeliever?</verse>
<verse>Or what agreement has the temple of God with idols? For we are the temple of the living God; just as God said, "I WILL DWELL IN THEM AND WALK AMONG THEM; AND I WILL BE THEIR GOD, AND THEY SHALL BE MY PEOPLE.</verse>
<verse>"Therefore, COME OUT FROM THEIR MIDST AND BE SEPARATE," says the Lord. "AND DO NOT TOUCH WHAT IS UNCLEAN; And I will welcome you.</verse>
<verse>"And I will be a father to you, And you shall be sons and daughters to Me," Says the Lord Almighty.</verse>
</chapter>