<chapter translation="MSG" testament="New" book="John" book_id="43" n="11">
<verse>A man was sick, Lazarus of Bethany, the town of Mary and her sister Martha.</verse>
<verse>This was the same Mary who massaged the Lord's feet with aromatic oils and then wiped them with her hair. It was her brother Lazarus who was sick.</verse>
<verse>So the sisters sent word to Jesus, "Master, the one you love so very much is sick."</verse>
<verse>When Jesus got the message, he said, "This sickness is not fatal. It will become an occasion to show God's glory by glorifying God's Son."</verse>
<verse>Jesus loved Martha and her sister and Lazarus,</verse>
<verse>but oddly, when he heard that Lazarus was sick, he stayed on where he was for two more days.</verse>
<verse>After the two days, he said to his disciples, "Let's go back to Judea."</verse>
<verse>They said, "Rabbi, you can't do that. The Jews are out to kill you, and you're going back?"</verse>
<verse>Jesus replied, "Are there not twelve hours of daylight? Anyone who walks in daylight doesn't stumble because there's plenty of light from the sun.</verse>
<verse>Walking at night, he might very well stumble because he can't see where he's going."</verse>
<verse>He said these things, and then announced, "Our friend Lazarus has fallen asleep. I'm going to wake him up."</verse>
<verse>The disciples said, "Master, if he's gone to sleep, he'll get a good rest and wake up feeling fine."</verse>
<verse>Jesus was talking about death, while his disciples thought he was talking about taking a nap.</verse>
<verse>Then Jesus became explicit: "Lazarus died.</verse>
<verse>And I am glad for your sakes that I wasn't there. You're about to be given new grounds for believing. Now let's go to him."</verse>
<verse>That's when Thomas, the one called the Twin, said to his companions, "Come along. We might as well die with him."</verse>
<verse>When Jesus finally got there, he found Lazarus already four days dead.</verse>
<verse>Bethany was near Jerusalem, only a couple of miles away,</verse>
<verse>and many of the Jews were visiting Martha and Mary, sympathizing with them over their brother.</verse>
<verse>Martha heard Jesus was coming and went out to meet him. Mary remained in the house.</verse>
<verse>Martha said, "Master, if you'd been here, my brother wouldn't have died.</verse>
<verse>Even now, I know that whatever you ask God he will give you."</verse>
<verse>Jesus said, "Your brother will be raised up."</verse>
<verse>Martha replied, "I know that he will be raised up in the resurrection at the end of time."</verse>
<verse>"You don't have to wait for the End. I am, right now, Resurrection and Life. The one who believes in me, even though he or she dies, will live.</verse>
<verse>And everyone who lives believing in me does not ultimately die at all. Do you believe this?"</verse>
<verse>"Yes, Master. All along I have believed that you are the Messiah, the Son of God who comes into the world."</verse>
<verse>After saying this, she went to her sister Mary and whispered in her ear, "The Teacher is here and is asking for you."</verse>
<verse>The moment she heard that, she jumped up and ran out to him.</verse>
<verse>Jesus had not yet entered the town but was still at the place where Martha had met him.</verse>
<verse>When her sympathizing Jewish friends saw Mary run off, they followed her, thinking she was on her way to the tomb to weep there.</verse>
<verse>Mary came to where Jesus was waiting and fell at his feet, saying, "Master, if only you had been here, my brother would not have died."</verse>
<verse>When Jesus saw her sobbing and the Jews with her sobbing, a deep anger welled up within him.</verse>
<verse>He said, "Where did you put him?Master, come and see," they said.</verse>
<verse>Now Jesus wept.</verse>
<verse>The Jews said, "Look how deeply he loved him."</verse>
<verse>Others among them said, "Well, if he loved him so much, why didn't he do something to keep him from dying? After all, he opened the eyes of a blind man."</verse>
<verse>Then Jesus, the anger again welling up within him, arrived at the tomb. It was a simple cave in the hillside with a slab of stone laid against it.</verse>
<verse>Jesus said, "Remove the stone." The sister of the dead man, Martha, said, "Master, by this time there's a stench. He's been dead four days!"</verse>
<verse>Jesus looked her in the eye. "Didn't I tell you that if you believed, you would see the glory of God?"</verse>
<verse>Then, to the others, "Go ahead, take away the stone." They removed the stone. Jesus raised his eyes to heaven and prayed, "Father, I'm grateful that you have listened to me.</verse>
<verse>I know you always do listen, but on account of this crowd standing here I've spoken so that they might believe that you sent me."</verse>
<verse>Then he shouted, "Lazarus, come out!"</verse>
<verse>And he came out, a cadaver, wrapped from head to toe, and with a kerchief over his face. Jesus told them, "Unwrap him and let him loose."</verse>
<verse>That was a turnaround for many of the Jews who were with Mary. They saw what Jesus did, and believed in him.</verse>
<verse>But some went back to the Pharisees and told on Jesus.</verse>
<verse>The high priests and Pharisees called a meeting of the Jewish ruling body. "What do we do now?" they asked. "This man keeps on doing things, creating God-signs.</verse>
<verse>If we let him go on, pretty soon everyone will be believing in him and the Romans will come and remove what little power and privilege we still have."</verse>
<verse>Then one of them--it was Caiaphas, the designated Chief Priest that year--spoke up, "Don't you know anything?</verse>
<verse>Can't you see that it's to our advantage that one man dies for the people rather than the whole nation be destroyed?"</verse>
<verse>He didn't say this of his own accord, but as Chief Priest that year he unwittingly prophesied that Jesus was about to die sacrificially for the nation,</verse>
<verse>and not only for the nation but so that all God's exile-scattered children might be gathered together into one people.</verse>
<verse>From that day on, they plotted to kill him.</verse>
<verse>So Jesus no longer went out in public among the Jews. He withdrew into the country bordering the desert to a town called Ephraim and secluded himself there with his disciples.</verse>
<verse>The Jewish Passover was coming up. Crowds of people were making their way from the country up to Jerusalem to get themselves ready for the Feast.</verse>
<verse>They were curious about Jesus. There was a lot of talk of him among those standing around in the Temple: "What do you think? Do you think he'll show up at the Feast or not?"</verse>
<verse>Meanwhile, the high priests and Pharisees gave out the word that anyone getting wind of him should inform them. They were all set to arrest him.</verse>
</chapter>