<chapter translation="MSG" testament="New" book="John" book-id="43" n="14">
<verse>"Don't let this throw you. You trust God, don't you? Trust me.</verse>
<verse>There is plenty of room for you in my Father's home. If that weren't so, would I have told you that I'm on my way to get a room ready for you?</verse>
<verse>And if I'm on my way to get your room ready, I'll come back and get you so you can live where I live.</verse>
<verse>And you already know the road I'm taking."</verse>
<verse>Thomas said, "Master, we have no idea where you're going. How do you expect us to know the road?"</verse>
<verse>Jesus said, "I am the Road, also the Truth, also the Life. No one gets to the Father apart from me.</verse>
<verse>If you really knew me, you would know my Father as well. From now on, you do know him. You've even seen him!"</verse>
<verse>Philip said, "Master, show us the Father; then we'll be content."</verse>
<verse>"You've been with me all this time, Philip, and you still don't understand? To see me is to see the Father. So how can you ask, "Where is the Father?'</verse>
<verse>Don't you believe that I am in the Father and the Father is in me? The words that I speak to you aren't mere words. I don't just make them up on my own. The Father who resides in me crafts each word into a divine act.</verse>
<verse>"Believe me: I am in my Father and my Father is in me. If you can't believe that, believe what you see--these works.</verse>
<verse>The person who trusts me will not only do what I'm doing but even greater things, because I, on my way to the Father, am giving you the same work to do that I've been doing. You can count on it.</verse>
<verse>From now on, whatever you request along the lines of who I am and what I am doing, I'll do it. That's how the Father will be seen for who he is in the Son. I mean it.</verse>
<verse>Whatever you request in this way, I'll do.</verse>
<verse>"If you love me, show it by doing what I've told you.</verse>
<verse>I will talk to the Father, and he'll provide you another Friend so that you will always have someone with you.</verse>
<verse>This Friend is the Spirit of Truth. The godless world can't take him in because it doesn't have eyes to see him, doesn't know what to look for. But you know him already because he has been staying with you, and will even be in you!</verse>
<verse>"I will not leave you orphaned. I'm coming back.</verse>
<verse>In just a little while the world will no longer see me, but you're going to see me because I am alive and you're about to come alive.</verse>
<verse>At that moment you will know absolutely that I'm in my Father, and you're in me, and I'm in you.</verse>
<verse>"The person who knows my commandments and keeps them, that's who loves me. And the person who loves me will be loved by my Father, and I will love him and make myself plain to him."</verse>
<verse>Judas (not Iscariot) said, "Master, why is it that you are about to make yourself plain to us but not to the world?"</verse>
<verse>"Because a loveless world," said Jesus, "is a sightless world. If anyone loves me, he will carefully keep my word and my Father will love him--we'll move right into the neighborhood!</verse>
<verse>Not loving me means not keeping my words. The message you are hearing isn't mine. It's the message of the Father who sent me.</verse>
<verse>"I'm telling you these things while I'm still living with you.</verse>
<verse>The Friend, the Holy Spirit whom the Father will send at my request, will make everything plain to you. He will remind you of all the things I have told you.</verse>
<verse>I'm leaving you well and whole. That's my parting gift to you. Peace. I don't leave you the way you're used to being left--feeling abandoned, bereft. So don't be upset. Don't be distraught.</verse>
<verse>"You've heard me tell you, "I'm going away, and I'm coming back.' If you loved me, you would be glad that I'm on my way to the Father because the Father is the goal and purpose of my life.</verse>
<verse>"I've told you this ahead of time, before it happens, so that when it does happen, the confirmation will deepen your belief in me.</verse>
<verse>I'll not be talking with you much more like this because the chief of this godless world is about to attack. But don't worry--he has nothing on me, no claim on me.</verse>
<verse>But so the world might know how thoroughly I love the Father, I am carrying out my Father's instructions right down to the last detail. "Get up. Let's go. It's time to leave here.</verse>
</chapter>