<chapter translation="MSG" testament="New" book="John" book_id="43" n="19">
<verse>So Pilate took Jesus and had him whipped.</verse>
<verse>The soldiers, having braided a crown from thorns, set it on his head, threw a purple robe over him,</verse>
<verse>and approached him with, "Hail, King of the Jews!" Then they greeted him with slaps in the face.</verse>
<verse>Pilate went back out again and said to them, "I present him to you, but I want you to know that I do not find him guilty of any crime."</verse>
<verse>Just then Jesus came out wearing the thorn crown and purple robe. Pilate announced, "Here he is: the Man."</verse>
<verse>When the high priests and police saw him, they shouted in a frenzy, "Crucify! Crucify!" Pilate told them, "You take him. You crucify him. I find nothing wrong with him."</verse>
<verse>The Jews answered, "We have a law, and by that law he must die because he claimed to be the Son of God."</verse>
<verse>When Pilate heard this, he became even more scared.</verse>
<verse>He went back into the palace and said to Jesus, "Where did you come from?" Jesus gave no answer.</verse>
<verse>Pilate said, "You won't talk? Don't you know that I have the authority to pardon you, and the authority to--crucify you?"</verse>
<verse>Jesus said, "You haven't a shred of authority over me except what has been given you from heaven. That's why the one who betrayed me to you has committed a far greater fault."</verse>
<verse>At this, Pilate tried his best to pardon him, but the Jews shouted him down: "If you pardon this man, you're no friend of Caesar's. Anyone setting himself up as "king' defies Caesar."</verse>
<verse>When Pilate heard those words, he led Jesus outside. He sat down at the judgment seat in the area designated Stone Court (in Hebrew, Gabbatha).</verse>
<verse>It was the preparation day for Passover. The hour was noon. Pilate said to the Jews, "Here is your king."</verse>
<verse>They shouted back, "Kill him! Kill him! Crucify him!" Pilate said, "I am to crucify your king?" The high priests answered, "We have no king except Caesar."</verse>
<verse>Pilate caved in to their demand. He turned him over to be crucified. They took Jesus away.</verse>
<verse>Carrying his cross, Jesus went out to the place called Skull Hill (the name in Hebrew is Golgotha),</verse>
<verse>where they crucified him, and with him two others, one on each side, Jesus in the middle.</verse>
<verse>Pilate wrote a sign and had it placed on the cross. It read: JESUS THE NAZARENE THE KING OF THE JEWS.</verse>
<verse>Many of the Jews read the sign because the place where Jesus was crucified was right next to the city. It was written in Hebrew, Latin, and Greek.</verse>
<verse>The Jewish high priests objected. "Don't write," they said to Pilate, The King of the Jews.' Make it, "This man said, "I am the King of the Jews."'"</verse>
<verse>Pilate said, "What I've written, I've written."</verse>
<verse>When they crucified him, the Roman soldiers took his clothes and divided them up four ways, to each soldier a fourth. But his robe was seamless, a single piece of weaving,</verse>
<verse>so they said to each other, "Let's not tear it up. Let's throw dice to see who gets it." This confirmed the Scripture that said, "They divided up my clothes among them and threw dice for my coat." (The soldiers validated the Scriptures!) While the soldiers were looking after themselves,</verse>
<verse>Jesus' mother, his aunt, Mary the wife of Clopas, and Mary Magdalene stood at the foot of the cross.</verse>
<verse>Jesus saw his mother and the disciple he loved standing near her. He said to his mother, "Woman, here is your son."</verse>
<verse>Then to the disciple, "Here is your mother." From that moment the disciple accepted her as his own mother.</verse>
<verse>Jesus, seeing that everything had been completed so that the Scripture record might also be complete, then said, "I'm thirsty."</verse>
<verse>A jug of sour wine was standing by. Someone put a sponge soaked with the wine on a javelin and lifted it to his mouth.</verse>
<verse>After he took the wine, Jesus said, "It's done... complete." Bowing his head, he offered up his spirit.</verse>
<verse>Then the Jews, since it was the day of Sabbath preparation, and so the bodies wouldn't stay on the crosses over the Sabbath (it was a high holy day that year), petitioned Pilate that their legs be broken to speed death, and the bodies taken down.</verse>
<verse>So the soldiers came and broke the legs of the first man crucified with Jesus, and then the other.</verse>
<verse>When they got to Jesus, they saw that he was already dead, so they didn't break his legs.</verse>
<verse>One of the soldiers stabbed him in the side with his spear. Blood and water gushed out.</verse>
<verse>The eyewitness to these things has presented an accurate report. He saw it himself and is telling the truth so that you, also, will believe.</verse>
<verse>These things that happened confirmed the Scripture, "Not a bone in his body was broken,"</verse>
<verse>and the other Scripture that reads, "They will stare at the one they pierced." [JC]</verse>
<verse>After all this, Joseph of Arimathea (he was a disciple of Jesus, but secretly, because he was intimidated by the Jews) petitioned Pilate to take the body of Jesus. Pilate gave permission. So Joseph came and took the body.</verse>
<verse>Nicodemus, who had first come to Jesus at night, came now in broad daylight carrying a mixture of myrrh and aloes, about seventy-five pounds.</verse>
<verse>They took Jesus' body and, following the Jewish burial custom, wrapped it in linen with the spices.</verse>
<verse>There was a garden near the place he was crucified, and in the garden a new tomb in which no one had yet been placed.</verse>
<verse>So, because it was Sabbath preparation for the Jews and the tomb was convenient, they placed Jesus in it.</verse>
</chapter>