<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Malachi" book_id="39" n="2">
<verse>"And now this indictment, you priests!</verse>
<verse>If you refuse to obediently listen, and if you refuse to honor me, GOD-of-the-Angel-Armies, in worship, then I'll put you under a curse. I'll exchange all your blessings for curses. In fact, the curses are already at work because you're not serious about honoring me.</verse>
<verse>Yes, and the curse will extend to your children. I'm going to plaster your faces with rotting garbage, garbage thrown out from your feasts. That's what you have to look forward to!</verse>
<verse>"Maybe that will wake you up. Maybe then you'll realize that I'm indicting you in order to put new life into my covenant with the priests of Levi, the covenant of GOD-of-the-Angel-Armies.</verse>
<verse>My covenant with Levi was to give life and peace. I kept my covenant with him, and he honored me. He stood in reverent awe before me.</verse>
<verse>He taught the truth and did not lie. He walked with me in peace and uprightness. He kept many out of the ditch, kept them on the road.</verse>
<verse>"It's the job of priests to teach the truth. People are supposed to look to them for guidance. The priest is the messenger of GOD-of-the-Angel-Armies.</verse>
<verse>But you priests have abandoned the way of priests. Your teaching has messed up many lives. You have corrupted the covenant of priest Levi. GOD-of-the-Angel-Armies says so.</verse>
<verse>And so I am showing you up for who you are. Everyone will be disgusted with you and avoid you because you don't live the way I told you to live, and you don't teach my revelation truly and impartially."</verse>
<verse>Don't we all come from one Father? Aren't we all created by the same God? So why can't we get along? Why do we desecrate the covenant of our ancestors that binds us together?</verse>
<verse>Judah has cheated on GOD-a sickening violation of trust in Israel and Jerusalem: Judah has desecrated the holiness of GOD by falling in love and running off with foreign women, women who worship alien gods.</verse>
<verse>GOD's curse on those who do this! Drive them out of house and home! They're no longer fit to be part of the community no matter how many offerings they bring to GOD-of-the-Angel-Armies.</verse>
<verse>And here's a second offense: You fill the place of worship with your whining and sniveling because you don't get what you want from GOD.</verse>
<verse>Do you know why? Simple. Because GOD was there as a witness when you spoke your marriage vows to your young bride, and now you've broken those vows, broken the faith-bond with your vowed companion, your covenant wife.</verse>
<verse>GOD, not you, made marriage. His Spirit inhabits even the smallest details of marriage. And what does he want from marriage? Children of God, that's what. So guard the spirit of marriage within you. Don't cheat on your spouse.</verse>
<verse>"I hate divorce," says the GOD of Israel. GOD-of-the-Angel-Armies says, "I hate the violent dismembering of the "one flesh' of marriage." So watch yourselves. Don't let your guard down. Don't cheat.</verse>
<verse>You make GOD tired with all your talk. "How do we tire him out?" you ask. By saying, "GOD loves sinners and sin alike. GOD loves all." And also by saying, "Judgment? GOD's too nice to judge."</verse>
</chapter>