<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Malachi" book_id="39" n="3">
<verse>"Look! I'm sending my messenger on ahead to clear the way for me. Suddenly, out of the blue, the Leader you've been looking for will enter his Temple--yes, the Messenger of the Covenant, the one you've been waiting for. Look! He's on his way!" A Message from the mouth of GOD-of-the-Angel-Armies.</verse>
<verse>But who will be able to stand up to that coming? Who can survive his appearance? He'll be like white-hot fire from the smelter's furnace. He'll be like the strongest lye soap at the laundry.</verse>
<verse>He'll take his place as a refiner of silver, as a cleanser of dirty clothes. He'll scrub the Levite priests clean, refine them like gold and silver, until they're fit for GOD, fit to present offerings of righteousness.</verse>
<verse>Then, and only then, will Judah and Jerusalem be fit and pleasing to GOD, as they used to be in the years long ago.</verse>
<verse>[JC] "Yes, I'm on my way to visit you with Judgment. I'll present compelling evidence against sorcerers, adulterers, liars, those who exploit workers, those who take advantage of widows and orphans, those who are inhospitable to the homeless--anyone and everyone who doesn't honor me." A Message from GOD-of-the-Angel-Armies. [JC]</verse>
<verse>"I am GOD-yes, I AM. I haven't changed. And because I haven't changed, you, the descendants of Jacob, haven't been destroyed.</verse>
<verse>You have a long history of ignoring my commands. You haven't done a thing I've told you. Return to me so I can return to you," says GOD-of-the-Angel-Armies. "You ask, "But how do we return?'</verse>
<verse>"Begin by being honest. Do honest people rob God? But you rob me day after day. "You ask, "How have we robbed you?'"The tithe and the offering--that's how!</verse>
<verse>And now you're under a curse--the whole lot of you--because you're robbing me.</verse>
<verse>Bring your full tithe to the Temple treasury so there will be ample provisions in my Temple. Test me in this and see if I don't open up heaven itself to you and pour out blessings beyond your wildest dreams.</verse>
<verse>For my part, I will defend you against marauders, protect your wheat fields and vegetable gardens against plunderers." The Message of GOD-of-the-Angel-Armies.</verse>
<verse>"You'll be voted "Happiest Nation.' You'll experience what it's like to be a country of grace." GOD-of-the-Angel-Armies says so.</verse>
<verse>GOD says, "You have spoken hard, rude words to me. "You ask, "When did we ever do that?'</verse>
<verse>"When you said, "It doesn't pay to serve God. What do we ever get out of it? When we did what he said and went around with long faces, serious about GOD-of-the-Angel-Armies, what difference did it make?</verse>
<verse>Those who take life into their own hands are the lucky ones. They break all the rules and get ahead anyway. They push God to the limit and get by with it.'"</verse>
<verse>Then those whose lives honored GOD got together and talked it over. GOD saw what they were doing and listened in. A book was opened in God's presence and minutes were taken of the meeting, with the names of the GOD-fearers written down, all the names of those who honored GOD's name.</verse>
<verse>GOD-of-the-Angel-Armies said, "They're mine, all mine. They'll get special treatment when I go into action. I treat them with the same consideration and kindness that parents give the child who honors them.</verse>
<verse>Once more you'll see the difference it makes between being a person who does the right thing and one who doesn't, between serving God and not serving him.</verse>
</chapter>