<?xml version="1.0"?>
<chapter translation="KJV" testament="New" book="Luke" n="18" book-chapters="24">
      <verse>And he spake a parable unto them <supplied>to this end,</supplied> that men ought always to pray, and not to faint;
</verse><verse>Saying, <jesus>There was in a city a judge, which feared not God, neither regarded man: </jesus></verse><verse><jesus>And there was a widow in that city; and she came unto him, saying, Avenge me of mine adversary. </jesus></verse><verse><jesus>And he would not for a while: but
afterward he said within himself, Though I fear not God, nor regard man; </jesus></verse><verse><jesus>Yet because this widow troubleth me, I will avenge her, lest by her continual coming she weary me. </jesus></verse><verse>And the Lord said, <jesus>Hear what the unjust judge
saith. </jesus></verse><verse><jesus>And shall not God avenge his own elect, which cry day and night unto him, though he bear long with them? </jesus></verse><verse><jesus>I tell you that he will avenge them speedily. Nevertheless when the Son of man cometh, shall he find faith on
the earth? </jesus></verse><verse>And he spake this parable unto certain which trusted in themselves that they were righteous, and despised others:
</verse><verse><jesus>Two men went up into the temple to pray; the one a Pharisee, and the other a publican. </jesus></verse><verse><jesus>The Pharisee stood and prayed thus with himself, God, I thank thee, that I am not as other men <supplied>are,</supplied> extortioners, unjust,
adulterers, or even as this publican. </jesus></verse><verse><jesus>I fast twice in the week, I give tithes of all that I possess. </jesus></verse><verse><jesus>And the publican, standing afar off, would not lift up so much as <supplied>his</supplied> eyes unto heaven, but smote upon his
breast, saying, God be merciful to me a sinner. </jesus></verse><verse><jesus>I tell you, this man went down to his house justified <supplied>rather</supplied> than the other: for every one that exalteth himself shall be abased; and he that humbleth himself shall be exalted.
</jesus></verse><verse>And they brought unto him also infants, that he would touch them: but when <supplied>his</supplied> disciples saw <supplied>it,</supplied> they rebuked them.
</verse><verse>But Jesus called them <supplied>unto him,</supplied> and said, <jesus>Suffer little children to come unto me, and forbid them not: for of such is the kingdom of God. </jesus></verse><verse><jesus>Verily I say unto you, Whosoever shall not receive the kingdom of God as a
little child shall in no wise enter therein. </jesus></verse><verse>And a certain ruler asked him, saying, Good Master, what shall I do to inherit eternal life?
</verse><verse>And Jesus said unto him, <jesus>Why callest thou me good? none <supplied>is</supplied> good, save one, <supplied>that is,</supplied> God. </jesus></verse><verse><jesus>Thou knowest the commandments, Do not commit adultery, Do not kill, Do not steal, Do not bear false witness, Honour thy
father and thy mother. </jesus></verse><verse>And he said, All these have I kept from my youth up.
</verse><verse>Now when Jesus heard these things, he said unto him, <jesus>Yet lackest thou one thing: sell all that thou hast, and distribute unto the poor, and thou shalt have treasure in heaven: and come, follow me. </jesus></verse><verse>And when he heard this, he was
very sorrowful: for he was very rich.
</verse><verse>And when Jesus saw that he was very sorrowful, he said, <jesus>How hardly shall they that have riches enter into the kingdom of God! </jesus></verse><verse><jesus>For it is easier for a camel to go through a needle&#x2019;s eye, than for a rich man to enter into the
kingdom of God. </jesus></verse><verse>And they that heard <supplied>it</supplied> said, Who then can be saved?
</verse><verse>And he said, <jesus>The things which are impossible with men are possible with God. </jesus></verse><verse>Then Peter said, Lo, we have left all, and followed thee.
</verse><verse>And he said unto them, <jesus>Verily I say unto you, There is no man that hath left house, or parents, or brethren, or wife, or children, for the kingdom of God&#x2019;s sake, </jesus></verse><verse><jesus>Who shall not receive manifold more in this present time, and
in the world to come life everlasting.
     
      </jesus>
      </verse>
      <verse>Then he took <supplied>unto him</supplied> the twelve, and said unto them, <jesus>Behold, we go up to Jerusalem, and all things that are written by the prophets concerning the Son of man shall be accomplished. </jesus></verse><verse><jesus>For he shall be delivered unto
the Gentiles, and shall be mocked, and spitefully entreated, and spitted on: </jesus></verse><verse><jesus>And they shall scourge <supplied>him,</supplied> and put him to death: and the third day he shall rise again. </jesus></verse><verse>And they understood none of these things: and this
saying was hid from them, neither knew they the things which were spoken.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>And it came to pass, that as he was come nigh unto Jericho, a certain blind man sat by the way side begging:
</verse><verse>And hearing the multitude pass by, he asked what it meant.
</verse><verse>And they told him, that Jesus of Nazareth passeth by.
</verse><verse>And he cried, saying, Jesus, <supplied>thou</supplied> Son of David, have mercy on me.
</verse><verse>And they which went before rebuked him, that he should hold his peace: but he cried so much the more, <supplied>Thou</supplied> Son of David, have mercy on me.
</verse><verse>And Jesus stood, and commanded him to be brought unto him: and when he was come near, he asked him,
</verse><verse>Saying, <jesus>What wilt thou that I shall do unto thee?</jesus> And he said, Lord, that I may receive my sight.
</verse><verse>And Jesus said unto him, <jesus>Receive thy sight: thy faith hath saved thee. </jesus></verse><verse>And immediately he received his sight, and followed him, glorifying God: and all the people, when they saw <supplied>it,</supplied> gave praise unto God.
     
      </verse>
      </chapter>
