<chapter translation="ESV" testament="Old" book="Proverbs" book-id="20" n="11">
<verse>A false balance is an abomination to the LORD, but a just weight is his delight.</verse>
<verse>When pride comes, then comes disgrace, but with the humble is wisdom.</verse>
<verse>The integrity of the upright guides them, but the crookedness of the treacherous destroys them.</verse>
<verse>Riches do not profit in the day of wrath, but righteousness delivers from death.</verse>
<verse>The righteousness of the blameless keeps his way straight, but the wicked falls by his own wickedness.</verse>
<verse>The righteousness of the upright delivers them, but the treacherous are taken captive by their lust.</verse>
<verse>When the wicked dies, his hope will perish, and the expectation of wealth perishes too.</verse>
<verse>The righteous is delivered from trouble, and the wicked walks into it instead.</verse>
<verse>With his mouth the godless man would destroy his neighbor, but by knowledge the righteous are delivered.</verse>
<verse>When it goes well with the righteous, the city rejoices, and when the wicked perish there are shouts of gladness.</verse>
<verse>By the blessing of the upright a city is exalted, but by the mouth of the wicked it is overthrown.</verse>
<verse>Whoever belittles his neighbor lacks sense, but a man of understanding remains silent.</verse>
<verse>Whoever goes about slandering reveals secrets, but he who is trustworthy in spirit keeps a thing covered.</verse>
<verse>Where there is no guidance, a people falls, but in an abundance of counselors there is safety.</verse>
<verse>Whoever puts up security for a stranger will surely suffer harm, but he who hates striking hands in pledge is secure.</verse>
<verse>A gracious woman gets honor, and violent men get riches.</verse>
<verse>A man who is kind benefits himself, but a cruel man hurts himself.</verse>
<verse>The wicked earns deceptive wages, but one who sows righteousness gets a sure reward.</verse>
<verse>Whoever is steadfast in righteousness will live, but he who pursues evil will die.</verse>
<verse>Those of crooked heart are an abomination to the LORD, but those of blameless ways are his delight.</verse>
<verse>Be assured, an evil person will not go unpunished, but the offspring of the righteous will be delivered.</verse>
<verse>Like a gold ring in a pig's snout is a beautiful woman without discretion.</verse>
<verse>The desire of the righteous ends only in good; the expectation of the wicked in wrath.</verse>
<verse>One gives freely, yet grows all the richer; another withholds what he should give, and only suffers want.</verse>
<verse>Whoever brings blessing will be enriched, and one who waters will himself be watered.</verse>
<verse>The people curse him who holds back grain, but a blessing is on the head of him who sells it.</verse>
<verse>Whoever diligently seeks good seeks favor, but evil comes to him who searches for it.</verse>
<verse>Whoever trusts in his riches will fall, but the righteous will flourish like a green leaf.</verse>
<verse>Whoever troubles his own household will inherit the wind, and the fool will be servant to the wise of heart.</verse>
<verse>The fruit of the righteous is a tree of life, and whoever captures souls is wise.</verse>
<verse>If the righteous is repaid on earth, how much more the wicked and the sinner!</verse>
</chapter>