<chapter translation="ESV" testament="Old" book="Proverbs" book_id="20" n="13">
<verse>A wise son hears his father's instruction, but a scoffer does not listen to rebuke.</verse>
<verse>From the fruit of his mouth a man eats what is good, but the desire of the treacherous is for violence.</verse>
<verse>Whoever guards his mouth preserves his life; he who opens wide his lips comes to ruin.</verse>
<verse>The soul of the sluggard craves and gets nothing, while the soul of the diligent is richly supplied.</verse>
<verse>The righteous hates falsehood, but the wicked brings shame and disgrace.</verse>
<verse>Righteousness guards him whose way is blameless, but sin overthrows the wicked.</verse>
<verse>One pretends to be rich, yet has nothing; another pretends to be poor, yet has great wealth.</verse>
<verse>The ransom of a man's life is his wealth, but a poor man hears no threat.</verse>
<verse>The light of the righteous rejoices, but the lamp of the wicked will be put out.</verse>
<verse>By insolence comes nothing but strife, but with those who take advice is wisdom.</verse>
<verse>Wealth gained hastily will dwindle, but whoever gathers little by little will increase it.</verse>
<verse>Hope deferred makes the heart sick, but a desire fulfilled is a tree of life.</verse>
<verse>Whoever despises the word brings destruction on himself, but he who reveres the commandment will be rewarded.</verse>
<verse>The teaching of the wise is a fountain of life, that one may turn away from the snares of death.</verse>
<verse>Good sense wins favor, but the way of the treacherous is their ruin.</verse>
<verse>In everything the prudent acts with knowledge, but a fool flaunts his folly.</verse>
<verse>A wicked messenger falls into trouble, but a faithful envoy brings healing.</verse>
<verse>Poverty and disgrace come to him who ignores instruction, but whoever heeds reproof is honored.</verse>
<verse>A desire fulfilled is sweet to the soul, but to turn away from evil is an abomination to fools.</verse>
<verse>Whoever walks with the wise becomes wise, but the companion of fools will suffer harm.</verse>
<verse>Disaster pursues sinners, but the righteous are rewarded with good.</verse>
<verse>A good man leaves an inheritance to his children's children, but the sinner's wealth is laid up for the righteous.</verse>
<verse>The fallow ground of the poor would yield much food, but it is swept away through injustice.</verse>
<verse>Whoever spares the rod hates his son, but he who loves him is diligent to discipline him.</verse>
<verse>The righteous has enough to satisfy his appetite, but the belly of the wicked suffers want.</verse>
</chapter>