<chapter translation="ESV" testament="Old" book="Proverbs" book_id="20" n="14">
<verse>The wisest of women builds her house, but folly with her own hands tears it down.</verse>
<verse>Whoever walks in uprightness fears the LORD, but he who is devious in his ways despises him.</verse>
<verse>By the mouth of a fool comes a rod for his back, but the lips of the wise will preserve them.</verse>
<verse>Where there are no oxen, the manger is clean, but abundant crops come by the strength of the ox.</verse>
<verse>A faithful witness does not lie, but a false witness breathes out lies.</verse>
<verse>A scoffer seeks wisdom in vain, but knowledge is easy for a man of understanding.</verse>
<verse>Leave the presence of a fool, for there you do not meet words of knowledge.</verse>
<verse>The wisdom of the prudent is to discern his way, but the folly of fools is deceiving.</verse>
<verse>Fools mock at the guilt offering, but the upright enjoy acceptance.</verse>
<verse>The heart knows its own bitterness, and no stranger shares its joy.</verse>
<verse>The house of the wicked will be destroyed, but the tent of the upright will flourish.</verse>
<verse>There is a way that seems right to a man, but its end is the way to death.</verse>
<verse>Even in laughter the heart may ache, and the end of joy may be grief.</verse>
<verse>The backslider in heart will be filled with the fruit of his ways, and a good man will be filled with the fruit of his ways.</verse>
<verse>The simple believes everything, but the prudent gives thought to his steps.</verse>
<verse>One who is wise is cautious and turns away from evil, but a fool is reckless and careless.</verse>
<verse>A man of quick temper acts foolishly, and a man of evil devices is hated.</verse>
<verse>The simple inherit folly, but the prudent are crowned with knowledge.</verse>
<verse>The evil bow down before the good, the wicked at the gates of the righteous.</verse>
<verse>The poor is disliked even by his neighbor, but the rich has many friends.</verse>
<verse>Whoever despises his neighbor is a sinner, but blessed is he who is generous to the poor.</verse>
<verse>Do they not go astray who devise evil? Those who devise good meet steadfast love and faithfulness.</verse>
<verse>In all toil there is profit, but mere talk tends only to poverty.</verse>
<verse>The crown of the wise is their wealth, but the folly of fools brings folly.</verse>
<verse>A truthful witness saves lives, but one who breathes out lies is deceitful.</verse>
<verse>In the fear of the LORD one has strong confidence, and his children will have a refuge.</verse>
<verse>The fear of the LORD is a fountain of life, that one may turn away from the snares of death.</verse>
<verse>In a multitude of people is the glory of a king, but without people a prince is ruined.</verse>
<verse>Whoever is slow to anger has great understanding, but he who has a hasty temper exalts folly.</verse>
<verse>A tranquil heart gives life to the flesh, but envy makes the bones rot.</verse>
<verse>Whoever oppresses a poor man insults his Maker, but he who is generous to the needy honors him.</verse>
<verse>The wicked is overthrown through his evildoing, but the righteous finds refuge in his death.</verse>
<verse>Wisdom rests in the heart of a man of understanding, but it makes itself known even in the midst of fools.</verse>
<verse>Righteousness exalts a nation, but sin is a reproach to any people.</verse>
<verse>A servant who deals wisely has the king's favor, but his wrath falls on one who acts shamefully.</verse>
</chapter>