<chapter translation="ESV" testament="Old" book="Proverbs" book-id="20" n="18">
<verse>Whoever isolates himself seeks his own desire; he breaks out against all sound judgment.</verse>
<verse>A fool takes no pleasure in understanding, but only in expressing his opinion.</verse>
<verse>When wickedness comes, contempt comes also, and with dishonor comes disgrace.</verse>
<verse>The words of a man's mouth are deep waters; the fountain of wisdom is a bubbling brook.</verse>
<verse>It is not good to be partial to the wicked or to deprive the righteous of justice.</verse>
<verse>A fool's lips walk into a fight, and his mouth invites a beating.</verse>
<verse>A fool's mouth is his ruin, and his lips are a snare to his soul.</verse>
<verse>The words of a whisperer are like delicious morsels; they go down into the inner parts of the body.</verse>
<verse>Whoever is slack in his work is a brother to him who destroys.</verse>
<verse>The name of the LORD is a strong tower; the righteous man runs into it and is safe.</verse>
<verse>A rich man's wealth is his strong city, and like a high wall in his imagination.</verse>
<verse>Before destruction a man's heart is haughty, but humility comes before honor.</verse>
<verse>If one gives an answer before he hears, it is his folly and shame.</verse>
<verse>A man's spirit will endure sickness, but a crushed spirit who can bear?</verse>
<verse>An intelligent heart acquires knowledge, and the ear of the wise seeks knowledge.</verse>
<verse>A man's gift makes room for him and brings him before the great.</verse>
<verse>The one who states his case first seems right, until the other comes and examines him.</verse>
<verse>The lot puts an end to quarrels and decides between powerful contenders.</verse>
<verse>A brother offended is more unyielding than a strong city, and quarreling is like the bars of a castle.</verse>
<verse>From the fruit of a man's mouth his stomach is satisfied; he is satisfied by the yield of his lips.</verse>
<verse>Death and life are in the power of the tongue, and those who love it will eat its fruits.</verse>
<verse>He who finds a wife finds a good thing and obtains favor from the LORD.</verse>
<verse>The poor use entreaties, but the rich answer roughly.</verse>
<verse>A man of many companions may come to ruin, but there is a friend who sticks closer than a brother.</verse>
</chapter>