<chapter translation="ESV" testament="Old" book="Proverbs" book-id="20" n="26">
<verse>Like snow in summer or rain in harvest, so honor is not fitting for a fool.</verse>
<verse>Like a sparrow in its flitting, like a swallow in its flying, a curse that is causeless does not alight.</verse>
<verse>A whip for the horse, a bridle for the donkey, and a rod for the back of fools.</verse>
<verse>Answer not a fool according to his folly, lest you be like him yourself.</verse>
<verse>Answer a fool according to his folly, lest he be wise in his own eyes.</verse>
<verse>Whoever sends a message by the hand of a fool cuts off his own feet and drinks violence.</verse>
<verse>Like a lame man's legs, which hang useless, is a proverb in the mouth of fools.</verse>
<verse>Like one who binds the stone in the sling is one who gives honor to a fool.</verse>
<verse>Like a thorn that goes up into the hand of a drunkard is a proverb in the mouth of fools.</verse>
<verse>Like an archer who wounds everyone is one who hires a passing fool or drunkard.</verse>
<verse>Like a dog that returns to his vomit is a fool who repeats his folly.</verse>
<verse>Do you see a man who is wise in his own eyes? There is more hope for a fool than for him.</verse>
<verse>The sluggard says, "There is a lion in the road! There is a lion in the streets!"</verse>
<verse>As a door turns on its hinges, so does a sluggard on his bed.</verse>
<verse>The sluggard buries his hand in the dish; it wears him out to bring it back to his mouth.</verse>
<verse>The sluggard is wiser in his own eyes than seven men who can answer sensibly.</verse>
<verse>Whoever meddles in a quarrel not his own is like one who takes a passing dog by the ears.</verse>
<verse>Like a madman who throws firebrands, arrows, and death</verse>
<verse>is the man who deceives his neighbor and says, "I am only joking!"</verse>
<verse>For lack of wood the fire goes out, and where there is no whisperer, quarreling ceases.</verse>
<verse>As charcoal to hot embers and wood to fire, so is a quarrelsome man for kindling strife.</verse>
<verse>The words of a whisperer are like delicious morsels; they go down into the inner parts of the body.</verse>
<verse>Like the glaze covering an earthen vessel are fervent lips with an evil heart.</verse>
<verse>Whoever hates disguises himself with his lips and harbors deceit in his heart;</verse>
<verse>when he speaks graciously, believe him not, for there are seven abominations in his heart;</verse>
<verse>though his hatred be covered with deception, his wickedness will be exposed in the assembly.</verse>
<verse>Whoever digs a pit will fall into it, and a stone will come back on him who starts it rolling.</verse>
<verse>A lying tongue hates its victims, and a flattering mouth works ruin.</verse>
</chapter>