<chapter translation="ESV" testament="Old" book="Proverbs" book-id="20" n="27">
<verse>Do not boast about tomorrow, for you do not know what a day may bring.</verse>
<verse>Let another praise you, and not your own mouth; a stranger, and not your own lips.</verse>
<verse>A stone is heavy, and sand is weighty, but a fool's provocation is heavier than both.</verse>
<verse>Wrath is cruel, anger is overwhelming, but who can stand before jealousy?</verse>
<verse>Better is open rebuke than hidden love.</verse>
<verse>Faithful are the wounds of a friend; profuse are the kisses of an enemy.</verse>
<verse>One who is full loathes honey, but to one who is hungry everything bitter is sweet.</verse>
<verse>Like a bird that strays from its nest is a man who strays from his home.</verse>
<verse>Oil and perfume make the heart glad, and the sweetness of a friend comes from his earnest counsel.</verse>
<verse>Do not forsake your friend and your father's friend, and do not go to your brother's house in the day of your calamity. Better is a neighbor who is near than a brother who is far away.</verse>
<verse>Be wise, my son, and make my heart glad, that I may answer him who reproaches me.</verse>
<verse>The prudent sees danger and hides himself, but the simple go on and suffer for it.</verse>
<verse>Take a man's garment when he has put up security for a stranger, and hold it in pledge when he puts up security for an adulteress.</verse>
<verse>Whoever blesses his neighbor with a loud voice, rising early in the morning, will be counted as cursing.</verse>
<verse>A continual dripping on a rainy day and a quarrelsome wife are alike;</verse>
<verse>to restrain her is to restrain the wind or to grasp oil in one's right hand.</verse>
<verse>Iron sharpens iron, and one man sharpens another.</verse>
<verse>Whoever tends a fig tree will eat its fruit, and he who guards his master will be honored.</verse>
<verse>As in water face reflects face, so the heart of man reflects the man.</verse>
<verse>Sheol and Abaddon are never satisfied, and never satisfied are the eyes of man.</verse>
<verse>The crucible is for silver, and the furnace is for gold, and a man is tested by his praise.</verse>
<verse>Crush a fool in a mortar with a pestle along with crushed grain, yet his folly will not depart from him.</verse>
<verse>Know well the condition of your flocks, and give attention to your herds,</verse>
<verse>for riches do not last forever; and does a crown endure to all generations?</verse>
<verse>When the grass is gone and the new growth appears and the vegetation of the mountains is gathered,</verse>
<verse>the lambs will provide your clothing, and the goats the price of a field.</verse>
<verse>There will be enough goats' milk for your food, for the food of your household and maintenance for your girls.</verse>
</chapter>