<chapter translation="ESV" testament="Old" book="Proverbs" book-id="20" n="28">
<verse>The wicked flee when no one pursues, but the righteous are bold as a lion.</verse>
<verse>When a land transgresses, it has many rulers, but with a man of understanding and knowledge, its stability will long continue.</verse>
<verse>A poor man who oppresses the poor is a beating rain that leaves no food.</verse>
<verse>Those who forsake the law praise the wicked, but those who keep the law strive against them.</verse>
<verse>Evil men do not understand justice, but those who seek the LORD understand it completely.</verse>
<verse>Better is a poor man who walks in his integrity than a rich man who is crooked in his ways.</verse>
<verse>The one who keeps the law is a son with understanding, but a companion of gluttons shames his father.</verse>
<verse>Whoever multiplies his wealth by interest and profit gathers it for him who is generous to the poor.</verse>
<verse>If one turns away his ear from hearing the law, even his prayer is an abomination.</verse>
<verse>Whoever misleads the upright into an evil way will fall into his own pit, but the blameless will have a goodly inheritance.</verse>
<verse>A rich man is wise in his own eyes, but a poor man who has understanding will find him out.</verse>
<verse>When the righteous triumph, there is great glory, but when the wicked rise, people hide themselves.</verse>
<verse>Whoever conceals his transgressions will not prosper, but he who confesses and forsakes them will obtain mercy.</verse>
<verse>Blessed is the one who fears the LORD always, but whoever hardens his heart will fall into calamity.</verse>
<verse>Like a roaring lion or a charging bear is a wicked ruler over a poor people.</verse>
<verse>A ruler who lacks understanding is a cruel oppressor, but he who hates unjust gain will prolong his days.</verse>
<verse>If one is burdened with the blood of another, he will be a fugitive until death; let no one help him.</verse>
<verse>Whoever walks in integrity will be delivered, but he who is crooked in his ways will suddenly fall.</verse>
<verse>Whoever works his land will have plenty of bread, but he who follows worthless pursuits will have plenty of poverty.</verse>
<verse>A faithful man will abound with blessings, but whoever hastens to be rich will not go unpunished.</verse>
<verse>To show partiality is not good, but for a piece of bread a man will do wrong.</verse>
<verse>A stingy man hastens after wealth and does not know that poverty will come upon him.</verse>
<verse>Whoever rebukes a man will afterward find more favor than he who flatters with his tongue.</verse>
<verse>Whoever robs his father or his mother and says, "That is no transgression," is a companion to a man who destroys.</verse>
<verse>A greedy man stirs up strife, but the one who trusts in the LORD will be enriched.</verse>
<verse>Whoever trusts in his own mind is a fool, but he who walks in wisdom will be delivered.</verse>
<verse>Whoever gives to the poor will not want, but he who hides his eyes will get many a curse.</verse>
<verse>When the wicked rise, people hide themselves, but when they perish, the righteous increase.</verse>
</chapter>