<chapter translation="ESV" testament="Old" book="Proverbs" book_id="20" n="4">
<verse>Hear, O sons, a father's instruction, and be attentive, that you may gain insight,</verse>
<verse>for I give you good precepts; do not forsake my teaching.</verse>
<verse>When I was a son with my father, tender, the only one in the sight of my mother,</verse>
<verse>he taught me and said to me, "Let your heart hold fast my words; keep my commandments, and live.</verse>
<verse>Get wisdom; get insight; do not forget, and do not turn away from the words of my mouth.</verse>
<verse>Do not forsake her, and she will keep you; love her, and she will guard you.</verse>
<verse>The beginning of wisdom is this: Get wisdom, and whatever you get, get insight.</verse>
<verse>Prize her highly, and she will exalt you; she will honor you if you embrace her.</verse>
<verse>She will place on your head a graceful garland; she will bestow on you a beautiful crown."</verse>
<verse>Hear, my son, and accept my words, that the years of your life may be many.</verse>
<verse>I have taught you the way of wisdom; I have led you in the paths of uprightness.</verse>
<verse>When you walk, your step will not be hampered, and if you run, you will not stumble.</verse>
<verse>Keep hold of instruction; do not let go; guard her, for she is your life.</verse>
<verse>Do not enter the path of the wicked, and do not walk in the way of the evil.</verse>
<verse>Avoid it; do not go on it; turn away from it and pass on.</verse>
<verse>For they cannot sleep unless they have done wrong; they are robbed of sleep unless they have made someone stumble.</verse>
<verse>For they eat the bread of wickedness and drink the wine of violence.</verse>
<verse>But the path of the righteous is like the light of dawn, which shines brighter and brighter until full day.</verse>
<verse>The way of the wicked is like deep darkness; they do not know over what they stumble.</verse>
<verse>My son, be attentive to my words; incline your ear to my sayings.</verse>
<verse>Let them not escape from your sight; keep them within your heart.</verse>
<verse>For they are life to those who find them, and healing to all their flesh.</verse>
<verse>Keep your heart with all vigilance, for from it flow the springs of life.</verse>
<verse>Put away from you crooked speech, and put devious talk far from you.</verse>
<verse>Let your eyes look directly forward, and your gaze be straight before you.</verse>
<verse>Ponder the path of your feet; then all your ways will be sure.</verse>
<verse>Do not swerve to the right or to the left; turn your foot away from evil.</verse>
</chapter>