<chapter translation="ESV" testament="Old" book="Proverbs" book-id="20" n="6">
<verse>My son, if you have put up security for your neighbor, have given your pledge for a stranger,</verse>
<verse>if you are snared in the words of your mouth, caught in the words of your mouth,</verse>
<verse>then do this, my son, and save yourself, for you have come into the hand of your neighbor: go, hasten, and plead urgently with your neighbor.</verse>
<verse>Give your eyes no sleep and your eyelids no slumber;</verse>
<verse>save yourself like a gazelle from the hand of the hunter, like a bird from the hand of the fowler.</verse>
<verse>Go to the ant, O sluggard; consider her ways, and be wise.</verse>
<verse>Without having any chief, officer, or ruler,</verse>
<verse>she prepares her bread in summer and gathers her food in harvest.</verse>
<verse>How long will you lie there, O sluggard? When will you arise from your sleep?</verse>
<verse>A little sleep, a little slumber, a little folding of the hands to rest,</verse>
<verse>and poverty will come upon you like a robber, and want like an armed man.</verse>
<verse>A worthless person, a wicked man, goes about with crooked speech,</verse>
<verse>winks with his eyes, signals with his feet, points with his finger,</verse>
<verse>with perverted heart devises evil, continually sowing discord;</verse>
<verse>therefore calamity will come upon him suddenly; in a moment he will be broken beyond healing.</verse>
<verse>There are six things that the LORD hates, seven that are an abomination to him:</verse>
<verse>haughty eyes, a lying tongue, and hands that shed innocent blood,</verse>
<verse>a heart that devises wicked plans, feet that make haste to run to evil,</verse>
<verse>a false witness who breathes out lies, and one who sows discord among brothers.</verse>
<verse>My son, keep your father's commandment, and forsake not your mother's teaching.</verse>
<verse>Bind them on your heart always; tie them around your neck.</verse>
<verse>When you walk, they will lead you; when you lie down, they will watch over you; and when you awake, they will talk with you.</verse>
<verse>For the commandment is a lamp and the teaching a light, and the reproofs of discipline are the way of life,</verse>
<verse>to preserve you from the evil woman, from the smooth tongue of the adulteress.</verse>
<verse>Do not desire her beauty in your heart, and do not let her capture you with her eyelashes;</verse>
<verse>for the price of a prostitute is only a loaf of bread, but a married woman hunts down a precious life.</verse>
<verse>Can a man carry fire next to his chest and his clothes not be burned?</verse>
<verse>Or can one walk on hot coals and his feet not be scorched?</verse>
<verse>So is he who goes in to his neighbor's wife; none who touches her will go unpunished.</verse>
<verse>People do not despise a thief if he steals to satisfy his appetite when he is hungry,</verse>
<verse>but if he is caught, he will pay sevenfold; he will give all the goods of his house.</verse>
<verse>He who commits adultery lacks sense; he who does it destroys himself.</verse>
<verse>Wounds and dishonor will he get, and his disgrace will not be wiped away.</verse>
<verse>For jealousy makes a man furious, and he will not spare when he takes revenge.</verse>
<verse>He will accept no compensation; he will refuse though you multiply gifts.</verse>
</chapter>