<chapter translation="ESV" testament="Old" book="Proverbs" book_id="20" n="7">
<verse>My son, keep my words and treasure up my commandments with you;</verse>
<verse>keep my commandments and live; keep my teaching as the apple of your eye;</verse>
<verse>bind them on your fingers; write them on the tablet of your heart.</verse>
<verse>Say to wisdom, "You are my sister," and call insight your intimate friend,</verse>
<verse>to keep you from the forbidden woman, from the adulteress with her smooth words.</verse>
<verse>For at the window of my house I have looked out through my lattice,</verse>
<verse>and I have seen among the simple, I have perceived among the youths, a young man lacking sense,</verse>
<verse>passing along the street near her corner, taking the road to her house</verse>
<verse>in the twilight, in the evening, at the time of night and darkness.</verse>
<verse>And behold, the woman meets him, dressed as a prostitute, wily of heart.</verse>
<verse>She is loud and wayward; her feet do not stay at home;</verse>
<verse>now in the street, now in the market, and at every corner she lies in wait.</verse>
<verse>She seizes him and kisses him, and with bold face she says to him,</verse>
<verse>"I had to offer sacrifices, and today I have paid my vows;</verse>
<verse>so now I have come out to meet you, to seek you eagerly, and I have found you.</verse>
<verse>I have spread my couch with coverings, colored linens from Egyptian linen;</verse>
<verse>I have perfumed my bed with myrrh, aloes, and cinnamon.</verse>
<verse>Come, let us take our fill of love till morning; let us delight ourselves with love.</verse>
<verse>For my husband is not at home; he has gone on a long journey;</verse>
<verse>he took a bag of money with him; at full moon he will come home."</verse>
<verse>With much seductive speech she persuades him; with her smooth talk she compels him.</verse>
<verse>All at once he follows her, as an ox goes to the slaughter, or as a stag is caught fast</verse>
<verse>till an arrow pierces its liver; as a bird rushes into a snare; he does not know that it will cost him his life.</verse>
<verse>And now, O sons, listen to me, and be attentive to the words of my mouth.</verse>
<verse>Let not your heart turn aside to her ways; do not stray into her paths,</verse>
<verse>for many a victim has she laid low, and all her slain are a mighty throng.</verse>
<verse>Her house is the way to Sheol, going down to the chambers of death.</verse>
</chapter>