<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Joel" book-id="29" n="3">
<verse>"For behold, in those days and at that time, When I restore the fortunes of Judah and Jerusalem,</verse>
<verse>I will gather all the nations And bring them down to the valley of Jehoshaphat. Then I will enter into judgment with them there On behalf of My people and My inheritance, Israel, Whom they have scattered among the nations; And they have divided up My land.</verse>
<verse>"They have also cast lots for My people, Traded a boy for a harlot And sold a girl for wine that they may drink.</verse>
<verse>"Moreover, what are you to Me, O Tyre, Sidon and all the regions of Philistia? Are you rendering Me a recompense? But if you do recompense Me, swiftly and speedily I will return your recompense on your head.</verse>
<verse>"Since you have taken My silver and My gold, brought My precious treasures to your temples,</verse>
<verse>and sold the sons of Judah and Jerusalem to the Greeks in order to remove them far from their territory,</verse>
<verse>behold, I am going to arouse them from the place where you have sold them, and return your recompense on your head.</verse>
<verse>"Also I will sell your sons and your daughters into the hand of the sons of Judah, and they will sell them to the Sabeans, to a distant nation," for the LORD has spoken.</verse>
<verse>Proclaim this among the nations: Prepare a war; rouse the mighty men! Let all the soldiers draw near, let them come up!</verse>
<verse>Beat your plowshares into swords And your pruning hooks into spears; Let the weak say, "I am a mighty man."</verse>
<verse>Hasten and come, all you surrounding nations, And gather yourselves there. Bring down, O LORD, Your mighty ones.</verse>
<verse>Let the nations be aroused And come up to the valley of Jehoshaphat, For there I will sit to judge All the surrounding nations.</verse>
<verse>Put in the sickle, for the harvest is ripe. Come, tread, for the wine press is full; The vats overflow, for their wickedness is great.</verse>
<verse>Multitudes, multitudes in the valley of decision! For the day of the LORD is near in the valley of decision.</verse>
<verse>The sun and moon grow dark And the stars lose their brightness.</verse>
<verse>The LORD roars from Zion And utters His voice from Jerusalem, And the heavens and the earth tremble. But the LORD is a refuge for His people And a stronghold to the sons of Israel.</verse>
<verse>Then you will know that I am the LORD your God, Dwelling in Zion, My holy mountain. So Jerusalem will be holy, And strangers will pass through it no more.</verse>
<verse>And in that day The mountains will drip with sweet wine, And the hills will flow with milk, And all the brooks of Judah will flow with water; And a spring will go out from the house of the LORD To water the valley of Shittim.</verse>
<verse>Egypt will become a waste, And Edom will become a desolate wilderness, Because of the violence done to the sons of Judah, In whose land they have shed innocent blood.</verse>
<verse>But Judah will be inhabited forever And Jerusalem for all generations.</verse>
<verse>And I will avenge their blood which I have not avenged, For the LORD dwells in Zion.</verse>
</chapter>