<chapter translation="MSG" testament="New" book="Romans" book_id="45" n="13">
<verse>Be a good citizen. All governments are under God. Insofar as there is peace and order, it's God's order. So live responsibly as a citizen.</verse>
<verse>If you're irresponsible to the state, then you're irresponsible with God, and God will hold you responsible.</verse>
<verse>Duly constituted authorities are only a threat if you're trying to get by with something. Decent citizens should have nothing to fear. Do you want to be on good terms with the government? Be a responsible citizen and you'll get on just fine,</verse>
<verse>the government working to your advantage. But if you're breaking the rules right and left, watch out. The police aren't there just to be admired in their uniforms. God also has an interest in keeping order, and he uses them to do it.</verse>
<verse>That's why you must live responsibly--not just to avoid punishment but also because it's the right way to live.</verse>
<verse>That's also why you pay taxes--so that an orderly way of life can be maintained.</verse>
<verse>Fulfill your obligations as a citizen. Pay your taxes, pay your bills, respect your leaders. [JC]</verse>
<verse>Don't run up debts, except for the huge debt of love you owe each other. When you love others, you complete what the law has been after all along.</verse>
<verse>The law code--don't sleep with another person's spouse, don't take someone's life, don't take what isn't yours, don't always be wanting what you don't have, and any other "don't" you can think of--finally adds up to this: Love other people as well as you do yourself.</verse>
<verse>You can't go wrong when you love others. When you add up everything in the law code, the sum total is love.</verse>
<verse>But make sure that you don't get so absorbed and exhausted in taking care of all your day-by-day obligations that you lose track of the time and doze off, oblivious to God.</verse>
<verse>The night is about over, dawn is about to break. Be up and awake to what God is doing! God is putting the finishing touches on the salvation work he began when we first believed.</verse>
<verse>We can't afford to waste a minute, must not squander these precious daylight hours in frivolity and indulgence, in sleeping around and dissipation, in bickering and grabbing everything in sight.</verse>
<verse>Get out of bed and get dressed! Don't loiter and linger, waiting until the very last minute. Dress yourselves in Christ, and be up and about!</verse>
</chapter>