<?xml version="1.0"?>
<chapter translation="KJV" testament="Old" book="Joel" n="3" book_id="29">
      <verse>For, behold, in those days, and in that time, when I shall bring again the captivity of Judah and Jerusalem,
</verse><verse>I will also gather all nations, and will bring them down into the valley of Jehoshaphat, and will plead with them there for my people and <supplied>for</supplied> my heritage Israel, whom they have scattered among the nations, and parted my land.
</verse><verse>And they have cast lots for my people; and have given a boy for an harlot, and sold a girl for wine, that they might drink.
</verse><verse>Yea, and what have ye to do with me, O Tyre, and Zidon, and all the coasts of Palestine? will ye render me a recompence? and if ye recompense me, swiftly <supplied>and</supplied> speedily will I return your recompence upon your own head;
</verse><verse>Because ye have taken my silver and my gold, and have carried into your temples my goodly pleasant things:
</verse><verse>The children also of Judah and the children of Jerusalem have ye sold unto the Grecians, that ye might remove them far from their border.
</verse><verse>Behold, I will raise them out of the place whither ye have sold them, and will return your recompence upon your own head:
</verse><verse>And I will sell your sons and your daughters into the hand of the children of Judah, and they shall sell them to the Sabeans, to a people far off: for the LORD hath spoken <supplied>it.</supplied>
     
      </verse>
      <verse>Proclaim ye this among the Gentiles; Prepare war, wake up the mighty men, let all the men of war draw near; let them come up:
</verse><verse>Beat your plowshares into swords, and your pruninghooks into spears: let the weak say, I <supplied>am</supplied> strong.
</verse><verse>Assemble yourselves, and come, all ye heathen, and gather yourselves together round about: thither cause thy mighty ones to come down, O LORD.
</verse><verse>Let the heathen be wakened, and come up to the valley of Jehoshaphat: for there will I sit to judge all the heathen round about.
</verse><verse>Put ye in the sickle, for the harvest is ripe: come, get you down; for the press is full, the fats overflow; for their wickedness <supplied>is</supplied> great.
</verse><verse>Multitudes, multitudes in the valley of decision: for the day of the LORD <supplied>is</supplied> near in the valley of decision.
</verse><verse>The sun and the moon shall be darkened, and the stars shall withdraw their shining.
</verse><verse>The LORD also shall roar out of Zion, and utter his voice from Jerusalem; and the heavens and the earth shall shake: but the LORD <supplied>will be</supplied> the hope of his people, and the strength of the children of Israel.
</verse><verse>So shall ye know that I <supplied>am</supplied> the LORD your God dwelling in Zion, my holy mountain: then shall Jerusalem be holy, and there shall no strangers pass through her any more.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>And it shall come to pass in that day, <supplied>that</supplied> the mountains shall drop down new wine, and the hills shall flow with milk, and all the rivers of Judah shall flow with waters, and a fountain shall come forth of the house of the LORD, and
shall water the valley of Shittim.
</verse><verse>Egypt shall be a desolation, and Edom shall be a desolate wilderness, for the violence <supplied>against</supplied> the children of Judah, because they have shed innocent blood in their land.
</verse><verse>But Judah shall dwell for ever, and Jerusalem from generation to generation.
</verse><verse>For I will cleanse their blood <supplied>that</supplied> I have not cleansed: for the LORD dwelleth in Zion.
     
     
      </verse>
      </chapter>
