<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Exodus" book_id="2" n="19">
<verse>In the third month after the sons of Israel had gone out of the land of Egypt, on that very day they came into the wilderness of Sinai.</verse>
<verse>When they set out from Rephidim, they came to the wilderness of Sinai and camped in the wilderness; and there Israel camped in front of the mountain.</verse>
<verse>Moses went up to God, and the LORD called to him from the mountain, saying, "Thus you shall say to the house of Jacob and tell the sons of Israel:</verse>
<verse>'You yourselves have seen what I did to the Egyptians, and how I bore you on eagles' wings, and brought you to Myself.</verse>
<verse>'Now then, if you will indeed obey My voice and keep My covenant, then you shall be My own possession among all the peoples, for all the earth is Mine;</verse>
<verse>and you shall be to Me a kingdom of priests and a holy nation.' These are the words that you shall speak to the sons of Israel."</verse>
<verse>So Moses came and called the elders of the people, and set before them all these words which the LORD had commanded him.</verse>
<verse>All the people answered together and said, "All that the LORD has spoken we will do!" And Moses brought back the words of the people to the LORD.</verse>
<verse>The LORD said to Moses, "Behold, I will come to you in a thick cloud, so that the people may hear when I speak with you and may also believe in you forever." Then Moses told the words of the people to the LORD.</verse>
<verse>The LORD also said to Moses, "Go to the people and consecrate them today and tomorrow, and let them wash their garments;</verse>
<verse>and let them be ready for the third day, for on the third day the LORD will come down on Mount Sinai in the sight of all the people.</verse>
<verse>"You shall set bounds for the people all around, saying, 'Beware that you do not go up on the mountain or touch the border of it; whoever touches the mountain shall surely be put to death.</verse>
<verse>'No hand shall touch him, but he shall surely be stoned or shot through; whether beast or man, he shall not live.' When the ram's horn sounds a long blast, they shall come up to the mountain."</verse>
<verse>So Moses went down from the mountain to the people and consecrated the people, and they washed their garments.</verse>
<verse>He said to the people, "Be ready for the third day; do not go near a woman."</verse>
<verse>So it came about on the third day, when it was morning, that there were thunder and lightning flashes and a thick cloud upon the mountain and a very loud trumpet sound, so that all the people who were in the camp trembled.</verse>
<verse>And Moses brought the people out of the camp to meet God, and they stood at the foot of the mountain.</verse>
<verse>Now Mount Sinai was all in smoke because the LORD descended upon it in fire; and its smoke ascended like the smoke of a furnace, and the whole mountain quaked violently.</verse>
<verse>When the sound of the trumpet grew louder and louder, Moses spoke and God answered him with thunder.</verse>
<verse>The LORD came down on Mount Sinai, to the top of the mountain; and the LORD called Moses to the top of the mountain, and Moses went up.</verse>
<verse>Then the LORD spoke to Moses, "Go down, warn the people, so that they do not break through to the LORD to gaze, and many of them perish.</verse>
<verse>"Also let the priests who come near to the LORD consecrate themselves, or else the LORD will break out against them."</verse>
<verse>Moses said to the LORD, "The people cannot come up to Mount Sinai, for You warned us, saying, 'Set bounds about the mountain and consecrate it.'"</verse>
<verse>Then the LORD said to him, "Go down and come up again, you and Aaron with you; but do not let the priests and the people break through to come up to the LORD, or He will break forth upon them."</verse>
<verse>So Moses went down to the people and told them.</verse>
</chapter>