<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Exodus" book-id="2" n="27">
<verse>"And you shall make the altar of acacia wood, five cubits long and five cubits wide; the altar shall be square, and its height shall be three cubits.</verse>
<verse>"You shall make its horns on its four corners; its horns shall be of one piece with it, and you shall overlay it with bronze.</verse>
<verse>"You shall make its pails for removing its ashes, and its shovels and its basins and its forks and its firepans; you shall make all its utensils of bronze.</verse>
<verse>"You shall make for it a grating of network of bronze, and on the net you shall make four bronze rings at its four corners.</verse>
<verse>"You shall put it beneath, under the ledge of the altar, so that the net will reach halfway up the altar.</verse>
<verse>"You shall make poles for the altar, poles of acacia wood, and overlay them with bronze.</verse>
<verse>"Its poles shall be inserted into the rings, so that the poles shall be on the two sides of the altar when it is carried.</verse>
<verse>"You shall make it hollow with planks; as it was shown to you in the mountain, so they shall make it.</verse>
<verse>"You shall make the court of the tabernacle. On the south side there shall be hangings for the court of fine twisted linen one hundred cubits long for one side;</verse>
<verse>and its pillars shall be twenty, with their twenty sockets of bronze; the hooks of the pillars and their bands shall be of silver.</verse>
<verse>"Likewise for the north side in length there shall be hangings one hundred cubits long, and its twenty pillars with their twenty sockets of bronze; the hooks of the pillars and their bands shall be of silver.</verse>
<verse>"For the width of the court on the west side shall be hangings of fifty cubits with their ten pillars and their ten sockets.</verse>
<verse>"The width of the court on the east side shall be fifty cubits.</verse>
<verse>"The hangings for the one side of the gate shall be fifteen cubits with their three pillars and their three sockets.</verse>
<verse>"And for the other side shall be hangings of fifteen cubits with their three pillars and their three sockets.</verse>
<verse>"For the gate of the court there shall be a screen of twenty cubits, of blue and purple and scarlet material and fine twisted linen, the work of a weaver, with their four pillars and their four sockets.</verse>
<verse>"All the pillars around the court shall be furnished with silver bands with their hooks of silver and their sockets of bronze.</verse>
<verse>"The length of the court shall be one hundred cubits, and the width fifty throughout, and the height five cubits of fine twisted linen, and their sockets of bronze.</verse>
<verse>"All the utensils of the tabernacle used in all its service, and all its pegs, and all the pegs of the court, shall be of bronze.</verse>
<verse>"You shall charge the sons of Israel, that they bring you clear oil of beaten olives for the light, to make a lamp burn continually.</verse>
<verse>"In the tent of meeting, outside the veil which is before the testimony, Aaron and his sons shall keep it in order from evening to morning before the LORD; it shall be a perpetual statute throughout their generations for the sons of Israel.</verse>
</chapter>