<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Exodus" book-id="2" n="31">
<verse>Now the LORD spoke to Moses, saying,</verse>
<verse>"See, I have called by name Bezalel, the son of Uri, the son of Hur, of the tribe of Judah.</verse>
<verse>"I have filled him with the Spirit of God in wisdom, in understanding, in knowledge, and in all kinds of craftsmanship,</verse>
<verse>to make artistic designs for work in gold, in silver, and in bronze,</verse>
<verse>and in the cutting of stones for settings, and in the carving of wood, that he may work in all kinds of craftsmanship.</verse>
<verse>"And behold, I Myself have appointed with him Oholiab, the son of Ahisamach, of the tribe of Dan; and in the hearts of all who are skillful I have put skill, that they may make all that I have commanded you:</verse>
<verse>the tent of meeting, and the ark of testimony, and the mercy seat upon it, and all the furniture of the tent,</verse>
<verse>the table also and its utensils, and the pure gold lampstand with all its utensils, and the altar of incense,</verse>
<verse>the altar of burnt offering also with all its utensils, and the laver and its stand,</verse>
<verse>the woven garments as well, and the holy garments for Aaron the priest, and the garments of his sons, with which to carry on their priesthood;</verse>
<verse>the anointing oil also, and the fragrant incense for the holy place, they are to make them according to all that I have commanded you."</verse>
<verse>The LORD spoke to Moses, saying,</verse>
<verse>"But as for you, speak to the sons of Israel, saying, 'You shall surely observe My sabbaths; for this is a sign between Me and you throughout your generations, that you may know that I am the LORD who sanctifies you.</verse>
<verse>'Therefore you are to observe the sabbath, for it is holy to you. Everyone who profanes it shall surely be put to death; for whoever does any work on it, that person shall be cut off from among his people.</verse>
<verse>'For six days work may be done, but on the seventh day there is a sabbath of complete rest, holy to the LORD; whoever does any work on the sabbath day shall surely be put to death.</verse>
<verse>'So the sons of Israel shall observe the sabbath, to celebrate the sabbath throughout their generations as a perpetual covenant.'</verse>
<verse>"It is a sign between Me and the sons of Israel forever; for in six days the LORD made heaven and earth, but on the seventh day He ceased from labor, and was refreshed."</verse>
<verse>When He had finished speaking with him upon Mount Sinai, He gave Moses the two tablets of the testimony, tablets of stone, written by the finger of God.</verse>
</chapter>