<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Exodus" book-id="2" n="37">
<verse>Now Bezalel made the ark of acacia wood; its length was two and a half cubits, and its width one and a half cubits, and its height one and a half cubits;</verse>
<verse>and he overlaid it with pure gold inside and out, and made a gold molding for it all around.</verse>
<verse>He cast four rings of gold for it on its four feet; even two rings on one side of it, and two rings on the other side of it.</verse>
<verse>He made poles of acacia wood and overlaid them with gold.</verse>
<verse>He put the poles into the rings on the sides of the ark, to carry it.</verse>
<verse>He made a mercy seat of pure gold, two and a half cubits long and one and a half cubits wide.</verse>
<verse>He made two cherubim of gold; he made them of hammered work at the two ends of the mercy seat;</verse>
<verse>one cherub at the one end and one cherub at the other end; he made the cherubim of one piece with the mercy seat at the two ends.</verse>
<verse>The cherubim had their wings spread upward, covering the mercy seat with their wings, with their faces toward each other; the faces of the cherubim were toward the mercy seat.</verse>
<verse>Then he made the table of acacia wood, two cubits long and a cubit wide and one and a half cubits high.</verse>
<verse>He overlaid it with pure gold, and made a gold molding for it all around.</verse>
<verse>He made a rim for it of a handbreadth all around, and made a gold molding for its rim all around.</verse>
<verse>He cast four gold rings for it and put the rings on the four corners that were on its four feet.</verse>
<verse>Close by the rim were the rings, the holders for the poles to carry the table.</verse>
<verse>He made the poles of acacia wood and overlaid them with gold, to carry the table.</verse>
<verse>He made the utensils which were on the table, its dishes and its pans and its bowls and its jars, with which to pour out drink offerings, of pure gold.</verse>
<verse>Then he made the lampstand of pure gold. He made the lampstand of hammered work, its base and its shaft; its cups, its bulbs and its flowers were of one piece with it.</verse>
<verse>There were six branches going out of its sides; three branches of the lampstand from the one side of it and three branches of the lampstand from the other side of it;</verse>
<verse>three cups shaped like almond blossoms, a bulb and a flower in one branch, and three cups shaped like almond blossoms, a bulb and a flower in the other branch--so for the six branches going out of the lampstand.</verse>
<verse>In the lampstand there were four cups shaped like almond blossoms, its bulbs and its flowers;</verse>
<verse>and a bulb was under the first pair of branches coming out of it, and a bulb under the second pair of branches coming out of it, and a bulb under the third pair of branches coming out of it, for the six branches coming out of the lampstand.</verse>
<verse>Their bulbs and their branches were of one piece with it; the whole of it was a single hammered work of pure gold.</verse>
<verse>He made its seven lamps with its snuffers and its trays of pure gold.</verse>
<verse>He made it and all its utensils from a talent of pure gold.</verse>
<verse>Then he made the altar of incense of acacia wood: a cubit long and a cubit wide, square, and two cubits high; its horns were of one piece with it.</verse>
<verse>He overlaid it with pure gold, its top and its sides all around, and its horns; and he made a gold molding for it all around.</verse>
<verse>He made two golden rings for it under its molding, on its two sides--on opposite sides--as holders for poles with which to carry it.</verse>
<verse>He made the poles of acacia wood and overlaid them with gold.</verse>
<verse>And he made the holy anointing oil and the pure, fragrant incense of spices, the work of a perfumer.</verse>
</chapter>