<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Exodus" book-id="2" n="6">
<verse>Then the LORD said to Moses, "Now you shall see what I will do to Pharaoh; for under compulsion he will let them go, and under compulsion he will drive them out of his land."</verse>
<verse>God spoke further to Moses and said to him, "I am the LORD;</verse>
<verse>and I appeared to Abraham, Isaac, and Jacob, as God Almighty, but by My name, LORD, I did not make Myself known to them.</verse>
<verse>"I also established My covenant with them, to give them the land of Canaan, the land in which they sojourned.</verse>
<verse>"Furthermore I have heard the groaning of the sons of Israel, because the Egyptians are holding them in bondage, and I have remembered My covenant.</verse>
<verse>"Say, therefore, to the sons of Israel, 'I am the LORD, and I will bring you out from under the burdens of the Egyptians, and I will deliver you from their bondage. I will also redeem you with an outstretched arm and with great judgments.</verse>
<verse>'Then I will take you for My people, and I will be your God; and you shall know that I am the LORD your God, who brought you out from under the burdens of the Egyptians.</verse>
<verse>'I will bring you to the land which I swore to give to Abraham, Isaac, and Jacob, and I will give it to you for a possession; I am the LORD.'"</verse>
<verse>So Moses spoke thus to the sons of Israel, but they did not listen to Moses on account of their despondency and cruel bondage.</verse>
<verse>Now the LORD spoke to Moses, saying,</verse>
<verse>"Go, tell Pharaoh king of Egypt to let the sons of Israel go out of his land."</verse>
<verse>But Moses spoke before the LORD, saying, "Behold, the sons of Israel have not listened to me; how then will Pharaoh listen to me, for I am unskilled in speech?"</verse>
<verse>Then the LORD spoke to Moses and to Aaron, and gave them a charge to the sons of Israel and to Pharaoh king of Egypt, to bring the sons of Israel out of the land of Egypt.</verse>
<verse>These are the heads of their fathers' households. The sons of Reuben, Israel's firstborn: Hanoch and Pallu, Hezron and Carmi; these are the families of Reuben.</verse>
<verse>The sons of Simeon: Jemuel and Jamin and Ohad and Jachin and Zohar and Shaul the son of a Canaanite woman; these are the families of Simeon.</verse>
<verse>These are the names of the sons of Levi according to their generations: Gershon and Kohath and Merari; and the length of Levi's life was one hundred and thirty-seven years.</verse>
<verse>The sons of Gershon: Libni and Shimei, according to their families.</verse>
<verse>The sons of Kohath: Amram and Izhar and Hebron and Uzziel; and the length of Kohath's life was one hundred and thirty-three years.</verse>
<verse>The sons of Merari: Mahli and Mushi. These are the families of the Levites according to their generations.</verse>
<verse>Amram married his father's sister Jochebed, and she bore him Aaron and Moses; and the length of Amram's life was one hundred and thirty-seven years.</verse>
<verse>The sons of Izhar: Korah and Nepheg and Zichri.</verse>
<verse>The sons of Uzziel: Mishael and Elzaphan and Sithri.</verse>
<verse>Aaron married Elisheba, the daughter of Amminadab, the sister of Nahshon, and she bore him Nadab and Abihu, Eleazar and Ithamar.</verse>
<verse>The sons of Korah: Assir and Elkanah and Abiasaph; these are the families of the Korahites.</verse>
<verse>Aaron's son Eleazar married one of the daughters of Putiel, and she bore him Phinehas. These are the heads of the fathers' households of the Levites according to their families.</verse>
<verse>It was the same Aaron and Moses to whom the LORD said, "Bring out the sons of Israel from the land of Egypt according to their hosts."</verse>
<verse>They were the ones who spoke to Pharaoh king of Egypt about bringing out the sons of Israel from Egypt; it was the same Moses and Aaron.</verse>
<verse>Now it came about on the day when the LORD spoke to Moses in the land of Egypt,</verse>
<verse>that the LORD spoke to Moses, saying, "I am the LORD; speak to Pharaoh king of Egypt all that I speak to you."</verse>
<verse>But Moses said before the LORD, "Behold, I am unskilled in speech; how then will Pharaoh listen to me?"</verse>
</chapter>