<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Exodus" book_id="2" n="9">
<verse>Then the LORD said to Moses, "Go to Pharaoh and speak to him, 'Thus says the LORD, the God of the Hebrews, "Let My people go, that they may serve Me.</verse>
<verse>"For if you refuse to let them go and continue to hold them,</verse>
<verse>behold, the hand of the LORD will come with a very severe pestilence on your livestock which are in the field, on the horses, on the donkeys, on the camels, on the herds, and on the flocks.</verse>
<verse>"But the LORD will make a distinction between the livestock of Israel and the livestock of Egypt, so that nothing will die of all that belongs to the sons of Israel."'"</verse>
<verse>The LORD set a definite time, saying, "Tomorrow the LORD will do this thing in the land."</verse>
<verse>So the LORD did this thing on the next day, and all the livestock of Egypt died; but of the livestock of the sons of Israel, not one died.</verse>
<verse>Pharaoh sent, and behold, there was not even one of the livestock of Israel dead. But the heart of Pharaoh was hardened, and he did not let the people go.</verse>
<verse>Then the LORD said to Moses and Aaron, "Take for yourselves handfuls of soot from a kiln, and let Moses throw it toward the sky in the sight of Pharaoh.</verse>
<verse>"It will become fine dust over all the land of Egypt, and will become boils breaking out with sores on man and beast through all the land of Egypt."</verse>
<verse>So they took soot from a kiln, and stood before Pharaoh; and Moses threw it toward the sky, and it became boils breaking out with sores on man and beast.</verse>
<verse>The magicians could not stand before Moses because of the boils, for the boils were on the magicians as well as on all the Egyptians.</verse>
<verse>And the LORD hardened Pharaoh's heart, and he did not listen to them, just as the LORD had spoken to Moses.</verse>
<verse>Then the LORD said to Moses, "Rise up early in the morning and stand before Pharaoh and say to him, 'Thus says the LORD, the God of the Hebrews, "Let My people go, that they may serve Me.</verse>
<verse>"For this time I will send all My plagues on you and your servants and your people, so that you may know that there is no one like Me in all the earth.</verse>
<verse>"For if by now I had put forth My hand and struck you and your people with pestilence, you would then have been cut off from the earth.</verse>
<verse>"But, indeed, for this reason I have allowed you to remain, in order to show you My power and in order to proclaim My name through all the earth.</verse>
<verse>"Still you exalt yourself against My people by not letting them go.</verse>
<verse>"Behold, about this time tomorrow, I will send a very heavy hail, such as has not been seen in Egypt from the day it was founded until now.</verse>
<verse>"Now therefore send, bring your livestock and whatever you have in the field to safety. Every man and beast that is found in the field and is not brought home, when the hail comes down on them, will die."'"</verse>
<verse>The one among the servants of Pharaoh who feared the word of the LORD made his servants and his livestock flee into the houses;</verse>
<verse>but he who paid no regard to the word of the LORD left his servants and his livestock in the field.</verse>
<verse>Now the LORD said to Moses, "Stretch out your hand toward the sky, that hail may fall on all the land of Egypt, on man and on beast and on every plant of the field, throughout the land of Egypt."</verse>
<verse>Moses stretched out his staff toward the sky, and the LORD sent thunder and hail, and fire ran down to the earth. And the LORD rained hail on the land of Egypt.</verse>
<verse>So there was hail, and fire flashing continually in the midst of the hail, very severe, such as had not been in all the land of Egypt since it became a nation.</verse>
<verse>The hail struck all that was in the field through all the land of Egypt, both man and beast; the hail also struck every plant of the field and shattered every tree of the field.</verse>
<verse>Only in the land of Goshen, where the sons of Israel were, there was no hail.</verse>
<verse>Then Pharaoh sent for Moses and Aaron, and said to them, "I have sinned this time; the LORD is the righteous one, and I and my people are the wicked ones.</verse>
<verse>"Make supplication to the LORD, for there has been enough of God's thunder and hail; and I will let you go, and you shall stay no longer."</verse>
<verse>Moses said to him, "As soon as I go out of the city, I will spread out my hands to the LORD; the thunder will cease and there will be hail no longer, that you may know that the earth is the LORD'S.</verse>
<verse>"But as for you and your servants, I know that you do not yet fear the LORD God."</verse>
<verse>(Now the flax and the barley were ruined, for the barley was in the ear and the flax was in bud.</verse>
<verse>But the wheat and the spelt were not ruined, for they ripen late.)</verse>
<verse>So Moses went out of the city from Pharaoh, and spread out his hands to the LORD; and the thunder and the hail ceased, and rain no longer poured on the earth.</verse>
<verse>But when Pharaoh saw that the rain and the hail and the thunder had ceased, he sinned again and hardened his heart, he and his servants.</verse>
<verse>Pharaoh's heart was hardened, and he did not let the sons of Israel go, just as the LORD had spoken through Moses.</verse>
</chapter>