<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Hosea" book_id="28" n="10">
<verse>Israel is a luxuriant vine; He produces fruit for himself. The more his fruit, The more altars he made; The richer his land, The better he made the sacred pillars.</verse>
<verse>Their heart is faithless; Now they must bear their guilt. The LORD will break down their altars And destroy their sacred pillars.</verse>
<verse>Surely now they will say, "We have no king, For we do not revere the LORD. As for the king, what can he do for us?"</verse>
<verse>They speak mere words, With worthless oaths they make covenants; And judgment sprouts like poisonous weeds in the furrows of the field.</verse>
<verse>The inhabitants of Samaria will fear For the calf of Beth-aven. Indeed, its people will mourn for it, And its idolatrous priests will cry out over it, Over its glory, since it has departed from it.</verse>
<verse>The thing itself will be carried to Assyria As tribute to King Jareb; Ephraim will be seized with shame And Israel will be ashamed of its own counsel.</verse>
<verse>Samaria will be cut off with her king Like a stick on the surface of the water.</verse>
<verse>Also the high places of Aven, the sin of Israel, will be destroyed; Thorn and thistle will grow on their altars; Then they will say to the mountains, "Cover us!" And to the hills, "Fall on us!"</verse>
<verse>From the days of Gibeah you have sinned, O Israel; There they stand! Will not the battle against the sons of iniquity overtake them in Gibeah?</verse>
<verse>When it is My desire, I will chastise them; And the peoples will be gathered against them When they are bound for their double guilt.</verse>
<verse>Ephraim is a trained heifer that loves to thresh, But I will come over her fair neck with a yoke; I will harness Ephraim, Judah will plow, Jacob will harrow for himself.</verse>
<verse>Sow with a view to righteousness, Reap in accordance with kindness; Break up your fallow ground, For it is time to seek the LORD Until He comes to rain righteousness on you.</verse>
<verse>You have plowed wickedness, you have reaped injustice, You have eaten the fruit of lies. Because you have trusted in your way, in your numerous warriors,</verse>
<verse>Therefore a tumult will arise among your people, And all your fortresses will be destroyed, As Shalman destroyed Beth-arbel on the day of battle, When mothers were dashed in pieces with their children.</verse>
<verse>Thus it will be done to you at Bethel because of your great wickedness. At dawn the king of Israel will be completely cut off.</verse>
</chapter>