<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Hosea" book_id="28" n="13">
<verse>When Ephraim spoke, there was trembling. He exalted himself in Israel, But through Baal he did wrong and died.</verse>
<verse>And now they sin more and more, And make for themselves molten images, Idols skillfully made from their silver, All of them the work of craftsmen. They say of them, "Let the men who sacrifice kiss the calves!"</verse>
<verse>Therefore they will be like the morning cloud And like dew which soon disappears, Like chaff which is blown away from the threshing floor And like smoke from a chimney.</verse>
<verse>Yet I have been the LORD your God Since the land of Egypt; And you were not to know any god except Me, For there is no savior besides Me.</verse>
<verse>I cared for you in the wilderness, In the land of drought.</verse>
<verse>As they had their pasture, they became satisfied, And being satisfied, their heart became proud; Therefore they forgot Me.</verse>
<verse>So I will be like a lion to them; Like a leopard I will lie in wait by the wayside.</verse>
<verse>I will encounter them like a bear robbed of her cubs, And I will tear open their chests; There I will also devour them like a lioness, As a wild beast would tear them.</verse>
<verse>It is your destruction, O Israel, That you are against Me, against your help.</verse>
<verse>Where now is your king That he may save you in all your cities, And your judges of whom you requested, "Give me a king and princes"?</verse>
<verse>I gave you a king in My anger And took him away in My wrath.</verse>
<verse>The iniquity of Ephraim is bound up; His sin is stored up.</verse>
<verse>The pains of childbirth come upon him; He is not a wise son, For it is not the time that he should delay at the opening of the womb.</verse>
<verse>Shall I ransom them from the power of Sheol? Shall I redeem them from death? O Death, where are your thorns? O Sheol, where is your sting? Compassion will be hidden from My sight.</verse>
<verse>Though he flourishes among the reeds, An east wind will come, The wind of the LORD coming up from the wilderness; And his fountain will become dry And his spring will be dried up; It will plunder his treasury of every precious article.</verse>
<verse>Samaria will be held guilty, For she has rebelled against her God. They will fall by the sword, Their little ones will be dashed in pieces, And their pregnant women will be ripped open.</verse>
</chapter>