<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Hosea" book-id="28" n="7">
<verse>When I would heal Israel, The iniquity of Ephraim is uncovered, And the evil deeds of Samaria, For they deal falsely; The thief enters in, Bandits raid outside,</verse>
<verse>And they do not consider in their hearts That I remember all their wickedness. Now their deeds are all around them; They are before My face.</verse>
<verse>With their wickedness they make the king glad, And the princes with their lies.</verse>
<verse>They are all adulterers, Like an oven heated by the baker Who ceases to stir up the fire From the kneading of the dough until it is leavened.</verse>
<verse>On the day of our king, the princes became sick with the heat of wine; He stretched out his hand with scoffers,</verse>
<verse>For their hearts are like an oven As they approach their plotting; Their anger smolders all night, In the morning it burns like a flaming fire.</verse>
<verse>All of them are hot like an oven, And they consume their rulers; All their kings have fallen. None of them calls on Me.</verse>
<verse>Ephraim mixes himself with the nations; Ephraim has become a cake not turned.</verse>
<verse>Strangers devour his strength, Yet he does not know it; Gray hairs also are sprinkled on him, Yet he does not know it.</verse>
<verse>Though the pride of Israel testifies against him, Yet they have not returned to the LORD their God, Nor have they sought Him, for all this.</verse>
<verse>So Ephraim has become like a silly dove, without sense; They call to Egypt, they go to Assyria.</verse>
<verse>When they go, I will spread My net over them; I will bring them down like the birds of the sky. I will chastise them in accordance with the proclamation to their assembly.</verse>
<verse>Woe to them, for they have strayed from Me! Destruction is theirs, for they have rebelled against Me! I would redeem them, but they speak lies against Me.</verse>
<verse>And they do not cry to Me from their heart When they wail on their beds; For the sake of grain and new wine they assemble themselves, They turn away from Me.</verse>
<verse>Although I trained and strengthened their arms, Yet they devise evil against Me.</verse>
<verse>They turn, but not upward, They are like a deceitful bow; Their princes will fall by the sword Because of the insolence of their tongue. This will be their derision in the land of Egypt.</verse>
</chapter>