<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Hosea" book-id="28" n="9">
<verse>Do not rejoice, O Israel, with exultation like the nations! For you have played the harlot, forsaking your God. You have loved harlots' earnings on every threshing floor.</verse>
<verse>Threshing floor and wine press will not feed them, And the new wine will fail them.</verse>
<verse>They will not remain in the LORD'S land, But Ephraim will return to Egypt, And in Assyria they will eat unclean food.</verse>
<verse>They will not pour out drink offerings of wine to the LORD, Their sacrifices will not please Him. Their bread will be like mourners' bread; All who eat of it will be defiled, For their bread will be for themselves alone; It will not enter the house of the LORD.</verse>
<verse>What will you do on the day of the appointed festival And on the day of the feast of the LORD?</verse>
<verse>For behold, they will go because of destruction; Egypt will gather them up, Memphis will bury them. Weeds will take over their treasures of silver; Thorns will be in their tents.</verse>
<verse>The days of punishment have come, The days of retribution have come; Let Israel know this! The prophet is a fool, The inspired man is demented, Because of the grossness of your iniquity, And because your hostility is so great.</verse>
<verse>Ephraim was a watchman with my God, a prophet; Yet the snare of a bird catcher is in all his ways, And there is only hostility in the house of his God.</verse>
<verse>They have gone deep in depravity As in the days of Gibeah; He will remember their iniquity, He will punish their sins.</verse>
<verse>I found Israel like grapes in the wilderness; I saw your forefathers as the earliest fruit on the fig tree in its first season. But they came to Baal-peor and devoted themselves to shame, And they became as detestable as that which they loved.</verse>
<verse>As for Ephraim, their glory will fly away like a bird--No birth, no pregnancy and no conception!</verse>
<verse>Though they bring up their children, Yet I will bereave them until not a man is left. Yes, woe to them indeed when I depart from them!</verse>
<verse>Ephraim, as I have seen, Is planted in a pleasant meadow like Tyre; But Ephraim will bring out his children for slaughter.</verse>
<verse>Give them, O LORD--what will You give? Give them a miscarrying womb and dry breasts.</verse>
<verse>All their evil is at Gilgal; Indeed, I came to hate them there! Because of the wickedness of their deeds I will drive them out of My house! I will love them no more; All their princes are rebels.</verse>
<verse>Ephraim is stricken, their root is dried up, They will bear no fruit. Even though they bear children, I will slay the precious ones of their womb.</verse>
<verse>My God will cast them away Because they have not listened to Him; And they will be wanderers among the nations.</verse>
</chapter>