<chapter translation="NASB" testament="New" book="Galatians" book_id="48" n="1">
<verse>Paul, an apostle ( not sent from men nor through the agency of man, but through Jesus Christ and God the Father, who raised Him from the dead),</verse>
<verse>and all the brethren who are with me, To the churches of Galatia:</verse>
<verse>Grace to you and peace from God our Father and the Lord Jesus Christ,</verse>
<verse>who gave Himself for our sins so that He might rescue us from this present evil age, according to the will of our God and Father,</verse>
<verse>to whom be the glory forevermore. Amen.</verse>
<verse>I am amazed that you are so quickly deserting Him who called you by the grace of Christ, for a different gospel;</verse>
<verse>which is really not another; only there are some who are disturbing you and want to distort the gospel of Christ.</verse>
<verse>But even if we, or an angel from heaven, should preach to you a gospel contrary to what we have preached to you, he is to be accursed!</verse>
<verse>As we have said before, so I say again now, if any man is preaching to you a gospel contrary to what you received, he is to be accursed!</verse>
<verse>For am I now seeking the favor of men, or of God? Or am I striving to please men? If I were still trying to please men, I would not be a bond-servant of Christ.</verse>
<verse>For I would have you know, brethren, that the gospel which was preached by me is not according to man.</verse>
<verse>For I neither received it from man, nor was I taught it, but I received it through a revelation of Jesus Christ.</verse>
<verse>For you have heard of my former manner of life in Judaism, how I used to persecute the church of God beyond measure and tried to destroy it;</verse>
<verse>and I was advancing in Judaism beyond many of my contemporaries among my countrymen, being more extremely zealous for my ancestral traditions.</verse>
<verse>But when God, who had set me apart even from my mother's womb and called me through His grace, was pleased</verse>
<verse>to reveal His Son in me so that I might preach Him among the Gentiles, I did not immediately consult with flesh and blood,</verse>
<verse>nor did I go up to Jerusalem to those who were apostles before me; but I went away to Arabia, and returned once more to Damascus.</verse>
<verse>Then three years later I went up to Jerusalem to become acquainted with Cephas, and stayed with him fifteen days.</verse>
<verse>But I did not see any other of the apostles except James, the Lord's brother.</verse>
<verse>(Now in what I am writing to you, I assure you before God that I am not lying.)</verse>
<verse>Then I went into the regions of Syria and Cilicia.</verse>
<verse>I was still unknown by sight to the churches of Judea which were in Christ;</verse>
<verse>but only, they kept hearing, "He who once persecuted us is now preaching the faith which he once tried to destroy."</verse>
<verse>And they were glorifying God because of me.</verse>
</chapter>