<chapter translation="NASB" testament="New" book="Galatians" book-id="48" n="5">
<verse>It was for freedom that Christ set us free; therefore keep standing firm and do not be subject again to a yoke of slavery.</verse>
<verse>Behold I, Paul, say to you that if you receive circumcision, Christ will be of no benefit to you.</verse>
<verse>And I testify again to every man who receives circumcision, that he is under obligation to keep the whole Law.</verse>
<verse>You have been severed from Christ, you who are seeking to be justified by law; you have fallen from grace.</verse>
<verse>For we through the Spirit, by faith, are waiting for the hope of righteousness.</verse>
<verse>For in Christ Jesus neither circumcision nor uncircumcision means anything, but faith working through love.</verse>
<verse>You were running well; who hindered you from obeying the truth?</verse>
<verse>This persuasion did not come from Him who calls you.</verse>
<verse>A little leaven leavens the whole lump of dough.</verse>
<verse>I have confidence in you in the Lord that you will adopt no other view; but the one who is disturbing you will bear his judgment, whoever he is.</verse>
<verse>But I, brethren, if I still preach circumcision, why am I still persecuted? Then the stumbling block of the cross has been abolished.</verse>
<verse>I wish that those who are troubling you would even mutilate themselves.</verse>
<verse>For you were called to freedom, brethren; only do not turn your freedom into an opportunity for the flesh, but through love serve one another.</verse>
<verse>For the whole Law is fulfilled in one word, in the statement, "YOU SHALL LOVE YOUR NEIGHBOR AS YOURSELF."</verse>
<verse>But if you bite and devour one another, take care that you are not consumed by one another.</verse>
<verse>But I say, walk by the Spirit, and you will not carry out the desire of the flesh.</verse>
<verse>For the flesh sets its desire against the Spirit, and the Spirit against the flesh; for these are in opposition to one another, so that you may not do the things that you please.</verse>
<verse>But if you are led by the Spirit, you are not under the Law.</verse>
<verse>Now the deeds of the flesh are evident, which are: immorality, impurity, sensuality,</verse>
<verse>idolatry, sorcery, enmities, strife, jealousy, outbursts of anger, disputes, dissensions, factions,</verse>
<verse>envying, drunkenness, carousing, and things like these, of which I forewarn you, just as I have forewarned you, that those who practice such things will not inherit the kingdom of God.</verse>
<verse>But the fruit of the Spirit is love, joy, peace, patience, kindness, goodness, faithfulness,</verse>
<verse>gentleness, self-control; against such things there is no law.</verse>
<verse>Now those who belong to Christ Jesus have crucified the flesh with its passions and desires.</verse>
<verse>If we live by the Spirit, let us also walk by the Spirit.</verse>
<verse>Let us not become boastful, challenging one another, envying one another.</verse>
</chapter>