<chapter translation="NASB" testament="New" book="Galatians" book-id="48" n="6">
<verse>Brethren, even if anyone is caught in any trespass, you who are spiritual, restore such a one in a spirit of gentleness; each one looking to yourself, so that you too will not be tempted.</verse>
<verse>Bear one another's burdens, and thereby fulfill the law of Christ.</verse>
<verse>For if anyone thinks he is something when he is nothing, he deceives himself.</verse>
<verse>But each one must examine his own work, and then he will have reason for boasting in regard to himself alone, and not in regard to another.</verse>
<verse>For each one will bear his own load.</verse>
<verse>The one who is taught the word is to share all good things with the one who teaches him.</verse>
<verse>Do not be deceived, God is not mocked; for whatever a man sows, this he will also reap.</verse>
<verse>For the one who sows to his own flesh will from the flesh reap corruption, but the one who sows to the Spirit will from the Spirit reap eternal life.</verse>
<verse>Let us not lose heart in doing good, for in due time we will reap if we do not grow weary.</verse>
<verse>So then, while we have opportunity, let us do good to all people, and especially to those who are of the household of the faith.</verse>
<verse>See with what large letters I am writing to you with my own hand.</verse>
<verse>Those who desire to make a good showing in the flesh try to compel you to be circumcised, simply so that they will not be persecuted for the cross of Christ.</verse>
<verse>For those who are circumcised do not even keep the Law themselves, but they desire to have you circumcised so that they may boast in your flesh.</verse>
<verse>But may it never be that I would boast, except in the cross of our Lord Jesus Christ, through which the world has been crucified to me, and I to the world.</verse>
<verse>For neither is circumcision anything, nor uncircumcision, but a new creation.</verse>
<verse>And those who will walk by this rule, peace and mercy be upon them, and upon the Israel of God.</verse>
<verse>From now on let no one cause trouble for me, for I bear on my body the brand-marks of Jesus.</verse>
<verse>The grace of our Lord Jesus Christ be with your spirit, brethren. Amen.</verse>
</chapter>