<chapter translation="MSG" testament="New" book="Matthew" book_id="40" n="26">
<verse>When Jesus finished saying these things, he told his disciples,</verse>
<verse>"You know that Passover comes in two days. That's when the Son of Man will be betrayed and handed over for crucifixion."</verse>
<verse>At that very moment, the party of high priests and religious leaders was meeting in the chambers of the Chief Priest named Caiaphas,</verse>
<verse>conspiring to seize Jesus by stealth and kill him.</verse>
<verse>They agreed that it should not be done during Passover Week. "We don't want a riot on our hands," they said.</verse>
<verse>When Jesus was at Bethany, a guest of Simon the Leper,</verse>
<verse>a woman came up to him as he was eating dinner and anointed him with a bottle of very expensive perfume.</verse>
<verse>When the disciples saw what was happening, they were furious. "That's criminal!</verse>
<verse>This could have been sold for a lot and the money handed out to the poor."</verse>
<verse>When Jesus realized what was going on, he intervened. "Why are you giving this woman a hard time? She has just done something wonderfully significant for me.</verse>
<verse>You will have the poor with you every day for the rest of your lives, but not me.</verse>
<verse>When she poured this perfume on my body, what she really did was anoint me for burial.</verse>
<verse>You can be sure that wherever in the whole world the Message is preached, what she has just done is going to be remembered and admired."</verse>
<verse>That is when one of the Twelve, the one named Judas Iscariot, went to the cabal of high priests</verse>
<verse>and said, "What will you give me if I hand him over to you?" They settled on thirty silver pieces.</verse>
<verse>He began looking for just the right moment to hand him over.</verse>
<verse>On the first of the Days of Unleavened Bread, the disciples came to Jesus and said, "Where do you want us to prepare your Passover meal?"</verse>
<verse>He said, "Enter the city. Go up to a certain man and say, "The Teacher says, My time is near. I and my disciples plan to celebrate the Passover meal at your house.'"</verse>
<verse>The disciples followed Jesus' instructions to the letter, and prepared the Passover meal.</verse>
<verse>After sunset, he and the Twelve were sitting around the table.</verse>
<verse>During the meal, he said, "I have something hard but important to say to you: One of you is going to hand me over to the conspirators."</verse>
<verse>They were stunned, and then began to ask, one after another, "It isn't me, is it, Master?"</verse>
<verse>Jesus answered, "The one who hands me over is someone I eat with daily, one who passes me food at the table.</verse>
<verse>In one sense the Son of Man is entering into a way of treachery well-marked by the Scriptures--no surprises here. In another sense that man who turns him in, turns traitor to the Son of Man--better never to have been born than do this!"</verse>
<verse>Then Judas, already turned traitor, said, "It isn't me, is it, Rabbi?" Jesus said, "Don't play games with me, Judas."</verse>
<verse>During the meal, Jesus took and blessed the bread, broke it, and gave it to his disciples: Take, eat. This is my body.</verse>
<verse>Taking the cup and thanking God, he gave it to them: Drink this, all of you.</verse>
<verse>This is my blood, God's new covenant poured out for many people for the forgiveness of sins.</verse>
<verse>"I'll not be drinking wine from this cup again until that new day when I'll drink with you in the kingdom of my Father."</verse>
<verse>They sang a hymn and went directly to Mount Olives.</verse>
<verse>Then Jesus told them, "Before the night's over, you're going to fall to pieces because of what happens to me. There is a Scripture that says, I'll strike the shepherd; helter-skelter the sheep will be scattered.</verse>
<verse>But after I am raised up, I, your Shepherd, will go ahead of you, leading the way to Galilee."</verse>
<verse>Peter broke in, "Even if everyone else falls to pieces on account of you, I won't."</verse>
<verse>"Don't be so sure," Jesus said. "This very night, before the rooster crows up the dawn, you will deny me three times."</verse>
<verse>Peter protested, "Even if I had to die with you, I would never deny you." All the others said the same thing.</verse>
<verse>Then Jesus went with them to a garden called Gethsemane and told his disciples, "Stay here while I go over there and pray."</verse>
<verse>Taking along Peter and the two sons of Zebedee, he plunged into an agonizing sorrow.</verse>
<verse>Then he said, "This sorrow is crushing my life out. Stay here and keep vigil with me."</verse>
<verse>Going a little ahead, he fell on his face, praying, "My Father, if there is any way, get me out of this. But please, not what I want. You, what do you want?"</verse>
<verse>When he came back to his disciples, he found them sound asleep. He said to Peter, "Can't you stick it out with me a single hour?</verse>
<verse>Stay alert; be in prayer so you don't wander into temptation without even knowing you're in danger. There is a part of you that is eager, ready for anything in God. But there's another part that's as lazy as an old dog sleeping by the fire."</verse>
<verse>He then left them a second time. Again he prayed, "My Father, if there is no other way than this, drinking this cup to the dregs, I'm ready. Do it your way."</verse>
<verse>When he came back, he again found them sound asleep. They simply couldn't keep their eyes open.</verse>
<verse>This time he let them sleep on, and went back a third time to pray, going over the same ground one last time.</verse>
<verse>When he came back the next time, he said, "Are you going to sleep on and make a night of it? My time is up, the Son of Man is about to be handed over to the hands of sinners.</verse>
<verse>Get up! Let's get going! My betrayer is here."</verse>
<verse>The words were barely out of his mouth when Judas (the one from the Twelve) showed up, and with him a gang from the high priests and religious leaders brandishing swords and clubs.</verse>
<verse>The betrayer had worked out a sign with them: "The one I kiss, that's the one--seize him."</verse>
<verse>He went straight to Jesus, greeted him, "How are you, Rabbi?" and kissed him.</verse>
<verse>Jesus said, "Friend, why this charade?" Then they came on him--grabbed him and roughed him up.</verse>
<verse>One of those with Jesus pulled his sword and, taking a swing at the Chief Priest's servant, cut off his ear.</verse>
<verse>Jesus said, "Put your sword back where it belongs. All who use swords are destroyed by swords.</verse>
<verse>Don't you realize that I am able right now to call to my Father, and twelve companies--more, if I want them--of fighting angels would be here, battle-ready?</verse>
<verse>But if I did that, how would the Scriptures come true that say this is the way it has to be?"</verse>
<verse>Then Jesus addressed the mob: "What is this--coming out after me with swords and clubs as if I were a dangerous criminal? Day after day I have been sitting in the Temple teaching, and you never so much as lifted a hand against me.</verse>
<verse>You've done it this way to confirm and fulfill the prophetic writings." Then all the disciples cut and ran.</verse>
<verse>The gang that had seized Jesus led him before Caiaphas the Chief Priest, where the religion scholars and leaders had assembled.</verse>
<verse>Peter followed at a safe distance until they got to the Chief Priest's courtyard. Then he slipped in and mingled with the servants, watching to see how things would turn out.</verse>
<verse>The high priests, conspiring with the Jewish Council, tried to cook up charges against Jesus in order to sentence him to death.</verse>
<verse>But even though many stepped up, making up one false accusation after another, nothing was believable. Finally two men came forward</verse>
<verse>with this: "He said, "I can tear down this Temple of God and after three days rebuild it.'"</verse>
<verse>The Chief Priest stood up and said, "What do you have to say to the accusation?"</verse>
<verse>Jesus kept silent. Then the Chief Priest said, "I command you by the authority of the living God to say if you are the Messiah, the Son of God."</verse>
<verse>Jesus was curt: "You yourself said it. And that's not all. Soon you'll see it for yourself: The Son of Man seated at the right hand of the Mighty One, Arriving on the clouds of heaven."</verse>
<verse>At that, the Chief Priest lost his temper, ripping his robes, yelling, "He blasphemed! Why do we need witnesses to accuse him? You all heard him blaspheme!</verse>
<verse>Are you going to stand for such blasphemy?" They all said, "Death! That seals his death sentence."</verse>
<verse>Then they were spitting in his face and banging him around. They jeered as they slapped him:</verse>
<verse>"Prophesy, Messiah: Who hit you that time?"</verse>
<verse>All this time, Peter was sitting out in the courtyard. One servant girl came up to him and said, "You were with Jesus the Galilean."</verse>
<verse>In front of everybody there, he denied it. "I don't know what you're talking about."</verse>
<verse>As he moved over toward the gate, someone else said to the people there, "This man was with Jesus the Nazarene."</verse>
<verse>Again he denied it, salting his denial with an oath: "I swear, I never laid eyes on the man."</verse>
<verse>Shortly after that, some bystanders approached Peter. "You've got to be one of them. Your accent gives you away."</verse>
<verse>Then he got really nervous and swore. "I don't know the man!" Just then a rooster crowed.</verse>
<verse>Peter remembered what Jesus had said: "Before the rooster crows, you will deny me three times." He went out and cried and cried and cried.</verse>
</chapter>