<chapter translation="MSG" testament="New" book="Matthew" book_id="40" n="3">
<verse>While Jesus was living in the Galilean hills, John, called "the Baptizer," was preaching in the desert country of Judea.</verse>
<verse>His message was simple and austere, like his desert surroundings: "Change your life. God's kingdom is here."</verse>
<verse>John and his message were authorized by Isaiah's prophecy: Thunder in the desert! Prepare for God's arrival! Make the road smooth and straight!</verse>
<verse>John dressed in a camel-hair habit tied at the waist by a leather strap. He lived on a diet of locusts and wild field honey.</verse>
<verse>People poured out of Jerusalem, Judea, and the Jordanian countryside to hear and see him in action.</verse>
<verse>There at the Jordan River those who came to confess their sins were baptized into a changed life.</verse>
<verse>When John realized that a lot of Pharisees and Sadducees were showing up for a baptismal experience because it was becoming the popular thing to do, he exploded: "Brood of snakes! What do you think you're doing slithering down here to the river? Do you think a little water on your snakeskins is going to make any difference?</verse>
<verse>It's your life that must change, not your skin!</verse>
<verse>And don't think you can pull rank by claiming Abraham as father. Being a descendant of Abraham is neither here nor there. Descendants of Abraham are a dime a dozen.</verse>
<verse>What counts is your life. Is it green and blossoming? Because if it's deadwood, it goes on the fire.</verse>
<verse>"I'm baptizing you here in the river, turning your old life in for a kingdom life. The real action comes next: The main character in this drama--compared to him I'm a mere stagehand--will ignite the kingdom life within you, a fire within you, the Holy Spirit within you, changing you from the inside out.</verse>
<verse>He's going to clean house--make a clean sweep of your lives. He'll place everything true in its proper place before God; everything false he'll put out with the trash to be burned." [JC]</verse>
<verse>Jesus then appeared, arriving at the Jordan River from Galilee. He wanted John to baptize him.</verse>
<verse>John objected, "I'm the one who needs to be baptized, not you!"</verse>
<verse>But Jesus insisted. "Do it. God's work, putting things right all these centuries, is coming together right now in this baptism." So John did it.</verse>
<verse>The moment Jesus came up out of the baptismal waters, the skies opened up and he saw God's Spirit--it looked like a dove--descending and landing on him.</verse>
<verse>And along with the Spirit, a voice: "This is my Son, chosen and marked by my love, delight of my life."</verse>
</chapter>