<chapter translation="MSG" testament="New" book="2 Timothy" book_id="55" n="2">
<verse>So, my son, throw yourself into this work for Christ.</verse>
<verse>Pass on what you heard from me--the whole congregation saying Amen!-to reliable leaders who are competent to teach others.</verse>
<verse>When the going gets rough, take it on the chin with the rest of us, the way Jesus did.</verse>
<verse>A soldier on duty doesn't get caught up in making deals at the marketplace. He concentrates on carrying out orders.</verse>
<verse>An athlete who refuses to play by the rules will never get anywhere.</verse>
<verse>It's the diligent farmer who gets the produce.</verse>
<verse>Think it over. God will make it all plain.</verse>
<verse>Fix this picture firmly in your mind: Jesus, descended from the line of David, raised from the dead. It's what you've heard from me all along.</verse>
<verse>It's what I'm sitting in jail for right now--but God's Word isn't in jail!</verse>
<verse>That's why I stick it out here--so that everyone God calls will get in on the salvation of Christ in all its glory.</verse>
<verse>This is a sure thing: If we die with him, we'll live with him;</verse>
<verse>If we stick it out with him, we'll rule with him; If we turn our backs on him, he'll turn his back on us;</verse>
<verse>If we give up on him, he does not give up--for there's no way he can be false to himself.</verse>
<verse>Repeat these basic essentials over and over to God's people. Warn them before God against pious nitpicking, which chips away at the faith. It just wears everyone out.</verse>
<verse>Concentrate on doing your best for God, work you won't be ashamed of, laying out the truth plain and simple.</verse>
<verse>Stay clear of pious talk that is only talk. Words are not mere words, you know. If they're not backed by a godly life,</verse>
<verse>they accumulate as poison in the soul. Hymenaeus and Philetus are examples,</verse>
<verse>throwing believers off stride and missing the truth by a mile by saying the resurrection is over and done with.</verse>
<verse>Meanwhile, God's firm foundation is as firm as ever, these sentences engraved on the stones: GOD KNOWS WHO BELONGS TO HIM SPURN EVIL ALL YOU WHO NAME GOD AS GOD.</verse>
<verse>In a well-furnished kitchen there are not only crystal goblets and silver platters, but waste cans and compost buckets--some containers used to serve fine meals, others to take out the garbage.</verse>
<verse>Become the kind of container God can use to present any and every kind of gift to his guests for their blessing.</verse>
<verse>Run away from infantile indulgence. Run after mature righteousness--faith, love, peace--joining those who are in honest and serious prayer before God.</verse>
<verse>Refuse to get involved in inane discussions; they always end up in fights.</verse>
<verse>God's servant must not be argumentative, but a gentle listener and a teacher who keeps cool,</verse>
<verse>working firmly but patiently with those who refuse to obey. You never know how or when God might sober them up with a change of heart and a turning to the truth,</verse>
<verse>enabling them to escape the Devil's trap, where they are caught and held captive, forced to run his errands.</verse>
</chapter>