<chapter translation="MSG" testament="New" book="2 Timothy" book-id="55" n="3">
<verse>Don't be naive. There are difficult times ahead.</verse>
<verse>As the end approaches, people are going to be self-absorbed, money-hungry, self-promoting, stuck-up, profane, contemptuous of parents, crude, coarse,</verse>
<verse>dog-eat-dog, unbending, slanderers, impulsively wild, savage, cynical,</verse>
<verse>treacherous, ruthless, bloated windbags, addicted to lust, and allergic to God.</verse>
<verse>They'll make a show of religion, but behind the scenes they're animals. Stay clear of these people.</verse>
<verse>These are the kind of people who smooth-talk themselves into the homes of unstable and needy women and take advantage of them; women who, depressed by their sinfulness, take up with every new religious fad that calls itself "truth."</verse>
<verse>They get exploited every time and never really learn.</verse>
<verse>These men are like those old Egyptian frauds Jannes and Jambres, who challenged Moses. They were rejects from the faith, twisted in their thinking, defying truth itself.</verse>
<verse>But nothing will come of these latest impostors. Everyone will see through them, just as people saw through that Egyptian hoax.</verse>
<verse>You've been a good apprentice to me, a part of my teaching, my manner of life, direction, faith, steadiness, love, patience,</verse>
<verse>troubles, sufferings--suffering along with me in all the grief I had to put up with in Antioch, Iconium, and Lystra. And you also well know that God rescued me!</verse>
<verse>Anyone who wants to live all out for Christ is in for a lot of trouble; there's no getting around it.</verse>
<verse>Unscrupulous con men will continue to exploit the faith. They're as deceived as the people they lead astray. As long as they are out there, things can only get worse.</verse>
<verse>But don't let it faze you. Stick with what you learned and believed, sure of the integrity of your teachers--</verse>
<verse>why, you took in the sacred Scriptures with your mother's milk! There's nothing like the written Word of God for showing you the way to salvation through faith in Christ Jesus.</verse>
<verse>Every part of Scripture is God-breathed and useful one way or another--showing us truth, exposing our rebellion, correcting our mistakes, training us to live God's way.</verse>
<verse>Through the Word we are put together and shaped up for the tasks God has for us.</verse>
</chapter>