<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Lamentations" book_id="25" n="3">
<verse>I am the man who has seen affliction by the rod of his wrath.</verse>
<verse>He has driven me away and made me walk in darkness rather than light;</verse>
<verse>indeed, he has turned his hand against me again and again, all day long.</verse>
<verse>He has made my skin and my flesh grow old and has broken my bones.</verse>
<verse>He has besieged me and surrounded me with bitterness and hardship.</verse>
<verse>He has made me dwell in darkness like those long dead.</verse>
<verse>He has walled me in so I cannot escape; he has weighed me down with chains.</verse>
<verse>Even when I call out or cry for help, he shuts out my prayer.</verse>
<verse>He has barred my way with blocks of stone; he has made my paths crooked.</verse>
<verse>Like a bear lying in wait, like a lion in hiding,</verse>
<verse>he dragged me from the path and mangled me and left me without help.</verse>
<verse>He drew his bow and made me the target for his arrows.</verse>
<verse>He pierced my heart with arrows from his quiver.</verse>
<verse>I became the laughingstock of all my people; they mock me in song all day long.</verse>
<verse>He has filled me with bitter herbs and sated me with gall.</verse>
<verse>He has broken my teeth with gravel; he has trampled me in the dust.</verse>
<verse>I have been deprived of peace; I have forgotten what prosperity is.</verse>
<verse>So I say, "My splendor is gone and all that I had hoped from the LORD."</verse>
<verse>I remember my affliction and my wandering, the bitterness and the gall.</verse>
<verse>I well remember them, and my soul is downcast within me.</verse>
<verse>Yet this I call to mind and therefore I have hope:</verse>
<verse>Because of the LORD's great love we are not consumed, for his compassions never fail.</verse>
<verse>They are new every morning; great is your faithfulness.</verse>
<verse>I say to myself, "The LORD is my portion; therefore I will wait for him."</verse>
<verse>The LORD is good to those whose hope is in him, to the one who seeks him;</verse>
<verse>it is good to wait quietly for the salvation of the LORD.</verse>
<verse>It is good for a man to bear the yoke while he is young.</verse>
<verse>Let him sit alone in silence, for the LORD has laid it on him.</verse>
<verse>Let him bury his face in the dust- there may yet be hope.</verse>
<verse>Let him offer his cheek to one who would strike him, and let him be filled with disgrace.</verse>
<verse>For men are not cast off by the Lord forever.</verse>
<verse>Though he brings grief, he will show compassion, so great is his unfailing love.</verse>
<verse>For he does not willingly bring affliction or grief to the children of men.</verse>
<verse>To crush underfoot all prisoners in the land,</verse>
<verse>to deny a man his rights before the Most High,</verse>
<verse>to deprive a man of justice- would not the Lord see such things?</verse>
<verse>Who can speak and have it happen if the Lord has not decreed it?</verse>
<verse>Is it not from the mouth of the Most High that both calamities and good things come?</verse>
<verse>Why should any living man complain when punished for his sins?</verse>
<verse>Let us examine our ways and test them, and let us return to the LORD.</verse>
<verse>Let us lift up our hearts and our hands to God in heaven, and say:</verse>
<verse>"We have sinned and rebelled and you have not forgiven.</verse>
<verse>"You have covered yourself with anger and pursued us; you have slain without pity.</verse>
<verse>You have covered yourself with a cloud so that no prayer can get through.</verse>
<verse>You have made us scum and refuse among the nations.</verse>
<verse>"All our enemies have opened their mouths wide against us.</verse>
<verse>We have suffered terror and pitfalls, ruin and destruction."</verse>
<verse>Streams of tears flow from my eyes because my people are destroyed.</verse>
<verse>My eyes will flow unceasingly, without relief,</verse>
<verse>until the LORD looks down from heaven and sees.</verse>
<verse>What I see brings grief to my soul because of all the women of my city.</verse>
<verse>Those who were my enemies without cause hunted me like a bird.</verse>
<verse>They tried to end my life in a pit and threw stones at me;</verse>
<verse>the waters closed over my head, and I thought I was about to be cut off.</verse>
<verse>I called on your name, O LORD, from the depths of the pit.</verse>
<verse>You heard my plea: "Do not close your ears to my cry for relief."</verse>
<verse>You came near when I called you, and you said, "Do not fear."</verse>
<verse>O Lord, you took up my case; you redeemed my life.</verse>
<verse>You have seen, O LORD, the wrong done to me. Uphold my cause!</verse>
<verse>You have seen the depth of their vengeance, all their plots against me.</verse>
<verse>O LORD, you have heard their insults, all their plots against me-</verse>
<verse>what my enemies whisper and mutter against me all day long.</verse>
<verse>Look at them! Sitting or standing, they mock me in their songs.</verse>
<verse>Pay them back what they deserve, O LORD, for what their hands have done.</verse>
<verse>Put a veil over their hearts, and may your curse be on them!</verse>
<verse>Pursue them in anger and destroy them from under the heavens of the LORD.</verse>
</chapter>