<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Lamentations" book_id="25" n="4">
<verse>How the gold has lost its luster, the fine gold become dull! The sacred gems are scattered at the head of every street.</verse>
<verse>How the precious sons of Zion, once worth their weight in gold, are now considered as pots of clay, the work of a potter's hands!</verse>
<verse>Even jackals offer their breasts to nurse their young, but my people have become heartless like ostriches in the desert.</verse>
<verse>Because of thirst the infant's tongue sticks to the roof of its mouth; the children beg for bread, but no one gives it to them.</verse>
<verse>Those who once ate delicacies are destitute in the streets. Those nurtured in purple now lie on ash heaps.</verse>
<verse>The punishment of my people is greater than that of Sodom, which was overthrown in a moment without a hand turned to help her.</verse>
<verse>Their princes were brighter than snow and whiter than milk, their bodies more ruddy than rubies, their appearance like sapphires.</verse>
<verse>But now they are blacker than soot; they are not recognized in the streets. Their skin has shriveled on their bones; it has become as dry as a stick.</verse>
<verse>Those killed by the sword are better off than those who die of famine; racked with hunger, they waste away for lack of food from the field.</verse>
<verse>With their own hands compassionate women have cooked their own children, who became their food when my people were destroyed.</verse>
<verse>The LORD has given full vent to his wrath; he has poured out his fierce anger. He kindled a fire in Zion that consumed her foundations.</verse>
<verse>The kings of the earth did not believe, nor did any of the world's people, that enemies and foes could enter the gates of Jerusalem.</verse>
<verse>But it happened because of the sins of her prophets and the iniquities of her priests, who shed within her the blood of the righteous.</verse>
<verse>Now they grope through the streets like men who are blind. They are so defiled with blood that no one dares to touch their garments.</verse>
<verse>"Go away! You are unclean!" men cry to them. "Away! Away! Don't touch us!" When they flee and wander about, people among the nations say, "They can stay here no longer."</verse>
<verse>The LORD himself has scattered them; he no longer watches over them. The priests are shown no honor, the elders no favor.</verse>
<verse>Moreover, our eyes failed, looking in vain for help; from our towers we watched for a nation that could not save us.</verse>
<verse>Men stalked us at every step, so we could not walk in our streets. Our end was near, our days were numbered, for our end had come.</verse>
<verse>Our pursuers were swifter than eagles in the sky; they chased us over the mountains and lay in wait for us in the desert.</verse>
<verse>The LORD's anointed, our very life breath, was caught in their traps. We thought that under his shadow we would live among the nations.</verse>
<verse>Rejoice and be glad, O Daughter of Edom, you who live in the land of Uz. But to you also the cup will be passed; you will be drunk and stripped naked.</verse>
<verse>O Daughter of Zion, your punishment will end; he will not prolong your exile. But, O Daughter of Edom, he will punish your sin and expose your wickedness.</verse>
</chapter>