<chapter translation="MSG" testament="New" book="1 Corinthians" book_id="46" n="1">
<verse>I, Paul, have been called and sent by Jesus, the Messiah, according to God's plan, along with my friend Sosthenes.</verse>
<verse>I send this letter to you in God's church at Corinth, Christians cleaned up by Jesus and set apart for a God-filled life. I include in my greeting all who call out to Jesus, wherever they live. He's their Master as well as ours!</verse>
<verse>May all the gifts and benefits that come from God our Father, and the Master, Jesus Christ, be yours.</verse>
<verse>Every time I think of you--and I think of you often!-I thank God for your lives of free and open access to God, given by Jesus.</verse>
<verse>There's no end to what has happened in you--it's beyond speech, beyond knowledge.</verse>
<verse>The evidence of Christ has been clearly verified in your lives.</verse>
<verse>Just think--you don't need a thing, you've got it all! All God's gifts are right in front of you as you wait expectantly for our Master Jesus to arrive on the scene for the Finale.</verse>
<verse>And not only that, but God himself is right alongside to keep you steady and on track until things are all wrapped up by Jesus.</verse>
<verse>God, who got you started in this spiritual adventure, shares with us the life of his Son and our Master Jesus. He will never give up on you. Never forget that.</verse>
<verse>I have a serious concern to bring up with you, my friends, using the authority of Jesus, our Master. I'll put it as urgently as I can: You must get along with each other. You must learn to be considerate of one another, cultivating a life in common.</verse>
<verse>I bring this up because some from Chloe's family brought a most disturbing report to my attention--that you're fighting among yourselves!</verse>
<verse>I'll tell you exactly what I was told: You're all picking sides, going around saying, "I'm on Paul's side," or "I'm for Apollos," or "Peter is my man," or "I'm in the Messiah group."</verse>
<verse>I ask you, "Has the Messiah been chopped up in little pieces so we can each have a relic all our own? Was Paul crucified for you? Was a single one of you baptized in Paul's name?"</verse>
<verse>I was not involved with any of your baptisms--except for Crispus and Gaius--and on getting this report, I'm sure glad I wasn't.</verse>
<verse>At least no one can go around saying he was baptized in my name.</verse>
<verse>(Come to think of it, I also baptized Stephanas's family, but as far as I can recall, that's it.)</verse>
<verse>God didn't send me out to collect a following for myself, but to preach the Message of what he has done, collecting a following for him. And he didn't send me to do it with a lot of fancy rhetoric of my own, lest the powerful action at the center--Christ on the Cross--be trivialized into mere words.</verse>
<verse>The Message that points to Christ on the Cross seems like sheer silliness to those hellbent on destruction, but for those on the way of salvation it makes perfect sense. This is the way God works, and most powerfully as it turns out.</verse>
<verse>It's written, I'll turn conventional wisdom on its head, I'll expose so-called experts as crackpots.</verse>
<verse>So where can you find someone truly wise, truly educated, truly intelligent in this day and age? Hasn't God exposed it all as pretentious nonsense?</verse>
<verse>Since the world in all its fancy wisdom never had a clue when it came to knowing God, God in his wisdom took delight in using what the world considered dumb--preaching, of all things!-to bring those who trust him into the way of salvation.</verse>
<verse>While Jews clamor for miraculous demonstrations and Greeks go in for philosophical wisdom,</verse>
<verse>we go right on proclaiming Christ, the Crucified. Jews treat this like an anti-miracle--and Greeks pass it off as absurd.</verse>
<verse>But to us who are personally called by God himself--both Jews and Greeks--Christ is God's ultimate miracle and wisdom all wrapped up in one.</verse>
<verse>Human wisdom is so tinny, so impotent, next to the seeming absurdity of God. Human strength can't begin to compete with God's "weakness."</verse>
<verse>Take a good look, friends, at who you were when you got called into this life. I don't see many of "the brightest and the best" among you, not many influential, not many from high-society families.</verse>
<verse>Isn't it obvious that God deliberately chose men and women that the culture overlooks and exploits and abuses,</verse>
<verse>chose these "nobodies" to expose the hollow pretensions of the "somebodies"?</verse>
<verse>That makes it quite clear that none of you can get by with blowing your own horn before God.</verse>
<verse>Everything that we have--right thinking and right living, a clean slate and a fresh start--comes from God by way of Jesus Christ.</verse>
<verse>That's why we have the saying, "If you're going to blow a horn, blow a trumpet for God."</verse>
</chapter>