<chapter translation="MSG" testament="New" book="1 Corinthians" book-id="46" n="16">
<verse>Regarding the relief offering for poor Christians that is being collected, you get the same instructions I gave the churches in Galatia.</verse>
<verse>Every Sunday each of you make an offering and put it in safekeeping. Be as generous as you can. When I get there you'll have it ready, and I won't have to make a special appeal.</verse>
<verse>Then after I arrive, I'll write letters authorizing whomever you delegate, and send them off to Jerusalem to deliver your gift.</verse>
<verse>If you think it best that I go along, I'll be glad to travel with them.</verse>
<verse>I plan to visit you after passing through northern Greece. I won't be staying long there,</verse>
<verse>but maybe I can stay awhile with you--maybe even spend the winter? Then you could give me a good send-off, wherever I may be headed next.</verse>
<verse>I don't want to just drop by in between other "primary" destinations. I want a good, long, leisurely visit. If the Master agrees, we'll have it!</verse>
<verse>For the present, I'm staying right here in Ephesus.</verse>
<verse>A huge door of opportunity for good work has opened up here. (There is also mushrooming opposition.)</verse>
<verse>If Timothy shows up, take good care of him. Make him feel completely at home among you. He works so hard for the Master, just as I do.</verse>
<verse>Don't let anyone disparage him. After a while, send him on to me with your blessing. Tell him I'm expecting him, and any friends he has with him.</verse>
<verse>About our friend Apollos, I've done my best to get him to pay you a visit, but haven't talked him into it yet. He doesn't think this is the right time. But there will be a "right time."</verse>
<verse>Keep your eyes open, hold tight to your convictions, give it all you've got, be resolute,</verse>
<verse>and love without stopping.</verse>
<verse>Would you do me a favor, friends, and give special recognition to the family of Stephanas? You know, they were among the first converts in Greece, and they've put themselves out, serving Christians ever since then. I want you to</verse>
<verse>honor and look up to people like that: companions and workers who show us how to do it, giving us something to aspire to.</verse>
<verse>I want you to know how delighted I am to have Stephanas, Fortunatus, and Achaicus here with me. They partially make up for your absence!</verse>
<verse>They've refreshed me by keeping me in touch with you. Be proud that you have people like this among you.</verse>
<verse>The churches here in western Asia send greetings. Aquila, Priscilla, and the church that meets in their house say hello.</verse>
<verse>All the friends here say hello. Pass the greetings around with holy embraces!</verse>
<verse>And I, Paul--in my own handwriting!-send you my regards.</verse>
<verse>If anyone won't love the Master, throw him out. Make room for the Master!</verse>
<verse>Our Master Jesus has his arms wide open for you.</verse>
<verse>And I love all of you in the Messiah, in Jesus.</verse>
</chapter>