<chapter translation="ESV" testament="New" book="Mark" book_id="41" n="1">
<verse>The beginning of the gospel of Jesus Christ, the Son of God.</verse>
<verse>As it is written in Isaiah the prophet, "Behold, I send my messenger before your face, who will prepare your way,</verse>
<verse>the voice of one crying in the wilderness: 'Prepare the way of the Lord, make his paths straight,'"</verse>
<verse>John appeared, baptizing in the wilderness and proclaiming a baptism of repentance for the forgiveness of sins.</verse>
<verse>And all the country of Judea and all Jerusalem were going out to him and were being baptized by him in the river Jordan, confessing their sins.</verse>
<verse>Now John was clothed with camel's hair and wore a leather belt around his waist and ate locusts and wild honey.</verse>
<verse>And he preached, saying, "After me comes he who is mightier than I, the strap of whose sandals I am not worthy to stoop down and untie.</verse>
<verse>I have baptized you with water, but he will baptize you with the Holy Spirit."</verse>
<verse>In those days Jesus came from Nazareth of Galilee and was baptized by John in the Jordan.</verse>
<verse>And when he came up out of the water, immediately he saw the heavens opening and the Spirit descending on him like a dove.</verse>
<verse>And a voice came from heaven, "You are my beloved Son; with you I am well pleased."</verse>
<verse>The Spirit immediately drove him out into the wilderness.</verse>
<verse>And he was in the wilderness forty days, being tempted by Satan. And he was with the wild animals, and the angels were ministering to him.</verse>
<verse>Now after John was arrested, Jesus came into Galilee, proclaiming the gospel of God,</verse>
<verse>and saying, "The time is fulfilled, and the kingdom of God is at hand; repent and believe in the gospel."</verse>
<verse>Passing alongside the Sea of Galilee, he saw Simon and Andrew the brother of Simon casting a net into the sea, for they were fishermen.</verse>
<verse>And Jesus said to them, "Follow me, and I will make you become fishers of men."</verse>
<verse>And immediately they left their nets and followed him.</verse>
<verse>And going on a little farther, he saw James the son of Zebedee and John his brother, who were in their boat mending the nets.</verse>
<verse>And immediately he called them, and they left their father Zebedee in the boat with the hired servants and followed him.</verse>
<verse>And they went into Capernaum, and immediately on the Sabbath he entered the synagogue and was teaching.</verse>
<verse>And they were astonished at his teaching, for he taught them as one who had authority, and not as the scribes.</verse>
<verse>And immediately there was in their synagogue a man with an unclean spirit. And he cried out,</verse>
<verse>"What have you to do with us, Jesus of Nazareth? Have you come to destroy us? I know who you are--the Holy One of God."</verse>
<verse>But Jesus rebuked him, saying, "Be silent, and come out of him!"</verse>
<verse>And the unclean spirit, convulsing him and crying out with a loud voice, came out of him.</verse>
<verse>And they were all amazed, so that they questioned among themselves, saying, "What is this? A new teaching with authority! He commands even the unclean spirits, and they obey him."</verse>
<verse>And at once his fame spread everywhere throughout all the surrounding region of Galilee.</verse>
<verse>And immediately he left the synagogue and entered the house of Simon and Andrew, with James and John.</verse>
<verse>Now Simon's mother-in-law lay ill with a fever, and immediately they told him about her.</verse>
<verse>And he came and took her by the hand and lifted her up, and the fever left her, and she began to serve them.</verse>
<verse>That evening at sundown they brought to him all who were sick or oppressed by demons.</verse>
<verse>And the whole city was gathered together at the door.</verse>
<verse>And he healed many who were sick with various diseases, and cast out many demons. And he would not permit the demons to speak, because they knew him.</verse>
<verse>And rising very early in the morning, while it was still dark, he departed and went out to a desolate place, and there he prayed.</verse>
<verse>And Simon and those who were with him searched for him,</verse>
<verse>and they found him and said to him, "Everyone is looking for you."</verse>
<verse>And he said to them, "Let us go on to the next towns, that I may preach there also, for that is why I came out."</verse>
<verse>And he went throughout all Galilee, preaching in their synagogues and casting out demons.</verse>
<verse>And a leper came to him, imploring him, and kneeling said to him, "If you will, you can make me clean."</verse>
<verse>Moved with pity, he stretched out his hand and touched him and said to him, "I will; be clean."</verse>
<verse>And immediately the leprosy left him, and he was made clean.</verse>
<verse>And Jesus sternly charged him and sent him away at once,</verse>
<verse>and said to him, "See that you say nothing to anyone, but go, show yourself to the priest and offer for your cleansing what Moses commanded, for a proof to them."</verse>
<verse>But he went out and began to talk freely about it, and to spread the news, so that Jesus could no longer openly enter a town, but was out in desolate places, and people were coming to him from every quarter.</verse>
</chapter>