<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Job" book_id="18" n="11">
<verse>Then Zophar the Naamathite answered,</verse>
<verse>"Shall a multitude of words go unanswered, And a talkative man be acquitted?</verse>
<verse>"Shall your boasts silence men? And shall you scoff and none rebuke?</verse>
<verse>"For you have said, 'My teaching is pure, And I am innocent in your eyes.'</verse>
<verse>"But would that God might speak, And open His lips against you,</verse>
<verse>And show you the secrets of wisdom! For sound wisdom has two sides. Know then that God forgets a part of your iniquity.</verse>
<verse>"Can you discover the depths of God? Can you discover the limits of the Almighty?</verse>
<verse>"They are high as the heavens, what can you do? Deeper than Sheol, what can you know?</verse>
<verse>"Its measure is longer than the earth And broader than the sea.</verse>
<verse>"If He passes by or shuts up, Or calls an assembly, who can restrain Him?</verse>
<verse>"For He knows false men, And He sees iniquity without investigating.</verse>
<verse>"An idiot will become intelligent When the foal of a wild donkey is born a man.</verse>
<verse>"If you would direct your heart right And spread out your hand to Him,</verse>
<verse>If iniquity is in your hand, put it far away, And do not let wickedness dwell in your tents;</verse>
<verse>"Then, indeed, you could lift up your face without moral defect, And you would be steadfast and not fear.</verse>
<verse>"For you would forget your trouble, As waters that have passed by, you would remember it.</verse>
<verse>"Your life would be brighter than noonday; Darkness would be like the morning.</verse>
<verse>"Then you would trust, because there is hope; And you would look around and rest securely.</verse>
<verse>"You would lie down and none would disturb you, And many would entreat your favor.</verse>
<verse>"But the eyes of the wicked will fail, And there will be no escape for them; And their hope is to breathe their last."</verse>
</chapter>