<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Job" book_id="18" n="12">
<verse>Then Job responded,</verse>
<verse>"Truly then you are the people, And with you wisdom will die!</verse>
<verse>"But I have intelligence as well as you; I am not inferior to you. And who does not know such things as these?</verse>
<verse>"I am a joke to my friends, The one who called on God and He answered him; The just and blameless man is a joke.</verse>
<verse>"He who is at ease holds calamity in contempt, As prepared for those whose feet slip.</verse>
<verse>"The tents of the destroyers prosper, And those who provoke God are secure, Whom God brings into their power.</verse>
<verse>"But now ask the beasts, and let them teach you; And the birds of the heavens, and let them tell you.</verse>
<verse>"Or speak to the earth, and let it teach you; And let the fish of the sea declare to you.</verse>
<verse>"Who among all these does not know That the hand of the LORD has done this,</verse>
<verse>In whose hand is the life of every living thing, And the breath of all mankind?</verse>
<verse>"Does not the ear test words, As the palate tastes its food?</verse>
<verse>"Wisdom is with aged men, With long life is understanding.</verse>
<verse>"With Him are wisdom and might; To Him belong counsel and understanding.</verse>
<verse>"Behold, He tears down, and it cannot be rebuilt; He imprisons a man, and there can be no release.</verse>
<verse>"Behold, He restrains the waters, and they dry up; And He sends them out, and they inundate the earth.</verse>
<verse>"With Him are strength and sound wisdom, The misled and the misleader belong to Him.</verse>
<verse>"He makes counselors walk barefoot And makes fools of judges.</verse>
<verse>"He loosens the bond of kings And binds their loins with a girdle.</verse>
<verse>"He makes priests walk barefoot And overthrows the secure ones.</verse>
<verse>"He deprives the trusted ones of speech And takes away the discernment of the elders.</verse>
<verse>"He pours contempt on nobles And loosens the belt of the strong.</verse>
<verse>"He reveals mysteries from the darkness And brings the deep darkness into light.</verse>
<verse>"He makes the nations great, then destroys them; He enlarges the nations, then leads them away.</verse>
<verse>"He deprives of intelligence the chiefs of the earth's people And makes them wander in a pathless waste.</verse>
<verse>"They grope in darkness with no light, And He makes them stagger like a drunken man.</verse>
</chapter>