<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Job" book-id="18" n="13">
<verse>"Behold, my eye has seen all this, My ear has heard and understood it.</verse>
<verse>"What you know I also know; I am not inferior to you.</verse>
<verse>"But I would speak to the Almighty, And I desire to argue with God.</verse>
<verse>"But you smear with lies; You are all worthless physicians.</verse>
<verse>"O that you would be completely silent, And that it would become your wisdom!</verse>
<verse>"Please hear my argument And listen to the contentions of my lips.</verse>
<verse>"Will you speak what is unjust for God, And speak what is deceitful for Him?</verse>
<verse>"Will you show partiality for Him? Will you contend for God?</verse>
<verse>"Will it be well when He examines you? Or will you deceive Him as one deceives a man?</verse>
<verse>"He will surely reprove you If you secretly show partiality.</verse>
<verse>"Will not His majesty terrify you, And the dread of Him fall on you?</verse>
<verse>"Your memorable sayings are proverbs of ashes, Your defenses are defenses of clay.</verse>
<verse>"Be silent before me so that I may speak; Then let come on me what may.</verse>
<verse>"Why should I take my flesh in my teeth And put my life in my hands?</verse>
<verse>"Though He slay me, I will hope in Him. Nevertheless I will argue my ways before Him.</verse>
<verse>"This also will be my salvation, For a godless man may not come before His presence.</verse>
<verse>"Listen carefully to my speech, And let my declaration fill your ears.</verse>
<verse>"Behold now, I have prepared my case; I know that I will be vindicated.</verse>
<verse>"Who will contend with me? For then I would be silent and die.</verse>
<verse>"Only two things do not do to me, Then I will not hide from Your face:</verse>
<verse>Remove Your hand from me, And let not the dread of You terrify me.</verse>
<verse>"Then call, and I will answer; Or let me speak, then reply to me.</verse>
<verse>"How many are my iniquities and sins? Make known to me my rebellion and my sin.</verse>
<verse>"Why do You hide Your face And consider me Your enemy?</verse>
<verse>"Will You cause a driven leaf to tremble? Or will You pursue the dry chaff?</verse>
<verse>"For You write bitter things against me And make me to inherit the iniquities of my youth.</verse>
<verse>"You put my feet in the stocks And watch all my paths; You set a limit for the soles of my feet,</verse>
<verse>While I am decaying like a rotten thing, Like a garment that is moth-eaten.</verse>
</chapter>