<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Job" book-id="18" n="14">
<verse>"Man, who is born of woman, Is short-lived and full of turmoil.</verse>
<verse>"Like a flower he comes forth and withers. He also flees like a shadow and does not remain.</verse>
<verse>"You also open Your eyes on him And bring him into judgment with Yourself.</verse>
<verse>"Who can make the clean out of the unclean? No one!</verse>
<verse>"Since his days are determined, The number of his months is with You; And his limits You have set so that he cannot pass.</verse>
<verse>"Turn Your gaze from him that he may rest, Until he fulfills his day like a hired man.</verse>
<verse>"For there is hope for a tree, When it is cut down, that it will sprout again, And its shoots will not fail.</verse>
<verse>"Though its roots grow old in the ground And its stump dies in the dry soil,</verse>
<verse>At the scent of water it will flourish And put forth sprigs like a plant.</verse>
<verse>"But man dies and lies prostrate. Man expires, and where is he?</verse>
<verse>"As water evaporates from the sea, And a river becomes parched and dried up,</verse>
<verse>So man lies down and does not rise. Until the heavens are no longer, He will not awake nor be aroused out of his sleep.</verse>
<verse>"Oh that You would hide me in Sheol, That You would conceal me until Your wrath returns to You, That You would set a limit for me and remember me!</verse>
<verse>"If a man dies, will he live again? All the days of my struggle I will wait Until my change comes.</verse>
<verse>"You will call, and I will answer You; You will long for the work of Your hands.</verse>
<verse>"For now You number my steps, You do not observe my sin.</verse>
<verse>"My transgression is sealed up in a bag, And You wrap up my iniquity.</verse>
<verse>"But the falling mountain crumbles away, And the rock moves from its place;</verse>
<verse>Water wears away stones, Its torrents wash away the dust of the earth; So You destroy man's hope.</verse>
<verse>"You forever overpower him and he departs; You change his appearance and send him away.</verse>
<verse>"His sons achieve honor, but he does not know it; Or they become insignificant, but he does not perceive it.</verse>
<verse>"But his body pains him, And he mourns only for himself."</verse>
</chapter>