<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Job" book_id="18" n="15">
<verse>Then Eliphaz the Temanite responded,</verse>
<verse>"Should a wise man answer with windy knowledge And fill himself with the east wind?</verse>
<verse>"Should he argue with useless talk, Or with words which are not profitable?</verse>
<verse>"Indeed, you do away with reverence And hinder meditation before God.</verse>
<verse>"For your guilt teaches your mouth, And you choose the language of the crafty.</verse>
<verse>"Your own mouth condemns you, and not I; And your own lips testify against you.</verse>
<verse>"Were you the first man to be born, Or were you brought forth before the hills?</verse>
<verse>"Do you hear the secret counsel of God, And limit wisdom to yourself?</verse>
<verse>"What do you know that we do not know? What do you understand that we do not?</verse>
<verse>"Both the gray-haired and the aged are among us, Older than your father.</verse>
<verse>"Are the consolations of God too small for you, Even the word spoken gently with you?</verse>
<verse>"Why does your heart carry you away? And why do your eyes flash,</verse>
<verse>That you should turn your spirit against God And allow such words to go out of your mouth?</verse>
<verse>"What is man, that he should be pure, Or he who is born of a woman, that he should be righteous?</verse>
<verse>"Behold, He puts no trust in His holy ones, And the heavens are not pure in His sight;</verse>
<verse>How much less one who is detestable and corrupt, Man, who drinks iniquity like water!</verse>
<verse>"I will tell you, listen to me; And what I have seen I will also declare;</verse>
<verse>What wise men have told, And have not concealed from their fathers,</verse>
<verse>To whom alone the land was given, And no alien passed among them.</verse>
<verse>"The wicked man writhes in pain all his days, And numbered are the years stored up for the ruthless.</verse>
<verse>"Sounds of terror are in his ears; While at peace the destroyer comes upon him.</verse>
<verse>"He does not believe that he will return from darkness, And he is destined for the sword.</verse>
<verse>"He wanders about for food, saying, 'Where is it?' He knows that a day of darkness is at hand.</verse>
<verse>"Distress and anguish terrify him, They overpower him like a king ready for the attack,</verse>
<verse>Because he has stretched out his hand against God And conducts himself arrogantly against the Almighty.</verse>
<verse>"He rushes headlong at Him With his massive shield.</verse>
<verse>"For he has covered his face with his fat And made his thighs heavy with flesh.</verse>
<verse>"He has lived in desolate cities, In houses no one would inhabit, Which are destined to become ruins.</verse>
<verse>"He will not become rich, nor will his wealth endure; And his grain will not bend down to the ground.</verse>
<verse>"He will not escape from darkness; The flame will wither his shoots, And by the breath of His mouth he will go away.</verse>
<verse>"Let him not trust in emptiness, deceiving himself; For emptiness will be his reward.</verse>
<verse>"It will be accomplished before his time, And his palm branch will not be green.</verse>
<verse>"He will drop off his unripe grape like the vine, And will cast off his flower like the olive tree.</verse>
<verse>"For the company of the godless is barren, And fire consumes the tents of the corrupt.</verse>
<verse>"They conceive mischief and bring forth iniquity, And their mind prepares deception."</verse>
</chapter>