<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Job" book-id="18" n="16">
<verse>Then Job answered,</verse>
<verse>"I have heard many such things; Sorry comforters are you all.</verse>
<verse>"Is there no limit to windy words? Or what plagues you that you answer?</verse>
<verse>"I too could speak like you, If I were in your place. I could compose words against you And shake my head at you.</verse>
<verse>"I could strengthen you with my mouth, And the solace of my lips could lessen your pain.</verse>
<verse>"If I speak, my pain is not lessened, And if I hold back, what has left me?</verse>
<verse>"But now He has exhausted me; You have laid waste all my company.</verse>
<verse>"You have shriveled me up, It has become a witness; And my leanness rises up against me, It testifies to my face.</verse>
<verse>"His anger has torn me and hunted me down, He has gnashed at me with His teeth; My adversary glares at me.</verse>
<verse>"They have gaped at me with their mouth, They have slapped me on the cheek with contempt; They have massed themselves against me.</verse>
<verse>"God hands me over to ruffians And tosses me into the hands of the wicked.</verse>
<verse>"I was at ease, but He shattered me, And He has grasped me by the neck and shaken me to pieces; He has also set me up as His target.</verse>
<verse>"His arrows surround me. Without mercy He splits my kidneys open; He pours out my gall on the ground.</verse>
<verse>"He breaks through me with breach after breach; He runs at me like a warrior.</verse>
<verse>"I have sewed sackcloth over my skin And thrust my horn in the dust.</verse>
<verse>"My face is flushed from weeping, And deep darkness is on my eyelids,</verse>
<verse>Although there is no violence in my hands, And my prayer is pure.</verse>
<verse>"O earth, do not cover my blood, And let there be no resting place for my cry.</verse>
<verse>"Even now, behold, my witness is in heaven, And my advocate is on high.</verse>
<verse>"My friends are my scoffers; My eye weeps to God.</verse>
<verse>"O that a man might plead with God As a man with his neighbor!</verse>
<verse>"For when a few years are past, I shall go the way of no return.</verse>
</chapter>