<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Job" book_id="18" n="19">
<verse>Then Job responded,</verse>
<verse>"How long will you torment me And crush me with words?</verse>
<verse>"These ten times you have insulted me; You are not ashamed to wrong me.</verse>
<verse>"Even if I have truly erred, My error lodges with me.</verse>
<verse>"If indeed you vaunt yourselves against me And prove my disgrace to me,</verse>
<verse>Know then that God has wronged me And has closed His net around me.</verse>
<verse>"Behold, I cry, 'Violence!' but I get no answer; I shout for help, but there is no justice.</verse>
<verse>"He has walled up my way so that I cannot pass, And He has put darkness on my paths.</verse>
<verse>"He has stripped my honor from me And removed the crown from my head.</verse>
<verse>"He breaks me down on every side, and I am gone; And He has uprooted my hope like a tree.</verse>
<verse>"He has also kindled His anger against me And considered me as His enemy.</verse>
<verse>"His troops come together, And build up their way against me And camp around my tent.</verse>
<verse>"He has removed my brothers far from me, And my acquaintances are completely estranged from me.</verse>
<verse>"My relatives have failed, And my intimate friends have forgotten me.</verse>
<verse>"Those who live in my house and my maids consider me a stranger. I am a foreigner in their sight.</verse>
<verse>"I call to my servant, but he does not answer; I have to implore him with my mouth.</verse>
<verse>"My breath is offensive to my wife, And I am loathsome to my own brothers.</verse>
<verse>"Even young children despise me; I rise up and they speak against me.</verse>
<verse>"All my associates abhor me, And those I love have turned against me.</verse>
<verse>"My bone clings to my skin and my flesh, And I have escaped only by the skin of my teeth.</verse>
<verse>"Pity me, pity me, O you my friends, For the hand of God has struck me.</verse>
<verse>"Why do you persecute me as God does, And are not satisfied with my flesh?</verse>
<verse>"Oh that my words were written! Oh that they were inscribed in a book!</verse>
<verse>"That with an iron stylus and lead They were engraved in the rock forever!</verse>
<verse>"As for me, I know that my Redeemer lives, And at the last He will take His stand on the earth.</verse>
<verse>"Even after my skin is destroyed, Yet from my flesh I shall see God;</verse>
<verse>Whom I myself shall behold, And whom my eyes will see and not another. My heart faints within me!</verse>
<verse>"If you say, 'How shall we persecute him?' And 'What pretext for a case against him can we find?'</verse>
<verse>"Then be afraid of the sword for yourselves, For wrath brings the punishment of the sword, So that you may know there is judgment."</verse>
</chapter>