<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Job" book_id="18" n="20">
<verse>Then Zophar the Naamathite answered,</verse>
<verse>"Therefore my disquieting thoughts make me respond, Even because of my inward agitation.</verse>
<verse>"I listened to the reproof which insults me, And the spirit of my understanding makes me answer.</verse>
<verse>"Do you know this from of old, From the establishment of man on earth,</verse>
<verse>That the triumphing of the wicked is short, And the joy of the godless momentary?</verse>
<verse>"Though his loftiness reaches the heavens, And his head touches the clouds,</verse>
<verse>He perishes forever like his refuse; Those who have seen him will say, 'Where is he?'</verse>
<verse>"He flies away like a dream, and they cannot find him; Even like a vision of the night he is chased away.</verse>
<verse>"The eye which saw him sees him no longer, And his place no longer beholds him.</verse>
<verse>"His sons favor the poor, And his hands give back his wealth.</verse>
<verse>"His bones are full of his youthful vigor, But it lies down with him in the dust.</verse>
<verse>"Though evil is sweet in his mouth And he hides it under his tongue,</verse>
<verse>Though he desires it and will not let it go, But holds it in his mouth,</verse>
<verse>Yet his food in his stomach is changed To the venom of cobras within him.</verse>
<verse>"He swallows riches, But will vomit them up; God will expel them from his belly.</verse>
<verse>"He sucks the poison of cobras; The viper's tongue slays him.</verse>
<verse>"He does not look at the streams, The rivers flowing with honey and curds.</verse>
<verse>"He returns what he has attained And cannot swallow it; As to the riches of his trading, He cannot even enjoy them.</verse>
<verse>"For he has oppressed and forsaken the poor; He has seized a house which he has not built.</verse>
<verse>"Because he knew no quiet within him, He does not retain anything he desires.</verse>
<verse>"Nothing remains for him to devour, Therefore his prosperity does not endure.</verse>
<verse>"In the fullness of his plenty he will be cramped; The hand of everyone who suffers will come against him.</verse>
<verse>"When he fills his belly, God will send His fierce anger on him And will rain it on him while he is eating.</verse>
<verse>"He may flee from the iron weapon, But the bronze bow will pierce him.</verse>
<verse>"It is drawn forth and comes out of his back, Even the glittering point from his gall. Terrors come upon him,</verse>
<verse>Complete darkness is held in reserve for his treasures, And unfanned fire will devour him; It will consume the survivor in his tent.</verse>
<verse>"The heavens will reveal his iniquity, And the earth will rise up against him.</verse>
<verse>"The increase of his house will depart; His possessions will flow away in the day of His anger.</verse>
<verse>"This is the wicked man's portion from God, Even the heritage decreed to him by God."</verse>
</chapter>