<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Job" book_id="18" n="22">
<verse>Then Eliphaz the Temanite responded,</verse>
<verse>"Can a vigorous man be of use to God, Or a wise man be useful to himself?</verse>
<verse>"Is there any pleasure to the Almighty if you are righteous, Or profit if you make your ways perfect?</verse>
<verse>"Is it because of your reverence that He reproves you, That He enters into judgment against you?</verse>
<verse>"Is not your wickedness great, And your iniquities without end?</verse>
<verse>"For you have taken pledges of your brothers without cause, And stripped men naked.</verse>
<verse>"To the weary you have given no water to drink, And from the hungry you have withheld bread.</verse>
<verse>"But the earth belongs to the mighty man, And the honorable man dwells in it.</verse>
<verse>"You have sent widows away empty, And the strength of the orphans has been crushed.</verse>
<verse>"Therefore snares surround you, And sudden dread terrifies you,</verse>
<verse>Or darkness, so that you cannot see, And an abundance of water covers you.</verse>
<verse>"Is not God in the height of heaven? Look also at the distant stars, how high they are!</verse>
<verse>"You say, 'What does God know? Can He judge through the thick darkness?</verse>
<verse>'Clouds are a hiding place for Him, so that He cannot see; And He walks on the vault of heaven.'</verse>
<verse>"Will you keep to the ancient path Which wicked men have trod,</verse>
<verse>Who were snatched away before their time, Whose foundations were washed away by a river?</verse>
<verse>"They said to God, 'Depart from us!' And 'What can the Almighty do to them?'</verse>
<verse>"Yet He filled their houses with good things; But the counsel of the wicked is far from me.</verse>
<verse>"The righteous see and are glad, And the innocent mock them,</verse>
<verse>Saying, 'Truly our adversaries are cut off, And their abundance the fire has consumed.'</verse>
<verse>"Yield now and be at peace with Him; Thereby good will come to you.</verse>
<verse>"Please receive instruction from His mouth And establish His words in your heart.</verse>
<verse>"If you return to the Almighty, you will be restored; If you remove unrighteousness far from your tent,</verse>
<verse>And place your gold in the dust, And the gold of Ophir among the stones of the brooks,</verse>
<verse>Then the Almighty will be your gold And choice silver to you.</verse>
<verse>"For then you will delight in the Almighty And lift up your face to God.</verse>
<verse>"You will pray to Him, and He will hear you; And you will pay your vows.</verse>
<verse>"You will also decree a thing, and it will be established for you; And light will shine on your ways.</verse>
<verse>"When you are cast down, you will speak with confidence, And the humble person He will save.</verse>
<verse>"He will deliver one who is not innocent, And he will be delivered through the cleanness of your hands."</verse>
</chapter>