<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Job" book-id="18" n="24">
<verse>"Why are times not stored up by the Almighty, And why do those who know Him not see His days?</verse>
<verse>"Some remove the landmarks; They seize and devour flocks.</verse>
<verse>"They drive away the donkeys of the orphans; They take the widow's ox for a pledge.</verse>
<verse>"They push the needy aside from the road; The poor of the land are made to hide themselves altogether.</verse>
<verse>"Behold, as wild donkeys in the wilderness They go forth seeking food in their activity, As bread for their children in the desert.</verse>
<verse>"They harvest their fodder in the field And glean the vineyard of the wicked.</verse>
<verse>"They spend the night naked, without clothing, And have no covering against the cold.</verse>
<verse>"They are wet with the mountain rains And hug the rock for want of a shelter.</verse>
<verse>"Others snatch the orphan from the breast, And against the poor they take a pledge.</verse>
<verse>"They cause the poor to go about naked without clothing, And they take away the sheaves from the hungry.</verse>
<verse>"Within the walls they produce oil; They tread wine presses but thirst.</verse>
<verse>"From the city men groan, And the souls of the wounded cry out; Yet God does not pay attention to folly.</verse>
<verse>"Others have been with those who rebel against the light; They do not want to know its ways Nor abide in its paths.</verse>
<verse>"The murderer arises at dawn; He kills the poor and the needy, And at night he is as a thief.</verse>
<verse>"The eye of the adulterer waits for the twilight, Saying, 'No eye will see me.' And he disguises his face.</verse>
<verse>"In the dark they dig into houses, They shut themselves up by day; They do not know the light.</verse>
<verse>"For the morning is the same to him as thick darkness, For he is familiar with the terrors of thick darkness.</verse>
<verse>"They are insignificant on the surface of the water; Their portion is cursed on the earth. They do not turn toward the vineyards.</verse>
<verse>"Drought and heat consume the snow waters, So does Sheol those who have sinned.</verse>
<verse>"A mother will forget him; The worm feeds sweetly till he is no longer remembered. And wickedness will be broken like a tree.</verse>
<verse>"He wrongs the barren woman And does no good for the widow.</verse>
<verse>"But He drags off the valiant by His power; He rises, but no one has assurance of life.</verse>
<verse>"He provides them with security, and they are supported; And His eyes are on their ways.</verse>
<verse>"They are exalted a little while, then they are gone; Moreover, they are brought low and like everything gathered up; Even like the heads of grain they are cut off.</verse>
<verse>"Now if it is not so, who can prove me a liar, And make my speech worthless?"</verse>
</chapter>