<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Job" book_id="18" n="27">
<verse>Then Job continued his discourse and said,</verse>
<verse>"As God lives, who has taken away my right, And the Almighty, who has embittered my soul,</verse>
<verse>For as long as life is in me, And the breath of God is in my nostrils,</verse>
<verse>My lips certainly will not speak unjustly, Nor will my tongue mutter deceit.</verse>
<verse>"Far be it from me that I should declare you right; Till I die I will not put away my integrity from me.</verse>
<verse>"I hold fast my righteousness and will not let it go. My heart does not reproach any of my days.</verse>
<verse>"May my enemy be as the wicked And my opponent as the unjust.</verse>
<verse>"For what is the hope of the godless when he is cut off, When God requires his life?</verse>
<verse>"Will God hear his cry When distress comes upon him?</verse>
<verse>"Will he take delight in the Almighty? Will he call on God at all times?</verse>
<verse>"I will instruct you in the power of God; What is with the Almighty I will not conceal.</verse>
<verse>"Behold, all of you have seen it; Why then do you act foolishly?</verse>
<verse>"This is the portion of a wicked man from God, And the inheritance which tyrants receive from the Almighty.</verse>
<verse>"Though his sons are many, they are destined for the sword; And his descendants will not be satisfied with bread.</verse>
<verse>"His survivors will be buried because of the plague, And their widows will not be able to weep.</verse>
<verse>"Though he piles up silver like dust And prepares garments as plentiful as the clay,</verse>
<verse>He may prepare it, but the just will wear it And the innocent will divide the silver.</verse>
<verse>"He has built his house like the spider's web, Or as a hut which the watchman has made.</verse>
<verse>"He lies down rich, but never again; He opens his eyes, and it is no longer.</verse>
<verse>"Terrors overtake him like a flood; A tempest steals him away in the night.</verse>
<verse>"The east wind carries him away, and he is gone, For it whirls him away from his place.</verse>
<verse>"For it will hurl at him without sparing; He will surely try to flee from its power.</verse>
<verse>"Men will clap their hands at him And will hiss him from his place.</verse>
</chapter>