<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Job" book-id="18" n="28">
<verse>"Surely there is a mine for silver And a place where they refine gold.</verse>
<verse>"Iron is taken from the dust, And copper is smelted from rock.</verse>
<verse>"Man puts an end to darkness, And to the farthest limit he searches out The rock in gloom and deep shadow.</verse>
<verse>"He sinks a shaft far from habitation, Forgotten by the foot; They hang and swing to and fro far from men.</verse>
<verse>"The earth, from it comes food, And underneath it is turned up as fire.</verse>
<verse>"Its rocks are the source of sapphires, And its dust contains gold.</verse>
<verse>"The path no bird of prey knows, Nor has the falcon's eye caught sight of it.</verse>
<verse>"The proud beasts have not trodden it, Nor has the fierce lion passed over it.</verse>
<verse>"He puts his hand on the flint; He overturns the mountains at the base.</verse>
<verse>"He hews out channels through the rocks, And his eye sees anything precious.</verse>
<verse>"He dams up the streams from flowing, And what is hidden he brings out to the light.</verse>
<verse>"But where can wisdom be found? And where is the place of understanding?</verse>
<verse>"Man does not know its value, Nor is it found in the land of the living.</verse>
<verse>"The deep says, 'It is not in me'; And the sea says, 'It is not with me.'</verse>
<verse>"Pure gold cannot be given in exchange for it, Nor can silver be weighed as its price.</verse>
<verse>"It cannot be valued in the gold of Ophir, In precious onyx, or sapphire.</verse>
<verse>"Gold or glass cannot equal it, Nor can it be exchanged for articles of fine gold.</verse>
<verse>"Coral and crystal are not to be mentioned; And the acquisition of wisdom is above that of pearls.</verse>
<verse>"The topaz of Ethiopia cannot equal it, Nor can it be valued in pure gold.</verse>
<verse>"Where then does wisdom come from? And where is the place of understanding?</verse>
<verse>"Thus it is hidden from the eyes of all living And concealed from the birds of the sky.</verse>
<verse>"Abaddon and Death say, 'With our ears we have heard a report of it.'</verse>
<verse>"God understands its way, And He knows its place.</verse>
<verse>"For He looks to the ends of the earth And sees everything under the heavens.</verse>
<verse>"When He imparted weight to the wind And meted out the waters by measure,</verse>
<verse>When He set a limit for the rain And a course for the thunderbolt,</verse>
<verse>Then He saw it and declared it; He established it and also searched it out.</verse>
<verse>"And to man He said, 'Behold, the fear of the Lord, that is wisdom; And to depart from evil is understanding.'"</verse>
</chapter>