<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Job" book-id="18" n="29">
<verse>And Job again took up his discourse and said,</verse>
<verse>"Oh that I were as in months gone by, As in the days when God watched over me;</verse>
<verse>When His lamp shone over my head, And by His light I walked through darkness;</verse>
<verse>As I was in the prime of my days, When the friendship of God was over my tent;</verse>
<verse>When the Almighty was yet with me, And my children were around me;</verse>
<verse>When my steps were bathed in butter, And the rock poured out for me streams of oil!</verse>
<verse>"When I went out to the gate of the city, When I took my seat in the square,</verse>
<verse>The young men saw me and hid themselves, And the old men arose and stood.</verse>
<verse>"The princes stopped talking And put their hands on their mouths;</verse>
<verse>The voice of the nobles was hushed, And their tongue stuck to their palate.</verse>
<verse>"For when the ear heard, it called me blessed, And when the eye saw, it gave witness of me,</verse>
<verse>Because I delivered the poor who cried for help, And the orphan who had no helper.</verse>
<verse>"The blessing of the one ready to perish came upon me, And I made the widow's heart sing for joy.</verse>
<verse>"I put on righteousness, and it clothed me; My justice was like a robe and a turban.</verse>
<verse>"I was eyes to the blind And feet to the lame.</verse>
<verse>"I was a father to the needy, And I investigated the case which I did not know.</verse>
<verse>"I broke the jaws of the wicked And snatched the prey from his teeth.</verse>
<verse>"Then I thought, 'I shall die in my nest, And I shall multiply my days as the sand.</verse>
<verse>'My root is spread out to the waters, And dew lies all night on my branch.</verse>
<verse>'My glory is ever new with me, And my bow is renewed in my hand.'</verse>
<verse>"To me they listened and waited, And kept silent for my counsel.</verse>
<verse>"After my words they did not speak again, And my speech dropped on them.</verse>
<verse>"They waited for me as for the rain, And opened their mouth as for the spring rain.</verse>
<verse>"I smiled on them when they did not believe, And the light of my face they did not cast down.</verse>
<verse>"I chose a way for them and sat as chief, And dwelt as a king among the troops, As one who comforted the mourners.</verse>
</chapter>