<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Job" book-id="18" n="3">
<verse>Afterward Job opened his mouth and cursed the day of his birth.</verse>
<verse>And Job said,</verse>
<verse>"Let the day perish on which I was to be born, And the night which said, 'A boy is conceived.'</verse>
<verse>"May that day be darkness; Let not God above care for it, Nor light shine on it.</verse>
<verse>"Let darkness and black gloom claim it; Let a cloud settle on it; Let the blackness of the day terrify it.</verse>
<verse>"As for that night, let darkness seize it; Let it not rejoice among the days of the year; Let it not come into the number of the months.</verse>
<verse>"Behold, let that night be barren; Let no joyful shout enter it.</verse>
<verse>"Let those curse it who curse the day, Who are prepared to rouse Leviathan.</verse>
<verse>"Let the stars of its twilight be darkened; Let it wait for light but have none, And let it not see the breaking dawn;</verse>
<verse>Because it did not shut the opening of my mother's womb, Or hide trouble from my eyes.</verse>
<verse>"Why did I not die at birth, Come forth from the womb and expire?</verse>
<verse>"Why did the knees receive me, And why the breasts, that I should suck?</verse>
<verse>"For now I would have lain down and been quiet; I would have slept then, I would have been at rest,</verse>
<verse>With kings and with counselors of the earth, Who rebuilt ruins for themselves;</verse>
<verse>Or with princes who had gold, Who were filling their houses with silver.</verse>
<verse>"Or like a miscarriage which is discarded, I would not be, As infants that never saw light.</verse>
<verse>"There the wicked cease from raging, And there the weary are at rest.</verse>
<verse>"The prisoners are at ease together; They do not hear the voice of the taskmaster.</verse>
<verse>"The small and the great are there, And the slave is free from his master.</verse>
<verse>"Why is light given to him who suffers, And life to the bitter of soul,</verse>
<verse>Who long for death, but there is none, And dig for it more than for hidden treasures,</verse>
<verse>Who rejoice greatly, And exult when they find the grave?</verse>
<verse>"Why is light given to a man whose way is hidden, And whom God has hedged in?</verse>
<verse>"For my groaning comes at the sight of my food, And my cries pour out like water.</verse>
<verse>"For what I fear comes upon me, And what I dread befalls me.</verse>
<verse>"I am not at ease, nor am I quiet, And I am not at rest, but turmoil comes."</verse>
</chapter>