<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Job" book-id="18" n="30">
<verse>"But now those younger than I mock me, Whose fathers I disdained to put with the dogs of my flock.</verse>
<verse>"Indeed, what good was the strength of their hands to me? Vigor had perished from them.</verse>
<verse>"From want and famine they are gaunt Who gnaw the dry ground by night in waste and desolation,</verse>
<verse>Who pluck mallow by the bushes, And whose food is the root of the broom shrub.</verse>
<verse>"They are driven from the community; They shout against them as against a thief,</verse>
<verse>So that they dwell in dreadful valleys, In holes of the earth and of the rocks.</verse>
<verse>"Among the bushes they cry out; Under the nettles they are gathered together.</verse>
<verse>"Fools, even those without a name, They were scourged from the land.</verse>
<verse>"And now I have become their taunt, I have even become a byword to them.</verse>
<verse>"They abhor me and stand aloof from me, And they do not refrain from spitting at my face.</verse>
<verse>"Because He has loosed His bowstring and afflicted me, They have cast off the bridle before me.</verse>
<verse>"On the right hand their brood arises; They thrust aside my feet and build up against me their ways of destruction.</verse>
<verse>"They break up my path, They profit from my destruction; No one restrains them.</verse>
<verse>"As through a wide breach they come, Amid the tempest they roll on.</verse>
<verse>"Terrors are turned against me; They pursue my honor as the wind, And my prosperity has passed away like a cloud.</verse>
<verse>"And now my soul is poured out within me; Days of affliction have seized me.</verse>
<verse>"At night it pierces my bones within me, And my gnawing pains take no rest.</verse>
<verse>"By a great force my garment is distorted; It binds me about as the collar of my coat.</verse>
<verse>"He has cast me into the mire, And I have become like dust and ashes.</verse>
<verse>"I cry out to You for help, but You do not answer me; I stand up, and You turn Your attention against me.</verse>
<verse>"You have become cruel to me; With the might of Your hand You persecute me.</verse>
<verse>"You lift me up to the wind and cause me to ride; And You dissolve me in a storm.</verse>
<verse>"For I know that You will bring me to death And to the house of meeting for all living.</verse>
<verse>"Yet does not one in a heap of ruins stretch out his hand, Or in his disaster therefore cry out for help?</verse>
<verse>"Have I not wept for the one whose life is hard? Was not my soul grieved for the needy?</verse>
<verse>"When I expected good, then evil came; When I waited for light, then darkness came.</verse>
<verse>"I am seething within and cannot relax; Days of affliction confront me.</verse>
<verse>"I go about mourning without comfort; I stand up in the assembly and cry out for help.</verse>
<verse>"I have become a brother to jackals And a companion of ostriches.</verse>
<verse>"My skin turns black on me, And my bones burn with fever.</verse>
<verse>"Therefore my harp is turned to mourning, And my flute to the sound of those who weep.</verse>
</chapter>