<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Job" book_id="18" n="31">
<verse>"I have made a covenant with my eyes; How then could I gaze at a virgin?</verse>
<verse>"And what is the portion of God from above Or the heritage of the Almighty from on high?</verse>
<verse>"Is it not calamity to the unjust And disaster to those who work iniquity?</verse>
<verse>"Does He not see my ways And number all my steps?</verse>
<verse>"If I have walked with falsehood, And my foot has hastened after deceit,</verse>
<verse>Let Him weigh me with accurate scales, And let God know my integrity.</verse>
<verse>"If my step has turned from the way, Or my heart followed my eyes, Or if any spot has stuck to my hands,</verse>
<verse>Let me sow and another eat, And let my crops be uprooted.</verse>
<verse>"If my heart has been enticed by a woman, Or I have lurked at my neighbor's doorway,</verse>
<verse>May my wife grind for another, And let others kneel down over her.</verse>
<verse>"For that would be a lustful crime; Moreover, it would be an iniquity punishable by judges.</verse>
<verse>"For it would be fire that consumes to Abaddon, And would uproot all my increase.</verse>
<verse>"If I have despised the claim of my male or female slaves When they filed a complaint against me,</verse>
<verse>What then could I do when God arises? And when He calls me to account, what will I answer Him?</verse>
<verse>"Did not He who made me in the womb make him, And the same one fashion us in the womb?</verse>
<verse>"If I have kept the poor from their desire, Or have caused the eyes of the widow to fail,</verse>
<verse>Or have eaten my morsel alone, And the orphan has not shared it</verse>
<verse>(But from my youth he grew up with me as with a father, And from infancy I guided her),</verse>
<verse>If I have seen anyone perish for lack of clothing, Or that the needy had no covering,</verse>
<verse>If his loins have not thanked me, And if he has not been warmed with the fleece of my sheep,</verse>
<verse>If I have lifted up my hand against the orphan, Because I saw I had support in the gate,</verse>
<verse>Let my shoulder fall from the socket, And my arm be broken off at the elbow.</verse>
<verse>"For calamity from God is a terror to me, And because of His majesty I can do nothing.</verse>
<verse>"If I have put my confidence in gold, And called fine gold my trust,</verse>
<verse>If I have gloated because my wealth was great, And because my hand had secured so much;</verse>
<verse>If I have looked at the sun when it shone Or the moon going in splendor,</verse>
<verse>And my heart became secretly enticed, And my hand threw a kiss from my mouth,</verse>
<verse>That too would have been an iniquity calling for judgment, For I would have denied God above.</verse>
<verse>"Have I rejoiced at the extinction of my enemy, Or exulted when evil befell him?</verse>
<verse>"No, I have not allowed my mouth to sin By asking for his life in a curse.</verse>
<verse>"Have the men of my tent not said, 'Who can find one who has not been satisfied with his meat'?</verse>
<verse>"The alien has not lodged outside, For I have opened my doors to the traveler.</verse>
<verse>"Have I covered my transgressions like Adam, By hiding my iniquity in my bosom,</verse>
<verse>Because I feared the great multitude, And the contempt of families terrified me, And kept silent and did not go out of doors?</verse>
<verse>"Oh that I had one to hear me! Behold, here is my signature; Let the Almighty answer me! And the indictment which my adversary has written,</verse>
<verse>Surely I would carry it on my shoulder, I would bind it to myself like a crown.</verse>
<verse>"I would declare to Him the number of my steps; Like a prince I would approach Him.</verse>
<verse>"If my land cries out against me, And its furrows weep together;</verse>
<verse>If I have eaten its fruit without money, Or have caused its owners to lose their lives,</verse>
<verse>Let briars grow instead of wheat, And stinkweed instead of barley." The words of Job are ended.</verse>
</chapter>