<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Job" book_id="18" n="33">
<verse>"However now, Job, please hear my speech, And listen to all my words.</verse>
<verse>"Behold now, I open my mouth, My tongue in my mouth speaks.</verse>
<verse>"My words are from the uprightness of my heart, And my lips speak knowledge sincerely.</verse>
<verse>"The Spirit of God has made me, And the breath of the Almighty gives me life.</verse>
<verse>"Refute me if you can; Array yourselves before me, take your stand.</verse>
<verse>"Behold, I belong to God like you; I too have been formed out of the clay.</verse>
<verse>"Behold, no fear of me should terrify you, Nor should my pressure weigh heavily on you.</verse>
<verse>"Surely you have spoken in my hearing, And I have heard the sound of your words:</verse>
<verse>'I am pure, without transgression; I am innocent and there is no guilt in me.</verse>
<verse>'Behold, He invents pretexts against me; He counts me as His enemy.</verse>
<verse>'He puts my feet in the stocks; He watches all my paths.'</verse>
<verse>"Behold, let me tell you, you are not right in this, For God is greater than man.</verse>
<verse>"Why do you complain against Him That He does not give an account of all His doings?</verse>
<verse>"Indeed God speaks once, Or twice, yet no one notices it.</verse>
<verse>"In a dream, a vision of the night, When sound sleep falls on men, While they slumber in their beds,</verse>
<verse>Then He opens the ears of men, And seals their instruction,</verse>
<verse>That He may turn man aside from his conduct, And keep man from pride;</verse>
<verse>He keeps back his soul from the pit, And his life from passing over into Sheol.</verse>
<verse>"Man is also chastened with pain on his bed, And with unceasing complaint in his bones;</verse>
<verse>So that his life loathes bread, And his soul favorite food.</verse>
<verse>"His flesh wastes away from sight, And his bones which were not seen stick out.</verse>
<verse>"Then his soul draws near to the pit, And his life to those who bring death.</verse>
<verse>"If there is an angel as mediator for him, One out of a thousand, To remind a man what is right for him,</verse>
<verse>Then let him be gracious to him, and say, 'Deliver him from going down to the pit, I have found a ransom';</verse>
<verse>Let his flesh become fresher than in youth, Let him return to the days of his youthful vigor;</verse>
<verse>Then he will pray to God, and He will accept him, That he may see His face with joy, And He may restore His righteousness to man.</verse>
<verse>"He will sing to men and say, 'I have sinned and perverted what is right, And it is not proper for me.</verse>
<verse>'He has redeemed my soul from going to the pit, And my life shall see the light.'</verse>
<verse>"Behold, God does all these oftentimes with men,</verse>
<verse>To bring back his soul from the pit, That he may be enlightened with the light of life.</verse>
<verse>"Pay attention, O Job, listen to me; Keep silent, and let me speak.</verse>
<verse>"Then if you have anything to say, answer me; Speak, for I desire to justify you.</verse>
<verse>"If not, listen to me; Keep silent, and I will teach you wisdom."</verse>
</chapter>