<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Job" book-id="18" n="34">
<verse>Then Elihu continued and said,</verse>
<verse>"Hear my words, you wise men, And listen to me, you who know.</verse>
<verse>"For the ear tests words As the palate tastes food.</verse>
<verse>"Let us choose for ourselves what is right; Let us know among ourselves what is good.</verse>
<verse>"For Job has said, 'I am righteous, But God has taken away my right;</verse>
<verse>Should I lie concerning my right? My wound is incurable, though I am without transgression.'</verse>
<verse>"What man is like Job, Who drinks up derision like water,</verse>
<verse>Who goes in company with the workers of iniquity, And walks with wicked men?</verse>
<verse>"For he has said, 'It profits a man nothing When he is pleased with God.'</verse>
<verse>"Therefore, listen to me, you men of understanding. Far be it from God to do wickedness, And from the Almighty to do wrong.</verse>
<verse>"For He pays a man according to his work, And makes him find it according to his way.</verse>
<verse>"Surely, God will not act wickedly, And the Almighty will not pervert justice.</verse>
<verse>"Who gave Him authority over the earth? And who has laid on Him the whole world?</verse>
<verse>"If He should determine to do so, If He should gather to Himself His spirit and His breath,</verse>
<verse>All flesh would perish together, And man would return to dust.</verse>
<verse>"But if you have understanding, hear this; Listen to the sound of my words.</verse>
<verse>"Shall one who hates justice rule? And will you condemn the righteous mighty One,</verse>
<verse>Who says to a king, 'Worthless one,' To nobles, 'Wicked ones';</verse>
<verse>Who shows no partiality to princes Nor regards the rich above the poor, For they all are the work of His hands?</verse>
<verse>"In a moment they die, and at midnight People are shaken and pass away, And the mighty are taken away without a hand.</verse>
<verse>"For His eyes are upon the ways of a man, And He sees all his steps.</verse>
<verse>"There is no darkness or deep shadow Where the workers of iniquity may hide themselves.</verse>
<verse>"For He does not need to consider a man further, That he should go before God in judgment.</verse>
<verse>"He breaks in pieces mighty men without inquiry, And sets others in their place.</verse>
<verse>"Therefore He knows their works, And He overthrows them in the night, And they are crushed.</verse>
<verse>"He strikes them like the wicked In a public place,</verse>
<verse>Because they turned aside from following Him, And had no regard for any of His ways;</verse>
<verse>So that they caused the cry of the poor to come to Him, And that He might hear the cry of the afflicted--</verse>
<verse>When He keeps quiet, who then can condemn? And when He hides His face, who then can behold Him, That is, in regard to both nation and man?--</verse>
<verse>So that godless men would not rule Nor be snares of the people.</verse>
<verse>"For has anyone said to God, 'I have borne chastisement; I will not offend anymore;</verse>
<verse>Teach me what I do not see; If I have done iniquity, I will not do it again'?</verse>
<verse>"Shall He recompense on your terms, because you have rejected it? For you must choose, and not I; Therefore declare what you know.</verse>
<verse>"Men of understanding will say to me, And a wise man who hears me,</verse>
<verse>'Job speaks without knowledge, And his words are without wisdom.</verse>
<verse>'Job ought to be tried to the limit, Because he answers like wicked men.</verse>
<verse>'For he adds rebellion to his sin; He claps his hands among us, And multiplies his words against God.'"</verse>
</chapter>