<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Job" book_id="18" n="37">
<verse>"At this also my heart trembles, And leaps from its place.</verse>
<verse>"Listen closely to the thunder of His voice, And the rumbling that goes out from His mouth.</verse>
<verse>"Under the whole heaven He lets it loose, And His lightning to the ends of the earth.</verse>
<verse>"After it, a voice roars; He thunders with His majestic voice, And He does not restrain the lightnings when His voice is heard.</verse>
<verse>"God thunders with His voice wondrously, Doing great things which we cannot comprehend.</verse>
<verse>"For to the snow He says, 'Fall on the earth,' And to the downpour and the rain, 'Be strong.'</verse>
<verse>"He seals the hand of every man, That all men may know His work.</verse>
<verse>"Then the beast goes into its lair And remains in its den.</verse>
<verse>"Out of the south comes the storm, And out of the north the cold.</verse>
<verse>"From the breath of God ice is made, And the expanse of the waters is frozen.</verse>
<verse>"Also with moisture He loads the thick cloud; He disperses the cloud of His lightning.</verse>
<verse>"It changes direction, turning around by His guidance, That it may do whatever He commands it On the face of the inhabited earth.</verse>
<verse>"Whether for correction, or for His world, Or for lovingkindness, He causes it to happen.</verse>
<verse>"Listen to this, O Job, Stand and consider the wonders of God.</verse>
<verse>"Do you know how God establishes them, And makes the lightning of His cloud to shine?</verse>
<verse>"Do you know about the layers of the thick clouds, The wonders of one perfect in knowledge,</verse>
<verse>You whose garments are hot, When the land is still because of the south wind?</verse>
<verse>"Can you, with Him, spread out the skies, Strong as a molten mirror?</verse>
<verse>"Teach us what we shall say to Him; We cannot arrange our case because of darkness.</verse>
<verse>"Shall it be told Him that I would speak? Or should a man say that he would be swallowed up?</verse>
<verse>"Now men do not see the light which is bright in the skies; But the wind has passed and cleared them.</verse>
<verse>"Out of the north comes golden splendor; Around God is awesome majesty.</verse>
<verse>"The Almighty--we cannot find Him; He is exalted in power And He will not do violence to justice and abundant righteousness.</verse>
<verse>"Therefore men fear Him; He does not regard any who are wise of heart."</verse>
</chapter>