<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Job" book-id="18" n="38">
<verse>Then the LORD answered Job out of the whirlwind and said,</verse>
<verse>"Who is this that darkens counsel By words without knowledge?</verse>
<verse>"Now gird up your loins like a man, And I will ask you, and you instruct Me!</verse>
<verse>"Where were you when I laid the foundation of the earth? Tell Me, if you have understanding,</verse>
<verse>Who set its measurements? Since you know. Or who stretched the line on it?</verse>
<verse>"On what were its bases sunk? Or who laid its cornerstone,</verse>
<verse>When the morning stars sang together And all the sons of God shouted for joy?</verse>
<verse>"Or who enclosed the sea with doors When, bursting forth, it went out from the womb;</verse>
<verse>When I made a cloud its garment And thick darkness its swaddling band,</verse>
<verse>And I placed boundaries on it And set a bolt and doors,</verse>
<verse>And I said, 'Thus far you shall come, but no farther; And here shall your proud waves stop'?</verse>
<verse>"Have you ever in your life commanded the morning, And caused the dawn to know its place,</verse>
<verse>That it might take hold of the ends of the earth, And the wicked be shaken out of it?</verse>
<verse>"It is changed like clay under the seal; And they stand forth like a garment.</verse>
<verse>"From the wicked their light is withheld, And the uplifted arm is broken.</verse>
<verse>"Have you entered into the springs of the sea Or walked in the recesses of the deep?</verse>
<verse>"Have the gates of death been revealed to you, Or have you seen the gates of deep darkness?</verse>
<verse>"Have you understood the expanse of the earth? Tell Me, if you know all this.</verse>
<verse>"Where is the way to the dwelling of light? And darkness, where is its place,</verse>
<verse>That you may take it to its territory And that you may discern the paths to its home?</verse>
<verse>"You know, for you were born then, And the number of your days is great!</verse>
<verse>"Have you entered the storehouses of the snow, Or have you seen the storehouses of the hail,</verse>
<verse>Which I have reserved for the time of distress, For the day of war and battle?</verse>
<verse>"Where is the way that the light is divided, Or the east wind scattered on the earth?</verse>
<verse>"Who has cleft a channel for the flood, Or a way for the thunderbolt,</verse>
<verse>To bring rain on a land without people, On a desert without a man in it,</verse>
<verse>To satisfy the waste and desolate land And to make the seeds of grass to sprout?</verse>
<verse>"Has the rain a father? Or who has begotten the drops of dew?</verse>
<verse>"From whose womb has come the ice? And the frost of heaven, who has given it birth?</verse>
<verse>"Water becomes hard like stone, And the surface of the deep is imprisoned.</verse>
<verse>"Can you bind the chains of the Pleiades, Or loose the cords of Orion?</verse>
<verse>"Can you lead forth a constellation in its season, And guide the Bear with her satellites?</verse>
<verse>"Do you know the ordinances of the heavens, Or fix their rule over the earth?</verse>
<verse>"Can you lift up your voice to the clouds, So that an abundance of water will cover you?</verse>
<verse>"Can you send forth lightnings that they may go And say to you, 'Here we are'?</verse>
<verse>"Who has put wisdom in the innermost being Or given understanding to the mind?</verse>
<verse>"Who can count the clouds by wisdom, Or tip the water jars of the heavens,</verse>
<verse>When the dust hardens into a mass And the clods stick together?</verse>
<verse>"Can you hunt the prey for the lion, Or satisfy the appetite of the young lions,</verse>
<verse>When they crouch in their dens And lie in wait in their lair?</verse>
<verse>"Who prepares for the raven its nourishment When its young cry to God And wander about without food?</verse>
</chapter>