<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Job" book-id="18" n="39">
<verse>"Do you know the time the mountain goats give birth? Do you observe the calving of the deer?</verse>
<verse>"Can you count the months they fulfill, Or do you know the time they give birth?</verse>
<verse>"They kneel down, they bring forth their young, They get rid of their labor pains.</verse>
<verse>"Their offspring become strong, they grow up in the open field; They leave and do not return to them.</verse>
<verse>"Who sent out the wild donkey free? And who loosed the bonds of the swift donkey,</verse>
<verse>To whom I gave the wilderness for a home And the salt land for his dwelling place?</verse>
<verse>"He scorns the tumult of the city, The shoutings of the driver he does not hear.</verse>
<verse>"He explores the mountains for his pasture And searches after every green thing.</verse>
<verse>"Will the wild ox consent to serve you, Or will he spend the night at your manger?</verse>
<verse>"Can you bind the wild ox in a furrow with ropes, Or will he harrow the valleys after you?</verse>
<verse>"Will you trust him because his strength is great And leave your labor to him?</verse>
<verse>"Will you have faith in him that he will return your grain And gather it from your threshing floor?</verse>
<verse>"The ostriches' wings flap joyously With the pinion and plumage of love,</verse>
<verse>For she abandons her eggs to the earth And warms them in the dust,</verse>
<verse>And she forgets that a foot may crush them, Or that a wild beast may trample them.</verse>
<verse>"She treats her young cruelly, as if they were not hers; Though her labor be in vain, she is unconcerned;</verse>
<verse>Because God has made her forget wisdom, And has not given her a share of understanding.</verse>
<verse>"When she lifts herself on high, She laughs at the horse and his rider.</verse>
<verse>"Do you give the horse his might? Do you clothe his neck with a mane?</verse>
<verse>"Do you make him leap like the locust? His majestic snorting is terrible.</verse>
<verse>"He paws in the valley, and rejoices in his strength; He goes out to meet the weapons.</verse>
<verse>"He laughs at fear and is not dismayed; And he does not turn back from the sword.</verse>
<verse>"The quiver rattles against him, The flashing spear and javelin.</verse>
<verse>"With shaking and rage he races over the ground, And he does not stand still at the voice of the trumpet.</verse>
<verse>"As often as the trumpet sounds he says, 'Aha!' And he scents the battle from afar, And the thunder of the captains and the war cry.</verse>
<verse>"Is it by your understanding that the hawk soars, Stretching his wings toward the south?</verse>
<verse>"Is it at your command that the eagle mounts up And makes his nest on high?</verse>
<verse>"On the cliff he dwells and lodges, Upon the rocky crag, an inaccessible place.</verse>
<verse>"From there he spies out food; His eyes see it from afar.</verse>
<verse>"His young ones also suck up blood; And where the slain are, there is he."</verse>
</chapter>