<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Job" book_id="18" n="4">
<verse>Then Eliphaz the Temanite answered,</verse>
<verse>"If one ventures a word with you, will you become impatient? But who can refrain from speaking?</verse>
<verse>"Behold you have admonished many, And you have strengthened weak hands.</verse>
<verse>"Your words have helped the tottering to stand, And you have strengthened feeble knees.</verse>
<verse>"But now it has come to you, and you are impatient; It touches you, and you are dismayed.</verse>
<verse>"Is not your fear of God your confidence, And the integrity of your ways your hope?</verse>
<verse>"Remember now, who ever perished being innocent? Or where were the upright destroyed?</verse>
<verse>"According to what I have seen, those who plow iniquity And those who sow trouble harvest it.</verse>
<verse>"By the breath of God they perish, And by the blast of His anger they come to an end.</verse>
<verse>"The roaring of the lion and the voice of the fierce lion, And the teeth of the young lions are broken.</verse>
<verse>"The lion perishes for lack of prey, And the whelps of the lioness are scattered.</verse>
<verse>"Now a word was brought to me stealthily, And my ear received a whisper of it.</verse>
<verse>"Amid disquieting thoughts from the visions of the night, When deep sleep falls on men,</verse>
<verse>Dread came upon me, and trembling, And made all my bones shake.</verse>
<verse>"Then a spirit passed by my face; The hair of my flesh bristled up.</verse>
<verse>"It stood still, but I could not discern its appearance; A form was before my eyes; There was silence, then I heard a voice:</verse>
<verse>'Can mankind be just before God? Can a man be pure before his Maker?</verse>
<verse>'He puts no trust even in His servants; And against His angels He charges error.</verse>
<verse>'How much more those who dwell in houses of clay, Whose foundation is in the dust, Who are crushed before the moth!</verse>
<verse>'Between morning and evening they are broken in pieces; Unobserved, they perish forever.</verse>
<verse>'Is not their tent-cord plucked up within them? They die, yet without wisdom.'</verse>
</chapter>