<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Job" book_id="18" n="40">
<verse>Then the LORD said to Job,</verse>
<verse>"Will the faultfinder contend with the Almighty? Let him who reproves God answer it."</verse>
<verse>Then Job answered the LORD and said,</verse>
<verse>"Behold, I am insignificant; what can I reply to You? I lay my hand on my mouth.</verse>
<verse>"Once I have spoken, and I will not answer; Even twice, and I will add nothing more."</verse>
<verse>Then the LORD answered Job out of the storm and said,</verse>
<verse>"Now gird up your loins like a man; I will ask you, and you instruct Me.</verse>
<verse>"Will you really annul My judgment? Will you condemn Me that you may be justified?</verse>
<verse>"Or do you have an arm like God, And can you thunder with a voice like His?</verse>
<verse>"Adorn yourself with eminence and dignity, And clothe yourself with honor and majesty.</verse>
<verse>"Pour out the overflowings of your anger, And look on everyone who is proud, and make him low.</verse>
<verse>"Look on everyone who is proud, and humble him, And tread down the wicked where they stand.</verse>
<verse>"Hide them in the dust together; Bind them in the hidden place.</verse>
<verse>"Then I will also confess to you, That your own right hand can save you.</verse>
<verse>"Behold now, Behemoth, which I made as well as you; He eats grass like an ox.</verse>
<verse>"Behold now, his strength in his loins And his power in the muscles of his belly.</verse>
<verse>"He bends his tail like a cedar; The sinews of his thighs are knit together.</verse>
<verse>"His bones are tubes of bronze; His limbs are like bars of iron.</verse>
<verse>"He is the first of the ways of God; Let his maker bring near his sword.</verse>
<verse>"Surely the mountains bring him food, And all the beasts of the field play there.</verse>
<verse>"Under the lotus plants he lies down, In the covert of the reeds and the marsh.</verse>
<verse>"The lotus plants cover him with shade; The willows of the brook surround him.</verse>
<verse>"If a river rages, he is not alarmed; He is confident, though the Jordan rushes to his mouth.</verse>
<verse>"Can anyone capture him when he is on watch, With barbs can anyone pierce his nose?</verse>
</chapter>