<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Job" book-id="18" n="41">
<verse>"Can you draw out Leviathan with a fishhook? Or press down his tongue with a cord?</verse>
<verse>"Can you put a rope in his nose Or pierce his jaw with a hook?</verse>
<verse>"Will he make many supplications to you, Or will he speak to you soft words?</verse>
<verse>"Will he make a covenant with you? Will you take him for a servant forever?</verse>
<verse>"Will you play with him as with a bird, Or will you bind him for your maidens?</verse>
<verse>"Will the traders bargain over him? Will they divide him among the merchants?</verse>
<verse>"Can you fill his skin with harpoons, Or his head with fishing spears?</verse>
<verse>"Lay your hand on him; Remember the battle; you will not do it again!</verse>
<verse>"Behold, your expectation is false; Will you be laid low even at the sight of him?</verse>
<verse>"No one is so fierce that he dares to arouse him; Who then is he that can stand before Me?</verse>
<verse>"Who has given to Me that I should repay him? Whatever is under the whole heaven is Mine.</verse>
<verse>"I will not keep silence concerning his limbs, Or his mighty strength, or his orderly frame.</verse>
<verse>"Who can strip off his outer armor? Who can come within his double mail?</verse>
<verse>"Who can open the doors of his face? Around his teeth there is terror.</verse>
<verse>"His strong scales are his pride, Shut up as with a tight seal.</verse>
<verse>"One is so near to another That no air can come between them.</verse>
<verse>"They are joined one to another; They clasp each other and cannot be separated.</verse>
<verse>"His sneezes flash forth light, And his eyes are like the eyelids of the morning.</verse>
<verse>"Out of his mouth go burning torches; Sparks of fire leap forth.</verse>
<verse>"Out of his nostrils smoke goes forth As from a boiling pot and burning rushes.</verse>
<verse>"His breath kindles coals, And a flame goes forth from his mouth.</verse>
<verse>"In his neck lodges strength, And dismay leaps before him.</verse>
<verse>"The folds of his flesh are joined together, Firm on him and immovable.</verse>
<verse>"His heart is as hard as a stone, Even as hard as a lower millstone.</verse>
<verse>"When he raises himself up, the mighty fear; Because of the crashing they are bewildered.</verse>
<verse>"The sword that reaches him cannot avail, Nor the spear, the dart or the javelin.</verse>
<verse>"He regards iron as straw, Bronze as rotten wood.</verse>
<verse>"The arrow cannot make him flee; Slingstones are turned into stubble for him.</verse>
<verse>"Clubs are regarded as stubble; He laughs at the rattling of the javelin.</verse>
<verse>"His underparts are like sharp potsherds; He spreads out like a threshing sledge on the mire.</verse>
<verse>"He makes the depths boil like a pot; He makes the sea like a jar of ointment.</verse>
<verse>"Behind him he makes a wake to shine; One would think the deep to be gray-haired.</verse>
<verse>"Nothing on earth is like him, One made without fear.</verse>
<verse>"He looks on everything that is high; He is king over all the sons of pride."</verse>
</chapter>