<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Job" book-id="18" n="5">
<verse>"Call now, is there anyone who will answer you? And to which of the holy ones will you turn?</verse>
<verse>"For anger slays the foolish man, And jealousy kills the simple.</verse>
<verse>"I have seen the foolish taking root, And I cursed his abode immediately.</verse>
<verse>"His sons are far from safety, They are even oppressed in the gate, And there is no deliverer.</verse>
<verse>"His harvest the hungry devour And take it to a place of thorns, And the schemer is eager for their wealth.</verse>
<verse>"For affliction does not come from the dust, Nor does trouble sprout from the ground,</verse>
<verse>For man is born for trouble, As sparks fly upward.</verse>
<verse>"But as for me, I would seek God, And I would place my cause before God;</verse>
<verse>Who does great and unsearchable things, Wonders without number.</verse>
<verse>"He gives rain on the earth And sends water on the fields,</verse>
<verse>So that He sets on high those who are lowly, And those who mourn are lifted to safety.</verse>
<verse>"He frustrates the plotting of the shrewd, So that their hands cannot attain success.</verse>
<verse>"He captures the wise by their own shrewdness, And the advice of the cunning is quickly thwarted.</verse>
<verse>"By day they meet with darkness, And grope at noon as in the night.</verse>
<verse>"But He saves from the sword of their mouth, And the poor from the hand of the mighty.</verse>
<verse>"So the helpless has hope, And unrighteousness must shut its mouth.</verse>
<verse>"Behold, how happy is the man whom God reproves, So do not despise the discipline of the Almighty.</verse>
<verse>"For He inflicts pain, and gives relief; He wounds, and His hands also heal.</verse>
<verse>"From six troubles He will deliver you, Even in seven evil will not touch you.</verse>
<verse>"In famine He will redeem you from death, And in war from the power of the sword.</verse>
<verse>"You will be hidden from the scourge of the tongue, And you will not be afraid of violence when it comes.</verse>
<verse>"You will laugh at violence and famine, And you will not be afraid of wild beasts.</verse>
<verse>"For you will be in league with the stones of the field, And the beasts of the field will be at peace with you.</verse>
<verse>"You will know that your tent is secure, For you will visit your abode and fear no loss.</verse>
<verse>"You will know also that your descendants will be many, And your offspring as the grass of the earth.</verse>
<verse>"You will come to the grave in full vigor, Like the stacking of grain in its season.</verse>
<verse>"Behold this; we have investigated it, and so it is. Hear it, and know for yourself."</verse>
</chapter>