<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Job" book-id="18" n="6">
<verse>Then Job answered,</verse>
<verse>"Oh that my grief were actually weighed And laid in the balances together with my calamity!</verse>
<verse>"For then it would be heavier than the sand of the seas; Therefore my words have been rash.</verse>
<verse>"For the arrows of the Almighty are within me, Their poison my spirit drinks; The terrors of God are arrayed against me.</verse>
<verse>"Does the wild donkey bray over his grass, Or does the ox low over his fodder?</verse>
<verse>"Can something tasteless be eaten without salt, Or is there any taste in the white of an egg?</verse>
<verse>"My soul refuses to touch them; They are like loathsome food to me.</verse>
<verse>"Oh that my request might come to pass, And that God would grant my longing!</verse>
<verse>"Would that God were willing to crush me, That He would loose His hand and cut me off!</verse>
<verse>"But it is still my consolation, And I rejoice in unsparing pain, That I have not denied the words of the Holy One.</verse>
<verse>"What is my strength, that I should wait? And what is my end, that I should endure?</verse>
<verse>"Is my strength the strength of stones, Or is my flesh bronze?</verse>
<verse>"Is it that my help is not within me, And that deliverance is driven from me?</verse>
<verse>"For the despairing man there should be kindness from his friend; So that he does not forsake the fear of the Almighty.</verse>
<verse>"My brothers have acted deceitfully like a wadi, Like the torrents of wadis which vanish,</verse>
<verse>Which are turbid because of ice And into which the snow melts.</verse>
<verse>"When they become waterless, they are silent, When it is hot, they vanish from their place.</verse>
<verse>"The paths of their course wind along, They go up into nothing and perish.</verse>
<verse>"The caravans of Tema looked, The travelers of Sheba hoped for them.</verse>
<verse>"They were disappointed for they had trusted, They came there and were confounded.</verse>
<verse>"Indeed, you have now become such, You see a terror and are afraid.</verse>
<verse>"Have I said, 'Give me something,' Or, 'Offer a bribe for me from your wealth,'</verse>
<verse>Or, 'Deliver me from the hand of the adversary,' Or, 'Redeem me from the hand of the tyrants'?</verse>
<verse>"Teach me, and I will be silent; And show me how I have erred.</verse>
<verse>"How painful are honest words! But what does your argument prove?</verse>
<verse>"Do you intend to reprove my words, When the words of one in despair belong to the wind?</verse>
<verse>"You would even cast lots for the orphans And barter over your friend.</verse>
<verse>"Now please look at me, And see if I lie to your face.</verse>
<verse>"Desist now, let there be no injustice; Even desist, my righteousness is yet in it.</verse>
<verse>"Is there injustice on my tongue? Cannot my palate discern calamities?</verse>
</chapter>