<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Job" book_id="18" n="7">
<verse>"Is not man forced to labor on earth, And are not his days like the days of a hired man?</verse>
<verse>"As a slave who pants for the shade, And as a hired man who eagerly waits for his wages,</verse>
<verse>So am I allotted months of vanity, And nights of trouble are appointed me.</verse>
<verse>"When I lie down I say, 'When shall I arise?' But the night continues, And I am continually tossing until dawn.</verse>
<verse>"My flesh is clothed with worms and a crust of dirt, My skin hardens and runs.</verse>
<verse>"My days are swifter than a weaver's shuttle, And come to an end without hope.</verse>
<verse>"Remember that my life is but breath; My eye will not again see good.</verse>
<verse>"The eye of him who sees me will behold me no longer; Your eyes will be on me, but I will not be.</verse>
<verse>"When a cloud vanishes, it is gone, So he who goes down to Sheol does not come up.</verse>
<verse>"He will not return again to his house, Nor will his place know him anymore.</verse>
<verse>"Therefore I will not restrain my mouth; I will speak in the anguish of my spirit, I will complain in the bitterness of my soul.</verse>
<verse>"Am I the sea, or the sea monster, That You set a guard over me?</verse>
<verse>"If I say, 'My bed will comfort me, My couch will ease my complaint,'</verse>
<verse>Then You frighten me with dreams And terrify me by visions;</verse>
<verse>So that my soul would choose suffocation, Death rather than my pains.</verse>
<verse>"I waste away; I will not live forever. Leave me alone, for my days are but a breath.</verse>
<verse>"What is man that You magnify him, And that You are concerned about him,</verse>
<verse>That You examine him every morning And try him every moment?</verse>
<verse>"Will You never turn Your gaze away from me, Nor let me alone until I swallow my spittle?</verse>
<verse>"Have I sinned? What have I done to You, O watcher of men? Why have You set me as Your target, So that I am a burden to myself?</verse>
<verse>"Why then do You not pardon my transgression And take away my iniquity? For now I will lie down in the dust; And You will seek me, but I will not be."</verse>
</chapter>