<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Job" book_id="18" n="8">
<verse>Then Bildad the Shuhite answered,</verse>
<verse>"How long will you say these things, And the words of your mouth be a mighty wind?</verse>
<verse>"Does God pervert justice? Or does the Almighty pervert what is right?</verse>
<verse>"If your sons sinned against Him, Then He delivered them into the power of their transgression.</verse>
<verse>"If you would seek God And implore the compassion of the Almighty,</verse>
<verse>If you are pure and upright, Surely now He would rouse Himself for you And restore your righteous estate.</verse>
<verse>"Though your beginning was insignificant, Yet your end will increase greatly.</verse>
<verse>"Please inquire of past generations, And consider the things searched out by their fathers.</verse>
<verse>"For we are only of yesterday and know nothing, Because our days on earth are as a shadow.</verse>
<verse>"Will they not teach you and tell you, And bring forth words from their minds?</verse>
<verse>"Can the papyrus grow up without a marsh? Can the rushes grow without water?</verse>
<verse>"While it is still green and not cut down, Yet it withers before any other plant.</verse>
<verse>"So are the paths of all who forget God; And the hope of the godless will perish,</verse>
<verse>Whose confidence is fragile, And whose trust a spider's web.</verse>
<verse>"He trusts in his house, but it does not stand; He holds fast to it, but it does not endure.</verse>
<verse>"He thrives before the sun, And his shoots spread out over his garden.</verse>
<verse>"His roots wrap around a rock pile, He grasps a house of stones.</verse>
<verse>"If he is removed from his place, Then it will deny him, saying, 'I never saw you.'</verse>
<verse>"Behold, this is the joy of His way; And out of the dust others will spring.</verse>
<verse>"Lo, God will not reject a man of integrity, Nor will He support the evildoers.</verse>
<verse>"He will yet fill your mouth with laughter And your lips with shouting.</verse>
<verse>"Those who hate you will be clothed with shame, And the tent of the wicked will be no longer."</verse>
</chapter>