<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Job" book-id="18" n="9">
<verse>Then Job answered,</verse>
<verse>"In truth I know that this is so; But how can a man be in the right before God?</verse>
<verse>"If one wished to dispute with Him, He could not answer Him once in a thousand times.</verse>
<verse>"Wise in heart and mighty in strength, Who has defied Him without harm?</verse>
<verse>"It is God who removes the mountains, they know not how, When He overturns them in His anger;</verse>
<verse>Who shakes the earth out of its place, And its pillars tremble;</verse>
<verse>Who commands the sun not to shine, And sets a seal upon the stars;</verse>
<verse>Who alone stretches out the heavens And tramples down the waves of the sea;</verse>
<verse>Who makes the Bear, Orion and the Pleiades, And the chambers of the south;</verse>
<verse>Who does great things, unfathomable, And wondrous works without number.</verse>
<verse>"Were He to pass by me, I would not see Him; Were He to move past me, I would not perceive Him.</verse>
<verse>"Were He to snatch away, who could restrain Him? Who could say to Him, 'What are You doing?'</verse>
<verse>"God will not turn back His anger; Beneath Him crouch the helpers of Rahab.</verse>
<verse>"How then can I answer Him, And choose my words before Him?</verse>
<verse>"For though I were right, I could not answer; I would have to implore the mercy of my judge.</verse>
<verse>"If I called and He answered me, I could not believe that He was listening to my voice.</verse>
<verse>"For He bruises me with a tempest And multiplies my wounds without cause.</verse>
<verse>"He will not allow me to get my breath, But saturates me with bitterness.</verse>
<verse>"If it is a matter of power, behold, He is the strong one! And if it is a matter of justice, who can summon Him?</verse>
<verse>"Though I am righteous, my mouth will condemn me; Though I am guiltless, He will declare me guilty.</verse>
<verse>"I am guiltless; I do not take notice of myself; I despise my life.</verse>
<verse>"It is all one; therefore I say, 'He destroys the guiltless and the wicked.'</verse>
<verse>"If the scourge kills suddenly, He mocks the despair of the innocent.</verse>
<verse>"The earth is given into the hand of the wicked; He covers the faces of its judges. If it is not He, then who is it?</verse>
<verse>"Now my days are swifter than a runner; They flee away, they see no good.</verse>
<verse>"They slip by like reed boats, Like an eagle that swoops on its prey.</verse>
<verse>"Though I say, 'I will forget my complaint, I will leave off my sad countenance and be cheerful,'</verse>
<verse>I am afraid of all my pains, I know that You will not acquit me.</verse>
<verse>"I am accounted wicked, Why then should I toil in vain?</verse>
<verse>"If I should wash myself with snow And cleanse my hands with lye,</verse>
<verse>Yet You would plunge me into the pit, And my own clothes would abhor me.</verse>
<verse>"For He is not a man as I am that I may answer Him, That we may go to court together.</verse>
<verse>"There is no umpire between us, Who may lay his hand upon us both.</verse>
<verse>"Let Him remove His rod from me, And let not dread of Him terrify me.</verse>
<verse>"Then I would speak and not fear Him; But I am not like that in myself.</verse>
</chapter>