<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Lamentations" book_id="25" n="3">
<verse>I'm the man who has seen trouble, trouble coming from the lash of GOD's anger.</verse>
<verse>He took me by the hand and walked me into pitch-black darkness.</verse>
<verse>Yes, he's given me the back of his hand over and over and over again.</verse>
<verse>He turned me into a scarecrow of skin and bones, then broke the bones.</verse>
<verse>He hemmed me in, ganged up on me, poured on the trouble and hard times.</verse>
<verse>He locked me up in deep darkness, like a corpse nailed inside a coffin.</verse>
<verse>He shuts me in so I'll never get out, manacles my hands, shackles my feet.</verse>
<verse>Even when I cry out and plead for help, he locks up my prayers and throws away the key.</verse>
<verse>He sets up blockades with quarried limestone. He's got me cornered.</verse>
<verse>He's a prowling bear tracking me down, a lion in hiding ready to pounce.</verse>
<verse>He knocked me from the path and ripped me to pieces. When he finished, there was nothing left of me.</verse>
<verse>He took out his bow and arrows and used me for target practice.</verse>
<verse>He shot me in the stomach with arrows from his quiver.</verse>
<verse>Everyone took me for a joke, made me the butt of their mocking ballads.</verse>
<verse>He forced rotten, stinking food down my throat, bloated me with vile drinks.</verse>
<verse>He ground my face into the gravel. He pounded me into the mud.</verse>
<verse>I gave up on life altogether. I've forgotten what the good life is like.</verse>
<verse>I said to myself, "This is it. I'm finished. GOD is a lost cause."</verse>
<verse>I'll never forget the trouble, the utter lostness, the taste of ashes, the poison I've swallowed.</verse>
<verse>I remember it all--oh, how well I remember--the feeling of hitting the bottom.</verse>
<verse>But there's one other thing I remember, and remembering, I keep a grip on hope:</verse>
<verse>GOD's loyal love couldn't have run out, his merciful love couldn't have dried up.</verse>
<verse>They're created new every morning. How great your faithfulness!</verse>
<verse>I'm sticking with GOD (I say it over and over). He's all I've got left.</verse>
<verse>GOD proves to be good to the man who passionately waits, to the woman who diligently seeks.</verse>
<verse>It's a good thing to quietly hope, quietly hope for help from GOD.</verse>
<verse>It's a good thing when you're young to stick it out through the hard times.</verse>
<verse>When life is heavy and hard to take, go off by yourself. Enter the silence.</verse>
<verse>Bow in prayer. Don't ask questions: Wait for hope to appear.</verse>
<verse>Don't run from trouble. Take it full-face. The "worst" is never the worst.</verse>
<verse>Why? Because the Master won't ever walk out and fail to return.</verse>
<verse>If he works severely, he also works tenderly. His stockpiles of loyal love are immense.</verse>
<verse>He takes no pleasure in making life hard, in throwing roadblocks in the way:</verse>
<verse>Stomping down hard on luckless prisoners,</verse>
<verse>Refusing justice to victims in the court of High God,</verse>
<verse>Tampering with evidence--the Master does not approve of such things.</verse>
<verse>Who do you think "spoke and it happened"? It's the Master who gives such orders.</verse>
<verse>Doesn't the High God speak everything, good things and hard things alike, into being?</verse>
<verse>And why would anyone gifted with life complain when punished for sin?</verse>
<verse>Let's take a good look at the way we're living and reorder our lives under GOD.</verse>
<verse>Let's lift our hearts and hands at one and the same time, praying to God in heaven:</verse>
<verse>"We've been contrary and willful, and you haven't forgiven.</verse>
<verse>"You lost your temper with us, holding nothing back. You chased us and cut us down without mercy.</verse>
<verse>You wrapped yourself in thick blankets of clouds so no prayers could get through.</verse>
<verse>You treated us like dirty dishwater, threw us out in the backyard of the nations.</verse>
<verse>"Our enemies shout abuse, their mouths full of derision, spitting invective.</verse>
<verse>We've been to hell and back. We've nowhere to turn, nowhere to go.</verse>
<verse>Rivers of tears pour from my eyes at the smashup of my dear people.</verse>
<verse>"The tears stream from my eyes, an artesian well of tears,</verse>
<verse>Until you, GOD, look down from on high, look and see my tears.</verse>
<verse>When I see what's happened to the young women in the city, the pain breaks my heart.</verse>
<verse>"Enemies with no reason to be enemies hunted me down like a bird.</verse>
<verse>They threw me into a pit, then pelted me with stones.</verse>
<verse>Then the rains came and filled the pit. The water rose over my head. I said, "It's all over.'</verse>
<verse>"I called out your name, O GOD, called from the bottom of the pit.</verse>
<verse>You listened when I called out, "Don't shut your ears! Get me out of here! Save me!'</verse>
<verse>You came close when I called out. You said, "It's going to be all right.'</verse>
<verse>"You took my side, Master; you brought me back alive!</verse>
<verse>GOD, you saw the wrongs heaped on me. Give me my day in court!</verse>
<verse>Yes, you saw their mean-minded schemes, their plots to destroy me.</verse>
<verse>"You heard, GOD, their vicious gossip, their behind-my-back plots to ruin me.</verse>
<verse>They never quit, these enemies of mine, dreaming up mischief, hatching out malice, day after day after day.</verse>
<verse>Sitting down or standing up--just look at them!- they mock me with vulgar doggerel.</verse>
<verse>"Make them pay for what they've done, GOD. Give them their just deserts.</verse>
<verse>Break their miserable hearts! Damn their eyes!</verse>
<verse>Get good and angry. Hunt them down. Make a total demolition here under your heaven!"</verse>
</chapter>