<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Lamentations" book_id="25" n="5">
<verse>"Remember, GOD, all we've been through. Study our plight, the black mark we've made in history.</verse>
<verse>Our precious land has been given to outsiders, our homes to strangers.</verse>
<verse>Orphans we are, not a father in sight, and our mothers no better than widows.</verse>
<verse>We have to pay to drink our own water. Even our firewood comes at a price.</verse>
<verse>We're nothing but slaves, bullied and bowed, worn out and without any rest.</verse>
<verse>We sold ourselves to Assyria and Egypt just to get something to eat.</verse>
<verse>Our parents sinned and are no more, and now we're paying for the wrongs they did.</verse>
<verse>Slaves rule over us; there's no escape from their grip.</verse>
<verse>We risk our lives to gather food in the bandit-infested desert.</verse>
<verse>Our skin has turned black as an oven, dried out like old leather from the famine.</verse>
<verse>Our wives were raped in the streets in Zion, and our virgins in the cities of Judah.</verse>
<verse>They hanged our princes by their hands, dishonored our elders.</verse>
<verse>Strapping young men were put to women's work, mere boys forced to do men's work.</verse>
<verse>The city gate is empty of wise elders. Music from the young is heard no more.</verse>
<verse>All the joy is gone from our hearts. Our dances have turned into dirges.</verse>
<verse>The crown of glory has toppled from our head. Woe! Woe! Would that we'd never sinned!</verse>
<verse>Because of all this we're heartsick; we can't see through the tears.</verse>
<verse>On Mount Zion, wrecked and ruined, jackals pace and prowl.</verse>
<verse>And yet, GOD, you're sovereign still, your throne intact and eternal.</verse>
<verse>So why do you keep forgetting us? Why dump us and leave us like this?</verse>
<verse>Bring us back to you, GOD-we're ready to come back. Give us a fresh start.</verse>
<verse>As it is, you've cruelly disowned us. You've been so very angry with us."</verse>
</chapter>