<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Numbers" book-id="4" n="23">
<verse>Balaam said, "Build me seven altars here, and prepare seven bulls and seven rams for me."</verse>
<verse>Balak did as Balaam said, and the two of them offered a bull and a ram on each altar.</verse>
<verse>Then Balaam said to Balak, "Stay here beside your offering while I go aside. Perhaps the LORD will come to meet with me. Whatever he reveals to me I will tell you." Then he went off to a barren height.</verse>
<verse>God met with him, and Balaam said, "I have prepared seven altars, and on each altar I have offered a bull and a ram."</verse>
<verse>The LORD put a message in Balaam's mouth and said, "Go back to Balak and give him this message."</verse>
<verse>So he went back to him and found him standing beside his offering, with all the princes of Moab.</verse>
<verse>Then Balaam uttered his oracle: "Balak brought me from Aram, the king of Moab from the eastern mountains. 'Come,' he said, 'curse Jacob for me; come, denounce Israel.'</verse>
<verse>How can I curse those whom God has not cursed? How can I denounce those whom the LORD has not denounced?</verse>
<verse>From the rocky peaks I see them, from the heights I view them. I see a people who live apart and do not consider themselves one of the nations.</verse>
<verse>Who can count the dust of Jacob or number the fourth part of Israel? Let me die the death of the righteous, and may my end be like theirs!"</verse>
<verse>Balak said to Balaam, "What have you done to me? I brought you to curse my enemies, but you have done nothing but bless them!"</verse>
<verse>He answered, "Must I not speak what the LORD puts in my mouth?"</verse>
<verse>Then Balak said to him, "Come with me to another place where you can see them; you will see only a part but not all of them. And from there, curse them for me."</verse>
<verse>So he took him to the field of Zophim on the top of Pisgah, and there he built seven altars and offered a bull and a ram on each altar.</verse>
<verse>Balaam said to Balak, "Stay here beside your offering while I meet with him over there."</verse>
<verse>The LORD met with Balaam and put a message in his mouth and said, "Go back to Balak and give him this message."</verse>
<verse>So he went to him and found him standing beside his offering, with the princes of Moab. Balak asked him, "What did the LORD say?"</verse>
<verse>Then he uttered his oracle: "Arise, Balak, and listen; hear me, son of Zippor.</verse>
<verse>God is not a man, that he should lie, nor a son of man, that he should change his mind. Does he speak and then not act? Does he promise and not fulfill?</verse>
<verse>I have received a command to bless; he has blessed, and I cannot change it.</verse>
<verse>"No misfortune is seen in Jacob, no misery observed in Israel. The LORD their God is with them; the shout of the King is among them.</verse>
<verse>God brought them out of Egypt; they have the strength of a wild ox.</verse>
<verse>There is no sorcery against Jacob, no divination against Israel. It will now be said of Jacob and of Israel, 'See what God has done!'</verse>
<verse>The people rise like a lioness; they rouse themselves like a lion that does not rest till he devours his prey and drinks the blood of his victims."</verse>
<verse>Then Balak said to Balaam, "Neither curse them at all nor bless them at all!"</verse>
<verse>Balaam answered, "Did I not tell you I must do whatever the LORD says?"</verse>
<verse>Then Balak said to Balaam, "Come, let me take you to another place. Perhaps it will please God to let you curse them for me from there."</verse>
<verse>And Balak took Balaam to the top of Peor, overlooking the wasteland.</verse>
<verse>Balaam said, "Build me seven altars here, and prepare seven bulls and seven rams for me."</verse>
<verse>Balak did as Balaam had said, and offered a bull and a ram on each altar.</verse>
</chapter>