<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Numbers" book_id="4" n="29">
<verse>"'On the first day of the seventh month hold a sacred assembly and do no regular work. It is a day for you to sound the trumpets.</verse>
<verse>As an aroma pleasing to the LORD, prepare a burnt offering of one young bull, one ram and seven male lambs a year old, all without defect.</verse>
<verse>With the bull prepare a grain offering of three-tenths of an ephah of fine flour mixed with oil; with the ram, two-tenths;</verse>
<verse>and with each of the seven lambs, one-tenth.</verse>
<verse>Include one male goat as a sin offering to make atonement for you.</verse>
<verse>These are in addition to the monthly and daily burnt offerings with their grain offerings and drink offerings as specified. They are offerings made to the LORD by fire-a pleasing aroma.</verse>
<verse>"'On the tenth day of this seventh month hold a sacred assembly. You must deny yourselves and do no work.</verse>
<verse>Present as an aroma pleasing to the LORD a burnt offering of one young bull, one ram and seven male lambs a year old, all without defect.</verse>
<verse>With the bull prepare a grain offering of three-tenths of an ephah of fine flour mixed with oil; with the ram, two-tenths;</verse>
<verse>and with each of the seven lambs, one-tenth.</verse>
<verse>Include one male goat as a sin offering, in addition to the sin offering for atonement and the regular burnt offering with its grain offering, and their drink offerings.</verse>
<verse>"'On the fifteenth day of the seventh month, hold a sacred assembly and do no regular work. Celebrate a festival to the LORD for seven days.</verse>
<verse>Present an offering made by fire as an aroma pleasing to the LORD, a burnt offering of thirteen young bulls, two rams and fourteen male lambs a year old, all without defect.</verse>
<verse>With each of the thirteen bulls prepare a grain offering of three-tenths of an ephah of fine flour mixed with oil; with each of the two rams, two-tenths;</verse>
<verse>and with each of the fourteen lambs, one-tenth.</verse>
<verse>Include one male goat as a sin offering, in addition to the regular burnt offering with its grain offering and drink offering.</verse>
<verse>"'On the second day prepare twelve young bulls, two rams and fourteen male lambs a year old, all without defect.</verse>
<verse>With the bulls, rams and lambs, prepare their grain offerings and drink offerings according to the number specified.</verse>
<verse>Include one male goat as a sin offering, in addition to the regular burnt offering with its grain offering, and their drink offerings.</verse>
<verse>"'On the third day prepare eleven bulls, two rams and fourteen male lambs a year old, all without defect.</verse>
<verse>With the bulls, rams and lambs, prepare their grain offerings and drink offerings according to the number specified.</verse>
<verse>Include one male goat as a sin offering, in addition to the regular burnt offering with its grain offering and drink offering.</verse>
<verse>"'On the fourth day prepare ten bulls, two rams and fourteen male lambs a year old, all without defect.</verse>
<verse>With the bulls, rams and lambs, prepare their grain offerings and drink offerings according to the number specified.</verse>
<verse>Include one male goat as a sin offering, in addition to the regular burnt offering with its grain offering and drink offering.</verse>
<verse>"'On the fifth day prepare nine bulls, two rams and fourteen male lambs a year old, all without defect.</verse>
<verse>With the bulls, rams and lambs, prepare their grain offerings and drink offerings according to the number specified.</verse>
<verse>Include one male goat as a sin offering, in addition to the regular burnt offering with its grain offering and drink offering.</verse>
<verse>"'On the sixth day prepare eight bulls, two rams and fourteen male lambs a year old, all without defect.</verse>
<verse>With the bulls, rams and lambs, prepare their grain offerings and drink offerings according to the number specified.</verse>
<verse>Include one male goat as a sin offering, in addition to the regular burnt offering with its grain offering and drink offering.</verse>
<verse>"'On the seventh day prepare seven bulls, two rams and fourteen male lambs a year old, all without defect.</verse>
<verse>With the bulls, rams and lambs, prepare their grain offerings and drink offerings according to the number specified.</verse>
<verse>Include one male goat as a sin offering, in addition to the regular burnt offering with its grain offering and drink offering.</verse>
<verse>"'On the eighth day hold an assembly and do no regular work.</verse>
<verse>Present an offering made by fire as an aroma pleasing to the LORD, a burnt offering of one bull, one ram and seven male lambs a year old, all without defect.</verse>
<verse>With the bull, the ram and the lambs, prepare their grain offerings and drink offerings according to the number specified.</verse>
<verse>Include one male goat as a sin offering, in addition to the regular burnt offering with its grain offering and drink offering.</verse>
<verse>"'In addition to what you vow and your freewill offerings, prepare these for the LORD at your appointed feasts: your burnt offerings, grain offerings, drink offerings and fellowship offerings. '"</verse>
<verse>Moses told the Israelites all that the LORD commanded him.</verse>
</chapter>