<chapter translation="NASB" testament="New" book="Colossians" book_id="51" n="4">
<verse>Masters, grant to your slaves justice and fairness, knowing that you too have a Master in heaven.</verse>
<verse>Devote yourselves to prayer, keeping alert in it with an attitude of thanksgiving;</verse>
<verse>praying at the same time for us as well, that God will open up to us a door for the word, so that we may speak forth the mystery of Christ, for which I have also been imprisoned;</verse>
<verse>that I may make it clear in the way I ought to speak.</verse>
<verse>Conduct yourselves with wisdom toward outsiders, making the most of the opportunity.</verse>
<verse>Let your speech always be with grace, as though seasoned with salt, so that you will know how you should respond to each person.</verse>
<verse>As to all my affairs, Tychicus, our beloved brother and faithful servant and fellow bond-servant in the Lord, will bring you information.</verse>
<verse>For I have sent him to you for this very purpose, that you may know about our circumstances and that he may encourage your hearts;</verse>
<verse>and with him Onesimus, our faithful and beloved brother, who is one of your number. They will inform you about the whole situation here.</verse>
<verse>Aristarchus, my fellow prisoner, sends you his greetings; and also Barnabas's cousin Mark (about whom you received instructions; if he comes to you, welcome him);</verse>
<verse>and also Jesus who is called Justus; these are the only fellow workers for the kingdom of God who are from the circumcision, and they have proved to be an encouragement to me.</verse>
<verse>Epaphras, who is one of your number, a bondslave of Jesus Christ, sends you his greetings, always laboring earnestly for you in his prayers, that you may stand perfect and fully assured in all the will of God.</verse>
<verse>For I testify for him that he has a deep concern for you and for those who are in Laodicea and Hierapolis.</verse>
<verse>Luke, the beloved physician, sends you his greetings, and also Demas.</verse>
<verse>Greet the brethren who are in Laodicea and also Nympha and the church that is in her house.</verse>
<verse>When this letter is read among you, have it also read in the church of the Laodiceans; and you, for your part read my letter that is coming from Laodicea.</verse>
<verse>Say to Archippus, "Take heed to the ministry which you have received in the Lord, that you may fulfill it."</verse>
<verse>I, Paul, write this greeting with my own hand. Remember my imprisonment. Grace be with you.</verse>
</chapter>