<?xml version="1.0"?>
<chapter translation="KJV" testament="Old" book="1 Chronicles" n="2">
      <verse>These <supplied>are</supplied> the sons of Israel; Reuben, Simeon, Levi, and Judah, Issachar, and Zebulun,
</verse><verse>Dan, Joseph, and Benjamin, Naphtali, Gad, and Asher.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>The sons of Judah; Er, and Onan, and Shelah: <supplied>which</supplied> three were born unto him of the daughter of Shua the Canaanitess. And Er, the firstborn of Judah, was evil in the sight of the LORD; and he slew him.
</verse><verse>And Tamar his daughter in law bare him Pharez and Zerah. All the sons of Judah <supplied>were</supplied> five.
</verse><verse>The sons of Pharez; Hezron, and Hamul.
</verse><verse>And the sons of Zerah; Zimri, and Ethan, and Heman, and Calcol, and Dara: five of them in all.
</verse><verse>And the sons of Carmi; Achar, the troubler of Israel, who transgressed in the thing accursed.
</verse><verse>And the sons of Ethan; Azariah.
</verse><verse>The sons also of Hezron, that were born unto him; Jerahmeel, and Ram, and Chelubai.
</verse><verse>And Ram begat Amminadab; and Amminadab begat Nahshon, prince of the children of Judah;
</verse><verse>And Nahshon begat Salma, and Salma begat Boaz,
</verse><verse>And Boaz begat Obed, and Obed begat Jesse,
     
      </verse>
      <verse>And Jesse begat his firstborn Eliab, and Abinadab the second, and Shimma the third,
</verse><verse>Nethaneel the fourth, Raddai the fifth,
</verse><verse>Ozem the sixth, David the seventh:
</verse><verse>Whose sisters <supplied>were</supplied> Zeruiah, and Abigail. And the sons of Zeruiah; Abishai, and Joab, and Asahel, three.
</verse><verse>And Abigail bare Amasa: and the father of Amasa <supplied>was</supplied> Jether the Ishmeelite.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>And Caleb the son of Hezron begat <supplied>children</supplied> of Azubah <supplied>his</supplied> wife, and of Jerioth: her sons <supplied>are</supplied> these; Jesher, and Shobab, and Ardon.
</verse><verse>And when Azubah was dead, Caleb took unto him Ephrath, which bare him Hur.
</verse><verse>And Hur begat Uri, and Uri begat Bezaleel.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>And afterward Hezron went in to the daughter of Machir the father of Gilead, whom he married when he <supplied>was</supplied> threescore years old; and she bare him Segub.
</verse><verse>And Segub begat Jair, who had three and twenty cities in the land of Gilead.
</verse><verse>And he took Geshur, and Aram, with the towns of Jair, from them, with Kenath, and the towns thereof, <supplied>even</supplied> threescore cities. All these <supplied>belonged to</supplied> the sons of Machir the father of Gilead.
</verse><verse>And after that Hezron was dead in Caleb-ephratah, then Abiah Hezron&#x2019;s wife bare him Ashur the father of Tekoa.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>And the sons of Jerahmeel the firstborn of Hezron were, Ram the firstborn, and Bunah, and Oren, and Ozem, <supplied>and</supplied> Ahijah.
</verse><verse>Jerahmeel had also another wife, whose name <supplied>was</supplied> Atarah; she <supplied>was</supplied> the mother of Onam.
</verse><verse>And the sons of Ram the firstborn of Jerahmeel were, Maaz, and Jamin, and Eker.
</verse><verse>And the sons of Onam were, Shammai, and Jada. And the sons of Shammai; Nadab, and Abishur.
</verse><verse>And the name of the wife of Abishur <supplied>was</supplied> Abihail, and she bare him Ahban, and Molid.
</verse><verse>And the sons of Nadab; Seled, and Appaim: but Seled died without children.
</verse><verse>And the sons of Appaim; Ishi. And the sons of Ishi; Sheshan. And the children of Sheshan; Ahlai.
</verse><verse>And the sons of Jada the brother of Shammai; Jether and Jonathan: and Jether died without children.
</verse><verse>And the sons of Jonathan; Peleth, and Zaza. These were the sons of Jerahmeel.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>Now Sheshan had no sons, but daughters. And Sheshan had a servant, an Egyptian, whose name <supplied>was</supplied> Jarha.
</verse><verse>And Sheshan gave his daughter to Jarha his servant to wife; and she bare him Attai.
</verse><verse>And Attai begat Nathan, and Nathan begat Zabad,
</verse><verse>And Zabad begat Ephlal, and Ephlal begat Obed,
</verse><verse>And Obed begat Jehu, and Jehu begat Azariah,
</verse><verse>And Azariah begat Helez, and Helez begat Eleasah,
</verse><verse>And Eleasah begat Sisamai, and Sisamai begat Shallum,
</verse><verse>And Shallum begat Jekamiah, and Jekamiah begat Elishama.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>Now the sons of Caleb the brother of Jerahmeel <supplied>were,</supplied> Mesha his firstborn, which was the father of Ziph; and the sons of Mareshah the father of Hebron.
</verse><verse>And the sons of Hebron; Korah, and Tappuah, and Rekem, and Shema.
</verse><verse>And Shema begat Raham, the father of Jorkoam: and Rekem begat Shammai.
</verse><verse>And the son of Shammai <supplied>was</supplied> Maon: and Maon <supplied>was</supplied> the father of Beth-zur.
</verse><verse>And Ephah, Caleb&#x2019;s concubine, bare Haran, and Moza, and Gazez: and Haran begat Gazez.
</verse><verse>And the sons of Jahdai; Regem, and Jotham, and Gesham, and Pelet, and Ephah, and Shaaph.
</verse><verse>Maachah, Caleb&#x2019;s concubine, bare Sheber, and Tirhanah.
</verse><verse>She bare also Shaaph the father of Madmannah, Sheva the father of Machbenah, and the father of Gibea: and the daughter of Caleb <supplied>was</supplied> Achsa.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>These were the sons of Caleb the son of Hur, the firstborn of Ephratah; Shobal the father of Kirjath-jearim,
</verse><verse>Salma the father of Bethlehem, Hareph the father of Beth- gader.
</verse><verse>And Shobal the father of Kirjath-jearim had sons; Haroeh, <supplied>and</supplied> half of the Manahethites.
</verse><verse>And the families of Kirjath-jearim; the Ithrites, and the Puhites, and the Shumathites, and the Mishraites; of them came the Zareathites, and the Eshtaulites.
</verse><verse>The sons of Salma; Bethlehem, and the Netophathites, Ataroth, the house of Joab, and half of the Manahethites, the Zorites.
</verse><verse>And the families of the scribes which dwelt at Jabez; the Tirathites, the Shimeathites, <supplied>and</supplied> Suchathites. These <supplied>are</supplied> the Kenites that came of Hemath, the father of the house of Rechab.
     
      </verse>
      </chapter>
