<chapter translation="MSG" testament="New" book="James" book-id="59" n="1">
<verse>I, James, am a slave of God and the Master Jesus, writing to the twelve tribes scattered to Kingdom Come: Hello!</verse>
<verse>Consider it a sheer gift, friends, when tests and challenges come at you from all sides.</verse>
<verse>You know that under pressure, your faith-life is forced into the open and shows its true colors.</verse>
<verse>So don't try to get out of anything prematurely. Let it do its work so you become mature and well-developed, not deficient in any way.</verse>
<verse>If you don't know what you're doing, pray to the Father. He loves to help. You'll get his help, and won't be condescended to when you ask for it.</verse>
<verse>Ask boldly, believingly, without a second thought. People who "worry their prayers" are like wind-whipped waves.</verse>
<verse>Don't think you're going to get anything from the Master that way,</verse>
<verse>adrift at sea, keeping all your options open.</verse>
<verse>When down-and-outers get a break, cheer!</verse>
<verse>And when the arrogant rich are brought down to size, cheer! Prosperity is as short-lived as a wildflower, so don't ever count on it.</verse>
<verse>You know that as soon as the sun rises, pouring down its scorching heat, the flower withers. Its petals wilt and, before you know it, that beautiful face is a barren stem. Well, that's a picture of the "prosperous life." At the very moment everyone is looking on in admiration, it fades away to nothing.</verse>
<verse>Anyone who meets a testing challenge head-on and manages to stick it out is mighty fortunate. For such persons loyally in love with God, the reward is life and more life.</verse>
<verse>Don't let anyone under pressure to give in to evil say, "God is trying to trip me up." God is impervious to evil, and puts evil in no one's way.</verse>
<verse>The temptation to give in to evil comes from us and only us. We have no one to blame but the leering, seducing flare-up of our own lust.</verse>
<verse>Lust gets pregnant, and has a baby: sin! Sin grows up to adulthood, and becomes a real killer.</verse>
<verse>So, my very dear friends, don't get thrown off course.</verse>
<verse>Every desirable and beneficial gift comes out of heaven. The gifts are rivers of light cascading down from the Father of Light. There is nothing deceitful in God, nothing two-faced, nothing fickle.</verse>
<verse>He brought us to life using the true Word, showing us off as the crown of all his creatures.</verse>
<verse>Post this at all the intersections, dear friends: Lead with your ears, follow up with your tongue, and let anger straggle along in the rear.</verse>
<verse>God's righteousness doesn't grow from human anger.</verse>
<verse>So throw all spoiled virtue and cancerous evil in the garbage. In simple humility, let our gardener, God, landscape you with the Word, making a salvation-garden of your life.</verse>
<verse>Don't fool yourself into thinking that you are a listener when you are anything but, letting the Word go in one ear and out the other. Act on what you hear!</verse>
<verse>Those who hear and don't act are like those who glance in the mirror,</verse>
<verse>walk away, and two minutes later have no idea who they are, what they look like.</verse>
<verse>But whoever catches a glimpse of the revealed counsel of God--the free life!-even out of the corner of his eye, and sticks with it, is no distracted scatterbrain but a man or woman of action. That person will find delight and affirmation in the action.</verse>
<verse>Anyone who sets himself up as "religious" by talking a good game is self-deceived. This kind of religion is hot air and only hot air.</verse>
<verse>Real religion, the kind that passes muster before God the Father, is this: Reach out to the homeless and loveless in their plight, and guard against corruption from the godless world.</verse>
</chapter>