<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Isaiah" book-id="23" n="16">
<verse>"Dispatch a gift of lambs," says Moab, "to the leaders in Jerusalem--Lambs from Sela sent across the desert to buy the goodwill of Jerusalem.</verse>
<verse>The towns and people of Moab are at a loss, New-hatched birds knocked from the nest, fluttering helplessly At the banks of the Arnon River, unable to cross:</verse>
<verse>"Tell us what to do, help us out! Protect us, hide us!</verse>
<verse>Give the refugees from Moab sanctuary with you. Be a safe place for those on the run from the killing fields.'When this is all over," Judah answers, "the tyrant toppled, The killing at an end, all signs of these cruelties long gone,</verse>
<verse>A new government of love will be established in the venerable David tradition. A Ruler you can depend upon will head this government, A Ruler passionate for justice, a Ruler quick to set things right." [JC]</verse>
<verse>We've heard--everyone's heard!-of Moab's pride, world-famous for pride--Arrogant, self-important, insufferable, full of hot air.</verse>
<verse>So now let Moab lament for a change, with antiphonal mock-laments from the neighbors! What a shame! How terrible! No more fine fruitcakes and Kir-hareseth candies!</verse>
<verse>All those lush Heshbon fields dried up, the rich Sibmah vineyards withered! Foreign thugs have crushed and torn out the famous grapevines That once reached all the way to Jazer, right to the edge of the desert, Ripped out the crops in every direction as far as the eye can see.</verse>
<verse>I'll join the weeping. I'll weep right along with Jazer, weep for the Sibmah vineyards. And yes, Heshbon and Elealeh, I'll mingle my tears with your tears! The joyful shouting at harvest is gone. Instead of song and celebration, dead silence.</verse>
<verse>No more boisterous laughter in the orchards, no more hearty work songs in the vineyards. Instead of the bustle and sound of good work in the fields, silence--deathly and deadening silence.</verse>
<verse>My heartstrings throb like harp strings for Moab, my soul in sympathy for sad Kir-heres.</verse>
<verse>When Moab trudges to the shrine to pray, he wastes both time and energy. Going to the sanctuary and praying for relief is useless. Nothing ever happens.</verse>
<verse>This is GOD's earlier Message on Moab.</verse>
<verse>GOD's updated Message is, "In three years, no longer than the term of an enlisted soldier, Moab's impressive presence will be gone, that splendid hot-air balloon will be punctured, and instead of a vigorous population, just a few shuffling bums cadging handouts."</verse>
</chapter>