<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Isaiah" book_id="23" n="21">
<verse>A Message concerning the desert at the sea: As tempests drive through the Negev Desert, coming out of the desert, that terror-filled place,</verse>
<verse>A hard vision is given me: The betrayer betrayed, the plunderer plundered. Attack, Elam! Lay siege, Media! Persians, attack! Attack, Babylon! I'll put an end to all the moaning and groaning.</verse>
<verse>Because of this news I'm doubled up in pain, writhing in pain like a woman having a baby, Baffled by what I hear, undone by what I see.</verse>
<verse>Absolutely stunned, horror-stricken, I had hoped for a relaxed evening, but it has turned into a nightmare.</verse>
<verse>The banquet is spread, the guests reclining in luxurious ease, Eating and drinking, having a good time, and then, "To arms, princes! The fight is on!"</verse>
<verse>The Master told me, "Go, post a lookout. Have him report whatever he spots.</verse>
<verse>When he sees horses and wagons in battle formation, lines of donkeys and columns of camels, Tell him to keep his ear to the ground, note every whisper, every rumor."</verse>
<verse>Just then, the lookout shouted, "I'm at my post, Master, Sticking to my post day after day and all through the night!</verse>
<verse>I watched them come, the horses and wagons in battle formation. I heard them call out the war news in headlines: "Babylon fallen! Fallen! And all its precious god-idols smashed to pieces on the ground.'"</verse>
<verse>Dear Israel, you've been through a lot, you've been put through the mill. The good news I get from GOD-of-the-Angel-Armies, the God of Israel, I now pass on to you. [JC]</verse>
<verse>A Message concerning Edom: A voice calls to me from the Seir mountains in Edom, "Night watchman! How long till daybreak? How long will this night last?"</verse>
<verse>The night watchman calls back, "Morning's coming, But for now it's still night. If you ask me again, I'll give the same answer." [JC]</verse>
<verse>A Message concerning Arabia: You'll have to camp out in the desert badlands, you caravans of Dedanites.</verse>
<verse>Haul water to the thirsty, greet fugitives with bread. Show your desert hospitality, you who live in Tema.</verse>
<verse>The desert's swarming with refugees escaping the horrors of war.</verse>
<verse>The Master told me, "Hang on. Within one year--I'll sign a contract on it!-the arrogant brutality of Kedar, those hooligans of the desert, will be over,</verse>
<verse>nothing much left of the Kedar toughs." The GOD of Israel says so.</verse>
</chapter>