<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Isaiah" book-id="23" n="33">
<verse>Doom to you, Destroyer, not yet destroyed; And doom to you, Betrayer, not yet betrayed. When you finish destroying, your turn will come--destroyed! When you quit betraying, your turn will come--betrayed!</verse>
<verse>GOD, treat us kindly. You're our only hope. First thing in the morning, be there for us! When things go bad, help us out!</verse>
<verse>You spoke in thunder and everyone ran. You showed up and nations scattered.</verse>
<verse>Your people, for a change, got in on the loot, picking the field clean of the enemy spoils.</verse>
<verse>GOD is supremely esteemed. His center holds. Zion brims over with all that is just and right.</verse>
<verse>GOD keeps your days stable and secure--salvation, wisdom, and knowledge in surplus, and best of all, Zion's treasure, Fear-of-GOD.</verse>
<verse>But look! Listen! Tough men weep openly. Peacemaking diplomats are in bitter tears.</verse>
<verse>The roads are empty--not a soul out on the streets. The peace treaty is broken, its conditions violated, its signers reviled.</verse>
<verse>The very ground under our feet mourns, the Lebanon mountains hang their heads, Flowering Sharon is a weed-choked gully, and the forests of Bashan and Carmel? Bare branches.</verse>
<verse>"Now I'm stepping in," GOD says. "From now on, I'm taking over. The gloves come off. Now see how mighty I am.</verse>
<verse>There's nothing to you. Pregnant with chaff, you produce straw babies; full of hot air, you self-destruct.</verse>
<verse>You're good for nothing but fertilizer and fuel. Earth to earth--and the sooner the better.</verse>
<verse>"If you're far away, get the reports on what I've done, And if you're in the neighborhood, pay attention to my record.</verse>
<verse>The sinners in Zion are rightly terrified; the godless are at their wit's end: "Who among us can survive this firestorm? Who of us can get out of this purge with our lives?'"</verse>
<verse>The answer's simple: Live right, speak the truth, despise exploitation, refuse bribes, reject violence, avoid evil amusements.</verse>
<verse>This is how you raise your standard of living! A safe and stable way to live. A nourishing, satisfying way to live.</verse>
<verse>Oh, you'll see the king--a beautiful sight! And you'll take in the wide vistas of land.</verse>
<verse>In your mind you'll go over the old terrors: "What happened to that Assyrian inspector who condemned and confiscated? And the one who gouged us of taxes? And that cheating moneychanger?"</verse>
<verse>Gone! Out of sight forever! Their insolence nothing now but a fading stain on the carpet! No more putting up with a language you can't understand, no more sounds of gibberish in your ears.</verse>
<verse>Just take a look at Zion, will you? Centering our worship in festival feasts! Feast your eyes on Jerusalem, a quiet and permanent place to live. No more pulling up stakes and moving on, no more patched-together lean-tos.</verse>
<verse>Instead, GOD! GOD majestic, God himself the place in a country of broad rivers and streams, But rivers blocked to invading ships, off--limits to predatory pirates.</verse>
<verse>For GOD makes all the decisions here. GOD is our king. GOD runs this place and he'll keep us safe.</verse>
<verse>Ha! Your sails are in shreds, your mast wobbling, your hold leaking. The plunder is free for the taking, free for all--for weak and strong, insiders and outsiders.</verse>
<verse>No one in Zion will say, "I'm sick." Best of all, they'll all live guilt-free.</verse>
</chapter>