<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Isaiah" book_id="23" n="62">
<verse>Regarding Zion, I can't keep my mouth shut, regarding Jerusalem, I can't hold my tongue, Until her righteousness blazes down like the sun and her salvation flames up like a torch.</verse>
<verse>Foreign countries will see your righteousness, and world leaders your glory. You'll get a brand-new name straight from the mouth of GOD.</verse>
<verse>You'll be a stunning crown in the palm of GOD's hand, a jeweled gold cup held high in the hand of your God.</verse>
<verse>No more will anyone call you Rejected, and your country will no more be called Ruined. You'll be called Hephzibah (My Delight), and your land Beulah (Married), Because GOD delights in you and your land will be like a wedding celebration.</verse>
<verse>For as a young man marries his virgin bride, so your builder marries you, And as a bridegroom is happy in his bride, so your God is happy with you.</verse>
<verse>I've posted watchmen on your walls, Jerusalem. Day and night they keep at it, praying, calling out, reminding GOD to remember.</verse>
<verse>They are to give him no peace until he does what he said, until he makes Jerusalem famous as the City of Praise.</verse>
<verse>GOD has taken a solemn oath, an oath he means to keep: "Never again will I open your grain-filled barns to your enemies to loot and eat. Never again will foreigners drink the wine that you worked so hard to produce.</verse>
<verse>No. The farmers who grow the food will eat the food and praise GOD for it. And those who make the wine will drink the wine in my holy courtyards."</verse>
<verse>Walk out of the gates. Get going! Get the road ready for the people. Build the highway. Get at it! Clear the debris, hoist high a flag, a signal to all peoples!</verse>
<verse>Yes! GOD has broadcast to all the world: "Tell daughter Zion, "Look! Your Savior comes, Ready to do what he said he'd do, prepared to complete what he promised.'"</verse>
<verse>Zion will be called new names: Holy People, GOD-Redeemed, Sought-Out, City-Not-Forsaken.</verse>
</chapter>