<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Habakkuk" book-id="35" n="1">
<verse>The oracle that Habakkuk the prophet received.</verse>
<verse>How long, O LORD, must I call for help, but you do not listen? Or cry out to you, "Violence!" but you do not save?</verse>
<verse>Why do you make me look at injustice? Why do you tolerate wrong? Destruction and violence are before me; there is strife, and conflict abounds.</verse>
<verse>Therefore the law is paralyzed, and justice never prevails. The wicked hem in the righteous, so that justice is perverted.</verse>
<verse>"Look at the nations and watch- and be utterly amazed. For I am going to do something in your days that you would not believe, even if you were told.</verse>
<verse>I am raising up the Babylonians, that ruthless and impetuous people, who sweep across the whole earth to seize dwelling places not their own.</verse>
<verse>They are a feared and dreaded people; they are a law to themselves and promote their own honor.</verse>
<verse>Their horses are swifter than leopards, fiercer than wolves at dusk. Their cavalry gallops headlong; their horsemen come from afar. They fly like a vulture swooping to devour;</verse>
<verse>they all come bent on violence. Their hordes advance like a desert wind and gather prisoners like sand.</verse>
<verse>They deride kings and scoff at rulers. They laugh at all fortified cities; they build earthen ramps and capture them.</verse>
<verse>Then they sweep past like the wind and go on- guilty men, whose own strength is their god."</verse>
<verse>O LORD, are you not from everlasting? My God, my Holy One, we will not die. O LORD, you have appointed them to execute judgment; O Rock, you have ordained them to punish.</verse>
<verse>Your eyes are too pure to look on evil; you cannot tolerate wrong. Why then do you tolerate the treacherous? Why are you silent while the wicked swallow up those more righteous than themselves?</verse>
<verse>You have made men like fish in the sea, like sea creatures that have no ruler.</verse>
<verse>The wicked foe pulls all of them up with hooks, he catches them in his net, he gathers them up in his dragnet; and so he rejoices and is glad.</verse>
<verse>Therefore he sacrifices to his net and burns incense to his dragnet, for by his net he lives in luxury and enjoys the choicest food.</verse>
<verse>Is he to keep on emptying his net, destroying nations without mercy?</verse>
</chapter>