<chapter translation="NIV" testament="New" book="Mark" book-id="41" n="15">
<verse>Very early in the morning, the chief priests, with the elders, the teachers of the law and the whole Sanhedrin, reached a decision. They bound Jesus, led him away and handed him over to Pilate.</verse>
<verse>"Are you the king of the Jews?" asked Pilate. "Yes, it is as you say," Jesus replied.</verse>
<verse>The chief priests accused him of many things.</verse>
<verse>So again Pilate asked him, "Aren't you going to answer? See how many things they are accusing you of."</verse>
<verse>But Jesus still made no reply, and Pilate was amazed.</verse>
<verse>Now it was the custom at the Feast to release a prisoner whom the people requested.</verse>
<verse>A man called Barabbas was in prison with the insurrectionists who had committed murder in the uprising.</verse>
<verse>The crowd came up and asked Pilate to do for them what he usually did.</verse>
<verse>"Do you want me to release to you the king of the Jews?" asked Pilate,</verse>
<verse>knowing it was out of envy that the chief priests had handed Jesus over to him.</verse>
<verse>But the chief priests stirred up the crowd to have Pilate release Barabbas instead.</verse>
<verse>"What shall I do, then, with the one you call the king of the Jews?" Pilate asked them.</verse>
<verse>"Crucify him!" they shouted.</verse>
<verse>"Why? What crime has he committed?" asked Pilate. But they shouted all the louder, "Crucify him!"</verse>
<verse>Wanting to satisfy the crowd, Pilate released Barabbas to them. He had Jesus flogged, and handed him over to be crucified.</verse>
<verse>The soldiers led Jesus away into the palace (that is, the Praetorium) and called together the whole company of soldiers.</verse>
<verse>They put a purple robe on him, then twisted together a crown of thorns and set it on him.</verse>
<verse>And they began to call out to him, "Hail, king of the Jews!"</verse>
<verse>Again and again they struck him on the head with a staff and spit on him. Falling on their knees, they paid homage to him.</verse>
<verse>And when they had mocked him, they took off the purple robe and put his own clothes on him. Then they led him out to crucify him.</verse>
<verse>A certain man from Cyrene, Simon, the father of Alexander and Rufus, was passing by on his way in from the country, and they forced him to carry the cross.</verse>
<verse>They brought Jesus to the place called Golgotha (which means The Place of the Skull).</verse>
<verse>Then they offered him wine mixed with myrrh, but he did not take it.</verse>
<verse>And they crucified him. Dividing up his clothes, they cast lots to see what each would get.</verse>
<verse>It was the third hour when they crucified him.</verse>
<verse>The written notice of the charge against him read: THE KING OF THE JEWS.</verse>
<verse>They crucified two robbers with him, one on his right and one on his left.</verse>
<verse>See Footnote</verse>
<verse>Those who passed by hurled insults at him, shaking their heads and saying, "So! You who are going to destroy the temple and build it in three days,</verse>
<verse>come down from the cross and save yourself!"</verse>
<verse>In the same way the chief priests and the teachers of the law mocked him among themselves. "He saved others," they said, "but he can't save himself!</verse>
<verse>Let this Christ, this King of Israel, come down now from the cross, that we may see and believe." Those crucified with him also heaped insults on him.</verse>
<verse>At the sixth hour darkness came over the whole land until the ninth hour.</verse>
<verse>And at the ninth hour Jesus cried out in a loud voice, "Eloi, Eloi, lama sabachthani?"--which means, "My God, my God, why have you forsaken me?"</verse>
<verse>When some of those standing near heard this, they said, "Listen, he's calling Elijah."</verse>
<verse>One man ran, filled a sponge with wine vinegar, put it on a stick, and offered it to Jesus to drink. "Now leave him alone. Let's see if Elijah comes to take him down," he said.</verse>
<verse>With a loud cry, Jesus breathed his last.</verse>
<verse>The curtain of the temple was torn in two from top to bottom.</verse>
<verse>And when the centurion, who stood there in front of Jesus, heard his cry and saw how he died, he said, "Surely this man was the Son of God!"</verse>
<verse>Some women were watching from a distance. Among them were Mary Magdalene, Mary the mother of James the younger and of Joses, and Salome.</verse>
<verse>In Galilee these women had followed him and cared for his needs. Many other women who had come up with him to Jerusalem were also there.</verse>
<verse>It was Preparation Day (that is, the day before the Sabbath). So as evening approached,</verse>
<verse>Joseph of Arimathea, a prominent member of the Council, who was himself waiting for the kingdom of God, went boldly to Pilate and asked for Jesus' body.</verse>
<verse>Pilate was surprised to hear that he was already dead. Summoning the centurion, he asked him if Jesus had already died.</verse>
<verse>When he learned from the centurion that it was so, he gave the body to Joseph.</verse>
<verse>So Joseph bought some linen cloth, took down the body, wrapped it in the linen, and placed it in a tomb cut out of rock. Then he rolled a stone against the entrance of the tomb.</verse>
<verse>Mary Magdalene and Mary the mother of Joses saw where he was laid.</verse>
</chapter>