<chapter translation="MSG" testament="New" book="1 Peter" book-id="60" n="5">
<verse>I have a special concern for you church leaders. I know what it's like to be a leader, in on Christ's sufferings as well as the coming glory.</verse>
<verse>Here's my concern: that you care for God's flock with all the diligence of a shepherd. Not because you have to, but because you want to please God. Not calculating what you can get out of it, but acting spontaneously.[</verse>
<verse>Not bossily telling others what to do, but tenderly showing them the way.</verse>
<verse>When God, who is the best shepherd of all, comes out in the open with his rule, he'll see that you've done it right and commend you lavishly.</verse>
<verse>And you who are younger must follow your leaders. But all of you, leaders and followers alike, are to be down to earth with each other, for--God has had it with the proud, But takes delight in just plain people.</verse>
<verse>So be content with who you are, and don't put on airs. God's strong hand is on you; he'll promote you at the right time.</verse>
<verse>Live carefree before God; he is most careful with you.</verse>
<verse>Keep a cool head. Stay alert. The Devil is poised to pounce, and would like nothing better than to catch you napping.</verse>
<verse>Keep your guard up. You're not the only ones plunged into these hard times. It's the same with Christians all over the world. So keep a firm grip on the faith.</verse>
<verse>The suffering won't last forever. It won't be long before this generous God who has great plans for us in Christ--eternal and glorious plans they are!-will have you put together and on your feet for good.</verse>
<verse>He gets the last word; yes, he does.</verse>
<verse>I'm sending this brief letter to you by Silas, a most dependable brother. I have the highest regard for him. I've written as urgently and accurately as I know how. This is God's generous truth; embrace it with both arms!</verse>
<verse>The church in exile here with me--but not for a moment forgotten by God--wants to be remembered to you. Mark, who is like a son to me, says hello.</verse>
<verse>Give holy embraces all around! Peace to you--to all who walk in Christ's ways.</verse>
</chapter>