<?xml version="1.0"?>
<chapter translation="KJV" testament="New" book="John" n="14" book-chapters="21">
      <verse>
      <jesus>Let not your heart be troubled: ye believe in God, believe also in me. </jesus></verse><verse><jesus>In my Father&#x2019;s house are many mansions: if <supplied>it were</supplied> not so, I would have told you. I go to prepare a place for you. </jesus></verse><verse><jesus>And if I
go and prepare a place for you, I will come again, and receive you unto myself; that where I am, <supplied>there</supplied> ye may be also. </jesus></verse><verse><jesus>And whither I go ye know, and the way ye know. </jesus></verse><verse>Thomas saith unto him, Lord, we know not whither thou
goest; and how can we know the way?
</verse><verse>Jesus saith unto him, <jesus>I am the way, the truth, and the life: no man cometh unto the Father, but by me. </jesus></verse><verse><jesus>If ye had known me, ye should have known my Father also: and from henceforth ye know him, and have seen him. </jesus></verse><verse>Philip
saith unto him, Lord, shew us the Father, and it sufficeth us.
</verse><verse>Jesus saith unto him, <jesus>Have I been so long time with you, and yet hast thou not known me, Philip? he that hath seen me hath seen the Father; and how sayest thou <supplied>then,</supplied> Shew us the Father? </jesus></verse><verse><jesus>Believest thou not that I am in
the Father, and the Father in me? the words that I speak unto you I speak not of myself: but the Father that dwelleth in me, he doeth the works. </jesus></verse><verse><jesus>Believe me that I <supplied>am</supplied> in the Father, and the Father in me: or else believe me for
the very works&#x2019; sake. </jesus></verse><verse><jesus>Verily, verily, I say unto you, He that believeth on me, the works that I do shall he do also; and greater <supplied>works</supplied> than these shall he do; because I go unto my Father. </jesus></verse><verse><jesus>And whatsoever ye shall
ask in my name, that will I do, that the Father may be glorified in the Son. </jesus></verse><verse><jesus>If ye shall ask any thing in my name, I will do <supplied>it.</supplied>
     
      </jesus>
      </verse>
      <verse>
      <jesus>If ye love me, keep my commandments. </jesus></verse><verse><jesus>And I will pray the Father, and he shall give you another Comforter, that he may abide with you for ever; </jesus></verse><verse><jesus><supplied>Even</supplied> the Spirit of truth; whom the world cannot
receive, because it seeth him not, neither knoweth him: but ye know him; for he dwelleth with you, and shall be in you. </jesus></verse><verse><jesus>I will not leave you comfortless: I will come to you. </jesus></verse><verse><jesus>Yet a little while, and the world seeth me no
more; but ye see me: because I live, ye shall live also. </jesus></verse><verse><jesus>At that day ye shall know that I <supplied>am</supplied> in my Father, and ye in me, and I in you. </jesus></verse><verse><jesus>He that hath my commandments, and keepeth them, he it is that loveth me: and
he that loveth me shall be loved of my Father, and I will love him, and will manifest myself to him. </jesus></verse><verse>Judas saith unto him, not Iscariot, Lord, how is it that thou wilt manifest thyself unto us, and not unto the world?
</verse><verse>Jesus answered and said unto him, <jesus>If a man love me, he will keep my words: and my Father will love him, and we will come unto him, and make our abode with him. </jesus></verse><verse><jesus>He that loveth me not keepeth not my sayings: and the word which
ye hear is not mine, but the Father&#x2019;s which sent me. </jesus></verse><verse><jesus>These things have I spoken unto you, being <supplied>yet</supplied> present with you. </jesus></verse><verse><jesus>But the Comforter, <supplied>which is</supplied> the Holy Ghost, whom the Father will send in my name, he
shall teach you all things, and bring all things to your remembrance, whatsoever I have said unto you. </jesus></verse><verse><jesus>Peace I leave with you, my peace I give unto you: not as the world giveth, give I unto you. Let not your heart be troubled, neither
let it be afraid. </jesus></verse><verse><jesus>Ye have heard how I said unto you, I go away, and come <supplied>again</supplied> unto you. If ye loved me, ye would rejoice, because I said, I go unto the Father: for my Father is greater than I. </jesus></verse><verse><jesus>And now I have told
you before it come to pass, that, when it is come to pass, ye might believe. </jesus></verse><verse><jesus>Hereafter I will not talk much with you: for the prince of this world cometh, and hath nothing in me. </jesus></verse><verse><jesus>But that the world may know that I love
the Father; and as the Father gave me commandment, even so I do. Arise, let us go hence.
     
      </jesus>
      </verse>
      </chapter>
