<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Jeremiah" book-id="24" n="11">
<verse>The Message that came to Jeremiah from GOD:</verse>
<verse>"Preach to the people of Judah and citizens of Jerusalem.</verse>
<verse>Tell them this: "This is GOD's Message, the Message of Israel's God to you. Anyone who does not keep the terms of this covenant is cursed.</verse>
<verse>The terms are clear. I made them plain to your ancestors when I delivered them from Egypt, out of the iron furnace of suffering. Obey what I tell you. Do exactly what I command you. Your obedience will close the deal. You'll be mine and I'll be yours.</verse>
<verse>This will provide the conditions in which I will be able to do what I promised your ancestors: to give them a fertile and lush land. And, as you know, that's what I did.'Yes, GOD," I replied. "That's true."</verse>
<verse>GOD continued: "Preach all this in the towns of Judah and the streets of Jerusalem. Say, "Listen to the terms of this covenant and carry them out!</verse>
<verse>I warned your ancestors when I delivered them from Egypt and I've kept up the warnings. I haven't quit warning them for a moment. I warned them from morning to night: "Obey me or else!"</verse>
<verse>But they didn't obey. They paid no attention to me. They did whatever they wanted to do, whenever they wanted to do it, until finally I stepped in and ordered the punishments set out in the covenant, which, despite all my warnings, they had ignored.'"</verse>
<verse>Then GOD said, "There's a conspiracy among the people of Judah and the citizens of Jerusalem.</verse>
<verse>They've plotted to reenact the sins of their ancestors--the ones who disobeyed me and decided to go after other gods and worship them. Israel and Judah are in this together, mindlessly breaking the covenant I made with their ancestors."</verse>
<verse>"Well, your God has something to say about this: Watch out! I'm about to visit doom on you, and no one will get out of it. You're going to cry for help but I won't listen.</verse>
<verse>Then all the people in Judah and Jerusalem will start praying to the gods you've been sacrificing to all these years, but it won't do a bit of good.</verse>
<verse>You've got as many gods as you have villages, Judah! And you've got enough altars for sacrifices to that impotent sex god Baal to put one on every street corner in Jerusalem!"</verse>
<verse>"And as for you, Jeremiah, I don't want you praying for this people. Nothing! Not a word of petition. Indeed, I'm not going to listen to a single syllable of their crisis-prayers."</verse>
<verse>"What business do the ones I love have figuring out how to get off the hook? And right in the house of worship! Do you think making promises and devising pious programs will save you from doom? Do you think you can get out of this by becoming more religious?</verse>
<verse>A mighty oak tree, majestic and glorious--that's how I once described you. But it will only take a clap of thunder and a bolt of lightning to leave you a shattered wreck.</verse>
<verse>"I, GOD-of-the-Angel-Armies, who planted you--yes, I have pronounced doom on you. Why? Because of the disastrous life you've lived, Israel and Judah alike, goading me to anger with your continuous worship and offerings to that sorry god Baal." [JC]</verse>
<verse>God told me what was going on. That's how I knew. You, GOD, opened my eyes to their evil scheming.</verse>
<verse>I had no idea what was going on--naive as a lamb being led to slaughter! I didn't know they had it in for me, didn't know of their behind-the-scenes plots: "Let's get rid of the preacher. That will stop the sermons! Let's get rid of him for good. He won't be remembered for long."</verse>
<verse>Then I said, "GOD-of-the-Angel-Armies, you're a fair judge. You examine and cross-examine human actions and motives. I want to see these people shown up and put down! I'm an open book before you. Clear my name."</verse>
<verse>That sent a signal to GOD, who spoke up: "Here's what I'll do to the men of Anathoth who are trying to murder you, the men who say, "Don't preach to us in GOD's name or we'll kill you.'</verse>
<verse>Yes, it's GOD-of-the-Angel-Armies speaking. Indeed! I'll call them to account: Their young people will die in battle, their children will die of starvation,</verse>
<verse>and there will be no one left at all, none. I'm visiting the men of Anathoth with doom. Doomsday!"</verse>
</chapter>