<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Ecclesiastes" book_id="21" n="1">
<verse>The words of the Teacher, son of David, king in Jerusalem:</verse>
<verse>"Meaningless! Meaningless!" says the Teacher. "Utterly meaningless! Everything is meaningless."</verse>
<verse>What does man gain from all his labor at which he toils under the sun?</verse>
<verse>Generations come and generations go, but the earth remains forever.</verse>
<verse>The sun rises and the sun sets, and hurries back to where it rises.</verse>
<verse>The wind blows to the south and turns to the north; round and round it goes, ever returning on its course.</verse>
<verse>All streams flow into the sea, yet the sea is never full. To the place the streams come from, there they return again.</verse>
<verse>All things are wearisome, more than one can say. The eye never has enough of seeing, nor the ear its fill of hearing.</verse>
<verse>What has been will be again, what has been done will be done again; there is nothing new under the sun.</verse>
<verse>Is there anything of which one can say, "Look! This is something new"? It was here already, long ago; it was here before our time.</verse>
<verse>There is no remembrance of men of old, and even those who are yet to come will not be remembered by those who follow.</verse>
<verse>I, the Teacher, was king over Israel in Jerusalem.</verse>
<verse>I devoted myself to study and to explore by wisdom all that is done under heaven. What a heavy burden God has laid on men!</verse>
<verse>I have seen all the things that are done under the sun; all of them are meaningless, a chasing after the wind.</verse>
<verse>What is twisted cannot be straightened; what is lacking cannot be counted.</verse>
<verse>I thought to myself, "Look, I have grown and increased in wisdom more than anyone who has ruled over Jerusalem before me; I have experienced much of wisdom and knowledge."</verse>
<verse>Then I applied myself to the understanding of wisdom, and also of madness and folly, but I learned that this, too, is a chasing after the wind.</verse>
<verse>For with much wisdom comes much sorrow; the more knowledge, the more grief.</verse>
</chapter>