<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Ecclesiastes" book-id="21" n="7">
<verse>A good name is better than fine perfume, and the day of death better than the day of birth.</verse>
<verse>It is better to go to a house of mourning than to go to a house of feasting, for death is the destiny of every man; the living should take this to heart.</verse>
<verse>Sorrow is better than laughter, because a sad face is good for the heart.</verse>
<verse>The heart of the wise is in the house of mourning, but the heart of fools is in the house of pleasure.</verse>
<verse>It is better to heed a wise man's rebuke than to listen to the song of fools.</verse>
<verse>Like the crackling of thorns under the pot, so is the laughter of fools. This too is meaningless.</verse>
<verse>Extortion turns a wise man into a fool, and a bribe corrupts the heart.</verse>
<verse>The end of a matter is better than its beginning, and patience is better than pride.</verse>
<verse>Do not be quickly provoked in your spirit, for anger resides in the lap of fools.</verse>
<verse>Do not say, "Why were the old days better than these?" For it is not wise to ask such questions.</verse>
<verse>Wisdom, like an inheritance, is a good thing and benefits those who see the sun.</verse>
<verse>Wisdom is a shelter as money is a shelter, but the advantage of knowledge is this: that wisdom preserves the life of its possessor.</verse>
<verse>Consider what God has done: Who can straighten what he has made crooked?</verse>
<verse>When times are good, be happy; but when times are bad, consider: God has made the one as well as the other. Therefore, a man cannot discover anything about his future.</verse>
<verse>In this meaningless life of mine I have seen both of these: a righteous man perishing in his righteousness, and a wicked man living long in his wickedness.</verse>
<verse>Do not be overrighteous, neither be overwise- why destroy yourself?</verse>
<verse>Do not be overwicked, and do not be a fool- why die before your time?</verse>
<verse>It is good to grasp the one and not let go of the other. The man who fears God will avoid all extremes.</verse>
<verse>Wisdom makes one wise man more powerful than ten rulers in a city.</verse>
<verse>There is not a righteous man on earth who does what is right and never sins.</verse>
<verse>Do not pay attention to every word people say, or you may hear your servant cursing you-</verse>
<verse>for you know in your heart that many times you yourself have cursed others.</verse>
<verse>All this I tested by wisdom and I said, "I am determined to be wise"- but this was beyond me.</verse>
<verse>Whatever wisdom may be, it is far off and most profound- who can discover it?</verse>
<verse>So I turned my mind to understand, to investigate and to search out wisdom and the scheme of things and to understand the stupidity of wickedness and the madness of folly.</verse>
<verse>I find more bitter than death the woman who is a snare, whose heart is a trap and whose hands are chains. The man who pleases God will escape her, but the sinner she will ensnare.</verse>
<verse>"Look," says the Teacher, "this is what I have discovered: "Adding one thing to another to discover the scheme of things-</verse>
<verse>while I was still searching but not finding- I found one upright man among a thousand, but not one upright woman among them all.</verse>
<verse>This only have I found: God made mankind upright, but men have gone in search of many schemes."</verse>
</chapter>