<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Genesis" book-id="1" n="10">
<verse>This is the family tree of the sons of Noah: Shem, Ham, and Japheth. After the flood, they themselves had sons.</verse>
<verse>The sons of Japheth: Gomer, Magog, Madai, Javan, Tubal, Meshech, Tiras.</verse>
<verse>The sons of Gomer: Ashkenaz, Riphath, Togarmah.</verse>
<verse>The sons of Javan: Elishah, Tarshish, Kittim, Rodanim.</verse>
<verse>The seafaring peoples developed from these, each in its own place by family, each with its own language.</verse>
<verse>The sons of Ham: Cush, Egypt, Put, Canaan.</verse>
<verse>The sons of Cush: Seba, Havilah, Sabtah, Raamah, Sabteca. The sons of Raamah: Sheba, Dedan.</verse>
<verse>Cush also had Nimrod. He was the first great warrior on Earth.</verse>
<verse>He was a great hunter before GOD. There was a saying, "Like Nimrod, a great hunter before GOD."</verse>
<verse>His kingdom got its start with Babel; then Erech, Akkad, and Calneh in the country of Shinar.</verse>
<verse>From there he went up to Asshur and built Nineveh, Rehoboth Ir, Calah,</verse>
<verse>and Resen between Nineveh and the great city Calah.</verse>
<verse>Egypt was ancestor to the Ludim, the Anamim, the Lehabim, the Naphtuhim,</verse>
<verse>the Pathrusim, the Casluhim (the origin of the Philistines), and the Kaphtorim.</verse>
<verse>Canaan had Sidon his firstborn, Heth,</verse>
<verse>the Jebusites, the Amorites, the Girgashites,</verse>
<verse>the Hivites, the Arkites, the Sinites,</verse>
<verse>the Arvadites, the Zemarites, and the Hamathites. Later the Canaanites spread out,</verse>
<verse>going from Sidon toward Gerar, as far south as Gaza, and then east all the way over to Sodom, Gomorrah, Admah, Zeboiim, and on to Lasha.</verse>
<verse>These are the descendants of Ham by family, language, country, and nation.</verse>
<verse>Shem, the older brother of Japheth, also had sons. Shem was ancestor to all the children of Eber.</verse>
<verse>The sons of Shem: Elam, Asshur, Arphaxad, Lud, and Aram.</verse>
<verse>The sons of Aram: Uz, Hul, Gether, Meshech.</verse>
<verse>Arphaxad had Shelah and Shelah had Eber.</verse>
<verse>Eber had two sons, Peleg (so named because in his days the human race divided) and Joktan.</verse>
<verse>Joktan had Almodad, Sheleph, Hazarmaveth, Jerah,</verse>
<verse>Hadoram, Uzal, Diklah,</verse>
<verse>Obal, Abimael, Sheba,</verse>
<verse>Ophir, Havilah, and Jobab--all sons of Joktan.</verse>
<verse>Their land goes from Mesha toward Sephar as far as the mountain ranges in the east.</verse>
<verse>These are the descendants of Shem by family, language, country, and nation.</verse>
<verse>This is the family tree of the sons of Noah as they developed into nations. From them nations developed all across the Earth after the flood.</verse>
</chapter>