<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Genesis" book-id="1" n="20">
<verse>Abraham traveled from there south to the Negev and settled down between Kadesh and Shur. While he was camping in Gerar,</verse>
<verse>Abraham said of his wife Sarah, "She's my sister." So Abimelech, king of Gerar, sent for Sarah and took her.</verse>
<verse>But God came to Abimelech in a dream that night and told him, "You're as good as dead--that woman you took, she's a married woman."</verse>
<verse>Now Abimelech had not yet slept with her, hadn't so much as touched her. He said, "Master, would you kill an innocent man?</verse>
<verse>Didn't he tell me, "She's my sister'? And didn't she herself say, "He's my brother'? I had no idea I was doing anything wrong when I did this."</verse>
<verse>God said to him in the dream, "Yes, I know your intentions were pure, that's why I kept you from sinning against me; I was the one who kept you from going to bed with her.</verse>
<verse>So now give the man's wife back to him. He's a prophet and will pray for you--pray for your life. If you don't give her back, know that it's certain death both for you and everyone in your family."</verse>
<verse>Abimelech was up first thing in the morning. He called all his house servants together and told them the whole story. They were shocked.</verse>
<verse>Then Abimelech called in Abraham and said, "What have you done to us? What have I ever done to you that you would bring on me and my kingdom this huge offense? What you've done to me ought never to have been done."</verse>
<verse>Abimelech went on to Abraham, "Whatever were you thinking of when you did this thing?"</verse>
<verse>Abraham said, "I just assumed that there was no fear of God in this place and that they'd kill me to get my wife.</verse>
<verse>Besides, the truth is that she is my half sister; she's my father's daughter but not my mother's.</verse>
<verse>When God sent me out as a wanderer from my father's home, I told her, "Do me a favor; wherever we go, tell people that I'm your brother.'"</verse>
<verse>Then Abimelech gave Sarah back to Abraham, and along with her sent sheep and cattle and servants, both male and female.</verse>
<verse>He said, "My land is open to you; live wherever you wish."</verse>
<verse>And to Sarah he said, "I've given your brother a thousand pieces of silver--that clears you of even a shadow of suspicion before the eyes of the world. You're vindicated."</verse>
<verse>Then Abraham prayed to God and God healed Abimelech, his wife and his maidservants, and they started having babies again.</verse>
<verse>For GOD had shut down every womb in Abimelech's household on account of Sarah, Abraham's wife. [JC]</verse>
</chapter>