<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Genesis" book_id="1" n="25">
<verse>Abraham married a second time; his new wife was named Keturah.</verse>
<verse>She gave birth to Zimran, Jokshan, Medan, Midian, Ishbak, and Shuah.</verse>
<verse>Jokshan had Sheba and Dedan. Dedan's descendants were the Asshurim, the Letushim, and the Leummim.</verse>
<verse>Midian had Ephah, Epher, Hanoch, Abida, and Eldaah--all from the line of Keturah.</verse>
<verse>But Abraham gave everything he possessed to Isaac.</verse>
<verse>While he was still living, he gave gifts to the sons he had by his concubines, but then sent them away to the country of the east, putting a good distance between them and his son Isaac.</verse>
<verse>Abraham lived 175 years.</verse>
<verse>Then he took his final breath. He died happy at a ripe old age, full of years, and was buried with his family.</verse>
<verse>His sons Isaac and Ishmael buried him in the cave of Machpelah in the field of Ephron son of Zohar the Hittite, next to Mamre.</verse>
<verse>It was the field that Abraham had bought from the Hittites. Abraham was buried next to his wife Sarah.</verse>
<verse>After Abraham's death, God blessed his son Isaac. Isaac lived at Beer Lahai Roi.</verse>
<verse>This is the family tree of Ishmael son of Abraham, the son that Hagar the Egyptian, Sarah's maid, bore to Abraham.</verse>
<verse>These are the names of Ishmael's sons in the order of their births: Nebaioth, Ishmael's first-born, Kedar, Adbeel, Mibsam,</verse>
<verse>Mishma, Dumah, Massa</verse>
<verse>, Hadad, Tema, Jetur, Naphish, and Kedemah-</verse>
<verse>all the sons of Ishmael. Their settlements and encampments were named after them. Twelve princes with their twelve tribes.</verse>
<verse>Ishmael lived 137 years. When he breathed his last and died he was buried with his family.</verse>
<verse>His children settled down all the way from Havilah near Egypt eastward to Shur in the direction of Assyria. The Ishmaelites didn't get along with any of their kin.</verse>
<verse>This is the family tree of Isaac son of Abraham: Abraham had Isaac.</verse>
<verse>Isaac was forty years old when he married Rebekah daughter of Bethuel the Aramean of Paddan Aram. She was the sister of Laban the Aramean.</verse>
<verse>Isaac prayed hard to GOD for his wife because she was barren. GOD answered his prayer and Rebekah became pregnant.</verse>
<verse>But the children tumbled and kicked inside her so much that she said, "If this is the way it's going to be, why go on living?" She went to GOD to find out what was going on.</verse>
<verse>GOD told her, Two nations are in your womb, two peoples butting heads while still in your body. One people will overpower the other, and the older will serve the younger.</verse>
<verse>When her time to give birth came, sure enough, there were twins in her womb.</verse>
<verse>The first came out reddish, as if snugly wrapped in a hairy blanket; they named him Esau (Hairy).</verse>
<verse>His brother followed, his fist clutched tight to Esau's heel; they named him Jacob (Heel). Isaac was sixty years old when they were born.</verse>
<verse>The boys grew up. Esau became an expert hunter, an outdoorsman. Jacob was a quiet man preferring life indoors among the tents.</verse>
<verse>Isaac loved Esau because he loved his game, but Rebekah loved Jacob.</verse>
<verse>One day Jacob was cooking a stew. Esau came in from the field, starved.</verse>
<verse>Esau said to Jacob, "Give me some of that red stew--I'm starved!" That's how he came to be called Edom (Red).</verse>
<verse>Jacob said, "Make me a trade: my stew for your rights as the firstborn."</verse>
<verse>Esau said, "I'm starving! What good is a birthright if I'm dead?"</verse>
<verse>Jacob said, "First, swear to me." And he did it. On oath Esau traded away his rights as the firstborn.</verse>
<verse>Jacob gave him bread and the stew of lentils. He ate and drank, got up and left. That's how Esau shrugged off his rights as the firstborn. [JC]</verse>
</chapter>