<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Genesis" book_id="1" n="33">
<verse>Jacob looked up and saw Esau coming with his four hundred men. He divided the children between Leah and Rachel and the two maidservants.</verse>
<verse>He put the maidservants out in front, Leah and her children next, and Rachel and Joseph last.</verse>
<verse>He led the way and, as he approached his brother, bowed seven times, honoring his brother.</verse>
<verse>But Esau ran up and embraced him, held him tight and kissed him. And they both wept.</verse>
<verse>Then Esau looked around and saw the women and children: "And who are these with you?" Jacob said, "The children that God saw fit to bless me with."</verse>
<verse>Then the maidservants came up with their children and bowed;</verse>
<verse>then Leah and her children, also bowing; and finally, Joseph and Rachel came up and bowed to Esau.</verse>
<verse>Esau then asked, "And what was the meaning of all those herds that I met?I was hoping that they would pave the way for my master to welcome me."</verse>
<verse>Esau said, "Oh, brother. I have plenty of everything--keep what is yours for yourself."</verse>
<verse>Jacob said, "Please. If you can find it in your heart to welcome me, accept these gifts. When I saw your face, it was as the face of God smiling on me.</verse>
<verse>Accept the gifts I have brought for you. God has been good to me and I have more than enough." Jacob urged the gifts on him and Esau accepted.</verse>
<verse>Then Esau said, "Let's start out on our way; I'll take the lead."</verse>
<verse>But Jacob said, "My master can see that the children are frail. And the flocks and herds are nursing, making for slow going. If I push them too hard, even for a day, I'd lose them all.</verse>
<verse>So, master, you go on ahead of your servant, while I take it easy at the pace of my flocks and children. I'll catch up with you in Seir."</verse>
<verse>Esau said, "Let me at least lend you some of my men.There's no need," said Jacob. "Your generous welcome is all I need or want."</verse>
<verse>So Esau set out that day and made his way back to Seir.</verse>
<verse>And Jacob left for Succoth. He built a shelter for himself and sheds for his livestock. That's how the place came to be called Succoth (Sheds).</verse>
<verse>And that's how it happened that Jacob arrived all in one piece in Shechem in the land of Canaan--all the way from Paddan Aram. He camped near the city.</verse>
<verse>He bought the land where he pitched his tent from the sons of Hamor, the father of Shechem. He paid a hundred silver coins for it.</verse>
<verse>Then he built an altar there and named it El-Elohe-Israel (Mighty Is the God of Israel). [JC]</verse>
</chapter>