<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Genesis" book-id="1" n="35">
<verse>God spoke to Jacob: "Go back to Bethel. Stay there and build an altar to the God who revealed himself to you when you were running for your life from your brother Esau."</verse>
<verse>Jacob told his family and all those who lived with him, "Throw out all the alien gods which you have, take a good bath and put on clean clothes,</verse>
<verse>we're going to Bethel. I'm going to build an altar there to the God who answered me when I was in trouble and has stuck with me everywhere I've gone since."</verse>
<verse>They turned over to Jacob all the alien gods they'd been holding on to, along with their lucky-charm earrings. Jacob buried them under the oak tree in Shechem.</verse>
<verse>Then they set out. A paralyzing fear descended on all the surrounding villages so that they were unable to pursue the sons of Jacob.</verse>
<verse>Jacob and his company arrived at Luz, that is, Bethel, in the land of Canaan.</verse>
<verse>He built an altar there and named it El-Bethel (God-of-Bethel) because that's where God revealed himself to him when he was running from his brother.</verse>
<verse>And that's when Rebekah's nurse, Deborah, died. She was buried just below Bethel under the oak tree. It was named Allon-Bacuth (Weeping-Oak).</verse>
<verse>God revealed himself once again to Jacob, after he had come back from Paddan Aram and blessed him:</verse>
<verse>"Your name is Jacob (Heel); but that's your name no longer. From now on your name is Israel (God-Wrestler)."</verse>
<verse>God continued, I am The Strong God. Have children! Flourish! A nation--a whole company of nations!- will come from you. Kings will come from your loins;</verse>
<verse>the land I gave Abraham and Isaac I now give to you, and pass it on to your descendants.</verse>
<verse>And then God was gone, ascended from the place where he had spoken with him.</verse>
<verse>Jacob set up a stone pillar on the spot where God had spoken with him. He poured a drink offering on it and anointed it with oil.</verse>
<verse>Jacob dedicated the place where God had spoken with him, Bethel (God's-House). [JC]</verse>
<verse>They left Bethel. They were still quite a ways from Ephrath when Rachel went into labor--hard, hard labor.</verse>
<verse>When her labor pains were at their worst, the midwife said to her, "Don't be afraid--you have another boy."</verse>
<verse>With her last breath, for she was now dying, she named him Ben-oni (Son-of-My-Pain), but his father named him Ben-jamin (Son-of-Good-Fortune).</verse>
<verse>Rachel died and was buried on the road to Ephrath, that is, Bethlehem.</verse>
<verse>Jacob set up a pillar to mark her grave. It is still there today, "Rachel's Grave Stone." [JC]</verse>
<verse>Israel kept on his way and set up camp at Migdal Eder.</verse>
<verse>While Israel was living in that region, Reuben went and slept with his father's concubine, Bilhah. And Israel heard of what he did. [JC] There were twelve sons of Jacob.</verse>
<verse>The sons by Leah: Reuben, Jacob's firstborn Simeon Levi Judah Issachar Zebulun.</verse>
<verse>The sons by Rachel: Joseph Benjamin.</verse>
<verse>The sons by Bilhah, Rachel's maid: Dan Naphtali.</verse>
<verse>The sons by Zilpah, Leah's maid: Gad Asher. These were Jacob's sons, born to him in Paddan Aram. [JC]</verse>
<verse>Finally, Jacob made it back home to his father Isaac at Mamre in Kiriath Arba, present-day Hebron, where Abraham and Isaac had lived.</verse>
<verse>Isaac was now 180 years old.</verse>
<verse>Isaac breathed his last and died--an old man full of years. He was buried with his family by his sons Esau and Jacob. [JC]</verse>
</chapter>