<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Genesis" book_id="1" n="36">
<verse>This is the family tree of Esau, who is also called Edom.</verse>
<verse>Esau married women of Canaan: Adah, daughter of Elon the Hittite; Oholibamah, daughter of Anah and the granddaughter of Zibeon the Hivite;</verse>
<verse>and Basemath, daughter of Ishmael and sister of Nebaioth.</verse>
<verse>Adah gave Esau Eliphaz; Basemath had Reuel;</verse>
<verse>Oholibamah had Jeush, Jalam, and Korah. These are the sons of Esau who were born to him in the land of Canaan.</verse>
<verse>Esau gathered up his wives, sons and daughters, and everybody in his household, along with all his livestock--all the animals and possessions he had gotten in Canaan--and moved a considerable distance away from his brother Jacob.</verse>
<verse>The brothers had too many possessions to live together in the same place; the land couldn't support their combined herds of livestock.</verse>
<verse>So Esau ended up settling in the hill country of Seir (Esau and Edom are the same).</verse>
<verse>So this is the family tree of Esau, ancestor of the people of Edom, in the hill country of Seir.</verse>
<verse>The names of Esau's sons: Eliphaz, son of Esau's wife Adah; Reuel, son of Esau's wife Basemath.</verse>
<verse>The sons of Eliphaz: Teman, Omar, Zepho, Gatam, and Kenaz.</verse>
<verse>(Eliphaz also had a concubine Timna, who had Amalek.) These are the grandsons of Esau's wife Adah.</verse>
<verse>And these are the sons of Reuel: Nahath, Zerah, Shammah, and Mizzah--grandsons of Esau's wife Basemath.</verse>
<verse>These are the sons of Esau's wife Oholibamah, daughter of Anah the son of Zibeon. She gave Esau his sons Jeush, Jalam, and Korah.</verse>
<verse>These are the chieftains in Esau's family tree. From the sons of Eliphaz, Esau's firstborn, came the chieftains Teman, Omar, Zepho, Kenaz,</verse>
<verse>Korah, Gatam, and Amalek--the chieftains of Eliphaz in the land of Edom; all of them sons of Adah.</verse>
<verse>From the sons of Esau's son Reuel, came the chieftains Nahath, Zerah, Shammah, and Mizzah. These are the chieftains of Reuel in the land of Edom; all these were sons of Esau's wife Basemath.</verse>
<verse>These are the sons of Esau's wife Oholibamah: the chieftains Jeush, Jalam, and Korah--chieftains born of Esau's wife Oholibamah, daughter of Anah.</verse>
<verse>These are the sons of Esau, that is, Edom, and these are their chieftains.</verse>
<verse>This is the family tree of Seir the Horite, who were native to that land: Lotan, Shobal, Zibeon, Anah,</verse>
<verse>Dishon, Ezer, and Dishan. These are the chieftains of the Horites, the sons of Seir in the land of Edom.</verse>
<verse>The sons of Lotan were Hori and Homam; Lotan's sister was Timna.</verse>
<verse>The sons of Shobal were Alvan, Manahath, Ebal, Shepho, and Onam.</verse>
<verse>The sons of Zibeon were Aiah and Anah--this is the same Anah who found the hot springs in the wilderness while herding his father Zibeon's donkeys.</verse>
<verse>The children of Anah were Dishon and his daughter Oholibamah.</verse>
<verse>The sons of Dishon were Hemdan, Eshban, Ithran, and Keran.</verse>
<verse>The sons of Ezer: Bilhan, Zaavan, and Akan.</verse>
<verse>The sons of Dishan: Uz and Aran.</verse>
<verse>And these were the Horite chieftains: Lotan, Shobal, Zibeon, Anah,</verse>
<verse>Dishon, Ezer, and Dishan--the Horite chieftains clan by clan in the land of Seir.</verse>
<verse>And these are the kings who ruled in Edom before there was a king in Israel:</verse>
<verse>Bela son of Beor was the king of Edom; the name of his city was Dinhabah.</verse>
<verse>When Bela died, Jobab son of Zerah from Bozrah became the next king.</verse>
<verse>When Jobab died, he was followed by Hushan from the land of the Temanites.</verse>
<verse>When Hushan died, he was followed by Hadad son of Bedad; he was the king who defeated the Midianites in Moab; the name of his city was Avith.</verse>
<verse>When Hadad died, Samlah of Masrekah became the next king.</verse>
<verse>When Samlah died, Shaul from Rehoboth-on-the-River became king.</verse>
<verse>When Shaul died, he was followed by Baal-Hanan son of Acbor.</verse>
<verse>When Baal-Hanan son of Acbor died, Hadad became king; the name of his city was Pau; his wife's name was Mehetabel daughter of Matred, daughter of Me-Zahab.</verse>
<verse>And these are the chieftains from the line of Esau, clan by clan, region by region: Timna, Alvah, Jetheth,</verse>
<verse>Oholibamah, Elah, Pinon,</verse>
<verse>Kenaz, Teman, Mibzar,</verse>
<verse>Magdiel, and Iram--the chieftains of Edom as they occupied their various regions. This accounts for the family tree of Esau, ancestor of all Edomites.</verse>
</chapter>