<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Genesis" book-id="1" n="4">
<verse>Adam slept with Eve his wife. She conceived and had Cain. She said, "I've gotten a man, with GOD's help!"</verse>
<verse>Then she had another baby, Abel. Abel was a herdsman and Cain a farmer.</verse>
<verse>Time passed. Cain brought an offering to GOD from the produce of his farm.</verse>
<verse>Abel also brought an offering, but from the firstborn animals of his herd, choice cuts of meat. GOD liked Abel and his offering,</verse>
<verse>but Cain and his offering didn't get his approval. Cain lost his temper and went into a sulk.</verse>
<verse>GOD spoke to Cain: "Why this tantrum? Why the sulking?</verse>
<verse>If you do well, won't you be accepted? And if you don't do well, sin is lying in wait for you, ready to pounce; it's out to get you, you've got to master it."</verse>
<verse>Cain had words with his brother. They were out in the field; Cain came at Abel his brother and killed him.</verse>
<verse>GOD said to Cain, "Where is Abel your brother?" He said, "How should I know? Am I his babysitter?"</verse>
<verse>GOD said, "What have you done! The voice of your brother's blood is calling to me from the ground.</verse>
<verse>From now on you'll get nothing but curses from this ground; you'll be driven from this ground that has opened its arms to receive the blood of your murdered brother.</verse>
<verse>You'll farm this ground, but it will no longer give you its best. You'll be a homeless wanderer on Earth."</verse>
<verse>Cain said to GOD, "My punishment is too much. I can't take it!</verse>
<verse>You've thrown me off the land and I can never again face you. I'm a homeless wanderer on Earth and whoever finds me will kill me."</verse>
<verse>GOD told him, "No. Anyone who kills Cain will pay for it seven times over." GOD put a mark on Cain to protect him so that no one who met him would kill him.</verse>
<verse>Cain left the presence of GOD and lived in No-Man's-Land, east of Eden.</verse>
<verse>Cain slept with his wife. She conceived and had Enoch. He then built a city and named it after his son, Enoch.</verse>
<verse>Enoch had Irad, Irad had Mehujael, Mehujael had Methushael, Methushael had Lamech.</verse>
<verse>Lamech married two wives, Adah and Zillah.</verse>
<verse>Adah gave birth to Jabal, the ancestor of all who live in tents and herd cattle.</verse>
<verse>His brother's name was Jubal, the ancestor of all who play the lyre and flute.</verse>
<verse>Zillah gave birth to Tubal-Cain, who worked at the forge making bronze and iron tools. Tubal-Cain's sister was Naamah.</verse>
<verse>Lamech said to his wives, Adah and Zillah, listen to me; you wives of Lamech, hear me out: I killed a man for wounding me, a young man who attacked me.</verse>
<verse>If Cain is avenged seven times, for Lamech it's seventy-seven!</verse>
<verse>Adam slept with his wife again. She had a son whom she named Seth. She said, "God has given me another child in place of Abel whom Cain killed."</verse>
<verse>And then Seth had a son whom he named Enosh. That's when men and women began praying and worshiping in the name of GOD.</verse>
</chapter>