<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Genesis" book-id="1" n="40">
<verse>As time went on, it happened that the cupbearer and the baker of the king of Egypt crossed their master, the king of Egypt.</verse>
<verse>Pharaoh was furious with his two officials, the head cupbearer and the head baker,</verse>
<verse>and put them in custody under the captain of the guard; it was the same jail where Joseph was held.</verse>
<verse>The captain of the guard assigned Joseph to see to their needs. After they had been in custody for a while,</verse>
<verse>the king's cupbearer and baker, while being held in the jail, both had a dream on the same night, each dream having its own meaning.</verse>
<verse>When Joseph arrived in the morning, he noticed that they were feeling low.</verse>
<verse>So he asked them, the two officials of Pharaoh who had been thrown into jail with him, "What's wrong? Why the long faces?"</verse>
<verse>They said, "We dreamed dreams and there's no one to interpret them." Joseph said, "Don't interpretations come from God? Tell me the dreams."</verse>
<verse>First the head cupbearer told his dream to Joseph: "In my dream there was a vine in front of me</verse>
<verse>with three branches on it: It budded, blossomed, and the clusters ripened into grapes.</verse>
<verse>I was holding Pharaoh's cup; I took the grapes, squeezed them into Pharaoh's cup, and gave the cup to Pharaoh."</verse>
<verse>Joseph said, "Here's the meaning. The three branches are three days.</verse>
<verse>Within three days, Pharaoh will get you out of here and put you back to your old work--you'll be giving Pharaoh his cup just as you used to do when you were his cupbearer.</verse>
<verse>Only remember me when things are going well with you again--tell Pharaoh about me and get me out of this place.</verse>
<verse>I was kidnapped from the land of the Hebrews. And since I've been here, I've done nothing to deserve being put in this hole."</verse>
<verse>When the head baker saw how well Joseph's interpretation turned out, he spoke up: "My dream went like this: I saw three wicker baskets on my head;</verse>
<verse>the top basket had assorted pastries from the bakery and birds were picking at them from the basket on my head."</verse>
<verse>Joseph said, "This is the interpretation: The three baskets are three days;</verse>
<verse>within three days Pharaoh will take off your head, impale you on a post, and the birds will pick your bones clean."</verse>
<verse>And sure enough, on the third day it was Pharaoh's birthday and he threw a feast for all his servants. He set the head cupbearer and the head baker in places of honor in the presence of all the guests.</verse>
<verse>Then he restored the head cupbearer to his cupbearing post; he handed Pharaoh his cup just as before.</verse>
<verse>And then he impaled the head baker on a post, following Joseph's interpretations exactly.</verse>
<verse>But the head cupbearer never gave Joseph another thought; he forgot all about him.</verse>
</chapter>