<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Genesis" book-id="1" n="5">
<verse>This is the family tree of the human race: When God created the human race, he made it godlike, with a nature akin to God.</verse>
<verse>He created both male and female and blessed them, the whole human race.</verse>
<verse>When Adam was 130 years old, he had a son who was just like him, his very spirit and image, and named him Seth.</verse>
<verse>After the birth of Seth, Adam lived another 800 years, having more sons and daughters.</verse>
<verse>Adam lived a total of 930 years. And he died.</verse>
<verse>When Seth was 105 years old, he had Enosh.</verse>
<verse>After Seth had Enosh, he lived another 807 years, having more sons and daughters.</verse>
<verse>Seth lived a total of 912 years. And he died.</verse>
<verse>When Enosh was ninety years old, he had Kenan.</verse>
<verse>After he had Kenan, he lived another 815 years, having more sons and daughters.</verse>
<verse>Enosh lived a total of 905 years. And he died.</verse>
<verse>When Kenan was seventy years old, he had Mahalalel.</verse>
<verse>After he had Mahalalel, he lived another 840 years, having more sons and daughters.</verse>
<verse>Kenan lived a total of 910 years. And he died.</verse>
<verse>When Mahalalel was sixty-five years old, he had Jared.</verse>
<verse>After he had Jared, he lived another 830 years, having more sons and daughters.</verse>
<verse>Mahalalel lived a total of 895 years. And he died.</verse>
<verse>When Jared was 162 years old, he had Enoch.</verse>
<verse>After he had Enoch, he lived another 800 years, having more sons and daughters.</verse>
<verse>Jared lived a total of 962 years. And he died.</verse>
<verse>When Enoch was sixty-five years old, he had Methuselah.</verse>
<verse>Enoch walked steadily with God. After he had Methuselah, he lived another 300 years, having more sons and daughters.</verse>
<verse>Enoch lived a total of 365 years.</verse>
<verse>Enoch walked steadily with God. And then one day he was simply gone: God took him.</verse>
<verse>When Methuselah was 187 years old, he had Lamech.</verse>
<verse>After he had Lamech, he lived another 782 years.</verse>
<verse>Methuselah lived a total of 969 years. And he died.</verse>
<verse>When Lamech was 182 years old, he had a son.</verse>
<verse>He named him Noah, saying, "This one will give us a break from the hard work of farming the ground that GOD cursed."</verse>
<verse>After Lamech had Noah, he lived another 595 years, having more sons and daughters.</verse>
<verse>Lamech lived a total of 777 years. And he died.</verse>
<verse>When Noah was 500 years old, he had Shem, Ham, and Japheth.</verse>
</chapter>