<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Genesis" book_id="1" n="7">
<verse>Next GOD said to Noah, "Now board the ship, you and all your family--out of everyone in this generation, you're the righteous one.</verse>
<verse>"Take on board with you seven pairs of every clean animal, a male and a female; one pair of every unclean animal, a male and a female;</verse>
<verse>and seven pairs of every kind of bird, a male and a female, to insure their survival on Earth.</verse>
<verse>In just seven days I will dump rain on Earth for forty days and forty nights. I'll make a clean sweep of everything that I've made."</verse>
<verse>Noah did everything GOD commanded him.</verse>
<verse>Noah was 600 years old when the floodwaters covered the Earth.</verse>
<verse>Noah and his wife and sons and their wives boarded the ship to escape the flood.</verse>
<verse>Clean and unclean animals, birds, and all the crawling creatures</verse>
<verse>came in pairs to Noah and to the ship, male and female, just as God had commanded Noah.</verse>
<verse>In seven days the floodwaters came.</verse>
<verse>It was the six-hundredth year of Noah's life, in the second month, on the seventeenth day of the month that it happened: all the underground springs erupted and all the windows of Heaven were thrown open.</verse>
<verse>Rain poured for forty days and forty nights.</verse>
<verse>That's the day Noah and his sons Shem, Ham, and Japheth, accompanied by his wife and his sons' wives, boarded the ship.</verse>
<verse>And with them every kind of wild and domestic animal, right down to all the kinds of creatures that crawl and all kinds of birds and anything that flies.</verse>
<verse>They came to Noah and to the ship in pairs--everything and anything that had the breath of life in it,</verse>
<verse>male and female of every creature came just as God had commanded Noah. Then GOD shut the door behind him.</verse>
<verse>The flood continued forty days and the waters rose and lifted the ship high over the Earth.</verse>
<verse>The waters kept rising, the flood deepened on the Earth, the ship floated on the surface.</verse>
<verse>The flood got worse until all the highest mountains were covered</verse>
<verse>-the high water mark reached twenty feet above the crest of the mountains.</verse>
<verse>Everything died. Anything that moved-dead. Birds, farm animals, wild animals, the entire teeming exuberance of life--dead. And all people--dead.</verse>
<verse>Every living, breathing creature that lived on dry land died;</verse>
<verse>he wiped out the whole works-people and animals, crawling creatures and flying birds, every last one of them, gone. Only Noah and his company on the ship lived.</verse>
<verse>The floodwaters took over for 150 days.</verse>
</chapter>