<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Genesis" book-id="1" n="9">
<verse>God blessed Noah and his sons: He said, "Prosper! Reproduce! Fill the Earth!</verse>
<verse>Every living creature--birds, animals, fish--will fall under your spell and be afraid of you. You're responsible for them.</verse>
<verse>All living creatures are yours for food; just as I gave you the plants, now I give you everything else.</verse>
<verse>Except for meat with its lifeblood still in it--don't eat that.</verse>
<verse>"But your own lifeblood I will avenge; I will avenge it against both animals and other humans.</verse>
<verse>Whoever sheds human blood, by humans let his blood be shed, Because God made humans in his image reflecting God's very nature.</verse>
<verse>You're here to bear fruit, reproduce, lavish life on the Earth, live bountifully!"</verse>
<verse>Then God spoke to Noah and his sons:</verse>
<verse>"I'm setting up my covenant with you including your children who will come after you,</verse>
<verse>along with everything alive around you--birds, farm animals, wild animals--that came out of the ship with you.</verse>
<verse>I'm setting up my covenant with you that never again will everything living be destroyed by floodwaters; no, never again will a flood destroy the Earth."</verse>
<verse>God continued, "This is the sign of the covenant I am making between me and you and everything living around you and everyone living after you.</verse>
<verse>I'm putting my rainbow in the clouds, a sign of the covenant between me and the Earth.</verse>
<verse>From now on, when I form a cloud over the Earth and the rainbow appears in the cloud,</verse>
<verse>I'll remember my covenant between me and you and everything living, that never again will floodwaters destroy all life.</verse>
<verse>When the rainbow appears in the cloud, I'll see it and remember the eternal covenant between God and everything living, every last living creature on Earth."</verse>
<verse>And God said, "This is the sign of the covenant that I've set up between me and everything living on the Earth."</verse>
<verse>The sons of Noah who came out of the ship were Shem, Ham, and Japheth. Ham was the father of Canaan.</verse>
<verse>These are the three sons of Noah; from these three the whole Earth was populated.</verse>
<verse>Noah, a farmer, was the first to plant a vineyard.</verse>
<verse>He drank from its wine, got drunk and passed out, naked in his tent.</verse>
<verse>Ham, the father of Canaan, saw that his father was naked and told his two brothers who were outside the tent.</verse>
<verse>Shem and Japheth took a cloak, held it between them from their shoulders, walked backwards and covered their father's nakedness, keeping their faces turned away so they did not see their father's exposed body.</verse>
<verse>When Noah woke up with his hangover, he learned what his youngest son had done.</verse>
<verse>He said, Cursed be Canaan! A slave of slaves, a slave to his brothers!</verse>
<verse>Blessed be GOD, the God of Shem, but Canaan shall be his slave.</verse>
<verse>God prosper Japheth, living spaciously in the tents of Shem. But Canaan shall be his slave.</verse>
<verse>Noah lived another 350 years following the flood.</verse>
<verse>He lived a total of 950 years. And he died. The Family Tree of Noah's Sons</verse>
</chapter>