<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Leviticus" book-id="3" n="1">
<verse>The LORD called to Moses and spoke to him from the Tent of Meeting. He said,</verse>
<verse>"Speak to the Israelites and say to them: 'When any of you brings an offering to the LORD, bring as your offering an animal from either the herd or the flock.</verse>
<verse>"'If the offering is a burnt offering from the herd, he is to offer a male without defect. He must present it at the entrance to the Tent of Meeting so that it will be acceptable to the LORD.</verse>
<verse>He is to lay his hand on the head of the burnt offering, and it will be accepted on his behalf to make atonement for him.</verse>
<verse>He is to slaughter the young bull before the LORD, and then Aaron's sons the priests shall bring the blood and sprinkle it against the altar on all sides at the entrance to the Tent of Meeting.</verse>
<verse>He is to skin the burnt offering and cut it into pieces.</verse>
<verse>The sons of Aaron the priest are to put fire on the altar and arrange wood on the fire.</verse>
<verse>Then Aaron's sons the priests shall arrange the pieces, including the head and the fat, on the burning wood that is on the altar.</verse>
<verse>He is to wash the inner parts and the legs with water, and the priest is to burn all of it on the altar. It is a burnt offering, an offering made by fire, an aroma pleasing to the LORD.</verse>
<verse>"'If the offering is a burnt offering from the flock, from either the sheep or the goats, he is to offer a male without defect.</verse>
<verse>He is to slaughter it at the north side of the altar before the LORD, and Aaron's sons the priests shall sprinkle its blood against the altar on all sides.</verse>
<verse>He is to cut it into pieces, and the priest shall arrange them, including the head and the fat, on the burning wood that is on the altar.</verse>
<verse>He is to wash the inner parts and the legs with water, and the priest is to bring all of it and burn it on the altar. It is a burnt offering, an offering made by fire, an aroma pleasing to the LORD.</verse>
<verse>"'If the offering to the LORD is a burnt offering of birds, he is to offer a dove or a young pigeon.</verse>
<verse>The priest shall bring it to the altar, wring off the head and burn it on the altar; its blood shall be drained out on the side of the altar.</verse>
<verse>He is to remove the crop with its contents and throw it to the east side of the altar, where the ashes are.</verse>
<verse>He shall tear it open by the wings, not severing it completely, and then the priest shall burn it on the wood that is on the fire on the altar. It is a burnt offering, an offering made by fire, an aroma pleasing to the LORD.</verse>
</chapter>