<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Leviticus" book_id="3" n="24">
<verse>The LORD said to Moses,</verse>
<verse>"Command the Israelites to bring you clear oil of pressed olives for the light so that the lamps may be kept burning continually.</verse>
<verse>Outside the curtain of the Testimony in the Tent of Meeting, Aaron is to tend the lamps before the LORD from evening till morning, continually. This is to be a lasting ordinance for the generations to come.</verse>
<verse>The lamps on the pure gold lampstand before the LORD must be tended continually.</verse>
<verse>"Take fine flour and bake twelve loaves of bread, using two-tenths of an ephah for each loaf.</verse>
<verse>Set them in two rows, six in each row, on the table of pure gold before the LORD.</verse>
<verse>Along each row put some pure incense as a memorial portion to represent the bread and to be an offering made to the LORD by fire.</verse>
<verse>This bread is to be set out before the LORD regularly, Sabbath after Sabbath, on behalf of the Israelites, as a lasting covenant.</verse>
<verse>It belongs to Aaron and his sons, who are to eat it in a holy place, because it is a most holy part of their regular share of the offerings made to the LORD by fire." A Blasphemer Stoned</verse>
<verse>Now the son of an Israelite mother and an Egyptian father went out among the Israelites, and a fight broke out in the camp between him and an Israelite.</verse>
<verse>The son of the Israelite woman blasphemed the Name with a curse; so they brought him to Moses. (His mother's name was Shelomith, the daughter of Dibri the Danite.)</verse>
<verse>They put him in custody until the will of the LORD should be made clear to them.</verse>
<verse>Then the LORD said to Moses:</verse>
<verse>"Take the blasphemer outside the camp. All those who heard him are to lay their hands on his head, and the entire assembly is to stone him.</verse>
<verse>Say to the Israelites: 'If anyone curses his God, he will be held responsible;</verse>
<verse>anyone who blasphemes the name of the LORD must be put to death. The entire assembly must stone him. Whether an alien or native-born, when he blasphemes the Name, he must be put to death.</verse>
<verse>"'If anyone takes the life of a human being, he must be put to death.</verse>
<verse>Anyone who takes the life of someone's animal must make restitution-life for life.</verse>
<verse>If anyone injures his neighbor, whatever he has done must be done to him:</verse>
<verse>fracture for fracture, eye for eye, tooth for tooth. As he has injured the other, so he is to be injured.</verse>
<verse>Whoever kills an animal must make restitution, but whoever kills a man must be put to death.</verse>
<verse>You are to have the same law for the alien and the native-born. I am the LORD your God.'"</verse>
<verse>Then Moses spoke to the Israelites, and they took the blasphemer outside the camp and stoned him. The Israelites did as the LORD commanded Moses.</verse>
</chapter>