<chapter translation="ESV" testament="Old" book="Job" book-id="18" n="12">
<verse>Then Job answered and said:</verse>
<verse>"No doubt you are the people, and wisdom will die with you.</verse>
<verse>But I have understanding as well as you; I am not inferior to you. Who does not know such things as these?</verse>
<verse>I am a laughingstock to my friends; I, who called to God and he answered me, a just and blameless man, am a laughingstock.</verse>
<verse>In the thought of one who is at ease there is contempt for misfortune; it is ready for those whose feet slip.</verse>
<verse>The tents of robbers are at peace, and those who provoke God are secure, who bring their god in their hand.</verse>
<verse>"But ask the beasts, and they will teach you; the birds of the heavens, and they will tell you;</verse>
<verse>or the bushes of the earth, and they will teach you; and the fish of the sea will declare to you.</verse>
<verse>Who among all these does not know that the hand of the LORD has done this?</verse>
<verse>In his hand is the life of every living thing and the breath of all mankind.</verse>
<verse>Does not the ear test words as the palate tastes food?</verse>
<verse>Wisdom is with the aged, and understanding in length of days.</verse>
<verse>"With God are wisdom and might; he has counsel and understanding.</verse>
<verse>If he tears down, none can rebuild; if he shuts a man in, none can open.</verse>
<verse>If he withholds the waters, they dry up; if he sends them out, they overwhelm the land.</verse>
<verse>With him are strength and sound wisdom; the deceived and the deceiver are his.</verse>
<verse>He leads counselors away stripped, and judges he makes fools.</verse>
<verse>He looses the bonds of kings and binds a waistcloth on their hips.</verse>
<verse>He leads priests away stripped and overthrows the mighty.</verse>
<verse>He deprives of speech those who are trusted and takes away the discernment of the elders.</verse>
<verse>He pours contempt on princes and loosens the belt of the strong.</verse>
<verse>He uncovers the deeps out of darkness and brings deep darkness to light.</verse>
<verse>He makes nations great, and he destroys them; he enlarges nations, and leads them away.</verse>
<verse>He takes away understanding from the chiefs of the people of the earth and makes them wander in a pathless waste.</verse>
<verse>They grope in the dark without light, and he makes them stagger like a drunken man.</verse>
</chapter>