<chapter translation="ESV" testament="Old" book="Job" book-id="18" n="15">
<verse>Then Eliphaz the Temanite answered and said:</verse>
<verse>"Should a wise man answer with windy knowledge, and fill his belly with the east wind?</verse>
<verse>Should he argue in unprofitable talk, or in words with which he can do no good?</verse>
<verse>But you are doing away with the fear of God and hindering meditation before God.</verse>
<verse>For your iniquity teaches your mouth, and you choose the tongue of the crafty.</verse>
<verse>Your own mouth condemns you, and not I; your own lips testify against you.</verse>
<verse>"Are you the first man who was born? Or were you brought forth before the hills?</verse>
<verse>Have you listened in the council of God? And do you limit wisdom to yourself?</verse>
<verse>What do you know that we do not know? What do you understand that is not clear to us?</verse>
<verse>Both the gray-haired and the aged are among us, older than your father.</verse>
<verse>Are the comforts of God too small for you, or the word that deals gently with you?</verse>
<verse>Why does your heart carry you away, and why do your eyes flash,</verse>
<verse>that you turn your spirit against God and bring such words out of your mouth?</verse>
<verse>What is man, that he can be pure? Or he who is born of a woman, that he can be righteous?</verse>
<verse>Behold, God puts no trust in his holy ones, and the heavens are not pure in his sight;</verse>
<verse>how much less one who is abominable and corrupt, a man who drinks injustice like water!</verse>
<verse>"I will show you; hear me, and what I have seen I will declare</verse>
<verse>(what wise men have told, without hiding it from their fathers,</verse>
<verse>to whom alone the land was given, and no stranger passed among them).</verse>
<verse>The wicked man writhes in pain all his days, through all the years that are laid up for the ruthless.</verse>
<verse>Dreadful sounds are in his ears; in prosperity the destroyer will come upon him.</verse>
<verse>He does not believe that he will return out of darkness, and he is marked for the sword.</verse>
<verse>He wanders abroad for bread, saying, 'Where is it?' He knows that a day of darkness is ready at his hand;</verse>
<verse>distress and anguish terrify him; they prevail against him, like a king ready for battle.</verse>
<verse>Because he has stretched out his hand against God and defies the Almighty,</verse>
<verse>running stubbornly against him with a thickly bossed shield;</verse>
<verse>because he has covered his face with his fat and gathered fat upon his waist</verse>
<verse>and has lived in desolate cities, in houses that none should inhabit, which were ready to become heaps of ruins;</verse>
<verse>he will not be rich, and his wealth will not endure, nor will his possessions spread over the earth;</verse>
<verse>he will not depart from darkness; the flame will dry up his shoots, and by the breath of his mouth he will depart.</verse>
<verse>Let him not trust in emptiness, deceiving himself, for emptiness will be his payment.</verse>
<verse>It will be paid in full before his time, and his branch will not be green.</verse>
<verse>He will shake off his unripe grape like the vine, and cast off his blossom like the olive tree.</verse>
<verse>For the company of the godless is barren, and fire consumes the tents of bribery.</verse>
<verse>They conceive trouble and give birth to evil, and their womb prepares deceit."</verse>
</chapter>