<chapter translation="ESV" testament="Old" book="Job" book_id="18" n="20">
<verse>Then Zophar the Naamathite answered and said:</verse>
<verse>"Therefore my thoughts answer me, because of my haste within me.</verse>
<verse>I hear censure that insults me, and out of my understanding a spirit answers me.</verse>
<verse>Do you not know this from of old, since man was placed on earth,</verse>
<verse>that the exulting of the wicked is short, and the joy of the godless but for a moment?</verse>
<verse>Though his height mount up to the heavens, and his head reach to the clouds,</verse>
<verse>he will perish forever like his own dung; those who have seen him will say, 'Where is he?'</verse>
<verse>He will fly away like a dream and not be found; he will be chased away like a vision of the night.</verse>
<verse>The eye that saw him will see him no more, nor will his place any more behold him.</verse>
<verse>His children will seek the favor of the poor, and his hands will give back his wealth.</verse>
<verse>His bones are full of his youthful vigor, but it will lie down with him in the dust.</verse>
<verse>"Though evil is sweet in his mouth, though he hides it under his tongue,</verse>
<verse>though he is loath to let it go and holds it in his mouth,</verse>
<verse>yet his food is turned in his stomach; it is the venom of cobras within him.</verse>
<verse>He swallows down riches and vomits them up again; God casts them out of his belly.</verse>
<verse>He will suck the poison of cobras; the tongue of a viper will kill him.</verse>
<verse>He will not look upon the rivers, the streams flowing with honey and curds.</verse>
<verse>He will give back the fruit of his toil and will not swallow it down; from the profit of his trading he will get no enjoyment.</verse>
<verse>For he has crushed and abandoned the poor; he has seized a house that he did not build.</verse>
<verse>"Because he knew no contentment in his belly, he will not let anything in which he delights escape him.</verse>
<verse>There was nothing left after he had eaten; therefore his prosperity will not endure.</verse>
<verse>In the fullness of his sufficiency he will be in distress; the hand of everyone in misery will come against him.</verse>
<verse>To fill his belly to the full God will send his burning anger against him and rain it upon him into his body.</verse>
<verse>He will flee from an iron weapon; a bronze arrow will strike him through.</verse>
<verse>It is drawn forth and comes out of his body; the glittering point comes out of his gallbladder; terrors come upon him.</verse>
<verse>Utter darkness is laid up for his treasures; a fire not fanned will devour him; what is left in his tent will be consumed.</verse>
<verse>The heavens will reveal his iniquity, and the earth will rise up against him.</verse>
<verse>The possessions of his house will be carried away, dragged off in the day of God's wrath.</verse>
<verse>This is the wicked man's portion from God, the heritage decreed for him by God."</verse>
</chapter>