<chapter translation="ESV" testament="Old" book="Job" book_id="18" n="21">
<verse>Then Job answered and said:</verse>
<verse>"Keep listening to my words, and let this be your comfort.</verse>
<verse>Bear with me, and I will speak, and after I have spoken, mock on.</verse>
<verse>As for me, is my complaint against man? Why should I not be impatient?</verse>
<verse>Look at me and be appalled, and lay your hand over your mouth.</verse>
<verse>When I remember I am dismayed, and shuddering seizes my flesh.</verse>
<verse>Why do the wicked live, reach old age, and grow mighty in power?</verse>
<verse>Their offspring are established in their presence, and their descendants before their eyes.</verse>
<verse>Their houses are safe from fear, and no rod of God is upon them.</verse>
<verse>Their bull breeds without fail; their cow calves and does not miscarry.</verse>
<verse>They send out their little boys like a flock, and their children dance.</verse>
<verse>They sing to the tambourine and the lyre and rejoice to the sound of the pipe.</verse>
<verse>They spend their days in prosperity, and in peace they go down to Sheol.</verse>
<verse>They say to God, 'Depart from us! We do not desire the knowledge of your ways.</verse>
<verse>What is the Almighty, that we should serve him? And what profit do we get if we pray to him?'</verse>
<verse>Behold, is not their prosperity in their hand? The counsel of the wicked is far from me.</verse>
<verse>"How often is it that the lamp of the wicked is put out? That their calamity comes upon them? That God distributes pains in his anger?</verse>
<verse>That they are like straw before the wind, and like chaff that the storm carries away?</verse>
<verse>You say, 'God stores up their iniquity for their children.' Let him pay it out to them, that they may know it.</verse>
<verse>Let their own eyes see their destruction, and let them drink of the wrath of the Almighty.</verse>
<verse>For what do they care for their houses after them, when the number of their months is cut off?</verse>
<verse>Will any teach God knowledge, seeing that he judges those who are on high?</verse>
<verse>One dies in his full vigor, being wholly at ease and secure,</verse>
<verse>his pails full of milk and the marrow of his bones moist.</verse>
<verse>Another dies in bitterness of soul, never having tasted of prosperity.</verse>
<verse>They lie down alike in the dust, and the worms cover them.</verse>
<verse>"Behold, I know your thoughts and your schemes to wrong me.</verse>
<verse>For you say, 'Where is the house of the prince? Where is the tent in which the wicked lived?'</verse>
<verse>Have you not asked those who travel the roads, and do you not accept their testimony</verse>
<verse>that the evil man is spared in the day of calamity, that he is rescued in the day of wrath?</verse>
<verse>Who declares his way to his face, and who repays him for what he has done?</verse>
<verse>When he is carried to the grave, watch is kept over his tomb.</verse>
<verse>The clods of the valley are sweet to him; all mankind follows after him, and those who go before him are innumerable.</verse>
<verse>How then will you comfort me with empty nothings? There is nothing left of your answers but falsehood."</verse>
</chapter>