<chapter translation="ESV" testament="Old" book="Job" book_id="18" n="27">
<verse>And Job again took up his discourse, and said:</verse>
<verse>"As God lives, who has taken away my right, and the Almighty, who has made my soul bitter,</verse>
<verse>as long as my breath is in me, and the spirit of God is in my nostrils,</verse>
<verse>my lips will not speak falsehood, and my tongue will not utter deceit.</verse>
<verse>Far be it from me to say that you are right; till I die I will not put away my integrity from me.</verse>
<verse>I hold fast my righteousness and will not let it go; my heart does not reproach me for any of my days.</verse>
<verse>"Let my enemy be as the wicked, and let him who rises up against me be as the unrighteous.</verse>
<verse>For what is the hope of the godless when God cuts him off, when God takes away his life?</verse>
<verse>Will God hear his cry when distress comes upon him?</verse>
<verse>Will he take delight in the Almighty? Will he call upon God at all times?</verse>
<verse>I will teach you concerning the hand of God; what is with the Almighty I will not conceal.</verse>
<verse>Behold, all of you have seen it yourselves; why then have you become altogether vain?</verse>
<verse>"This is the portion of a wicked man with God, and the heritage that oppressors receive from the Almighty:</verse>
<verse>If his children are multiplied, it is for the sword, and his descendants have not enough bread.</verse>
<verse>Those who survive him the pestilence buries, and his widows do not weep.</verse>
<verse>Though he heap up silver like dust, and pile up clothing like clay,</verse>
<verse>he may pile it up, but the righteous will wear it, and the innocent will divide the silver.</verse>
<verse>He builds his house like a moth's, like a booth that a watchman makes.</verse>
<verse>He goes to bed rich, but will do so no more; he opens his eyes, and his wealth is gone.</verse>
<verse>Terrors overtake him like a flood; in the night a whirlwind carries him off.</verse>
<verse>The east wind lifts him up and he is gone; it sweeps him out of his place.</verse>
<verse>It hurls at him without pity; he flees from its power in headlong flight.</verse>
<verse>It claps its hands at him and hisses at him from its place.</verse>
</chapter>