<chapter translation="ESV" testament="Old" book="Job" book_id="18" n="29">
<verse>And Job again took up his discourse, and said:</verse>
<verse>"Oh, that I were as in the months of old, as in the days when God watched over me,</verse>
<verse>when his lamp shone upon my head, and by his light I walked through darkness,</verse>
<verse>as I was in my prime, when the friendship of God was upon my tent,</verse>
<verse>when the Almighty was yet with me, when my children were all around me,</verse>
<verse>when my steps were washed with butter, and the rock poured out for me streams of oil!</verse>
<verse>When I went out to the gate of the city, when I prepared my seat in the square,</verse>
<verse>the young men saw me and withdrew, and the aged rose and stood;</verse>
<verse>the princes refrained from talking and laid their hand on their mouth;</verse>
<verse>the voice of the nobles was hushed, and their tongue stuck to the roof of their mouth.</verse>
<verse>When the ear heard, it called me blessed, and when the eye saw, it approved,</verse>
<verse>because I delivered the poor who cried for help, and the fatherless who had none to help him.</verse>
<verse>The blessing of him who was about to perish came upon me, and I caused the widow's heart to sing for joy.</verse>
<verse>I put on righteousness, and it clothed me; my justice was like a robe and a turban.</verse>
<verse>I was eyes to the blind and feet to the lame.</verse>
<verse>I was a father to the needy, and I searched out the cause of him whom I did not know.</verse>
<verse>I broke the fangs of the unrighteous and made him drop his prey from his teeth.</verse>
<verse>Then I thought, 'I shall die in my nest, and I shall multiply my days as the sand,</verse>
<verse>my roots spread out to the waters, with the dew all night on my branches,</verse>
<verse>my glory fresh with me, and my bow ever new in my hand.'</verse>
<verse>"Men listened to me and waited and kept silence for my counsel.</verse>
<verse>After I spoke they did not speak again, and my word dropped upon them.</verse>
<verse>They waited for me as for the rain, and they opened their mouths as for the spring rain.</verse>
<verse>I smiled on them when they had no confidence, and the light of my face they did not cast down.</verse>
<verse>I chose their way and sat as chief, and I lived like a king among his troops, like one who comforts mourners.</verse>
</chapter>