<chapter translation="ESV" testament="Old" book="Job" book-id="18" n="30">
<verse>"But now they laugh at me, men who are younger than I, whose fathers I would have disdained to set with the dogs of my flock.</verse>
<verse>What could I gain from the strength of their hands, men whose vigor is gone?</verse>
<verse>Through want and hard hunger they gnaw the dry ground by night in waste and desolation;</verse>
<verse>they pick saltwort and the leaves of bushes, and the roots of the broom tree for their food.</verse>
<verse>They are driven out from human company; they shout after them as after a thief.</verse>
<verse>In the gullies of the torrents they must dwell, in holes of the earth and of the rocks.</verse>
<verse>Among the bushes they bray; under the nettles they huddle together.</verse>
<verse>A senseless, a nameless brood, they have been whipped out of the land.</verse>
<verse>"And now I have become their song; I am a byword to them.</verse>
<verse>They abhor me; they keep aloof from me; they do not hesitate to spit at the sight of me.</verse>
<verse>Because God has loosed my cord and humbled me, they have cast off restraint in my presence.</verse>
<verse>On my right hand the rabble rise; they push away my feet; they cast up against me their ways of destruction.</verse>
<verse>They break up my path; they promote my calamity; they need no one to help them.</verse>
<verse>As through a wide breach they come; amid the crash they roll on.</verse>
<verse>Terrors are turned upon me; my honor is pursued as by the wind, and my prosperity has passed away like a cloud.</verse>
<verse>"And now my soul is poured out within me; days of affliction have taken hold of me.</verse>
<verse>The night racks my bones, and the pain that gnaws me takes no rest.</verse>
<verse>With great force my garment is disfigured; it binds me about like the collar of my tunic.</verse>
<verse>God has cast me into the mire, and I have become like dust and ashes.</verse>
<verse>I cry to you for help and you do not answer me; I stand, and you only look at me.</verse>
<verse>You have turned cruel to me; with the might of your hand you persecute me.</verse>
<verse>You lift me up on the wind; you make me ride on it, and you toss me about in the roar of the storm.</verse>
<verse>For I know that you will bring me to death and to the house appointed for all living.</verse>
<verse>"Yet does not one in a heap of ruins stretch out his hand, and in his disaster cry for help?</verse>
<verse>Did not I weep for him whose day was hard? Was not my soul grieved for the needy?</verse>
<verse>But when I hoped for good, evil came, and when I waited for light, darkness came.</verse>
<verse>My inward parts are in turmoil and never still; days of affliction come to meet me.</verse>
<verse>I go about darkened, but not by the sun; I stand up in the assembly and cry for help.</verse>
<verse>I am a brother of jackals and a companion of ostriches.</verse>
<verse>My skin turns black and falls from me, and my bones burn with heat.</verse>
<verse>My lyre is turned to mourning, and my pipe to the voice of those who weep.</verse>
</chapter>