<chapter translation="ESV" testament="Old" book="Job" book_id="18" n="31">
<verse>"I have made a covenant with my eyes; how then could I gaze at a virgin?</verse>
<verse>What would be my portion from God above and my heritage from the Almighty on high?</verse>
<verse>Is not calamity for the unrighteous, and disaster for the workers of iniquity?</verse>
<verse>Does not he see my ways and number all my steps?</verse>
<verse>"If I have walked with falsehood and my foot has hastened to deceit;</verse>
<verse>(Let me be weighed in a just balance, and let God know my integrity!)</verse>
<verse>if my step has turned aside from the way and my heart has gone after my eyes, and if any spot has stuck to my hands,</verse>
<verse>then let me sow, and another eat, and let what grows for me be rooted out.</verse>
<verse>"If my heart has been enticed toward a woman, and I have lain in wait at my neighbor's door,</verse>
<verse>then let my wife grind for another, and let others bow down on her.</verse>
<verse>For that would be a heinous crime; that would be an iniquity to be punished by the judges;</verse>
<verse>for that would be a fire that consumes as far as Abaddon, and it would burn to the root all my increase.</verse>
<verse>"If I have rejected the cause of my manservant or my maidservant, when they brought a complaint against me,</verse>
<verse>what then shall I do when God rises up? When he makes inquiry, what shall I answer him?</verse>
<verse>Did not he who made me in the womb make him? And did not one fashion us in the womb?</verse>
<verse>"If I have withheld anything that the poor desired, or have caused the eyes of the widow to fail,</verse>
<verse>or have eaten my morsel alone, and the fatherless has not eaten of it</verse>
<verse>(for from my youth the fatherless grew up with me as with a father, and from my mother's womb I guided the widow ),</verse>
<verse>if I have seen anyone perish for lack of clothing, or the needy without covering,</verse>
<verse>if his body has not blessed me, and if he was not warmed with the fleece of my sheep,</verse>
<verse>if I have raised my hand against the fatherless, because I saw my help in the gate,</verse>
<verse>then let my shoulder blade fall from my shoulder, and let my arm be broken from its socket.</verse>
<verse>For I was in terror of calamity from God, and I could not have faced his majesty.</verse>
<verse>"If I have made gold my trust or called fine gold my confidence,</verse>
<verse>if I have rejoiced because my wealth was abundant or because my hand had found much,</verse>
<verse>if I have looked at the sun when it shone, or the moon moving in splendor,</verse>
<verse>and my heart has been secretly enticed, and my mouth has kissed my hand,</verse>
<verse>this also would be an iniquity to be punished by the judges, for I would have been false to God above.</verse>
<verse>"If I have rejoiced at the ruin of him who hated me, or exulted when evil overtook him</verse>
<verse>(I have not let my mouth sin by asking for his life with a curse),</verse>
<verse>if the men of my tent have not said, 'Who is there that has not been filled with his meat?'</verse>
<verse>(the sojourner has not lodged in the street; I have opened my doors to the traveler),</verse>
<verse>if I have concealed my transgressions as others do by hiding my iniquity in my bosom,</verse>
<verse>because I stood in great fear of the multitude, and the contempt of families terrified me, so that I kept silence, and did not go out of doors--</verse>
<verse>Oh, that I had one to hear me! (Here is my signature! Let the Almighty answer me!) Oh, that I had the indictment written by my adversary!</verse>
<verse>Surely I would carry it on my shoulder; I would bind it on me as a crown;</verse>
<verse>I would give him an account of all my steps; like a prince I would approach him.</verse>
<verse>"If my land has cried out against me and its furrows have wept together,</verse>
<verse>if I have eaten its yield without payment and made its owners breathe their last,</verse>
<verse>let thorns grow instead of wheat, and foul weeds instead of barley."The words of Job are ended.</verse>
</chapter>