<chapter translation="ESV" testament="Old" book="Job" book_id="18" n="34">
<verse>Then Elihu answered and said:</verse>
<verse>"Hear my words, you wise men, and give ear to me, you who know;</verse>
<verse>for the ear tests words as the palate tastes food.</verse>
<verse>Let us choose what is right; let us know among ourselves what is good.</verse>
<verse>For Job has said, 'I am in the right, and God has taken away my right;</verse>
<verse>in spite of my right I am counted a liar; my wound is incurable, though I am without transgression.'</verse>
<verse>What man is like Job, who drinks up scoffing like water,</verse>
<verse>who travels in company with evildoers and walks with wicked men?</verse>
<verse>For he has said, 'It profits a man nothing that he should take delight in God.'</verse>
<verse>"Therefore, hear me, you men of understanding: far be it from God that he should do wickedness, and from the Almighty that he should do wrong.</verse>
<verse>For according to the work of a man he will repay him, and according to his ways he will make it befall him.</verse>
<verse>Of a truth, God will not do wickedly, and the Almighty will not pervert justice.</verse>
<verse>Who gave him charge over the earth, and who laid on him the whole world?</verse>
<verse>If he should set his heart to it and gather to himself his spirit and his breath,</verse>
<verse>all flesh would perish together, and man would return to dust.</verse>
<verse>"If you have understanding, hear this; listen to what I say.</verse>
<verse>Shall one who hates justice govern? Will you condemn him who is righteous and mighty,</verse>
<verse>who says to a king, 'Worthless one,' and to nobles, 'Wicked man,'</verse>
<verse>who shows no partiality to princes, nor regards the rich more than the poor, for they are all the work of his hands?</verse>
<verse>In a moment they die; at midnight the people are shaken and pass away, and the mighty are taken away by no human hand.</verse>
<verse>"For his eyes are on the ways of a man, and he sees all his steps.</verse>
<verse>There is no gloom or deep darkness where evildoers may hide themselves.</verse>
<verse>For God has no need to consider a man further, that he should go before God in judgment.</verse>
<verse>He shatters the mighty without investigation and sets others in their place.</verse>
<verse>Thus, knowing their works, he overturns them in the night, and they are crushed.</verse>
<verse>He strikes them for their wickedness in a place for all to see,</verse>
<verse>because they turned aside from following him and had no regard for any of his ways,</verse>
<verse>so that they caused the cry of the poor to come to him, and he heard the cry of the afflicted--</verse>
<verse>When he is quiet, who can condemn? When he hides his face, who can behold him, whether it be a nation or a man?--</verse>
<verse>that a godless man should not reign, that he should not ensnare the people.</verse>
<verse>"For has anyone said to God, 'I have borne punishment; I will not offend any more;</verse>
<verse>teach me what I do not see; if I have done iniquity, I will do it no more'?</verse>
<verse>Will he then make repayment to suit you, because you reject it? For you must choose, and not I; therefore declare what you know.</verse>
<verse>Men of understanding will say to me, and the wise man who hears me will say:</verse>
<verse>'Job speaks without knowledge; his words are without insight.'</verse>
<verse>Would that Job were tried to the end, because he answers like wicked men.</verse>
<verse>For he adds rebellion to his sin; he claps his hands among us and multiplies his words against God."</verse>
</chapter>