<chapter translation="ESV" testament="Old" book="Job" book_id="18" n="36">
<verse>And Elihu continued, and said:</verse>
<verse>"Bear with me a little, and I will show you, for I have yet something to say on God's behalf.</verse>
<verse>I will get my knowledge from afar and ascribe righteousness to my Maker.</verse>
<verse>For truly my words are not false; one who is perfect in knowledge is with you.</verse>
<verse>"Behold, God is mighty, and does not despise any; he is mighty in strength of understanding.</verse>
<verse>He does not keep the wicked alive, but gives the afflicted their right.</verse>
<verse>He does not withdraw his eyes from the righteous, but with kings on the throne he sets them forever, and they are exalted.</verse>
<verse>And if they are bound in chains and caught in the cords of affliction,</verse>
<verse>then he declares to them their work and their transgressions, that they are behaving arrogantly.</verse>
<verse>He opens their ears to instruction and commands that they return from iniquity.</verse>
<verse>If they listen and serve him, they complete their days in prosperity, and their years in pleasantness.</verse>
<verse>But if they do not listen, they perish by the sword and die without knowledge.</verse>
<verse>"The godless in heart cherish anger; they do not cry for help when he binds them.</verse>
<verse>They die in youth, and their life ends among the cult prostitutes.</verse>
<verse>He delivers the afflicted by their affliction and opens their ear by adversity.</verse>
<verse>He also allured you out of distress into a broad place where there was no cramping, and what was set on your table was full of fatness.</verse>
<verse>"But you are full of the judgment on the wicked; judgment and justice seize you.</verse>
<verse>Beware lest wrath entice you into scoffing, and let not the greatness of the ransom turn you aside.</verse>
<verse>Will your cry for help avail to keep you from distress, or all the force of your strength?</verse>
<verse>Do not long for the night, when peoples vanish in their place.</verse>
<verse>Take care; do not turn to iniquity, for this you have chosen rather than affliction.</verse>
<verse>Behold, God is exalted in his power; who is a teacher like him?</verse>
<verse>Who has prescribed for him his way, or who can say, 'You have done wrong'?</verse>
<verse>"Remember to extol his work, of which men have sung.</verse>
<verse>All mankind has looked on it; man beholds it from afar.</verse>
<verse>Behold, God is great, and we know him not; the number of his years is unsearchable.</verse>
<verse>For he draws up the drops of water; they distill his mist in rain,</verse>
<verse>which the skies pour down and drop on mankind abundantly.</verse>
<verse>Can anyone understand the spreading of the clouds, the thunderings of his pavilion?</verse>
<verse>Behold, he scatters his lightning about him and covers the roots of the sea.</verse>
<verse>For by these he judges peoples; he gives food in abundance.</verse>
<verse>He covers his hands with the lightning and commands it to strike the mark.</verse>
<verse>Its crashing declares his presence; the cattle also declare that he rises.</verse>
</chapter>