<chapter translation="ESV" testament="Old" book="Job" book-id="18" n="37">
<verse>"At this also my heart trembles and leaps out of its place.</verse>
<verse>Keep listening to the thunder of his voice and the rumbling that comes from his mouth.</verse>
<verse>Under the whole heaven he lets it go, and his lightning to the corners of the earth.</verse>
<verse>After it his voice roars; he thunders with his majestic voice, and he does not restrain the lightnings when his voice is heard.</verse>
<verse>God thunders wondrously with his voice; he does great things that we cannot comprehend.</verse>
<verse>For to the snow he says, 'Fall on the earth,' likewise to the downpour, his mighty downpour.</verse>
<verse>He seals up the hand of every man, that all men whom he made may know it.</verse>
<verse>Then the beasts go into their lairs, and remain in their dens.</verse>
<verse>From its chamber comes the whirlwind, and cold from the scattering winds.</verse>
<verse>By the breath of God ice is given, and the broad waters are frozen fast.</verse>
<verse>He loads the thick cloud with moisture; the clouds scatter his lightning.</verse>
<verse>They turn around and around by his guidance, to accomplish all that he commands them on the face of the habitable world.</verse>
<verse>Whether for correction or for his land or for love, he causes it to happen.</verse>
<verse>"Hear this, O Job; stop and consider the wondrous works of God.</verse>
<verse>Do you know how God lays his command upon them and causes the lightning of his cloud to shine?</verse>
<verse>Do you know the balancings of the clouds, the wondrous works of him who is perfect in knowledge,</verse>
<verse>you whose garments are hot when the earth is still because of the south wind?</verse>
<verse>Can you, like him, spread out the skies, hard as a cast metal mirror?</verse>
<verse>Teach us what we shall say to him; we cannot draw up our case because of darkness.</verse>
<verse>Shall it be told him that I would speak? Did a man ever wish that he would be swallowed up?</verse>
<verse>"And now no one looks on the light when it is bright in the skies, when the wind has passed and cleared them.</verse>
<verse>Out of the north comes golden splendor; God is clothed with awesome majesty.</verse>
<verse>The Almighty--we cannot find him; he is great in power; justice and abundant righteousness he will not violate.</verse>
<verse>Therefore men fear him; he does not regard any who are wise in their own conceit."</verse>
</chapter>