<chapter translation="ESV" testament="Old" book="Job" book-id="18" n="38">
<verse>Then the LORD answered Job out of the whirlwind and said:</verse>
<verse>"Who is this that darkens counsel by words without knowledge?</verse>
<verse>Dress for action like a man; I will question you, and you make it known to me.</verse>
<verse>"Where were you when I laid the foundation of the earth? Tell me, if you have understanding.</verse>
<verse>Who determined its measurements--surely you know! Or who stretched the line upon it?</verse>
<verse>On what were its bases sunk, or who laid its cornerstone,</verse>
<verse>when the morning stars sang together and all the sons of God shouted for joy?</verse>
<verse>"Or who shut in the sea with doors when it burst out from the womb,</verse>
<verse>when I made clouds its garment and thick darkness its swaddling band,</verse>
<verse>and prescribed limits for it and set bars and doors,</verse>
<verse>and said, 'Thus far shall you come, and no farther, and here shall your proud waves be stayed'?</verse>
<verse>"Have you commanded the morning since your days began, and caused the dawn to know its place,</verse>
<verse>that it might take hold of the skirts of the earth, and the wicked be shaken out of it?</verse>
<verse>It is changed like clay under the seal, and its features stand out like a garment.</verse>
<verse>From the wicked their light is withheld, and their uplifted arm is broken.</verse>
<verse>"Have you entered into the springs of the sea, or walked in the recesses of the deep?</verse>
<verse>Have the gates of death been revealed to you, or have you seen the gates of deep darkness?</verse>
<verse>Have you comprehended the expanse of the earth? Declare, if you know all this.</verse>
<verse>"Where is the way to the dwelling of light, and where is the place of darkness,</verse>
<verse>that you may take it to its territory and that you may discern the paths to its home?</verse>
<verse>You know, for you were born then, and the number of your days is great!</verse>
<verse>"Have you entered the storehouses of the snow, or have you seen the storehouses of the hail,</verse>
<verse>which I have reserved for the time of trouble, for the day of battle and war?</verse>
<verse>What is the way to the place where the light is distributed, or where the east wind is scattered upon the earth?</verse>
<verse>"Who has cleft a channel for the torrents of rain and a way for the thunderbolt,</verse>
<verse>to bring rain on a land where no man is, on the desert in which there is no man,</verse>
<verse>to satisfy the waste and desolate land, and to make the ground sprout with grass?</verse>
<verse>"Has the rain a father, or who has begotten the drops of dew?</verse>
<verse>From whose womb did the ice come forth, and who has given birth to the frost of heaven?</verse>
<verse>The waters become hard like stone, and the face of the deep is frozen.</verse>
<verse>"Can you bind the chains of the Pleiades or loose the cords of Orion?</verse>
<verse>Can you lead forth the Mazzaroth in their season, or can you guide the Bear with its children?</verse>
<verse>Do you know the ordinances of the heavens? Can you establish their rule on the earth?</verse>
<verse>"Can you lift up your voice to the clouds, that a flood of waters may cover you?</verse>
<verse>Can you send forth lightnings, that they may go and say to you, 'Here we are'?</verse>
<verse>Who has put wisdom in the inward parts or given understanding to the mind?</verse>
<verse>Who can number the clouds by wisdom? Or who can tilt the waterskins of the heavens,</verse>
<verse>when the dust runs into a mass and the clods stick fast together?</verse>
<verse>"Can you hunt the prey for the lion, or satisfy the appetite of the young lions,</verse>
<verse>when they crouch in their dens or lie in wait in their thicket?</verse>
<verse>Who provides for the raven its prey, when its young ones cry to God for help, and wander about for lack of food?</verse>
</chapter>