<chapter translation="ESV" testament="Old" book="Job" book_id="18" n="39">
<verse>"Do you know when the mountain goats give birth? Do you observe the calving of the does?</verse>
<verse>Can you number the months that they fulfill, and do you know the time when they give birth,</verse>
<verse>when they crouch, bring forth their offspring, and are delivered of their young?</verse>
<verse>Their young ones become strong; they grow up in the open; they go out and do not return to them.</verse>
<verse>"Who has let the wild donkey go free? Who has loosed the bonds of the swift donkey,</verse>
<verse>to whom I have given the arid plain for his home and the salt land for his dwelling place?</verse>
<verse>He scorns the tumult of the city; he hears not the shouts of the driver.</verse>
<verse>He ranges the mountains as his pasture, and he searches after every green thing.</verse>
<verse>"Is the wild ox willing to serve you? Will he spend the night at your manger?</verse>
<verse>Can you bind him in the furrow with ropes, or will he harrow the valleys after you?</verse>
<verse>Will you depend on him because his strength is great, and will you leave to him your labor?</verse>
<verse>Do you have faith in him that he will return your grain and gather it to your threshing floor?</verse>
<verse>"The wings of the ostrich wave proudly, but are they the pinions and plumage of love?</verse>
<verse>For she leaves her eggs to the earth and lets them be warmed on the ground,</verse>
<verse>forgetting that a foot may crush them and that the wild beast may trample them.</verse>
<verse>She deals cruelly with her young, as if they were not hers; though her labor be in vain, yet she has no fear,</verse>
<verse>because God has made her forget wisdom and given her no share in understanding.</verse>
<verse>When she rouses herself to flee, she laughs at the horse and his rider.</verse>
<verse>"Do you give the horse his might? Do you clothe his neck with a mane?</verse>
<verse>Do you make him leap like the locust? His majestic snorting is terrifying.</verse>
<verse>He paws in the valley and exults in his strength; he goes out to meet the weapons.</verse>
<verse>He laughs at fear and is not dismayed; he does not turn back from the sword.</verse>
<verse>Upon him rattle the quiver, the flashing spear and the javelin.</verse>
<verse>With fierceness and rage he swallows the ground; he cannot stand still at the sound of the trumpet.</verse>
<verse>When the trumpet sounds, he says 'Aha!' He smells the battle from afar, the thunder of the captains, and the shouting.</verse>
<verse>"Is it by your understanding that the hawk soars and spreads his wings toward the south?</verse>
<verse>Is it at your command that the eagle mounts up and makes his nest on high?</verse>
<verse>On the rock he dwells and makes his home, on the rocky crag and stronghold.</verse>
<verse>From there he spies out the prey; his eyes behold it afar off.</verse>
<verse>His young ones suck up blood, and where the slain are, there is he."</verse>
</chapter>