<chapter translation="ESV" testament="Old" book="Job" book-id="18" n="4">
<verse>Then Eliphaz the Temanite answered and said:</verse>
<verse>"If one ventures a word with you, will you be impatient? Yet who can keep from speaking?</verse>
<verse>Behold, you have instructed many, and you have strengthened the weak hands.</verse>
<verse>Your words have upheld him who was stumbling, and you have made firm the feeble knees.</verse>
<verse>But now it has come to you, and you are impatient; it touches you, and you are dismayed.</verse>
<verse>Is not your fear of God your confidence, and the integrity of your ways your hope?</verse>
<verse>"Remember: who that was innocent ever perished? Or where were the upright cut off?</verse>
<verse>As I have seen, those who plow iniquity and sow trouble reap the same.</verse>
<verse>By the breath of God they perish, and by the blast of his anger they are consumed.</verse>
<verse>The roar of the lion, the voice of the fierce lion, the teeth of the young lions are broken.</verse>
<verse>The strong lion perishes for lack of prey, and the cubs of the lioness are scattered.</verse>
<verse>"Now a word was brought to me stealthily; my ear received the whisper of it.</verse>
<verse>Amid thoughts from visions of the night, when deep sleep falls on men,</verse>
<verse>dread came upon me, and trembling, which made all my bones shake.</verse>
<verse>A spirit glided past my face; the hair of my flesh stood up.</verse>
<verse>It stood still, but I could not discern its appearance. A form was before my eyes; there was silence, then I heard a voice:</verse>
<verse>'Can mortal man be in the right before God? Can a man be pure before his Maker?</verse>
<verse>Even in his servants he puts no trust, and his angels he charges with error;</verse>
<verse>how much more those who dwell in houses of clay, whose foundation is in the dust, who are crushed like the moth.</verse>
<verse>Between morning and evening they are beaten to pieces; they perish forever without anyone regarding it.</verse>
<verse>Is not their tent-cord plucked up within them, do they not die, and that without wisdom?'</verse>
</chapter>