<chapter translation="ESV" testament="Old" book="Job" book-id="18" n="40">
<verse>And the LORD said to Job:</verse>
<verse>"Shall a faultfinder contend with the Almighty? He who argues with God, let him answer it."</verse>
<verse>Then Job answered the LORD and said:</verse>
<verse>"Behold, I am of small account; what shall I answer you? I lay my hand on my mouth.</verse>
<verse>I have spoken once, and I will not answer; twice, but I will proceed no further."</verse>
<verse>Then the LORD answered Job out of the whirlwind and said:</verse>
<verse>"Dress for action like a man; I will question you, and you make it known to me.</verse>
<verse>Will you even put me in the wrong? Will you condemn me that you may be in the right?</verse>
<verse>Have you an arm like God, and can you thunder with a voice like his?</verse>
<verse>"Adorn yourself with majesty and dignity; clothe yourself with glory and splendor.</verse>
<verse>Pour out the overflowings of your anger, and look on everyone who is proud and abase him.</verse>
<verse>Look on everyone who is proud and bring him low and tread down the wicked where they stand.</verse>
<verse>Hide them all in the dust together; bind their faces in the world below.</verse>
<verse>Then will I also acknowledge to you that your own right hand can save you.</verse>
<verse>"Behold, Behemoth, which I made as I made you; he eats grass like an ox.</verse>
<verse>Behold, his strength in his loins, and his power in the muscles of his belly.</verse>
<verse>He makes his tail stiff like a cedar; the sinews of his thighs are knit together.</verse>
<verse>His bones are tubes of bronze, his limbs like bars of iron.</verse>
<verse>"He is the first of the works of God; let him who made him bring near his sword!</verse>
<verse>For the mountains yield food for him where all the wild beasts play.</verse>
<verse>Under the lotus plants he lies, in the shelter of the reeds and in the marsh.</verse>
<verse>For his shade the lotus trees cover him; the willows of the brook surround him.</verse>
<verse>Behold, if the river is turbulent he is not frightened; he is confident though Jordan rushes against his mouth.</verse>
<verse>Can one take him by his eyes, or pierce his nose with a snare?</verse>
</chapter>