<chapter translation="ESV" testament="Old" book="Job" book_id="18" n="41">
<verse>"Can you draw out Leviathan with a fishhook or press down his tongue with a cord?</verse>
<verse>Can you put a rope in his nose or pierce his jaw with a hook?</verse>
<verse>Will he make many pleas to you? Will he speak to you soft words?</verse>
<verse>Will he make a covenant with you to take him for your servant forever?</verse>
<verse>Will you play with him as with a bird, or will you put him on a leash for your girls?</verse>
<verse>Will traders bargain over him? Will they divide him up among the merchants?</verse>
<verse>Can you fill his skin with harpoons or his head with fishing spears?</verse>
<verse>Lay your hands on him; remember the battle--you will not do it again!</verse>
<verse>Behold, the hope of a man is false; he is laid low even at the sight of him.</verse>
<verse>No one is so fierce that he dares to stir him up. Who then is he who can stand before me?</verse>
<verse>Who has first given to me, that I should repay him? Whatever is under the whole heaven is mine.</verse>
<verse>"I will not keep silence concerning his limbs, or his mighty strength, or his goodly frame.</verse>
<verse>Who can strip off his outer garment? Who would come near him with a bridle?</verse>
<verse>Who can open the doors of his face? Around his teeth is terror.</verse>
<verse>His back is made of rows of shields, shut up closely as with a seal.</verse>
<verse>One is so near to another that no air can come between them.</verse>
<verse>They are joined one to another; they clasp each other and cannot be separated.</verse>
<verse>His sneezings flash forth light, and his eyes are like the eyelids of the dawn.</verse>
<verse>Out of his mouth go flaming torches; sparks of fire leap forth.</verse>
<verse>Out of his nostrils comes forth smoke, as from a boiling pot and burning rushes.</verse>
<verse>His breath kindles coals, and a flame comes forth from his mouth.</verse>
<verse>In his neck abides strength, and terror dances before him.</verse>
<verse>The folds of his flesh stick together, firmly cast on him and immovable.</verse>
<verse>His heart is hard as a stone, hard as the lower millstone.</verse>
<verse>When he raises himself up the mighty are afraid; at the crashing they are beside themselves.</verse>
<verse>Though the sword reaches him, it does not avail, nor the spear, the dart, or the javelin.</verse>
<verse>He counts iron as straw, and bronze as rotten wood.</verse>
<verse>The arrow cannot make him flee; for him sling stones are turned to stubble.</verse>
<verse>Clubs are counted as stubble; he laughs at the rattle of javelins.</verse>
<verse>His underparts are like sharp potsherds; he spreads himself like a threshing sledge on the mire.</verse>
<verse>He makes the deep boil like a pot; he makes the sea like a pot of ointment.</verse>
<verse>Behind him he leaves a shining wake; one would think the deep to be white-haired.</verse>
<verse>On earth there is not his like, a creature without fear.</verse>
<verse>He sees everything that is high; he is king over all the sons of pride."</verse>
</chapter>