<chapter translation="ESV" testament="Old" book="Job" book-id="18" n="5">
<verse>"Call now; is there anyone who will answer you? To which of the holy ones will you turn?</verse>
<verse>Surely vexation kills the fool, and jealousy slays the simple.</verse>
<verse>I have seen the fool taking root, but suddenly I cursed his dwelling.</verse>
<verse>His children are far from safety; they are crushed in the gate, and there is no one to deliver them.</verse>
<verse>The hungry eat his harvest, and he takes it even out of thorns, and the thirsty pant after his wealth.</verse>
<verse>For affliction does not come from the dust, nor does trouble sprout from the ground,</verse>
<verse>but man is born to trouble as the sparks fly upward.</verse>
<verse>"As for me, I would seek God, and to God would I commit my cause,</verse>
<verse>who does great things and unsearchable, marvelous things without number:</verse>
<verse>he gives rain on the earth and sends waters on the fields;</verse>
<verse>he sets on high those who are lowly, and those who mourn are lifted to safety.</verse>
<verse>He frustrates the devices of the crafty, so that their hands achieve no success.</verse>
<verse>He catches the wise in their own craftiness, and the schemes of the wily are brought to a quick end.</verse>
<verse>They meet with darkness in the daytime and grope at noonday as in the night.</verse>
<verse>But he saves the needy from the sword of their mouth and from the hand of the mighty.</verse>
<verse>So the poor have hope, and injustice shuts her mouth.</verse>
<verse>"Behold, blessed is the one whom God reproves; therefore despise not the discipline of the Almighty.</verse>
<verse>For he wounds, but he binds up; he shatters, but his hands heal.</verse>
<verse>He will deliver you from six troubles; in seven no evil shall touch you.</verse>
<verse>In famine he will redeem you from death, and in war from the power of the sword.</verse>
<verse>You shall be hidden from the lash of the tongue, and shall not fear destruction when it comes.</verse>
<verse>At destruction and famine you shall laugh, and shall not fear the beasts of the earth.</verse>
<verse>For you shall be in league with the stones of the field, and the beasts of the field shall be at peace with you.</verse>
<verse>You shall know that your tent is at peace, and you shall inspect your fold and miss nothing.</verse>
<verse>You shall know also that your offspring shall be many, and your descendants as the grass of the earth.</verse>
<verse>You shall come to your grave in ripe old age, like a sheaf gathered up in its season.</verse>
<verse>Behold, this we have searched out; it is true. Hear, and know it for your good."</verse>
</chapter>