<chapter translation="ESV" testament="Old" book="Job" book_id="18" n="9">
<verse>Then Job answered and said:</verse>
<verse>"Truly I know that it is so: But how can a man be in the right before God?</verse>
<verse>If one wished to contend with him, one could not answer him once in a thousand times.</verse>
<verse>He is wise in heart and mighty in strength--who has hardened himself against him, and succeeded?--</verse>
<verse>he who removes mountains, and they know it not, when he overturns them in his anger,</verse>
<verse>who shakes the earth out of its place, and its pillars tremble;</verse>
<verse>who commands the sun, and it does not rise; who seals up the stars;</verse>
<verse>who alone stretched out the heavens and trampled the waves of the sea;</verse>
<verse>who made the Bear and Orion, the Pleiades and the chambers of the south;</verse>
<verse>who does great things beyond searching out, and marvelous things beyond number.</verse>
<verse>Behold, he passes by me, and I see him not; he moves on, but I do not perceive him.</verse>
<verse>Behold, he snatches away; who can turn him back? Who will say to him, 'What are you doing?'</verse>
<verse>"God will not turn back his anger; beneath him bowed the helpers of Rahab.</verse>
<verse>How then can I answer him, choosing my words with him?</verse>
<verse>Though I am in the right, I cannot answer him; I must appeal for mercy to my accuser.</verse>
<verse>If I summoned him and he answered me, I would not believe that he was listening to my voice.</verse>
<verse>For he crushes me with a tempest and multiplies my wounds without cause;</verse>
<verse>he will not let me get my breath, but fills me with bitterness.</verse>
<verse>If it is a contest of strength, behold, he is mighty! If it is a matter of justice, who can summon him?</verse>
<verse>Though I am in the right, my own mouth would condemn me; though I am blameless, he would prove me perverse.</verse>
<verse>I am blameless; I regard not myself; I loathe my life.</verse>
<verse>It is all one; therefore I say, He destroys both the blameless and the wicked.</verse>
<verse>When disaster brings sudden death, he mocks at the calamity of the innocent.</verse>
<verse>The earth is given into the hand of the wicked; he covers the faces of its judges--if it is not he, who then is it?</verse>
<verse>"My days are swifter than a runner; they flee away; they see no good.</verse>
<verse>They go by like skiffs of reed, like an eagle swooping on the prey.</verse>
<verse>If I say, 'I will forget my complaint, I will put off my sad face, and be of good cheer,'</verse>
<verse>I become afraid of all my suffering, for I know you will not hold me innocent.</verse>
<verse>I shall be condemned; why then do I labor in vain?</verse>
<verse>If I wash myself with snow and cleanse my hands with lye,</verse>
<verse>yet you will plunge me into a pit, and my own clothes will abhor me.</verse>
<verse>For he is not a man, as I am, that I might answer him, that we should come to trial together.</verse>
<verse>There is no arbiter between us, who might lay his hand on us both.</verse>
<verse>Let him take his rod away from me, and let not dread of him terrify me.</verse>
<verse>Then I would speak without fear of him, for I am not so in myself.</verse>
</chapter>