<chapter translation="NASB" testament="New" book="Acts" book_id="44" n="8">
<verse>Saul was in hearty agreement with putting him to death. And on that day a great persecution began against the church in Jerusalem, and they were all scattered throughout the regions of Judea and Samaria, except the apostles.</verse>
<verse>Some devout men buried Stephen, and made loud lamentation over him.</verse>
<verse>But Saul began ravaging the church, entering house after house, and dragging off men and women, he would put them in prison.</verse>
<verse>Therefore, those who had been scattered went about preaching the word.</verse>
<verse>Philip went down to the city of Samaria and began proclaiming Christ to them.</verse>
<verse>The crowds with one accord were giving attention to what was said by Philip, as they heard and saw the signs which he was performing.</verse>
<verse>For in the case of many who had unclean spirits, they were coming out of them shouting with a loud voice; and many who had been paralyzed and lame were healed.</verse>
<verse>So there was much rejoicing in that city.</verse>
<verse>Now there was a man named Simon, who formerly was practicing magic in the city and astonishing the people of Samaria, claiming to be someone great;</verse>
<verse>and they all, from smallest to greatest, were giving attention to him, saying, "This man is what is called the Great Power of God."</verse>
<verse>And they were giving him attention because he had for a long time astonished them with his magic arts.</verse>
<verse>But when they believed Philip preaching the good news about the kingdom of God and the name of Jesus Christ, they were being baptized, men and women alike.</verse>
<verse>Even Simon himself believed; and after being baptized, he continued on with Philip, and as he observed signs and great miracles taking place, he was constantly amazed.</verse>
<verse>Now when the apostles in Jerusalem heard that Samaria had received the word of God, they sent them Peter and John,</verse>
<verse>who came down and prayed for them that they might receive the Holy Spirit.</verse>
<verse>For He had not yet fallen upon any of them; they had simply been baptized in the name of the Lord Jesus.</verse>
<verse>Then they began laying their hands on them, and they were receiving the Holy Spirit.</verse>
<verse>Now when Simon saw that the Spirit was bestowed through the laying on of the apostles' hands, he offered them money,</verse>
<verse>saying, "Give this authority to me as well, so that everyone on whom I lay my hands may receive the Holy Spirit."</verse>
<verse>But Peter said to him, "May your silver perish with you, because you thought you could obtain the gift of God with money!</verse>
<verse>"You have no part or portion in this matter, for your heart is not right before God.</verse>
<verse>"Therefore repent of this wickedness of yours, and pray the Lord that, if possible, the intention of your heart may be forgiven you.</verse>
<verse>"For I see that you are in the gall of bitterness and in the bondage of iniquity."</verse>
<verse>But Simon answered and said, "Pray to the Lord for me yourselves, so that nothing of what you have said may come upon me."</verse>
<verse>So, when they had solemnly testified and spoken the word of the Lord, they started back to Jerusalem, and were preaching the gospel to many villages of the Samaritans.</verse>
<verse>But an angel of the Lord spoke to Philip saying, "Get up and go south to the road that descends from Jerusalem to Gaza." (This is a desert road.)</verse>
<verse>So he got up and went; and there was an Ethiopian eunuch, a court official of Candace, queen of the Ethiopians, who was in charge of all her treasure; and he had come to Jerusalem to worship,</verse>
<verse>and he was returning and sitting in his chariot, and was reading the prophet Isaiah.</verse>
<verse>Then the Spirit said to Philip, "Go up and join this chariot."</verse>
<verse>Philip ran up and heard him reading Isaiah the prophet, and said, "Do you understand what you are reading?"</verse>
<verse>And he said, "Well, how could I, unless someone guides me?" And he invited Philip to come up and sit with him.</verse>
<verse>Now the passage of Scripture which he was reading was this: "HE WAS LED AS A SHEEP TO SLAUGHTER; AND AS A LAMB BEFORE ITS SHEARER IS SILENT, SO HE DOES NOT OPEN HIS MOUTH.</verse>
<verse>"IN HUMILIATION HIS JUDGMENT WAS TAKEN AWAY; WHO WILL RELATE HIS GENERATION? FOR HIS LIFE IS REMOVED FROM THE EARTH."</verse>
<verse>The eunuch answered Philip and said, "Please tell me, of whom does the prophet say this? Of himself or of someone else?"</verse>
<verse>Then Philip opened his mouth, and beginning from this Scripture he preached Jesus to him.</verse>
<verse>As they went along the road they came to some water; and the eunuch said, "Look! Water! What prevents me from being baptized?"</verse>
<verse>[ And Philip said, "If you believe with all your heart, you may." And he answered and said, "I believe that Jesus Christ is the Son of God."]</verse>
<verse>And he ordered the chariot to stop; and they both went down into the water, Philip as well as the eunuch, and he baptized him.</verse>
<verse>When they came up out of the water, the Spirit of the Lord snatched Philip away; and the eunuch no longer saw him, but went on his way rejoicing.</verse>
<verse>But Philip found himself at Azotus, and as he passed through he kept preaching the gospel to all the cities until he came to Caesarea.</verse>
</chapter>