<?xml version="1.0"?>
<chapter translation="KJV" testament="Old" book="Hosea" n="13" chapters="14">
      <verse>When Ephraim spake trembling, he exalted himself in Israel; but when he offended in Baal, he died.
</verse><verse>And now they sin more and more, and have made them molten images of their silver, <supplied>and</supplied> idols according to their own understanding, all of it the work of the craftsmen: they say of them, Let the men that sacrifice kiss the calves.
</verse><verse>Therefore they shall be as the morning cloud, and as the early dew that passeth away, as the chaff <supplied>that</supplied> is driven with the whirlwind out of the floor, and as the smoke out of the chimney.
</verse><verse>Yet I <supplied>am</supplied> the LORD thy God from the land of Egypt, and thou shalt know no god but me: for <supplied>there is</supplied> no saviour beside me.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>I did know thee in the wilderness, in the land of great drought.
</verse><verse>According to their pasture, so were they filled; they were filled, and their heart was exalted; therefore have they forgotten me.
</verse><verse>Therefore I will be unto them as a lion: as a leopard by the way will I observe <supplied>them: </supplied></verse><verse>I will meet them as a bear <supplied>that is</supplied> bereaved <supplied>of her whelps,</supplied> and will rend the caul of their heart, and there will I devour them
like a lion: the wild beast shall tear them.
</verse><verse>O Israel, thou hast destroyed thyself; but in me <supplied>is</supplied> thine help.
</verse><verse>I will be thy king: where <supplied>is any other</supplied> that may save thee in all thy cities? and thy judges of whom thou saidst, Give me a king and princes?
</verse><verse>I gave thee a king in mine anger, and took <supplied>him</supplied> away in my wrath.
</verse><verse>The iniquity of Ephraim <supplied>is</supplied> bound up; his sin <supplied>is</supplied> hid.
</verse><verse>The sorrows of a travailing woman shall come upon him: he <supplied>is</supplied> an unwise son; for he should not stay long in <supplied>the place of</supplied> the breaking forth of children.
</verse><verse>I will ransom them from the power of the grave; I will redeem them from death: O death, I will be thy plagues; O grave, I will be thy destruction: repentance shall be hid from mine eyes.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>Though he be fruitful among <supplied>his</supplied> brethren, an east wind shall come, the wind of the LORD shall come up from the wilderness, and his spring shall become dry, and his fountain shall be dried up: he shall spoil the treasure of all pleasant
vessels.
</verse><verse>Samaria shall become desolate; for she hath rebelled against her God: they shall fall by the sword: their infants shall be dashed in pieces, and their women with child shall be ripped up.
     
      </verse>
      </chapter>
