<?xml version="1.0"?>
<chapter translation="KJV" testament="Old" book="1 Kings" n="15" book_id="11">
      <verse>Now in the eighteenth year of king Jeroboam the son of Nebat reigned Abijam over Judah.
</verse><verse>Three years reigned he in Jerusalem. And his mother&#x2019;s name <supplied>was</supplied> Maachah, the daughter of Abishalom.
</verse><verse>And he walked in all the sins of his father, which he had done before him: and his heart was not perfect with the LORD his God, as the heart of David his father.
</verse><verse>Nevertheless for David&#x2019;s sake did the LORD his God give him a lamp in Jerusalem, to set up his son after him, and to establish Jerusalem:
</verse><verse>Because David did <supplied>that which was</supplied> right in the eyes of the LORD, and turned not aside from any <supplied>thing</supplied> that he commanded him all the days of his life, save only in the matter of Uriah the Hittite.
</verse><verse>And there was war between Rehoboam and Jeroboam all the days of his life.
</verse><verse>Now the rest of the acts of Abijam, and all that he did, <supplied>are</supplied> they not written in the book of the chronicles of the kings of Judah? And there was war between Abijam and Jeroboam.
</verse><verse>And Abijam slept with his fathers; and they buried him in the city of David: and Asa his son reigned in his stead.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>And in the twentieth year of Jeroboam king of Israel reigned Asa over Judah.
</verse><verse>And forty and one years reigned he in Jerusalem. And his mother&#x2019;s name <supplied>was</supplied> Maachah, the daughter of Abishalom.
</verse><verse>And Asa did <supplied>that which was</supplied> right in the eyes of the LORD, as <supplied>did</supplied> David his father.
</verse><verse>And he took away the sodomites out of the land, and removed all the idols that his fathers had made.
</verse><verse>And also Maachah his mother, even her he removed from <supplied>being</supplied> queen, because she had made an idol in a grove; and Asa destroyed her idol, and burnt <supplied>it</supplied> by the brook Kidron.
</verse><verse>But the high places were not removed: nevertheless Asa&#x2019;s heart was perfect with the LORD all his days.
</verse><verse>And he brought in the things which his father had dedicated, and the things which himself had dedicated, into the house of the LORD, silver, and gold, and vessels.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>And there was war between Asa and Baasha king of Israel all their days.
</verse><verse>And Baasha king of Israel went up against Judah, and built Ramah, that he might not suffer any to go out or come in to Asa king of Judah.
</verse><verse>Then Asa took all the silver and the gold <supplied>that were</supplied> left in the treasures of the house of the LORD, and the treasures of the king&#x2019;s house, and delivered them into the hand of his servants: and king Asa sent them to Ben-hadad, the son
of Tabrimon, the son of Hezion, king of Syria, that dwelt at Damascus, saying,
</verse><verse><supplied>There is</supplied> a league between me and thee, <supplied>and</supplied> between my father and thy father: behold, I have sent unto thee a present of silver and gold; come and break thy league with Baasha king of Israel, that he may depart from me.
</verse><verse>So Ben- hadad hearkened unto king Asa, and sent the captains of the hosts which he had against the cities of Israel, and smote Ijon, and Dan, and Abel-beth-maachah, and all Cinneroth, with all the land of Naphtali.
</verse><verse>And it came to pass, when Baasha heard <supplied>thereof,</supplied> that he left off building of Ramah, and dwelt in Tirzah.
</verse><verse>Then king Asa made a proclamation throughout all Judah; none <supplied>was</supplied> exempted: and they took away the stones of Ramah, and the timber thereof, wherewith Baasha had builded; and king Asa built with them Geba of Benjamin, and Mizpah.
</verse><verse>The rest of all the acts of Asa, and all his might, and all that he did, and the cities which he built, <supplied>are</supplied> they not written in the book of the chronicles of the kings of Judah? Nevertheless in the time of his old age he was diseased
in his feet.
</verse><verse>And Asa slept with his fathers, and was buried with his fathers in the city of David his father: and Jehoshaphat his son reigned in his stead.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>And Nadab the son of Jeroboam began to reign over Israel in the second year of Asa king of Judah, and reigned over Israel two years.
</verse><verse>And he did evil in the sight of the LORD, and walked in the way of his father, and in his sin wherewith he made Israel to sin.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>And Baasha the son of Ahijah, of the house of Issachar, conspired against him; and Baasha smote him at Gibbethon, which <supplied>belonged</supplied> to the Philistines; for Nadab and all Israel laid siege to Gibbethon.
</verse><verse>Even in the third year of Asa king of Judah did Baasha slay him, and reigned in his stead.
</verse><verse>And it came to pass, when he reigned, <supplied>that</supplied> he smote all the house of Jeroboam; he left not to Jeroboam any that breathed, until he had destroyed him, according unto the saying of the LORD, which he spake by his servant Ahijah the
Shilonite:
</verse><verse>Because of the sins of Jeroboam which he sinned, and which he made Israel sin, by his provocation wherewith he provoked the LORD God of Israel to anger.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>Now the rest of the acts of Nadab, and all that he did, <supplied>are</supplied> they not written in the book of the chronicles of the kings of Israel?
</verse><verse>And there was war between Asa and Baasha king of Israel all their days.
</verse><verse>In the third year of Asa king of Judah began Baasha the son of Ahijah to reign over all Israel in Tirzah, twenty and four years.
</verse><verse>And he did evil in the sight of the LORD, and walked in the way of Jeroboam, and in his sin wherewith he made Israel to sin.
     
      </verse>
      </chapter>
