<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Lamentations" book_id="25" n="3">
<verse>I am the man who has seen affliction Because of the rod of His wrath.</verse>
<verse>He has driven me and made me walk In darkness and not in light.</verse>
<verse>Surely against me He has turned His hand Repeatedly all the day.</verse>
<verse>He has caused my flesh and my skin to waste away, He has broken my bones.</verse>
<verse>He has besieged and encompassed me with bitterness and hardship.</verse>
<verse>In dark places He has made me dwell, Like those who have long been dead.</verse>
<verse>He has walled me in so that I cannot go out; He has made my chain heavy.</verse>
<verse>Even when I cry out and call for help, He shuts out my prayer.</verse>
<verse>He has blocked my ways with hewn stone; He has made my paths crooked.</verse>
<verse>He is to me like a bear lying in wait, Like a lion in secret places.</verse>
<verse>He has turned aside my ways and torn me to pieces; He has made me desolate.</verse>
<verse>He bent His bow And set me as a target for the arrow.</verse>
<verse>He made the arrows of His quiver To enter into my inward parts.</verse>
<verse>I have become a laughingstock to all my people, Their mocking song all the day.</verse>
<verse>He has filled me with bitterness, He has made me drunk with wormwood.</verse>
<verse>He has broken my teeth with gravel; He has made me cower in the dust.</verse>
<verse>My soul has been rejected from peace; I have forgotten happiness.</verse>
<verse>So I say, "My strength has perished, And so has my hope from the LORD."</verse>
<verse>Remember my affliction and my wandering, the wormwood and bitterness.</verse>
<verse>Surely my soul remembers And is bowed down within me.</verse>
<verse>This I recall to my mind, Therefore I have hope.</verse>
<verse>The LORD'S lovingkindnesses indeed never cease, For His compassions never fail.</verse>
<verse>They are new every morning; Great is Your faithfulness.</verse>
<verse>"The LORD is my portion," says my soul, "Therefore I have hope in Him."</verse>
<verse>The LORD is good to those who wait for Him, To the person who seeks Him.</verse>
<verse>It is good that he waits silently For the salvation of the LORD.</verse>
<verse>It is good for a man that he should bear The yoke in his youth.</verse>
<verse>Let him sit alone and be silent Since He has laid it on him.</verse>
<verse>Let him put his mouth in the dust, Perhaps there is hope.</verse>
<verse>Let him give his cheek to the smiter, Let him be filled with reproach.</verse>
<verse>For the Lord will not reject forever,</verse>
<verse>For if He causes grief, Then He will have compassion According to His abundant lovingkindness.</verse>
<verse>For He does not afflict willingly Or grieve the sons of men.</verse>
<verse>To crush under His feet All the prisoners of the land,</verse>
<verse>To deprive a man of justice In the presence of the Most High,</verse>
<verse>To defraud a man in his lawsuit--Of these things the Lord does not approve.</verse>
<verse>Who is there who speaks and it comes to pass, Unless the Lord has commanded it?</verse>
<verse>Is it not from the mouth of the Most High That both good and ill go forth?</verse>
<verse>Why should any living mortal, or any man, Offer complaint in view of his sins?</verse>
<verse>Let us examine and probe our ways, And let us return to the LORD.</verse>
<verse>We lift up our heart and hands Toward God in heaven;</verse>
<verse>We have transgressed and rebelled, You have not pardoned.</verse>
<verse>You have covered Yourself with anger And pursued us; You have slain and have not spared.</verse>
<verse>You have covered Yourself with a cloud So that no prayer can pass through.</verse>
<verse>You have made us mere offscouring and refuse In the midst of the peoples.</verse>
<verse>All our enemies have opened their mouths against us.</verse>
<verse>Panic and pitfall have befallen us, Devastation and destruction;</verse>
<verse>My eyes run down with streams of water Because of the destruction of the daughter of my people.</verse>
<verse>My eyes pour down unceasingly, Without stopping,</verse>
<verse>Until the LORD looks down And sees from heaven.</verse>
<verse>My eyes bring pain to my soul Because of all the daughters of my city.</verse>
<verse>My enemies without cause Hunted me down like a bird;</verse>
<verse>They have silenced me in the pit And have placed a stone on me.</verse>
<verse>Waters flowed over my head; I said, "I am cut off!"</verse>
<verse>I called on Your name, O LORD, Out of the lowest pit.</verse>
<verse>You have heard my voice, "Do not hide Your ear from my prayer for relief, From my cry for help."</verse>
<verse>You drew near when I called on You; You said, "Do not fear!"</verse>
<verse>O Lord, You have pleaded my soul's cause; You have redeemed my life.</verse>
<verse>O LORD, You have seen my oppression; Judge my case.</verse>
<verse>You have seen all their vengeance, All their schemes against me.</verse>
<verse>You have heard their reproach, O LORD, All their schemes against me.</verse>
<verse>The lips of my assailants and their whispering Are against me all day long.</verse>
<verse>Look on their sitting and their rising; I am their mocking song.</verse>
<verse>You will recompense them, O LORD, According to the work of their hands.</verse>
<verse>You will give them hardness of heart, Your curse will be on them.</verse>
<verse>You will pursue them in anger and destroy them From under the heavens of the LORD!</verse>
</chapter>