<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Job" book-id="18" n="10">
<verse>"I can't stand my life--I hate it! -I'm putting it all out on the table,	all the bitterness of my life--I'm holding back nothing."</verse>
<verse>Job prayed: "Here's what I want to say: Don't, God, bring in a verdict of guilty without letting me know the charges you're bringing.</verse>
<verse>How does this fit into what you once called "good'--giving me a hard time, spurning me, a life you shaped by your very own hands, and then blessing the plots of the wicked?</verse>
<verse>You don't look at things the way we mortals do. You're not taken in by appearances, are you?</verse>
<verse>Unlike us, you're not working against a deadline. You have all eternity to work things out.</verse>
<verse>So what's this all about, anyway--this compulsion to dig up some dirt, to find some skeleton in my closet?</verse>
<verse>You know good and well I'm not guilty. You also know no one can help me.</verse>
<verse>"You made me like a handcrafted piece of pottery--and now are you going to smash me to pieces?</verse>
<verse>Don't you remember how beautifully you worked my clay? Will you reduce me now to a mud pie?</verse>
<verse>Oh, that marvel of conception as you stirred together semen and ovum--</verse>
<verse>What a miracle of skin and bone, muscle and brain!</verse>
<verse>You gave me life itself, and incredible love. You watched and guarded every breath I took.</verse>
<verse>"But you never told me about this part. I should have known that there was more to it--</verse>
<verse>That if I so much as missed a step, you'd notice and pounce, wouldn't let me get by with a thing.</verse>
<verse>If I'm truly guilty, I'm doomed. But if I'm innocent, it's no better--I'm still doomed. My belly is full of bitterness. I'm up to my ears in a swamp of affliction.</verse>
<verse>I try to make the best of it, try to brave it out, but you're too much for me, relentless, like a lion on the prowl.</verse>
<verse>You line up fresh witnesses against me. You compound your anger and pile on the grief and pain!</verse>
<verse>"So why did you have me born? I wish no one had ever laid eyes on me!</verse>
<verse>I wish I'd never lived--a stillborn, buried without ever having breathed.</verse>
<verse>Isn't it time to call it quits on my life? Can't you let up, and let me smile just once</verse>
<verse>Before I die and am buried, before I'm nailed into my coffin, sealed in the ground,</verse>
<verse>And banished for good to the land of the dead, blind in the final dark?" HKZophar's CounselHK How Wisdom Looks from the Inside</verse>
</chapter>