<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Job" book-id="18" n="12">
<verse>Job answered:</verse>
<verse>"I'm sure you speak for all the experts, and when you die there'll be no one left to tell us how to live.</verse>
<verse>But don't forget that I also have a brain--I don't intend to play second fiddle to you. It doesn't take an expert to know these things.</verse>
<verse>"I'm ridiculed by my friends: "So that's the man who had conversations with God!' Ridiculed without mercy: "Look at the man who never did wrong!'</verse>
<verse>It's easy for the well-to-do to point their fingers in blame, for the well-fixed to pour scorn on the strugglers.</verse>
<verse>Crooks reside safely in high-security houses, insolent blasphemers live in luxury; they've bought and paid for a god who'll protect them.</verse>
<verse>"But ask the animals what they think--let them teach you; let the birds tell you what's going on.</verse>
<verse>Put your ear to the earth--learn the basics. Listen--the fish in the ocean will tell you their stories.</verse>
<verse>Isn't it clear that they all know and agree that GOD is sovereign, that he holds all things in his hand--</verse>
<verse>Every living soul, yes, every breathing creature?</verse>
<verse>Isn't this all just common sense, as common as the sense of taste?</verse>
<verse>Do you think the elderly have a corner on wisdom, that you have to grow old before you understand life?</verse>
<verse>"True wisdom and real power belong to God; from him we learn how to live, and also what to live for.</verse>
<verse>If he tears something down, it's down for good; if he locks people up, they're locked up for good.</verse>
<verse>If he holds back the rain, there's a drought; if he lets it loose, there's a flood.</verse>
<verse>Strength and success belong to God; both deceived and deceiver must answer to him.</verse>
<verse>He strips experts of their vaunted credentials, exposes judges as witless fools.</verse>
<verse>He divests kings of their royal garments, then ties a rag around their waists.</verse>
<verse>He strips priests of their robes, and fires high officials from their jobs.</verse>
<verse>He forces trusted sages to keep silence, deprives elders of their good sense and wisdom.</verse>
<verse>He dumps contempt on famous people, disarms the strong and mighty.</verse>
<verse>He shines a spotlight into caves of darkness, hauls deepest darkness into the noonday sun.</verse>
<verse>He makes nations rise and then fall, builds up some and abandons others.</verse>
<verse>He robs world leaders of their reason, and sends them off into no man's land.</verse>
<verse>They grope in the dark without a clue, lurching and staggering like drunks.</verse>
</chapter>