<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Job" book-id="18" n="13">
<verse>"Yes, I've seen all this with my own eyes, heard and understood it with my very own ears.</verse>
<verse>Everything you know, I know, so I'm not taking a back seat to any of you.</verse>
<verse>I'm taking my case straight to God Almighty; I've had it with you--I'm going directly to God.</verse>
<verse>You graffiti my life with lies. You're a bunch of pompous quacks!</verse>
<verse>I wish you'd shut your mouths--silence is your only claim to wisdom.</verse>
<verse>"Listen now while I make my case, consider my side of things for a change.</verse>
<verse>Or are you going to keep on lying "to do God a service'? to make up stories "to get him off the hook'?</verse>
<verse>Why do you always take his side? Do you think he needs a lawyer to defend himself?</verse>
<verse>How would you fare if you were in the dock? Your lies might convince a jury--but would they convince God?</verse>
<verse>He'd reprimand you on the spot if he detected a bias in your witness.</verse>
<verse>Doesn't his splendor put you in awe? Aren't you afraid to speak cheap lies before him?</verse>
<verse>Your wise sayings are knickknack wisdom, good for nothing but gathering dust.</verse>
<verse>"So hold your tongue while I have my say, then I'll take whatever I have coming to me.</verse>
<verse>Why do I go out on a limb like this and take my life in my hands?</verse>
<verse>Because even if he killed me, I'd keep on hoping. I'd defend my innocence to the very end.</verse>
<verse>Just wait, this is going to work out for the best--my salvation! If I were guilt-stricken do you think I'd be doing this--laying myself on the line before God?</verse>
<verse>You'd better pay attention to what I'm telling you, listen carefully with both ears.</verse>
<verse>Now that I've laid out my defense, I'm sure that I'll be acquitted.</verse>
<verse>Can anyone prove charges against me? I've said my piece. I rest my case.</verse>
<verse>"Please, God, I have two requests; grant them so I'll know I count with you:</verse>
<verse>First, lay off the afflictions; the terror is too much for me.</verse>
<verse>Second, address me directly so I can answer you, or let me speak and then you answer me.</verse>
<verse>How many sins have been charged against me? Show me the list--how bad is it?</verse>
<verse>Why do you stay hidden and silent? Why treat me like I'm your enemy?</verse>
<verse>Why kick me around like an old tin can? Why beat a dead horse?</verse>
<verse>You compile a long list of mean things about me, even hold me accountable for the sins of my youth.</verse>
<verse>You hobble me so I can't move about. You watch every move I make, and brand me as a dangerous character.</verse>
<verse>"Like something rotten, human life fast decomposes, like a moth-eaten shirt or a mildewed blouse.</verse>
</chapter>