<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Job" book-id="18" n="14">
<verse>"We're all adrift in the same boat: too few days, too many troubles.</verse>
<verse>We spring up like wildflowers in the desert and then wilt, transient as the shadow of a cloud.</verse>
<verse>Do you occupy your time with such fragile wisps? Why even bother hauling me into court?</verse>
<verse>There's nothing much to us to start with; how do you expect us to amount to anything?</verse>
<verse>Mortals have a limited life span. You've already decided how long we'll live--you set the boundary and no one can cross it.</verse>
<verse>So why not give us a break? Ease up! Even ditchdiggers get occasional days off.</verse>
<verse>For a tree there is always hope. Chop it down and it still has a chance--its roots can put out fresh sprouts.</verse>
<verse>Even if its roots are old and gnarled, its stump long dormant,</verse>
<verse>At the first whiff of water it comes to life, buds and grows like a sapling.</verse>
<verse>But men and women? They die and stay dead. They breathe their last, and that's it.</verse>
<verse>Like lakes and rivers that have dried up, parched reminders of what once was,</verse>
<verse>So mortals lie down and never get up, never wake up again--never.</verse>
<verse>Why don't you just bury me alive, get me out of the way until your anger cools? But don't leave me there! Set a date when you'll see me again.</verse>
<verse>If we humans die, will we live again? That's my question. All through these difficult days I keep hoping, waiting for the final change--for resurrection!</verse>
<verse>Homesick with longing for the creature you made, you'll call--and I'll answer!</verse>
<verse>You'll watch over every step I take, but you won't keep track of my missteps.</verse>
<verse>My sins will be stuffed in a sack and thrown into the sea--sunk in deep ocean.</verse>
<verse>"Meanwhile, mountains wear down and boulders break up,</verse>
<verse>Stones wear smooth and soil erodes, as you relentlessly grind down our hope.</verse>
<verse>You're too much for us. As always, you get the last word. We don't like it and our faces show it, but you send us off anyway.</verse>
<verse>If our children do well for themselves, we never know it; if they do badly, we're spared the hurt.</verse>
<verse>Body and soul, that's it for us--a lifetime of pain, a lifetime of sorrow." HKEliphaz Attacks AgainHK You Trivialize Religion</verse>
</chapter>