<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Job" book_id="18" n="15">
<verse>Eliphaz of Teman spoke a second time:</verse>
<verse>"If you were truly wise, would you sound so much like a windbag, belching hot air?</verse>
<verse>Would you talk nonsense in the middle of a serious argument, babbling baloney?</verse>
<verse>Look at you! You trivialize religion, turn spiritual conversation into empty gossip.</verse>
<verse>It's your sin that taught you to talk this way. You chose an education in fraud.</verse>
<verse>Your own words have exposed your guilt. It's nothing I've said--you've incriminated yourself!</verse>
<verse>Do you think you're the first person to have to deal with these things? Have you been around as long as the hills?</verse>
<verse>Were you listening in when God planned all this? Do you think you're the only one who knows anything?</verse>
<verse>What do you know that we don't know? What insights do you have that we've missed?</verse>
<verse>Gray beards and white hair back us up--old folks who've been around a lot longer than you.</verse>
<verse>Are God's promises not enough for you, spoken so gently and tenderly?</verse>
<verse>Why do you let your emotions take over, lashing out and spitting fire,</verse>
<verse>Pitting your whole being against God by letting words like this come out of your mouth?</verse>
<verse>Do you think it's possible for any mere mortal to be sinless in God's sight, for anyone born of a human mother to get it all together?</verse>
<verse>Why, God can't even trust his holy angels. He sees the flaws in the very heavens themselves,</verse>
<verse>So how much less we humans, smelly and foul, who lap up evil like water?</verse>
<verse>"I've a thing or two to tell you, so listen up! I'm letting you in on my views;</verse>
<verse>It's what wise men and women have always taught, holding nothing back from what they were taught</verse>
<verse>By their parents, back in the days when they had this land all to themselves:</verse>
<verse>Those who live by their own rules, not God's, can expect nothing but trouble, and the longer they live, the worse it gets.</verse>
<verse>Every little sound terrifies them. Just when they think they have it made, disaster strikes.</verse>
<verse>They despair of things ever getting better--they're on the list of people for whom things always turn out for the worst.</verse>
<verse>They wander here and there, never knowing where the next meal is coming from--every day is doomsday!</verse>
<verse>They live in constant terror, always with their backs up against the wall</verse>
<verse>Because they insist on shaking their fists at God, defying God Almighty to his face,</verse>
<verse>Always and ever at odds with God, always on the defensive.</verse>
<verse>"Even if they're the picture of health, trim and fit and youthful,</verse>
<verse>They'll end up living in a ghost town sleeping in a hovel not fit for a dog, a ramshackle shack.</verse>
<verse>They'll never get ahead, never amount to a hill of beans.</verse>
<verse>And then death--don't think they'll escape that! They'll end up shriveled weeds, brought down by a puff of God's breath.</verse>
<verse>There's a lesson here: Whoever invests in lies, gets lies for interest,</verse>
<verse>Paid in full before the due date. Some investment!</verse>
<verse>They'll be like fruit frost-killed before it ripens, like buds sheared off before they bloom.</verse>
<verse>The godless are fruitless--a barren crew; a life built on bribes goes up in smoke.</verse>
<verse>They have sex with sin and give birth to evil. Their lives are wombs for breeding deceit." HKJob Defends HimselfHK If You Were in My Shoes</verse>
</chapter>