<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Job" book_id="18" n="16">
<verse>Then Job defended himself:</verse>
<verse>"I've had all I can take of your talk. What a bunch of miserable comforters!</verse>
<verse>Is there no end to your windbag speeches? What's your problem that you go on and on like this?</verse>
<verse>If you were in my shoes, I could talk just like you. I could put together a terrific harangue and really let you have it.</verse>
<verse>But I'd never do that. I'd console and comfort, make things better, not worse!</verse>
<verse>"When I speak up, I feel no better; if I say nothing, that doesn't help either.</verse>
<verse>I feel worn down. God, you have wasted me totally--me and my family!</verse>
<verse>You've shriveled me like a dried prune, showing the world that you're against me. My gaunt face stares back at me from the mirror, a mute witness to your treatment of me.</verse>
<verse>Your anger tears at me, your teeth rip me to shreds, your eyes burn holes in me--God, my enemy!</verse>
<verse>People take one look at me and gasp. Contemptuous, they slap me around and gang up against me.</verse>
<verse>And God just stands there and lets them do it, lets wicked people do what they want with me.</verse>
<verse>I was contentedly minding my business when God beat me up. He grabbed me by the neck and threw me around. He set me up as his target,</verse>
<verse>then rounded up archers to shoot at me. Merciless, they shot me full of arrows; bitter bile poured from my gut to the ground.</verse>
<verse>He burst in on me, onslaught after onslaught, charging me like a mad bull.</verse>
<verse>"I sewed myself a shroud and wore it like a shirt; I lay face down in the dirt.</verse>
<verse>Now my face is blotched red from weeping; look at the dark shadows under my eyes,</verse>
<verse>Even though I've never hurt a soul and my prayers are sincere!</verse>
<verse>"O Earth, don't cover up the wrong done to me! Don't muffle my cry!</verse>
<verse>There must be Someone in heaven who knows the truth about me, in highest heaven, some Attorney who can clear my name--</verse>
<verse>My Champion, my Friend, while I'm weeping my eyes out before God.</verse>
<verse>I appeal to the One who represents mortals before God as a neighbor stands up for a neighbor.</verse>
<verse>"Only a few years are left before I set out on the road of no return.</verse>
</chapter>