<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Job" book_id="18" n="19">
<verse>Job answered:</verse>
<verse>"How long are you going to keep battering away at me, pounding me with these harangues?</verse>
<verse>Time after time after time you jump all over me. Do you have no conscience, abusing me like this?</verse>
<verse>Even if I have, somehow or other, gotten off the track, what business is that of yours?</verse>
<verse>Why do you insist on putting me down, using my troubles as a stick to beat me?</verse>
<verse>Tell it to God--he's the one behind all this, he's the one who dragged me into this mess.</verse>
<verse>"Look at me--I shout "Murder!' and I'm ignored; I call for help and no one bothers to stop.</verse>
<verse>God threw a barricade across my path--I'm stymied; he turned out all the lights--I'm stuck in the dark.</verse>
<verse>He destroyed my reputation, robbed me of all self-respect.</verse>
<verse>He tore me apart piece by piece--I'm ruined! Then he yanked out hope by the roots.</verse>
<verse>He's angry with me--oh, how he's angry! He treats me like his worst enemy.</verse>
<verse>He has launched a major campaign against me, using every weapon he can think of, coming at me from all sides at once.</verse>
<verse>"God alienated my family from me;</verse>
<verse>everyone who knows me avoids me. My relatives and friends have all left; houseguests forget I ever existed.</verse>
<verse>The servant girls treat me like a bum off the street, look at me like they've never seen me before.</verse>
<verse>I call my attendant and he ignores me, ignores me even though I plead with him.</verse>
<verse>My wife can't stand to be around me anymore. I'm repulsive to my family.</verse>
<verse>Even street urchins despise me; when I come out, they taunt and jeer.</verse>
<verse>Everyone I've ever been close to abhors me; my dearest loved ones reject me.</verse>
<verse>I'm nothing but a bag of bones; my life hangs by a thread.</verse>
<verse>"Oh, friends, dear friends, take pity on me. God has come down hard on me!</verse>
<verse>Do you have to be hard on me too? Don't you ever tire of abusing me?</verse>
<verse>"If only my words were written in a book--</verse>
<verse>better yet, chiseled in stone!</verse>
<verse>Still, I know that God lives--the One who gives me back my life--and eventually he'll take his stand on earth.</verse>
<verse>And I'll see him--even though I get skinned alive!-</verse>
<verse>see God myself, with my very own eyes. Oh, how I long for that day!</verse>
<verse>"If you're thinking, "How can we get through to him, get him to see that his trouble is all his own fault?'</verse>
<verse>Forget it. Start worrying about yourselves. Worry about your own sins and God's coming judgment, for judgment is most certainly on the way." HKZophar Attacks Job--The Second RoundHK Savoring Evil as a Delicacy</verse>
</chapter>