<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Job" book_id="18" n="20">
<verse>Zophar from Naamath again took his turn:</verse>
<verse>"I can't believe what I'm hearing! You've put my teeth on edge, my stomach in a knot.</verse>
<verse>How dare you insult my intelligence like this! Well, here's a piece of my mind!</verse>
<verse>"Don't you even know the basics, how things have been since the earliest days, when Adam and Eve were first placed on earth?</verse>
<verse>The good times of the wicked are short-lived; godless joy is only momentary.</verse>
<verse>The evil might become world famous, strutting at the head of the celebrity parade,</verse>
<verse>But still end up in a pile of dung. Acquaintances look at them with disgust and say, "What's that?'</verse>
<verse>They fly off like a dream that can't be remembered, like a shadowy illusion that vanishes in the light.</verse>
<verse>Though once notorious public figures, now they're nobodies, unnoticed, whether they come or go.</verse>
<verse>Their children will go begging on skid row, and they'll have to give back their ill-gotten gain.</verse>
<verse>Right in the prime of life, and youthful and vigorous, they'll die.</verse>
<verse>"They savor evil as a delicacy, roll it around on their tongues,</verse>
<verse>Prolong the flavor, a dalliance in decadence--real gourmets of evil!</verse>
<verse>But then they get stomach cramps, a bad case of food poisoning.</verse>
<verse>They gag on all that rich food; God makes them vomit it up.</verse>
<verse>They gorge on evil, make a diet of that poison--a deadly diet--and it kills them.</verse>
<verse>No quiet picnics for them beside gentle streams with fresh-baked bread and cheese, and tall, cool drinks.</verse>
<verse>They spit out their food half-chewed, unable to relax and enjoy anything they've worked for.</verse>
<verse>And why? Because they exploited the poor, took what never belonged to them.</verse>
<verse>"Such God--denying people are never content with what they have or who they are; their greed drives them relentlessly.</verse>
<verse>They plunder everything but they can't hold on to any of it.</verse>
<verse>Just when they think they have it all, disaster strikes; they're served up a plate full of misery.</verse>
<verse>When they've filled their bellies with that, God gives them a taste of his anger, and they get to chew on that for a while.</verse>
<verse>As they run for their lives from one disaster, they run smack into another.</verse>
<verse>They're knocked around from pillar to post, beaten to within an inch of their lives. They're trapped in a house of horrors,</verse>
<verse>and see their loot disappear down a black hole. Their lives are a total loss--not a penny to their name, not so much as a bean.</verse>
<verse>God will strip them of their sin-soaked clothes and hang their dirty laundry out for all to see.</verse>
<verse>Life is a complete wipeout for them, nothing surviving God's wrath.</verse>
<verse>There! That's God's blueprint for the wicked--what they have to look forward to." Job's Response Why Do the Wicked Have It So Good?</verse>
</chapter>