<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Job" book-id="18" n="21">
<verse>Job replied:</verse>
<verse>"Now listen to me carefully, please listen, at least do me the favor of listening.</verse>
<verse>Put up with me while I have my say--then you can mock me later to your heart's content.</verse>
<verse>"It's not you I'm complaining to--it's God. Is it any wonder I'm getting fed up with his silence?</verse>
<verse>Take a good look at me. Aren't you appalled by what's happened? No! Don't say anything. I can do without your comments.</verse>
<verse>When I look back, I go into shock, my body is racked with spasms.</verse>
<verse>Why do the wicked have it so good, live to a ripe old age and get rich?</verse>
<verse>They get to see their children succeed, get to watch and enjoy their grandchildren.</verse>
<verse>Their homes are peaceful and free from fear; they never experience God's disciplining rod.</verse>
<verse>Their bulls breed with great vigor and their cows calve without fail.</verse>
<verse>They send their children out to play and watch them frolic like spring lambs.</verse>
<verse>They make music with fiddles and flutes, have good times singing and dancing.</verse>
<verse>They have a long life on easy street, and die painlessly in their sleep.</verse>
<verse>They say to God, "Get lost! We've no interest in you or your ways.</verse>
<verse>Why should we have dealings with God Almighty? What's there in it for us?'</verse>
<verse>But they're wrong, dead wrong--they're not gods. It's beyond me how they can carry on like this!</verse>
<verse>"Still, how often does it happen that the wicked fail, or disaster strikes, or they get their just deserts?</verse>
<verse>How often are they blown away by bad luck? Not very often.</verse>
<verse>You might say, "God is saving up the punishment for their children.' I say, "Give it to them right now so they'll know what they've done!'</verse>
<verse>They deserve to experience the effects of their evil, feel the full force of God's wrath firsthand.</verse>
<verse>What do they care what happens to their families after they're safely tucked away in the grave?</verse>
<verse>"But who are we to tell God how to run his affairs? He's dealing with matters that are way over our heads.</verse>
<verse>Some people die in the prime of life, with everything going for them--</verse>
<verse>fat and sassy.</verse>
<verse>Others die bitter and bereft, never getting a taste of happiness.</verse>
<verse>They're laid out side by side in the cemetery, where the worms can't tell one from the other.</verse>
<verse>"I'm not deceived. I know what you're up to, the plans you're cooking up to bring me down.</verse>
<verse>Naively you claim that the castles of tyrants fall to pieces, that the achievements of the wicked collapse.</verse>
<verse>Have you ever asked world travelers how they see it? Have you not listened to their stories</verse>
<verse>Of evil men and women who got off scot-free, who never had to pay for their wickedness?</verse>
<verse>Did anyone ever confront them with their crimes? Did they ever have to face the music?</verse>
<verse>Not likely--they're given fancy funerals with all the trimmings,</verse>
<verse>Gently lowered into expensive graves, with everyone telling lies about how wonderful they were.</verse>
<verse>"So how do you expect me to get any comfort from your nonsense? Your so-called comfort is a tissue of lies." Eliphaz Attacks Job--The Third Round Come to Terms with God</verse>
</chapter>