<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Job" book_id="18" n="22">
<verse>Once again Eliphaz the Temanite took up his theme:</verse>
<verse>"Are any of us strong enough to give God a hand, or smart enough to give him advice?</verse>
<verse>So what if you were righteous--would God Almighty even notice? Even if you gave a perfect performance, do you think he'd applaud?</verse>
<verse>Do you think it's because he cares about your purity that he's disciplining you, putting you on the spot?</verse>
<verse>Hardly! It's because you're a first-class moral failure, because there's no end to your sins.</verse>
<verse>When people came to you for help, you took the shirts off their backs, exploited their helplessness.</verse>
<verse>You wouldn't so much as give a drink to the thirsty, or food, not even a scrap, to the hungry.</verse>
<verse>And there you sat, strong and honored by everyone, surrounded by immense wealth!</verse>
<verse>You turned poor widows away from your door; heartless, you crushed orphans.</verse>
<verse>Now you're the one trapped in terror, paralyzed by fear. Suddenly the tables have turned!</verse>
<verse>How do you like living in the dark, sightless, up to your neck in flood waters?</verse>
<verse>"You agree, don't you, that God is in charge? He runs the universe--just look at the stars!</verse>
<verse>Yet you dare raise questions: "What does God know? From that distance and darkness, how can he judge?</verse>
<verse>He roams the heavens wrapped in clouds, so how can he see us?'</verse>
<verse>"Are you going to persist in that tired old line that wicked men and women have always used?</verse>
<verse>Where did it get them? They died young, flash floods sweeping them off to their doom.</verse>
<verse>They told God, "Get lost! What good is God Almighty to us?'</verse>
<verse>And yet it was God who gave them everything they had. It's beyond me how they can carry on like this!</verse>
<verse>"Good people see bad people crash, and call for a celebration. Relieved, they crow,</verse>
<verse>"At last! Our enemies--wiped out. Everything they had and stood for is up in smoke!'</verse>
<verse>"Give in to God, come to terms with him and everything will turn out just fine.</verse>
<verse>Let him tell you what to do; take his words to heart.</verse>
<verse>Come back to God Almighty and he'll rebuild your life. Clean house of everything evil.</verse>
<verse>Relax your grip on your money and abandon your gold-plated luxury.</verse>
<verse>God Almighty will be your treasure, more wealth than you can imagine.</verse>
<verse>"You'll take delight in God, the Mighty One, and look to him joyfully, boldly.</verse>
<verse>You'll pray to him and he'll listen; he'll help you do what you've promised.</verse>
<verse>You'll decide what you want and it will happen; your life will be bathed in light.</verse>
<verse>To those who feel low you'll say, "Chin up! Be brave!' and God will save them.</verse>
<verse>Yes, even the guilty will escape, escape through God's grace in your life." Job's Defense I'm Completely in the Dark</verse>
</chapter>