<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Job" book-id="18" n="24">
<verse>"But if Judgment Day isn't hidden from the Almighty, why are we kept in the dark?</verse>
<verse>There are people out there getting by with murder--stealing and lying and cheating.</verse>
<verse>They rip off the poor and exploit the unfortunate,</verse>
<verse>Push the helpless into the ditch, bully the weak so that they fear for their lives.</verse>
<verse>The poor, like stray dogs and cats, scavenge for food in back alleys.</verse>
<verse>They sort through the garbage of the rich, eke out survival on handouts.</verse>
<verse>Homeless, they shiver through cold nights on the street; they've no place to lay their heads.</verse>
<verse>Exposed to the weather, wet and frozen, they huddle in makeshift shelters.</verse>
<verse>Nursing mothers have their babies snatched from them; the infants of the poor are kidnapped and sold.</verse>
<verse>They go about patched and threadbare; even the hard workers go hungry.</verse>
<verse>No matter how back-breaking their labor, they can never make ends meet.</verse>
<verse>People are dying right and left, groaning in torment. The wretched cry out for help and God does nothing, acts like nothing's wrong!</verse>
<verse>"Then there are those who avoid light at all costs, who scorn the light-filled path.</verse>
<verse>When the sun goes down, the murderer gets up--kills the poor and robs the defenseless.</verse>
<verse>Sexual predators can't wait for nightfall, thinking, "No one can see us now.'</verse>
<verse>Burglars do their work at night, but keep well out of sight through the day. They want nothing to do with light.</verse>
<verse>Deep darkness is morning for that bunch; they make the terrors of darkness their companions in crime.</verse>
<verse>"They are scraps of wood floating on the water--useless, cursed junk, good for nothing.</verse>
<verse>As surely as snow melts under the hot, summer sun, sinners disappear in the grave.</verse>
<verse>The womb has forgotten them, worms have relished them--nothing that is evil lasts.</verse>
<verse>Unscrupulous, they prey on those less fortunate.</verse>
<verse>However much they strut and flex their muscles, there's nothing to them. They're hollow.</verse>
<verse>They may have an illusion of security, but God has his eye on them.</verse>
<verse>They may get their brief successes, but then it's over, nothing to show for it. Like yesterday's newspaper, they're used to wrap up the garbage.</verse>
<verse>You're free to try to prove me a liar, but you won't be able to do it." Bildad's Third Attack Even the Stars Aren't Perfect in God's Eyes</verse>
</chapter>