<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Job" book_id="18" n="27">
<verse>Having waited for Zophar, Job now resumed his defense:</verse>
<verse>"God--Alive! He's denied me justice! God Almighty! He's ruined my life!</verse>
<verse>But for as long as I draw breath, and for as long as God breathes life into me,</verse>
<verse>I refuse to say one word that isn't true. I refuse to confess to any charge that's false.</verse>
<verse>There is no way I'll ever agree to your accusations. I'll not deny my integrity even if it costs me my life.</verse>
<verse>I'm holding fast to my integrity and not loosening my grip--and, believe me, I'll never regret it.</verse>
<verse>"Let my enemy be exposed as wicked! Let my adversary be proven guilty!</verse>
<verse>What hope do people without God have when life is cut short? when God puts an end to life?</verse>
<verse>Do you think God will listen to their cry for help when disaster hits?</verse>
<verse>What interest have they ever shown in the Almighty? Have they ever been known to pray before?</verse>
<verse>"I've given you a clear account of God in action, suppressed nothing regarding God Almighty.</verse>
<verse>The evidence is right before you. You can all see it for yourselves, so why do you keep talking nonsense?</verse>
<verse>"I'll quote your own words back to you: This is how God treats the wicked, this is what evil people can expect from God Almighty:</verse>
<verse>Their children--all of them--will die violent deaths; they'll never have enough bread to put on the table.</verse>
<verse>They'll be wiped out by the plague, and none of the widows will shed a tear when they're gone.</verse>
<verse>Even if they make a lot of money and are resplendent in the latest fashions,</verse>
<verse>It's the good who will end up wearing the clothes and the decent who will divide up the money.</verse>
<verse>They build elaborate houses that won't survive a single winter.</verse>
<verse>They go to bed wealthy and wake up poor.</verse>
<verse>Terrors pour in on them like flash floods--a tornado snatches them away in the middle of the night,</verse>
<verse>A cyclone sweeps them up--gone! Not a trace of them left, not even a footprint.</verse>
<verse>Catastrophes relentlessly pursue them; they run this way and that, but there's no place to hide--</verse>
<verse>Pummeled by the weather, blown to kingdom come by the storm.'</verse>
</chapter>