<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Job" book-id="18" n="28">
<verse>"We all know how silver seams the rocks, we've seen the stuff from which gold is refined,</verse>
<verse>We're aware of how iron is dug out of the ground and copper is smelted from rock.</verse>
<verse>Miners penetrate the earth's darkness, searching the roots of the mountains for ore, digging away in the suffocating darkness.</verse>
<verse>Far from civilization, far from the traffic, they cut a shaft, and are lowered into it by ropes.</verse>
<verse>Earth's surface is a field for grain, but its depths are a forge</verse>
<verse>Firing sapphires from stones and chiseling gold from rocks.</verse>
<verse>Vultures are blind to its riches, hawks never lay eyes on it.</verse>
<verse>Wild animals are oblivious to it, lions don't know it's there.</verse>
<verse>Miners hammer away at the rock, they uproot the mountains.</verse>
<verse>They tunnel through the rock and find all kinds of beautiful gems.</verse>
<verse>They discover the origins of rivers, and bring earth's secrets to light.</verse>
<verse>"But where, oh where, will they find Wisdom? Where does Insight hide?</verse>
<verse>Mortals don't have a clue, haven't the slightest idea where to look.</verse>
<verse>Earth's depths say, "It's not here'; ocean deeps echo, "Never heard of it.'</verse>
<verse>It can't be bought with the finest gold; no amount of silver can get it.</verse>
<verse>Even famous Ophir gold can't buy it, not even diamonds and sapphires.</verse>
<verse>Neither gold nor emeralds are comparable; extravagant jewelry can't touch it.</verse>
<verse>Pearl necklaces and ruby bracelets--why bother? None of this is even a down payment on Wisdom!</verse>
<verse>Pile gold and African diamonds as high as you will, they can't hold a candle to Wisdom.</verse>
<verse>"So where does Wisdom come from? And where does Insight live?</verse>
<verse>It can't be found by looking, no matter how deep you dig, no matter how high you fly.</verse>
<verse>If you search through the graveyard and question the dead, they say, "We've only heard rumors of it.'</verse>
<verse>"God alone knows the way to Wisdom, he knows the exact place to find it.</verse>
<verse>He knows where everything is on earth, he sees everything under heaven.</verse>
<verse>After he commanded the winds to blow and measured out the waters,</verse>
<verse>Arranged for the rain and set off explosions of thunder and lightning,</verse>
<verse>He focused on Wisdom, made sure it was all set and tested and ready.</verse>
<verse>Then he addressed the human race: "Here it is! Fear-of-the-Lord--that's Wisdom, and Insight means shunning evil.'"</verse>
</chapter>