<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Job" book_id="18" n="29">
<verse>Job now resumed his response:</verse>
<verse>"Oh, how I long for the good old days, when God took such very good care of me.</verse>
<verse>He always held a lamp before me and I walked through the dark by its light.</verse>
<verse>Oh, how I miss those golden years when God's friendship graced my home,</verse>
<verse>When the Mighty One was still by my side and my children were all around me,</verse>
<verse>When everything was going my way, and nothing seemed too difficult.</verse>
<verse>"When I walked downtown and sat with my friends in the public square,</verse>
<verse>Young and old greeted me with respect; I was honored by everyone in town.</verse>
<verse>When I spoke, everyone listened;</verse>
<verse>they hung on my every word.</verse>
<verse>People who knew me spoke well of me; my reputation went ahead of me.</verse>
<verse>I was known for helping people in trouble and standing up for those who were down on their luck.</verse>
<verse>The dying blessed me, and the bereaved were cheered by my visits.</verse>
<verse>All my dealings with people were good. I was known for being fair to everyone I met.</verse>
<verse>I was eyes to the blind and feet to the lame,</verse>
<verse>Father to the needy, and champion of abused aliens.</verse>
<verse>I grabbed street thieves by the scruff of the neck and made them give back what they'd stolen.</verse>
<verse>I thought, "I'll die peacefully in my own bed, grateful for a long and full life,</verse>
<verse>A life deep-rooted and well-watered, a life limber and dew-fresh,</verse>
<verse>My soul suffused with glory and my body robust until the day I die.'</verse>
<verse>"Men and women listened when I spoke, hung expectantly on my every word.</verse>
<verse>After I spoke, they'd be quiet, taking it all in.</verse>
<verse>They welcomed my counsel like spring rain, drinking it all in.</verse>
<verse>When I smiled at them, they could hardly believe it; their faces lit up, their troubles took wing!</verse>
<verse>I was their leader, establishing the mood and setting the pace by which they lived. Where I led, they followed.</verse>
</chapter>