<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Job" book-id="18" n="3">
<verse>Then Job broke the silence. He spoke up and cursed his fate:</verse>
<verse>"Obliterate the day I was born. Blank out the night I was conceived!</verse>
<verse>Let it be a black hole in space. May God above forget it ever happened. Erase it from the books!</verse>
<verse>May the day of my birth be buried in deep darkness, shrouded by the fog, swallowed by the night.</verse>
<verse>And the night of my conception--the devil take it! Rip the date off the calendar, delete it from the almanac.</verse>
<verse>Oh, turn that night into pure nothingness--no sounds of pleasure from that night, ever!</verse>
<verse>May those who are good at cursing curse that day. Unleash the sea beast, Leviathan, on it.</verse>
<verse>May its morning stars turn to black cinders, waiting for a daylight that never comes, never once seeing the first light of dawn.</verse>
<verse>And why? Because it released me from my mother's womb into a life with so much trouble.</verse>
<verse>"Why didn't I die at birth, my first breath out of the womb my last?</verse>
<verse>Why were there arms to rock me, and breasts for me to drink from?</verse>
<verse>I could be resting in peace right now, asleep forever, feeling no pain,</verse>
<verse>In the company of kings and statesmen in their royal ruins,</verse>
<verse>Or with princes resplendent in their gold and silver tombs.</verse>
<verse>Why wasn't I stillborn and buried with all the babies who never saw light,</verse>
<verse>Where the wicked no longer trouble anyone and bone-weary people get a long-deserved rest?</verse>
<verse>Prisoners sleep undisturbed, never again to wake up to the bark of the guards.</verse>
<verse>The small and the great are equals in that place, and slaves are free from their masters.</verse>
<verse>"Why does God bother giving light to the miserable, why bother keeping bitter people alive,</verse>
<verse>Those who want in the worst way to die, and can't, who can't imagine anything better than death,</verse>
<verse>Who count the day of their death and burial the happiest day of their life?</verse>
<verse>What's the point of life when it doesn't make sense, when God blocks all the roads to meaning?</verse>
<verse>"Instead of bread I get groans for my supper, then leave the table and vomit my anguish.</verse>
<verse>The worst of my fears has come true, what I've dreaded most has happened.</verse>
<verse>My repose is shattered, my peace destroyed. No rest for me, ever--death has invaded life." Eliphaz Speaks Out Now You're the One in Trouble</verse>
</chapter>