<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Job" book_id="18" n="30">
<verse>"But no longer. Now I'm the butt of their jokes--young ruffians! whippersnappers!</verse>
<verse>Why, I considered their fathers mere inexperienced pups. But they are worse than dogs--good for nothing, stray, mangy animals,</verse>
<verse>Half-starved, scavenging the back alleys, howling at the moon;</verse>
<verse>Homeless guttersnipes chewing on old bones and licking old tin cans;</verse>
<verse>Outcasts from the community, cursed as dangerous delinquents.</verse>
<verse>Nobody would put up with them; they were driven from the neighborhood.</verse>
<verse>You could hear them out there at the edge of town, yelping and barking, huddled in junkyards,</verse>
<verse>A gang of beggars and no-names, thrown out on their ears.</verse>
<verse>"But now I'm the one they're after, mistreating me, taunting and mocking.</verse>
<verse>They abhor me, they abuse me. How dare those scoundrels--they spit in my face!</verse>
<verse>Now that God has undone me and left me in a heap, they hold nothing back. Anything goes.</verse>
<verse>They come at me from my blind side, trip me up, then jump on me while I'm down.</verse>
<verse>They throw every kind of obstacle in my path, determined to ruin me--and no one lifts a finger to help me!</verse>
<verse>They violate my broken body, trample through the rubble of my ruined life.</verse>
<verse>Terrors assault me--my dignity in shreds, salvation up in smoke.</verse>
<verse>"And now my life drains out, as suffering seizes and grips me hard.</verse>
<verse>Night gnaws at my bones; the pain never lets up.</verse>
<verse>I am tied hand and foot, my neck in a noose. I twist and turn.</verse>
<verse>Thrown facedown in the muck, I'm a muddy mess, inside and out.</verse>
<verse>"I shout for help, God, and get nothing, no answer! I stand to face you in protest, and you give me a blank stare!</verse>
<verse>You've turned into my tormenter--you slap me around, knock me about.</verse>
<verse>You raised me up so I was riding high and then dropped me, and I crashed.</verse>
<verse>I know you're determined to kill me, to put me six feet under.</verse>
<verse>"What did I do to deserve this? Did I ever hit anyone who was calling for help?</verse>
<verse>Haven't I wept for those who live a hard life, been heartsick over the lot of the poor?</verse>
<verse>But where did it get me? I expected good but evil showed up. I looked for light but darkness fell.</verse>
<verse>My stomach's in a constant churning, never settles down. Each day confronts me with more suffering.</verse>
<verse>I walk under a black cloud. The sun is gone. I stand in the congregation and protest.</verse>
<verse>I howl with the jackals, I hoot with the owls.</verse>
<verse>I'm black and blue all over, burning up with fever.</verse>
<verse>My fiddle plays nothing but the blues; my mouth harp wails laments.</verse>
</chapter>