<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Job" book-id="18" n="33">
<verse>"So please, Job, hear me out, honor me by listening to me.</verse>
<verse>What I'm about to say has been carefully thought out.</verse>
<verse>I have no ulterior motives in this; I'm speaking honestly from my heart.</verse>
<verse>The Spirit of God made me what I am, the breath of God Almighty gave me life!</verse>
<verse>"And if you think you can prove me wrong, do it. Lay out your arguments. Stand up for yourself!</verse>
<verse>Look, I'm human--no better than you; we're both made of the same kind of mud.</verse>
<verse>So let's work this through together; don't let my aggressiveness overwhelm you.</verse>
<verse>"Here's what you said. I heard you say it with my own ears.</verse>
<verse>You said, "I'm pure--I've done nothing wrong. Believe me, I'm clean--my conscience is clear.</verse>
<verse>But God keeps picking on me; he treats me like I'm his enemy.</verse>
<verse>He's thrown me in jail; he keeps me under constant surveillance.'</verse>
<verse>"But let me tell you, Job, you're wrong, dead wrong! God is far greater than any human.</verse>
<verse>So how dare you haul him into court, and then complain that he won't answer your charges?</verse>
<verse>God always answers, one way or another, even when people don't recognize his presence.</verse>
<verse>"In a dream, for instance, a vision at night, when men and women are deep in sleep, fast asleep in their beds--</verse>
<verse>God opens their ears and impresses them with warnings</verse>
<verse>To turn them back from something bad they're planning, from some reckless choice,</verse>
<verse>And keep them from an early grave, from the river of no return.</verse>
<verse>"Or, God might get their attention through pain, by throwing them on a bed of suffering,</verse>
<verse>So they can't stand the sight of food, have no appetite for their favorite treats.</verse>
<verse>They lose weight, wasting away to nothing, reduced to a bag of bones.</verse>
<verse>They hang on the cliff-edge of death, knowing the next breath may be their last.</verse>
<verse>"But even then an angel could come, a champion--there are thousands of them!- to take up your cause,</verse>
<verse>A messenger who would mercifully intervene, canceling the death sentence with the words: "I've come up with the ransom!'</verse>
<verse>Before you know it, you're healed, the very picture of health!</verse>
<verse>"Or, you may fall on your knees and pray--to God's delight! You'll see God's smile and celebrate, finding yourself set right with God.</verse>
<verse>You'll sing God's praises to everyone you meet, testifying, "I messed up my life--and let me tell you, it wasn't worth it.</verse>
<verse>But God stepped in and saved me from certain death. I'm alive again! Once more I see the light!'</verse>
<verse>"This is the way God works. Over and over again</verse>
<verse>He pulls our souls back from certain destruction so we'll see the light--and live in the light!</verse>
<verse>"Keep listening, Job. Don't interrupt--I'm not finished yet.</verse>
<verse>But if you think of anything I should know, tell me. There's nothing I'd like better than to see your name cleared.</verse>
<verse>Meanwhile, keep listening. Don't distract me with interruptions. I'm going to teach you the basics of wisdom." Elihu's Second Speech It's Impossible for God to Do Evil</verse>
</chapter>