<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Job" book-id="18" n="34">
<verse>Elihu continued:</verse>
<verse>"So, my fine friends--listen to me, and see what you think of this.</verse>
<verse>Isn't it just common sense--as common as the sense of taste--</verse>
<verse>To put our heads together and figure out what's going on here?</verse>
<verse>"We've all heard Job say, "I'm in the right, but God won't give me a fair trial.</verse>
<verse>When I defend myself, I'm called a liar to my face. I've done nothing wrong, and I get punished anyway.'</verse>
<verse>Have you ever heard anything to beat this? Does nothing faze this man Job?</verse>
<verse>Do you think he's spent too much time in bad company, hanging out with the wrong crowd,</verse>
<verse>So that now he's parroting their line: "It doesn't pay to try to please God'?</verse>
<verse>"You're veterans in dealing with these matters; certainly we're of one mind on this. It's impossible for God to do anything evil; no way can the Mighty One do wrong.</verse>
<verse>He makes us pay for exactly what we've done--no more, no less. Our chickens always come home to roost.</verse>
<verse>It's impossible for God to do anything wicked, for the Mighty One to subvert justice.</verse>
<verse>He's the one who runs the earth! He cradles the whole world in his hand!</verse>
<verse>If he decided to hold his breath,</verse>
<verse>every man, woman, and child would die for lack of air.</verse>
<verse>"So, Job, use your head; this is all pretty obvious.</verse>
<verse>Can someone who hates order, keep order? Do you dare condemn the righteous, mighty God?</verse>
<verse>Doesn't God always tell it like it is, exposing corrupt rulers as scoundrels and criminals?</verse>
<verse>Does he play favorites with the rich and famous and slight the poor? Isn't he equally responsible to everybody?</verse>
<verse>Don't people who deserve it die without notice? Don't wicked rulers tumble to their doom? When the so-called great ones are wiped out, we know God is working behind the scenes.</verse>
<verse>"He has his eyes on every man and woman. He doesn't miss a trick.</verse>
<verse>There is no night dark enough, no shadow deep enough, to hide those who do evil.</verse>
<verse>God doesn't need to gather any more evidence; their sin is an open-and-shut case.</verse>
<verse>He deposes the so-called high and mighty without asking questions, and replaces them at once with others.</verse>
<verse>Nobody gets by with anything; overnight, judgment is signed, sealed, and delivered.</verse>
<verse>He punishes the wicked for their wickedness out in the open where everyone can see it,</verse>
<verse>Because they quit following him, no longer even thought about him or his ways.</verse>
<verse>Their apostasy was announced by the cry of the poor; the cry of the afflicted got God's attention. Because You Refuse to Live on God's Terms</verse>
<verse>"If God is silent, what's that to you? If he turns his face away, what can you do about it? But whether silent or hidden, he's there, ruling,</verse>
<verse>so that those who hate God won't take over and ruin people's lives.</verse>
<verse>"So why don't you simply confess to God? Say, "I sinned, but I'll sin no more.</verse>
<verse>Teach me to see what I still don't see. Whatever evil I've done, I'll do it no more.'</verse>
<verse>Just because you refuse to live on God's terms, do you think he should start living on yours? You choose. I can't do it for you. Tell me what you decide.</verse>
<verse>"All right-thinking people say--and the wise who have listened to me concur--</verse>
<verse>"Job is an ignoramus. He talks utter nonsense.'</verse>
<verse>Job, you need to be pushed to the wall and called to account for wickedly talking back to God the way you have.</verse>
<verse>You've compounded your original sin by rebelling against God's discipline, Defiantly shaking your fist at God, piling up indictments against the Almighty One." Elihu's Third Speech When God Makes Creation a Classroom</verse>
</chapter>