<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Job" book_id="18" n="36">
<verse>Here Elihu took a deep breath, but kept going:</verse>
<verse>"Stay with me a little longer. I'll convince you. There's still more to be said on God's side.</verse>
<verse>I learned all this firsthand from the Source; everything I know about justice I owe to my Maker himself.</verse>
<verse>Trust me, I'm giving you undiluted truth; believe me, I know these things inside and out.</verse>
<verse>"It's true that God is all-powerful, but he doesn't bully innocent people.</verse>
<verse>For the wicked, though, it's a different story--he doesn't give them the time of day, but champions the rights of their victims.</verse>
<verse>He never takes his eyes off the righteous; he honors them lavishly, promotes them endlessly.</verse>
<verse>When things go badly, when affliction and suffering descend,</verse>
<verse>God tells them where they've gone wrong, shows them how their pride has caused their trouble.</verse>
<verse>He forces them to heed his warning, tells them they must repent of their bad life.</verse>
<verse>If they obey and serve him, they'll have a good, long life on easy street.</verse>
<verse>But if they disobey, they'll be cut down in their prime and never know the first thing about life.</verse>
<verse>Angry people without God pile grievance upon grievance, always blaming others for their troubles.</verse>
<verse>Living it up in sexual excesses, virility wasted, they die young.</verse>
<verse>But those who learn from their suffering, God delivers from their suffering.</verse>
<verse>"Oh, Job, don't you see how God's wooing you from the jaws of danger? How he's drawing you into wide-open places--inviting you to feast at a table laden with blessings?</verse>
<verse>And here you are laden with the guilt of the wicked, obsessed with putting the blame on God!</verse>
<verse>Don't let your great riches mislead you; don't think you can bribe your way out of this.</verse>
<verse>Did you plan to buy your way out of this? Not on your life!</verse>
<verse>And don't think that night, when people sleep off their troubles, will bring you any relief.</verse>
<verse>Above all, don't make things worse with more evil--that's what's behind your suffering as it is!</verse>
<verse>"Do you have any idea how powerful God is? Have you ever heard of a teacher like him?</verse>
<verse>Has anyone ever had to tell him what to do, or correct him, saying, "You did that all wrong!'?</verse>
<verse>Remember, then, to praise his workmanship, which is so often celebrated in song.</verse>
<verse>Everybody sees it; nobody is too far away to see it.</verse>
<verse>"Take a long, hard look. See how great he is--infinite, greater than anything you could ever imagine or figure out!</verse>
<verse>"He pulls water up out of the sea, distills it, and fills up his rain-cloud cisterns.</verse>
<verse>Then the skies open up and pour out soaking showers on everyone.</verse>
<verse>Does anyone have the slightest idea how this happens? How he arranges the clouds, how he speaks in thunder?</verse>
<verse>Just look at that lightning, his sky-filling light show illumining the dark depths of the sea!</verse>
<verse>These are the symbols of his sovereignty, his generosity, his loving care.</verse>
<verse>He hurls arrows of light, taking sure and accurate aim.</verse>
<verse>The High God roars in the thunder, angry against evil.</verse>
</chapter>