<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Job" book-id="18" n="37">
<verse>"Whenever this happens, my heart stops--I'm stunned, I can't catch my breath.</verse>
<verse>Listen to it! Listen to his thunder, the rolling, rumbling thunder of his voice.</verse>
<verse>He lets loose his lightnings from horizon to horizon, lighting up the earth from pole to pole.</verse>
<verse>In their wake, the thunder echoes his voice, powerful and majestic. He lets out all the stops, he holds nothing back. No one can mistake that voice--</verse>
<verse>His word thundering so wondrously, his mighty acts staggering our understanding.</verse>
<verse>He orders the snow, "Blanket the earth!' and the rain, "Soak the whole countryside!'</verse>
<verse>No one can escape the weather--it's there. And no one can escape from God.</verse>
<verse>Wild animals take shelter, crawling into their dens,</verse>
<verse>When blizzards roar out of the north and freezing rain crusts the land.</verse>
<verse>It's God's breath that forms the ice, it's God's breath that turns lakes and rivers solid.</verse>
<verse>And yes, it's God who fills clouds with rainwater and hurls lightning from them every which way.</verse>
<verse>He puts them through their paces--first this way, then that--commands them to do what he says all over the world.</verse>
<verse>Whether for discipline or grace or extravagant love, he makes sure they make their mark.</verse>
<verse>"Job, are you listening? Have you noticed all this? Stop in your tracks! Take in God's miracle-wonders!</verse>
<verse>Do you have any idea how God does it all, how he makes bright lightning from dark storms,</verse>
<verse>How he piles up the cumulus clouds--all these miracle-wonders of a perfect Mind?</verse>
<verse>Why, you don't even know how to keep cool on a sweltering hot day,</verse>
<verse>So how could you even dream of making a dent in that hot-tin-roof sky?</verse>
<verse>"If you're so smart, give us a lesson in how to address God. We're in the dark and can't figure it out.</verse>
<verse>Do you think I'm dumb enough to challenge God? Wouldn't that just be asking for trouble?</verse>
<verse>No one in his right mind stares straight at the sun on a clear and cloudless day.</verse>
<verse>As gold comes from the northern mountains, so a terrible beauty streams from God.</verse>
<verse>"Mighty God! Far beyond our reach! Unsurpassable in power and justice! It's unthinkable that he'd treat anyone unfairly.</verse>
<verse>So bow to him in deep reverence, one and all! If you're wise, you'll most certainly worship him." God Confronts Job Have You Gotten to the Bottom of Things?</verse>
</chapter>