<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Job" book_id="18" n="38">
<verse>And now, finally, GOD answered Job from the eye of a violent storm. He said:</verse>
<verse>"Why do you confuse the issue? Why do you talk without knowing what you're talking about?</verse>
<verse>Pull yourself together, Job! Up on your feet! Stand tall! I have some questions for you, and I want some straight answers.</verse>
<verse>Where were you when I created the earth? Tell me, since you know so much!</verse>
<verse>Who decided on its size? Certainly you'll know that! Who came up with the blueprints and measurements?</verse>
<verse>How was its foundation poured, and who set the cornerstone,</verse>
<verse>While the morning stars sang in chorus and all the angels shouted praise?</verse>
<verse>And who took charge of the ocean when it gushed forth like a baby from the womb?</verse>
<verse>That was me! I wrapped it in soft clouds, and tucked it in safely at night.</verse>
<verse>Then I made a playpen for it, a strong playpen so it couldn't run loose,</verse>
<verse>And said, "Stay here, this is your place. Your wild tantrums are confined to this place.'</verse>
<verse>"And have you ever ordered Morning, "Get up!' told Dawn, "Get to work!'</verse>
<verse>So you could seize Earth like a blanket and shake out the wicked like cockroaches?</verse>
<verse>As the sun brings everything to light, brings out all the colors and shapes,</verse>
<verse>The cover of darkness is snatched from the wicked--they're caught in the very act!</verse>
<verse>"Have you ever gotten to the true bottom of things, explored the labyrinthine caves of deep ocean?</verse>
<verse>Do you know the first thing about death? Do you have one clue regarding death's dark mysteries?</verse>
<verse>And do you have any idea how large this earth is? Speak up if you have even the beginning of an answer.</verse>
<verse>"Do you know where Light comes from and where Darkness lives</verse>
<verse>So you can take them by the hand and lead them home when they get lost?</verse>
<verse>Why, of course you know that. You've known them all your life, grown up in the same neighborhood with them!</verse>
<verse>"Have you ever traveled to where snow is made, seen the vault where hail is stockpiled,</verse>
<verse>The arsenals of hail and snow that I keep in readiness for times of trouble and battle and war?</verse>
<verse>Can you find your way to where lightning is launched, or to the place from which the wind blows?</verse>
<verse>Who do you suppose carves canyons for the downpours of rain, and charts the route of thunderstorms</verse>
<verse>That bring water to unvisited fields, deserts no one ever lays eyes on,</verse>
<verse>Drenching the useless wastelands so they're carpeted with wildflowers and grass?</verse>
<verse>And who do you think is the father of rain and dew,</verse>
<verse>the mother of ice and frost?</verse>
<verse>You don't for a minute imagine these marvels of weather just happen, do you?</verse>
<verse>"Can you catch the eye of the beautiful Pleiades sisters, or distract Orion from his hunt?</verse>
<verse>Can you get Venus to look your way, or get the Great Bear and her cubs to come out and play?</verse>
<verse>Do you know the first thing about the sky's constellations and how they affect things on Earth?</verse>
<verse>"Can you get the attention of the clouds, and commission a shower of rain?</verse>
<verse>Can you take charge of the lightning bolts and have them report to you for orders?</verse>
<verse>"Who do you think gave weather-wisdom to the ibis, and storm-savvy to the rooster?</verse>
<verse>Does anyone know enough to number all the clouds or tip over the rain barrels of heaven</verse>
<verse>When the earth is cracked and dry, the ground baked hard as a brick?</verse>
<verse>"Can you teach the lioness to stalk her prey and satisfy the appetite of her cubs</verse>
<verse>As they crouch in their den, waiting hungrily in their cave?</verse>
<verse>And who sets out food for the ravens when their young cry to God, fluttering about because they have no food?</verse>
</chapter>