<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Job" book_id="18" n="39">
<verse>"Do you know the month when mountain goats give birth? Have you ever watched a doe bear her fawn?</verse>
<verse>Do you know how many months she is pregnant? Do you know the season of her delivery,</verse>
<verse>when she crouches down and drops her offspring?</verse>
<verse>Her young ones flourish and are soon on their own; they leave and don't come back.</verse>
<verse>"Who do you think set the wild donkey free, opened the corral gates and let him go?</verse>
<verse>I gave him the whole wilderness to roam in, the rolling plains and wide-open places.</verse>
<verse>He laughs at his city cousins, who are harnessed and harried. He's oblivious to the cries of teamsters.</verse>
<verse>He grazes freely through the hills, nibbling anything that's green.</verse>
<verse>"Will the wild buffalo condescend to serve you, volunteer to spend the night in your barn?</verse>
<verse>Can you imagine hitching your plow to a buffalo and getting him to till your fields?</verse>
<verse>He's hugely strong, yes, but could you trust him, would you dare turn the job over to him?</verse>
<verse>You wouldn't for a minute depend on him, would you, to do what you said when you said it?</verse>
<verse>"The ostrich flaps her wings futilely--all those beautiful feathers, but useless!</verse>
<verse>She lays her eggs on the hard ground, leaves them there in the dirt, exposed to the weather,</verse>
<verse>Not caring that they might get stepped on and cracked or trampled by some wild animal.</verse>
<verse>She's negligent with her young, as if they weren't even hers. She cares nothing about anything.</verse>
<verse>She wasn't created very smart, that's for sure, wasn't given her share of good sense.</verse>
<verse>But when she runs, oh, how she runs, laughing, leaving horse and rider in the dust.</verse>
<verse>"Are you the one who gave the horse his prowess and adorned him with a shimmering mane?</verse>
<verse>Did you create him to prance proudly and strike terror with his royal snorts?</verse>
<verse>He paws the ground fiercely, eager and spirited, then charges into the fray.</verse>
<verse>He laughs at danger, fearless, doesn't shy away from the sword.</verse>
<verse>The banging and clanging of quiver and lance don't faze him.</verse>
<verse>He quivers with excitement, and at the trumpet blast races off at a gallop.</verse>
<verse>At the sound of the trumpet he neighs mightily, smelling the excitement of battle from a long way off, catching the rolling thunder of the war cries.</verse>
<verse>"Was it through your know how that the hawk learned to fly, soaring effortlessly on thermal updrafts?</verse>
<verse>Did you command the eagle's flight, and teach her to build her nest in the heights,</verse>
<verse>Perfectly at home on the high cliff-face, invulnerable on pinnacle and crag?</verse>
<verse>From her perch she searches for prey, spies it at a great distance.</verse>
<verse>Her young gorge themselves on carrion; wherever there's a roadkill, you'll see her circling."</verse>
</chapter>