<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Job" book-id="18" n="4">
<verse>Then Eliphaz from Teman spoke up:</verse>
<verse>"Would you mind if I said something to you? Under the circumstances it's hard to keep quiet.</verse>
<verse>You yourself have done this plenty of times, spoken words that clarify, encouraged those who were about to quit.</verse>
<verse>Your words have put stumbling people on their feet, put fresh hope in people about to collapse.</verse>
<verse>But now you're the one in trouble--you're hurting! You've been hit hard and you're reeling from the blow.</verse>
<verse>But shouldn't your devout life give you confidence now? Shouldn't your exemplary life give you hope?</verse>
<verse>"Think! Has a truly innocent person ever ended up on the scrap heap? Do genuinely upright people ever lose out in the end?</verse>
<verse>It's my observation that those who plow evil and sow trouble reap evil and trouble.</verse>
<verse>One breath from God and they fall apart, one blast of his anger and there's nothing left of them.</verse>
<verse>The mighty lion, king of the beasts, roars mightily, but when he's toothless he's useless--</verse>
<verse>No teeth, no prey--and the cubs wander off to fend for themselves.</verse>
<verse>"A word came to me in secret--a mere whisper of a word, but I heard it clearly.</verse>
<verse>It came in a scary dream one night, after I had fallen into a deep, deep sleep.</verse>
<verse>Dread stared me in the face, and Terror. I was scared to death--I shook from head to foot.</verse>
<verse>A spirit glided right in front of me--the hair on my head stood on end.</verse>
<verse>I couldn't tell what it was that appeared there--a blur... and then I heard a muffled voice:</verse>
<verse>How can mere mortals be more righteous than God? How can humans be purer than their Creator?</verse>
<verse>Why, God doesn't even trust his own servants, doesn't even cheer his angels,</verse>
<verse>So how much less these bodies composed of mud, fragile as moths?</verse>
<verse>These bodies of ours are here today and gone tomorrow, and no one even notices--gone without a trace.</verse>
<verse>When the tent stakes are ripped up, the tent collapses--we die and are never the wiser for having lived.'</verse>
</chapter>