<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Job" book_id="18" n="40">
<verse>GOD then confronted Job directly:</verse>
<verse>"Now what do you have to say for yourself? Are you going to haul me, the Mighty One, into court and press charges?" Job Answers God I'm Ready to Shut Up and Listen</verse>
<verse>Job answered:</verse>
<verse>"I'm speechless, in awe--words fail me. I should never have opened my mouth!</verse>
<verse>I've talked too much, way too much. I'm ready to shut up and listen." God's Second Set of Questions I Want Straight Answers</verse>
<verse>GOD addressed Job next from the eye of the storm, and this is what he said:</verse>
<verse>"I have some more questions for you, and I want straight answers.</verse>
<verse>"Do you presume to tell me what I'm doing wrong? Are you calling me a sinner so you can be a saint?</verse>
<verse>Do you have an arm like my arm? Can you shout in thunder the way I can?</verse>
<verse>Go ahead, show your stuff. Let's see what you're made of, what you can do.</verse>
<verse>Unleash your outrage. Target the arrogant and lay them flat.</verse>
<verse>Target the arrogant and bring them to their knees. Stop the wicked in their tracks--make mincemeat of them!</verse>
<verse>Dig a mass grave and dump them in it--faceless corpses in an unmarked grave.</verse>
<verse>I'll gladly step aside and hand things over to you--you can surely save yourself with no help from me!</verse>
<verse>"Look at the land beast, Behemoth. I created him as well as you. Grazing on grass, docile as a cow--</verse>
<verse>Just look at the strength of his back, the powerful muscles of his belly.</verse>
<verse>His tail sways like a cedar in the wind; his huge legs are like beech trees.</verse>
<verse>His skeleton is made of steel, every bone in his body hard as steel.</verse>
<verse>Most magnificent of all my creatures, but I still lead him around like a lamb!</verse>
<verse>The grass-covered hills serve him meals, while field mice frolic in his shadow.</verse>
<verse>He takes afternoon naps under shade trees, cools himself in the reedy swamps,</verse>
<verse>Lazily cool in the leafy shadows as the breeze moves through the willows.</verse>
<verse>And when the river rages he doesn't budge, stolid and unperturbed even when the Jordan goes wild.</verse>
<verse>But you'd never want him for a pet--you'd never be able to housebreak him!</verse>
</chapter>