<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Job" book-id="18" n="41">
<verse>"Or can you pull in the sea beast, Leviathan, with a fly rod	 and stuff him in your creel?</verse>
<verse>Can you lasso him with a rope, or snag him with an anchor?</verse>
<verse>Will he beg you over and over for mercy, or flatter you with flowery speech?</verse>
<verse>Will he apply for a job with you to run errands and serve you the rest of your life?</verse>
<verse>Will you play with him as if he were a pet goldfish? Will you make him the mascot of the neighborhood children?</verse>
<verse>Will you put him on display in the market and have shoppers haggle over the price?</verse>
<verse>Could you shoot him full of arrows like a pin cushion, or drive harpoons into his huge head?</verse>
<verse>If you so much as lay a hand on him, you won't live to tell the story.</verse>
<verse>What hope would you have with such a creature? Why, one look at him would do you in!</verse>
<verse>If you can't hold your own against his glowering visage, how, then, do you expect to stand up to me?</verse>
<verse>Who could confront me and get by with it? I'm in charge of all this--I run this universe!</verse>
<verse>"But I've more to say about Leviathan, the sea beast, his enormous bulk, his beautiful shape.</verse>
<verse>Who would even dream of piercing that tough skin or putting those jaws into bit and bridle?</verse>
<verse>And who would dare knock at the door of his mouth filled with row upon row of fierce teeth?</verse>
<verse>His pride is invincible; nothing can make a dent in that pride.</verse>
<verse>Nothing can get through that proud skin--impervious to weapons and weather,</verse>
<verse>The thickest and toughest of hides, impenetrable!</verse>
<verse>"He snorts and the world lights up with fire, he blinks and the dawn breaks.</verse>
<verse>Comets pour out of his mouth, fireworks arc and branch.</verse>
<verse>Smoke erupts from his nostrils like steam from a boiling pot.</verse>
<verse>He blows and fires blaze; flames of fire stream from his mouth.</verse>
<verse>All muscle he is--sheer and seamless muscle. To meet him is to dance with death.</verse>
<verse>Sinewy and lithe, there's not a soft spot in his entire body--</verse>
<verse>As tough inside as out, rock-hard, invulnerable.</verse>
<verse>Even angels run for cover when he surfaces, cowering before his tail-thrashing turbulence.</verse>
<verse>Javelins bounce harmlessly off his hide, harpoons ricochet wildly.</verse>
<verse>Iron bars are so much straw to him, bronze weapons beneath notice.</verse>
<verse>Arrows don't even make him blink; bullets make no more impression than raindrops.</verse>
<verse>A battle ax is nothing but a splinter of kindling; he treats a brandished harpoon as a joke.</verse>
<verse>His belly is armor-plated, inexorable--unstoppable as a barge.</verse>
<verse>He roils deep ocean the way you'd boil water, he whips the sea like you'd whip an egg into batter.</verse>
<verse>With a luminous trail stretching out behind him, you might think Ocean had grown a gray beard!</verse>
<verse>There's nothing on this earth quite like him, not an ounce of fear in that creature!</verse>
<verse>He surveys all the high and mighty--king of the ocean, king of the deep!" Job Worships God I Babbled On About Things Far Beyond Me</verse>
</chapter>