<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Job" book_id="18" n="42">
<verse>Job answered GOD:</verse>
<verse>"I'm convinced: You can do anything and everything. Nothing and no one can upset your plans.</verse>
<verse>You asked, "Who is this muddying the water, ignorantly confusing the issue, second-guessing my purposes?' I admit it. I was the one. I babbled on about things far beyond me, made small talk about wonders way over my head.</verse>
<verse>You told me, "Listen, and let me do the talking. Let me ask the questions. You give the answers.'</verse>
<verse>I admit I once lived by rumors of you; now I have it all firsthand--from my own eyes and ears!</verse>
<verse>I'm sorry--forgive me. I'll never do that again, I promise! I'll never again live on crusts of hearsay, crumbs of rumor."</verse>
<verse>After GOD had finished addressing Job, he turned to Eliphaz the Temanite and said, "I've had it with you and your two friends. I'm fed up! You haven't been honest either with me or about me--not the way my friend Job has.</verse>
<verse>So here's what you must do. Take seven bulls and seven rams, and go to my friend Job. Sacrifice a burnt offering on your own behalf. My friend Job will pray for you, and I will accept his prayer. He will ask me not to treat you as you deserve for talking nonsense about me, and for not being honest with me, as he has."</verse>
<verse>They did it. Eliphaz the Temanite, Bildad the Shuhite, and Zophar the Naamathite did what GOD commanded. And GOD accepted Job's prayer.</verse>
<verse>After Job had interceded for his friends, GOD restored his fortune--and then doubled it!</verse>
<verse>All his brothers and sisters and friends came to his house and celebrated. They told him how sorry they were, and consoled him for all the trouble GOD had brought him. Each of them brought generous housewarming gifts.</verse>
<verse>GOD blessed Job's later life even more than his earlier life. He ended up with fourteen thousand sheep, six thousand camels, one thousand teams of oxen, and one thousand donkeys.</verse>
<verse>He also had seven sons and three daughters.</verse>
<verse>He named the first daughter Dove, the second, Cinnamon, and the third, Darkeyes.</verse>
<verse>There was not a woman in that country as beautiful as Job's daughters. Their father treated them as equals with their brothers, providing the same inheritance.</verse>
<verse>Job lived on another hundred and forty years, living to see his children and grandchildren--four generations of them!</verse>
<verse>Then he died--an old man, a full life.</verse>
</chapter>