<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Job" book_id="18" n="5">
<verse>"Call for help, Job, if you think anyone will answer! To which of the holy angels will you turn?</verse>
<verse>The hot temper of a fool eventually kills him, the jealous anger of a simpleton does her in.</verse>
<verse>I've seen it myself--seen fools putting down roots, and then, suddenly, their houses are cursed.</verse>
<verse>Their children out in the cold, abused and exploited, with no one to stick up for them.</verse>
<verse>Hungry people off the street plunder their harvests, cleaning them out completely, taking thorns and all, insatiable for everything they have.</verse>
<verse>Don't blame fate when things go wrong--trouble doesn't come from nowhere.</verse>
<verse>It's human! Mortals are born and bred for trouble, as certainly as sparks fly upward.</verse>
<verse>"If I were in your shoes, I'd go straight to God, I'd throw myself on the mercy of God.</verse>
<verse>After all, he's famous for great and unexpected acts; there's no end to his surprises.</verse>
<verse>He gives rain, for instance, across the wide earth, sends water to irrigate the fields.</verse>
<verse>He raises up the down-and-out, gives firm footing to those sinking in grief.</verse>
<verse>He aborts the schemes of conniving crooks, so that none of their plots come to term.</verse>
<verse>He catches the know-it--alls in their conspiracies--all that intricate intrigue swept out with the trash!</verse>
<verse>Suddenly they're disoriented, plunged into darkness; they can't see to put one foot in front of the other.</verse>
<verse>But the downtrodden are saved by God, saved from the murderous plots, saved from the iron fist.</verse>
<verse>And so the poor continue to hope, while injustice is bound and gagged.</verse>
<verse>"So, what a blessing when God steps in and corrects you! Mind you, don't despise the discipline of Almighty God!</verse>
<verse>True, he wounds, but he also dresses the wound; the same hand that hurts you, heals you.</verse>
<verse>From one disaster after another he delivers you; no matter what the calamity, the evil can't touch you--</verse>
<verse>"In famine, he'll keep you from starving, in war, from being gutted by the sword.</verse>
<verse>You'll be protected from vicious gossip and live fearless through any catastrophe.</verse>
<verse>You'll shrug off disaster and famine, and stroll fearlessly among wild animals.</verse>
<verse>You'll be on good terms with rocks and mountains; wild animals will become your good friends.</verse>
<verse>You'll know that your place on earth is safe, you'll look over your goods and find nothing amiss.</verse>
<verse>You'll see your children grow up, your family lovely and lissome as orchard grass.</verse>
<verse>You'll arrive at your grave ripe with many good years, like sheaves of golden grain at harvest.</verse>
<verse>"Yes, this is the way things are--my word of honor! Take it to heart and you won't go wrong." JOB REPLIES TO ELIPHAZ God Has Dumped the Works on Me</verse>
</chapter>