<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Job" book_id="18" n="6">
<verse>Job answered:</verse>
<verse>"If my misery could be weighed, if you could pile the whole bitter load on the scales,</verse>
<verse>It would be heavier than all the sand of the sea! Is it any wonder that I'm screaming like a caged cat?</verse>
<verse>The arrows of God Almighty are in me, poison arrows--and I'm poisoned all through! God has dumped the whole works on me.</verse>
<verse>Donkeys bray and cows moo when they run out of pasture--so don't expect me to keep quiet in this.</verse>
<verse>Do you see what God has dished out for me? It's enough to turn anyone's stomach!</verse>
<verse>Everything in me is repulsed by it--it makes me sick.</verse>
<verse>"All I want is an answer to one prayer, a last request to be honored:</verse>
<verse>Let God step on me--squash me like a bug, and be done with me for good.</verse>
<verse>I'd at least have the satisfaction of not having blasphemed the Holy God, before being pressed past the limits.</verse>
<verse>Where's the strength to keep my hopes up? What future do I have to keep me going?</verse>
<verse>Do you think I have nerves of steel? Do you think I'm made of iron?</verse>
<verse>Do you think I can pull myself up by my bootstraps? Why, I don't even have any boots!</verse>
<verse>"When desperate people give up on God Almighty, their friends, at least, should stick with them.</verse>
<verse>But my brothers are fickle as a gulch in the desert--one day they're gushing with water</verse>
<verse>From melting ice and snow cascading out of the mountains,</verse>
<verse>But by midsummer they're dry, gullies baked dry in the sun.</verse>
<verse>Travelers who spot them and go out of their way for a drink, end up in a waterless gulch and die of thirst.</verse>
<verse>Merchant caravans from Tema see them and expect water, tourists from Sheba hope for a cool drink.</verse>
<verse>They arrive so confident--but what a disappointment! They get there, and their faces fall!</verse>
<verse>And you, my so-called friends, are no better--there's nothing to you! One look at a hard scene and you shrink in fear.</verse>
<verse>It's not as though I asked you for anything--I didn't ask you for one red cent--</verse>
<verse>Nor did I beg you to go out on a limb for me. So why all this dodging and shuffling?</verse>
<verse>"Confront me with the truth and I'll shut up, show me where I've gone off the track.</verse>
<verse>Honest words never hurt anyone, but what's the point of all this pious bluster?</verse>
<verse>You pretend to tell me what's wrong with my life, but treat my words of anguish as so much hot air.</verse>
<verse>Are people mere things to you? Are friends just items of profit and loss?</verse>
<verse>"Look me in the eyes! Do you think I'd lie to your face?</verse>
<verse>Think it over--no double-talk! Think carefully--my integrity is on the line!</verse>
<verse>Can you detect anything false in what I say? Don't you trust me to discern good from evil?</verse>
</chapter>