<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Job" book_id="18" n="7">
<verse>"Human life is a struggle, isn't it? It's a life sentence to hard labor.</verse>
<verse>Like field hands longing for quitting time and working stiffs with nothing to hope for but payday,</verse>
<verse>I'm given a life that meanders and goes nowhere--months of aimlessness, nights of misery!</verse>
<verse>I go to bed and think, "How long till I can get up?' I toss and turn as the night drags on--and I'm fed up!</verse>
<verse>I'm covered with maggots and scabs. My skin gets scaly and hard, then oozes with pus.</verse>
<verse>My days come and go swifter than the click of knitting needles, and then the yarn runs out--an unfinished life!</verse>
<verse>"God, don't forget that I'm only a puff of air! These eyes have had their last look at goodness.</verse>
<verse>And your eyes have seen the last of me; even while you're looking, there'll be nothing left to look at.</verse>
<verse>When a cloud evaporates, it's gone for good; those who go to the grave never come back.</verse>
<verse>They don't return to visit their families; never again will friends drop in for coffee.</verse>
<verse>"And so I'm not keeping one bit of this quiet, I'm laying it all out on the table; my complaining to high heaven is bitter, but honest.</verse>
<verse>Are you going to put a muzzle on me, the way you quiet the sea and still the storm?</verse>
<verse>If I say, "I'm going to bed, then I'll feel better. A little nap will lift my spirits,'</verse>
<verse>You come and so scare me with nightmares and frighten me with ghosts</verse>
<verse>That I'd rather strangle in the bedclothes than face this kind of life any longer.</verse>
<verse>I hate this life! Who needs any more of this? Let me alone! There's nothing to my life--it's nothing but smoke.</verse>
<verse>"What are mortals anyway, that you bother with them, that you even give them the time of day?</verse>
<verse>That you check up on them every morning, looking in on them to see how they're doing?</verse>
<verse>Let up on me, will you? Can't you even let me spit in peace?</verse>
<verse>Even suppose I'd sinned--how would that hurt you? You're responsible for every human being. Don't you have better things to do than pick on me? Why make a federal case out of me?</verse>
<verse>Why don't you just forgive my sins and start me off with a clean slate? The way things are going, I'll soon be dead. You'll look high and low, but I won't be around." BILDAD's RESPONSE Does God Mess Up?</verse>
</chapter>