<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Job" book-id="18" n="8">
<verse>Bildad from Shuhah was next to speak:</verse>
<verse>"How can you keep on talking like this? You're talking nonsense, and noisy nonsense at that.</verse>
<verse>Does God mess up? Does God Almighty ever get things backwards?</verse>
<verse>It's plain that your children sinned against him--otherwise, why would God have punished them?</verse>
<verse>Here's what you must do--and don't put it off any longer: Get down on your knees before God Almighty.</verse>
<verse>If you're as innocent and upright as you say, it's not too late--he'll come running; he'll set everything right again, reestablish your fortunes.</verse>
<verse>Even though you're not much right now, you'll end up better than ever.</verse>
<verse>"Put the question to our ancestors, study what they learned from their ancestors.</verse>
<verse>For we're newcomers at this, with a lot to learn, and not too long to learn it.</verse>
<verse>So why not let the ancients teach you, tell you what's what, instruct you in what they knew from experience?</verse>
<verse>Can mighty pine trees grow tall without soil? Can luscious tomatoes flourish without water?</verse>
<verse>Blossoming flowers look great before they're cut or picked, but without soil or water they wither more quickly than grass.</verse>
<verse>That's what happens to all who forget God--all their hopes come to nothing.</verse>
<verse>They hang their life from one thin thread, they hitch their fate to a spider web.</verse>
<verse>One jiggle and the thread breaks, one jab and the web collapses.</verse>
<verse>Or they're like weeds springing up in the sunshine, invading the garden,</verse>
<verse>Spreading everywhere, overtaking the flowers, getting a foothold even in the rocks.</verse>
<verse>But when the gardener rips them out by the roots, the garden doesn't miss them one bit.</verse>
<verse>The sooner the godless are gone, the better; then good plants can grow in their place.</verse>
<verse>"There's no way that God will reject a good person, and there is no way he'll help a bad one.</verse>
<verse>God will let you laugh again; you'll raise the roof with shouts of joy,</verse>
<verse>With your enemies thoroughly discredited, their house of cards collapsed." HKJob ContinuesHK How Can Mere Mortals Get Right with God?</verse>
</chapter>