<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Job" book-id="18" n="9">
<verse>Job continued by saying:</verse>
<verse>"So what's new? I know all this. The question is, "How can mere mortals get right with God?'</verse>
<verse>If we wanted to bring our case before him, what chance would we have? Not one in a thousand!</verse>
<verse>God's wisdom is so deep, God's power so immense, who could take him on and come out in one piece?</verse>
<verse>He moves mountains before they know what's happened, flips them on their heads on a whim.</verse>
<verse>He gives the earth a good shaking up, rocks it down to its very foundations.</verse>
<verse>He tells the sun, "Don't shine,' and it doesn't; he pulls the blinds on the stars.</verse>
<verse>All by himself he stretches out the heavens and strides on the waves of the sea.</verse>
<verse>He designed the Big Dipper and Orion, the Pleiades and Alpha Centauri.</verse>
<verse>We'll never comprehend all the great things he does; his miracle-surprises can't be counted.</verse>
<verse>Somehow, though he moves right in front of me, I don't see him; quietly but surely he's active, and I miss it.</verse>
<verse>If he steals you blind, who can stop him? Who's going to say, "Hey, what are you doing?'</verse>
<verse>God doesn't hold back on his anger; even dragon-bred monsters cringe before him.</verse>
<verse>"So how could I ever argue with him, construct a defense that would influence God?</verse>
<verse>Even though I'm innocent I could never prove it; I can only throw myself on the Judge's mercy.</verse>
<verse>If I called on God and he himself answered me, then, and only then, would I believe that he'd heard me.</verse>
<verse>As it is, he knocks me about from pillar to post, beating me up, black and blue, for no good reason.</verse>
<verse>He won't even let me catch my breath, piles bitterness upon bitterness.</verse>
<verse>If it's a question of who's stronger, he wins, hands down! If it's a question of justice, who'll serve him the subpoena?</verse>
<verse>Even though innocent, anything I say incriminates me; blameless as I am, my defense just makes me sound worse.</verse>
<verse>"Believe me, I'm blameless. I don't understand what's going on. I hate my life!</verse>
<verse>Since either way it ends up the same, I can only conclude that God destroys the good right along with the bad.</verse>
<verse>When calamity hits and brings sudden death, he folds his arms, aloof from the despair of the innocent.</verse>
<verse>He lets the wicked take over running the world, he installs judges who can't tell right from wrong. If he's not responsible, who is?</verse>
<verse>"My time is short--what's left of my life races off too fast for me to even glimpse the good.</verse>
<verse>My life is going fast, like a ship under full sail, like an eagle plummeting to its prey.</verse>
<verse>Even if I say, "I'll put all this behind me, I'll look on the bright side and force a smile,'</verse>
<verse>All these troubles would still be like grit in my gut since it's clear you're not going to let up.</verse>
<verse>The verdict has already been handed down-"Guilty!'- so what's the use of protests or appeals?</verse>
<verse>Even if I scrub myself all over and wash myself with the strongest soap I can find,</verse>
<verse>It wouldn't last--you'd push me into a pigpen, or worse, so nobody could stand me for the stink.</verse>
<verse>"God and I are not equals; I can't bring a case against him. We'll never enter a courtroom as peers.</verse>
<verse>How I wish we had an arbitrator to step in and let me get on with life--</verse>
<verse>To break God's death grip on me, to free me from this terror so I could breathe again.</verse>
<verse>Then I'd speak up and state my case boldly. As things stand, there is no way I can do it.</verse>
</chapter>