<chapter translation="MSG" testament="New" book="1 Timothy" book-id="54" n="4">
<verse>The Spirit makes it clear that as time goes on, some are going to give up on the faith and chase after demonic illusions put forth by professional liars.</verse>
<verse>These liars have lied so well and for so long that they've lost their capacity for truth.</verse>
<verse>They will tell you not to get married. They'll tell you not to eat this or that food--perfectly good food God created to be eaten heartily and with thanksgiving by Christians!</verse>
<verse>Everything God created is good, and to be received with thanks. Nothing is to be sneered at and thrown out.</verse>
<verse>God's Word and our prayers make every item in creation holy.</verse>
<verse>You've been raised on the Message of the faith and have followed sound teaching. Now pass on this counsel to the Christians there, and you'll be a good servant of Jesus.</verse>
<verse>Stay clear of silly stories that get dressed up as religion. Exercise daily in God--no spiritual flabbiness, please!</verse>
<verse>Workouts in the gymnasium are useful, but a disciplined life in God is far more so, making you fit both today and forever.</verse>
<verse>You can count on this. Take it to heart.</verse>
<verse>This is why we've thrown ourselves into this venture so totally. We're banking on the living God, Savior of all men and women, especially believers.</verse>
<verse>Get the word out. Teach all these things.</verse>
<verse>And don't let anyone put you down because you're young. Teach believers with your life: by word, by demeanor, by love, by faith, by integrity.</verse>
<verse>Stay at your post reading Scripture, giving counsel, teaching.</verse>
<verse>And that special gift of ministry you were given when the leaders of the church laid hands on you and prayed--keep that dusted off and in use.</verse>
<verse>Cultivate these things. Immerse yourself in them. The people will all see you mature right before their eyes!</verse>
<verse>Keep a firm grasp on both your character and your teaching. Don't be diverted. Just keep at it. Both you and those who hear you will experience salvation.</verse>
</chapter>