<chapter translation="NIV" testament="New" book="2 Corinthians" book-id="47" n="6">
<verse>As God's fellow workers we urge you not to receive God's grace in vain.</verse>
<verse>For he says, "In the time of my favor I heard you, and in the day of salvation I helped you." I tell you, now is the time of God's favor, now is the day of salvation.</verse>
<verse>We put no stumbling block in anyone's path, so that our ministry will not be discredited.</verse>
<verse>Rather, as servants of God we commend ourselves in every way: in great endurance; in troubles, hardships and distresses;</verse>
<verse>in beatings, imprisonments and riots; in hard work, sleepless nights and hunger;</verse>
<verse>in purity, understanding, patience and kindness; in the Holy Spirit and in sincere love;</verse>
<verse>in truthful speech and in the power of God; with weapons of righteousness in the right hand and in the left;</verse>
<verse>through glory and dishonor, bad report and good report; genuine, yet regarded as impostors;</verse>
<verse>known, yet regarded as unknown; dying, and yet we live on; beaten, and yet not killed;</verse>
<verse>sorrowful, yet always rejoicing; poor, yet making many rich; having nothing, and yet possessing everything.</verse>
<verse>We have spoken freely to you, Corinthians, and opened wide our hearts to you.</verse>
<verse>We are not withholding our affection from you, but you are withholding yours from us.</verse>
<verse>As a fair exchange--I speak as to my children--open wide your hearts also.</verse>
<verse>Do not be yoked together with unbelievers. For what do righteousness and wickedness have in common? Or what fellowship can light have with darkness?</verse>
<verse>What harmony is there between Christ and Belial? What does a believer have in common with an unbeliever?</verse>
<verse>What agreement is there between the temple of God and idols? For we are the temple of the living God. As God has said: "I will live with them and walk among them, and I will be their God, and they will be my people."</verse>
<verse>"Therefore come out from them and be separate, says the Lord. Touch no unclean thing, and I will receive you."</verse>
<verse>"I will be a Father to you, and you will be my sons and daughters, says the Lord Almighty."</verse>
</chapter>