<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Psalms" book_id="19" n="10">
<verse>GOD, are you avoiding me? Where are you when I need you?</verse>
<verse>Full of hot air, the wicked are hot on the trail of the poor. Trip them up, tangle them up in their fine-tuned plots.</verse>
<verse>The wicked are windbags, the swindlers have foul breath.</verse>
<verse>The wicked snub GOD, their noses stuck high in the air. Their graffiti are scrawled on the walls: "Catch us if you can!God is dead."</verse>
<verse>They care nothing for what you think; if you get in their way, they blow you off.</verse>
<verse>They live (they think) a charmed life: "We can't go wrong. This is our lucky year!"</verse>
<verse>They carry a mouthful of hexes, their tongues spit venom like adders.</verse>
<verse>They hide behind ordinary people, then pounce on their victims.</verse>
<verse>They mark the luckless, then wait like a hunter in a blind; When the poor wretch wanders too close, they stab him in the back.</verse>
<verse>The hapless fool is kicked to the ground, the unlucky victim is brutally axed.</verse>
<verse>He thinks God has dumped him, he's sure that God is indifferent to his plight.</verse>
<verse>Time to get up, GOD-get moving. The luckless think they're Godforsaken.</verse>
<verse>They wonder why the wicked scorn God and get away with it, Why the wicked are so cocksure they'll never come up for audit.</verse>
<verse>But you know all about it--the contempt, the abuse. I dare to believe that the luckless will get lucky someday in you. You won't let them down: orphans won't be orphans forever.</verse>
<verse>Break the wicked right arms, break all the evil left arms. Search and destroy every sign of crime.</verse>
<verse>GOD's grace and order wins; godlessness loses.</verse>
<verse>The victim's faint pulse picks up; the hearts of the hopeless pump red blood as you put your ear to their lips.</verse>
<verse>Orphans get parents, the homeless get homes. The reign of terror is over, the rule of the gang lords is ended.</verse>
</chapter>