<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Psalms" book_id="19" n="102">
<verse>GOD, listen! Listen to my prayer, listen to the pain in my cries.</verse>
<verse>Don't turn your back on me just when I need you so desperately. Pay attention! This is a cry for help! And hurry--this can't wait!</verse>
<verse>I'm wasting away to nothing, I'm burning up with fever.</verse>
<verse>I'm a ghost of my former self, half-consumed already by terminal illness.</verse>
<verse>My jaws ache from gritting my teeth; I'm nothing but skin and bones.</verse>
<verse>I'm like a buzzard in the desert, a crow perched on the rubble.</verse>
<verse>Insomniac, I twitter away, mournful as a sparrow in the gutter.</verse>
<verse>All day long my enemies taunt me, while others just curse.</verse>
<verse>They bring in meals--casseroles of ashes! I draw drink from a barrel of my tears.</verse>
<verse>And all because of your furious anger; you swept me up and threw me out.</verse>
<verse>There's nothing left of me--a withered weed, swept clean from the path.</verse>
<verse>Yet you, GOD, are sovereign still, always and ever sovereign.</verse>
<verse>You'll get up from your throne and help Zion--it's time for compassionate help.</verse>
<verse>Oh, how your servants love this city's rubble and weep with compassion over its dust!</verse>
<verse>The godless nations will sit up and take notice -see your glory, worship your name--</verse>
<verse>When GOD rebuilds Zion, when he shows up in all his glory,</verse>
<verse>When he attends to the prayer of the wretched. He won't dismiss their prayer.</verse>
<verse>Write this down for the next generation so people not yet born will praise GOD:</verse>
<verse>"GOD looked out from his high holy place; from heaven he surveyed the earth.</verse>
<verse>He listened to the groans of the doomed, he opened the doors of their death cells."</verse>
<verse>Write it so the story can be told in Zion, so GOD's praise will be sung in Jerusalem's streets</verse>
<verse>And wherever people gather together along with their rulers to worship him.</verse>
<verse>GOD sovereignly brought me to my knees, he cut me down in my prime.</verse>
<verse>"Oh, don't," I prayed, "please don't let me die. You have more years than you know what to do with!</verse>
<verse>You laid earth's foundations a long time ago, and handcrafted the very heavens;</verse>
<verse>You'll still be around when they're long gone, threadbare and discarded like an old suit of clothes. You'll throw them away like a worn-out coat,</verse>
<verse>but year after year you're as good as new.</verse>
<verse>Your servants' children will have a good place to live and their children will be at home with you."</verse>
</chapter>