<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Psalms" book-id="19" n="103">
<verse>O my soul, bless GOD. From head to toe, I'll bless his holy name!</verse>
<verse>O my soul, bless GOD, don't forget a single blessing!</verse>
<verse>He forgives your sins--every one. He heals your diseases--every one.</verse>
<verse>He redeems you from hell--saves your life! He crowns you with love and mercy--a paradise crown.</verse>
<verse>He wraps you in goodness--beauty eternal. He renews your youth--you're always young in his presence.</verse>
<verse>GOD makes everything come out right; he puts victims back on their feet.</verse>
<verse>He showed Moses how he went about his work, opened up his plans to all Israel.</verse>
<verse>GOD is sheer mercy and grace; not easily angered, he's rich in love.</verse>
<verse>He doesn't endlessly nag and scold, nor hold grudges forever.</verse>
<verse>He doesn't treat us as our sins deserve, nor pay us back in full for our wrongs.</verse>
<verse>As high as heaven is over the earth, so strong is his love to those who fear him.</verse>
<verse>And as far as sunrise is from sunset, he has separated us from our sins.</verse>
<verse>As parents feel for their children, GOD feels for those who fear him.</verse>
<verse>He knows us inside and out, keeps in mind that we're made of mud.</verse>
<verse>Men and women don't live very long; like wildflowers they spring up and blossom,</verse>
<verse>But a storm snuffs them out just as quickly, leaving nothing to show they were here.</verse>
<verse>GOD's love, though, is ever and always, eternally present to all who fear him, Making everything right for them and their children</verse>
<verse>as they follow his Covenant ways and remember to do whatever he said.</verse>
<verse>GOD has set his throne in heaven; he rules over us all. He's the King!</verse>
<verse>So bless GOD, you angels, ready and able to fly at his bidding, quick to hear and do what he says.</verse>
<verse>Bless GOD, all you armies of angels, alert to respond to whatever he wills.</verse>
<verse>Bless GOD, all creatures, wherever you are--everything and everyone made by GOD. And you, O my soul, bless GOD!</verse>
</chapter>