<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Psalms" book-id="19" n="104">
<verse>O my soul, bless GOD! GOD, my God, how great you are! beautifully, gloriously robed,</verse>
<verse>Dressed up in sunshine, and all heaven stretched out for your tent.</verse>
<verse>You built your palace on the ocean deeps, made a chariot out of clouds and took off on wind--wings.</verse>
<verse>You commandeered winds as messengers, appointed fire and flame as ambassadors.</verse>
<verse>You set earth on a firm foundation so that nothing can shake it, ever.</verse>
<verse>You blanketed earth with ocean, covered the mountains with deep waters;</verse>
<verse>Then you roared and the water ran away--your thunder crash put it to flight.</verse>
<verse>Mountains pushed up, valleys spread out in the places you assigned them.</verse>
<verse>You set boundaries between earth and sea; never again will earth be flooded.</verse>
<verse>You started the springs and rivers, sent them flowing among the hills.</verse>
<verse>All the wild animals now drink their fill, wild donkeys quench their thirst.</verse>
<verse>Along the riverbanks the birds build nests, ravens make their voices heard.</verse>
<verse>You water the mountains from your heavenly cisterns; earth is supplied with plenty of water.</verse>
<verse>You make grass grow for the livestock, hay for the animals that plow the ground. Oh yes, God brings grain from the land,</verse>
<verse>wine to make people happy, Their faces glowing with health, a people well-fed and hearty.</verse>
<verse>GOD's trees are well-watered--the Lebanon cedars he planted.</verse>
<verse>Birds build their nests in those trees; look--the stork at home in the treetop.</verse>
<verse>Mountain goats climb about the cliffs; badgers burrow among the rocks.</verse>
<verse>The moon keeps track of the seasons, the sun is in charge of each day.</verse>
<verse>When it's dark and night takes over, all the forest creatures come out.</verse>
<verse>The young lions roar for their prey, clamoring to God for their supper.</verse>
<verse>When the sun comes up, they vanish, lazily stretched out in their dens.</verse>
<verse>Meanwhile, men and women go out to work, busy at their jobs until evening.</verse>
<verse>What a wildly wonderful world, GOD! You made it all, with Wisdom at your side, made earth overflow with your wonderful creations.</verse>
<verse>Oh, look--the deep, wide sea, brimming with fish past counting, sardines and sharks and salmon.</verse>
<verse>Ships plow those waters, and Leviathan, your pet dragon, romps in them.</verse>
<verse>All the creatures look expectantly to you to give them their meals on time.</verse>
<verse>You come, and they gather around; you open your hand and they eat from it.</verse>
<verse>If you turned your back, they'd die in a minute--Take back your Spirit and they die, revert to original mud;</verse>
<verse>Send out your Spirit and they spring to life--the whole countryside in bloom and blossom.</verse>
<verse>The glory of GOD-let it last forever! Let GOD enjoy his creation!</verse>
<verse>He takes one look at earth and triggers an earthquake, points a finger at the mountains, and volcanoes erupt.</verse>
<verse>Oh, let me sing to GOD all my life long, sing hymns to my God as long as I live!</verse>
<verse>Oh, let my song please him; I'm so pleased to be singing to GOD.</verse>
<verse>But clear the ground of sinners--no more godless men and women! O my soul, bless GOD!</verse>
</chapter>