<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Psalms" book-id="19" n="105">
<verse>Hallelujah! Thank GOD! Pray to him by name! Tell everyone you meet what he has done!</verse>
<verse>Sing him songs, belt out hymns, translate his wonders into music!</verse>
<verse>Honor his holy name with Hallelujahs, you who seek GOD. Live a happy life!</verse>
<verse>Keep your eyes open for GOD, watch for his works; be alert for signs of his presence.</verse>
<verse>Remember the world of wonders he has made, his miracles, and the verdicts he's rendered--</verse>
<verse>O seed of Abraham, his servant, O child of Jacob, his chosen.</verse>
<verse>He's GOD, our God, in charge of the whole earth.</verse>
<verse>And he remembers, remembers his Covenant--for a thousand generations he's been as good as his word.</verse>
<verse>It's the Covenant he made with Abraham, the same oath he swore to Isaac,</verse>
<verse>The very statute he established with Jacob, the eternal Covenant with Israel,</verse>
<verse>Namely, "I give you the land. Canaan is your hill-country inheritance."</verse>
<verse>When they didn't count for much, a mere handful, and strangers at that,</verse>
<verse>Wandering from country to country, drifting from pillar to post,</verse>
<verse>He permitted no one to abuse them. He told kings to keep their hands off:</verse>
<verse>"Don't you dare lay a hand on my anointed, don't hurt a hair on the heads of my prophets."</verse>
<verse>Then he called down a famine on the country, he broke every last blade of wheat.</verse>
<verse>But he sent a man on ahead: Joseph, sold as a slave.</verse>
<verse>They put cruel chains on his ankles, an iron collar around his neck,</verse>
<verse>Until God's word came to the Pharaoh, and GOD confirmed his promise.</verse>
<verse>God sent the king to release him. The Pharaoh set Joseph free;</verse>
<verse>He appointed him master of his palace, put him in charge of all his business</verse>
<verse>To personally instruct his princes and train his advisors in wisdom.</verse>
<verse>Then Israel entered Egypt, Jacob immigrated to the Land of Ham.</verse>
<verse>God gave his people lots of babies; soon their numbers alarmed their foes.</verse>
<verse>He turned the Egyptians against his people; they abused and cheated God's servants.</verse>
<verse>Then he sent his servant Moses, and Aaron, whom he also chose.</verse>
<verse>They worked marvels in that spiritual wasteland, miracles in the Land of Ham.</verse>
<verse>He spoke, "Darkness!" and it turned dark--they couldn't see what they were doing.</verse>
<verse>He turned all their water to blood so that all their fish died;</verse>
<verse>He made frogs swarm through the land, even into the king's bedroom;</verse>
<verse>He gave the word and flies swarmed, gnats filled the air.</verse>
<verse>He substituted hail for rain, he stabbed their land with lightning;</verse>
<verse>He wasted their vines and fig trees, smashed their groves of trees to splinters;</verse>
<verse>With a word he brought in locusts, millions of locusts, armies of locusts;</verse>
<verse>They consumed every blade of grass in the country and picked the ground clean of produce;</verse>
<verse>He struck down every firstborn in the land, the first fruits of their virile powers.</verse>
<verse>He led Israel out, their arms filled with loot, and not one among his tribes even stumbled.</verse>
<verse>Egypt was glad to have them go--they were scared to death of them.</verse>
<verse>God spread a cloud to keep them cool through the day and a fire to light their way through the night;</verse>
<verse>They prayed and he brought quail, filled them with the bread of heaven;</verse>
<verse>He opened the rock and water poured out; it flowed like a river through that desert--</verse>
<verse>All because he remembered his Covenant, his promise to Abraham, his servant.</verse>
<verse>Remember this! He led his people out singing for joy; his chosen people marched, singing their hearts out!</verse>
<verse>He made them a gift of the country they entered, helped them seize the wealth of the nations</verse>
<verse>So they could do everything he told them--could follow his instructions to the letter. Hallelujah! al</verse>
</chapter>