<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Psalms" book-id="19" n="106">
<verse>Hallelujah! Thank GOD! And why? Because he's good, because his love lasts.</verse>
<verse>But who on earth can do it--declaim GOD's mighty acts, broadcast all his praises?</verse>
<verse>You're one happy man when you do what's right, one happy woman when you form the habit of justice.</verse>
<verse>Remember me, GOD, when you enjoy your people; include me when you save them;</verse>
<verse>I want to see your chosen succeed, celebrate with your celebrating nation, join the Hallelujahs of your pride and joy!</verse>
<verse>We've sinned a lot, both we and our parents; We've fallen short, hurt a lot of people.</verse>
<verse>After our parents left Egypt, they took your wonders for granted, forgot your great and wonderful love. They were barely beyond the Red Sea when they defied the High God</verse>
<verse>-the very place he saved them! -the place he revealed his amazing power!</verse>
<verse>He rebuked the Red Sea so that it dried up on the spot -he paraded them right through! -no one so much as got wet feet!</verse>
<verse>He saved them from a life of oppression, pried them loose from the grip of the enemy.</verse>
<verse>Then the waters flowed back on their oppressors; there wasn't a single survivor.</verse>
<verse>Then they believed his words were true and broke out in songs of praise.</verse>
<verse>But it wasn't long before they forgot the whole thing, wouldn't wait to be told what to do.</verse>
<verse>They only cared about pleasing themselves in that desert, provoked God with their insistent demands.</verse>
<verse>He gave them exactly what they asked for--but along with it they got an empty heart.</verse>
<verse>One day in camp some grew jealous of Moses, also of Aaron, holy priest of GOD.</verse>
<verse>The ground opened and swallowed Dathan, then buried Abiram's gang.</verse>
<verse>Fire flared against that rebel crew and torched them to a cinder.</verse>
<verse>They cast in metal a bull calf at Horeb and worshiped the statue they'd made.</verse>
<verse>They traded the Glory for a cheap piece of sculpture--a grass-chewing bull!</verse>
<verse>They forgot God, their very own Savior, who turned things around in Egypt,</verse>
<verse>Who created a world of wonders in the Land of Ham, who gave that stunning performance at the Red Sea.</verse>
<verse>Fed up, God decided to get rid of them--and except for Moses, his chosen, he would have. But Moses stood in the gap and deflected God's anger, prevented it from destroying them utterly.</verse>
<verse>They went on to reject the Blessed Land, didn't believe a word of what God promised.</verse>
<verse>They found fault with the life they had and turned a deaf ear to GOD's voice.</verse>
<verse>Exasperated, God swore that he'd lay them low in the desert,</verse>
<verse>Scattering their children hither and yon, strewing them all over the earth.</verse>
<verse>Then they linked up with Baal Peor, attending funeral banquets and eating idol food.</verse>
<verse>That made God so angry that a plague spread through their ranks;</verse>
<verse>Phinehas stood up and pled their case and the plague was stopped.</verse>
<verse>This was counted to his credit; his descendants will never forget it.</verse>
<verse>They angered God again at Meribah Springs; this time Moses got mixed up in their evil;</verse>
<verse>Because they defied GOD yet again, Moses exploded and lost his temper.</verse>
<verse>They didn't wipe out those godless cultures as ordered by GOD;</verse>
<verse>Instead they intermarried with the heathen, and in time became just like them.</verse>
<verse>They worshiped their idols, were caught in the trap of idols.</verse>
<verse>They sacrificed their sons and daughters at the altars of demon gods.</verse>
<verse>They slit the throats of their babies, murdered their infant girls and boys. They offered their babies to Canaan's gods; the blood of their babies stained the land.</verse>
<verse>Their way of life stank to high heaven; they lived like whores.</verse>
<verse>And GOD was furious--a wildfire anger; he couldn't stand even to look at his people.</verse>
<verse>He turned them over to the heathen so that the people who hated them ruled them.</verse>
<verse>Their enemies made life hard for them; they were tyrannized under that rule.</verse>
<verse>Over and over God rescued them, but they never learned--until finally their sins destroyed them.</verse>
<verse>Still, when God saw the trouble they were in and heard their cries for help,</verse>
<verse>He remembered his Covenant with them, and, immense with love, took them by the hand.</verse>
<verse>He poured out his mercy on them while their captors looked on, amazed.</verse>
<verse>Save us, GOD, our God! Gather us back out of exile So we can give thanks to your holy name and join in the glory when you are praised!</verse>
<verse>Blessed be GOD, Israel's God! Bless now, bless always! Oh! Let everyone say Amen! Hallelujah! al</verse>
</chapter>