<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Psalms" book_id="19" n="107">
<verse>Oh, thank GOD-he's so good! His love never runs out.</verse>
<verse>All of you set free by GOD, tell the world! Tell how he freed you from oppression,</verse>
<verse>Then rounded you up from all over the place, from the four winds, from the seven seas.</verse>
<verse>Some of you wandered for years in the desert, looking but not finding a good place to live,</verse>
<verse>Half-starved and parched with thirst, staggering and stumbling, on the brink of exhaustion.</verse>
<verse>Then, in your desperate condition, you called out to GOD. He got you out in the nick of time;</verse>
<verse>He put your feet on a wonderful road that took you straight to a good place to live.</verse>
<verse>So thank GOD for his marvelous love, for his miracle mercy to the children he loves.</verse>
<verse>He poured great draughts of water down parched throats; the starved and hungry got plenty to eat.</verse>
<verse>Some of you were locked in a dark cell, cruelly confined behind bars,</verse>
<verse>Punished for defying God's Word, for turning your back on the High God's counsel--</verse>
<verse>A hard sentence, and your hearts so heavy, and not a soul in sight to help.</verse>
<verse>Then you called out to GOD in your desperate condition; he got you out in the nick of time.</verse>
<verse>He led you out of your dark, dark cell, broke open the jail and led you out.</verse>
<verse>So thank GOD for his marvelous love, for his miracle mercy to the children he loves;</verse>
<verse>He shattered the heavy jailhouse doors, he snapped the prison bars like matchsticks!</verse>
<verse>Some of you were sick because you'd lived a bad life, your bodies feeling the effects of your sin;</verse>
<verse>You couldn't stand the sight of food, so miserable you thought you'd be better off dead.</verse>
<verse>Then you called out to GOD in your desperate condition; he got you out in the nick of time.</verse>
<verse>He spoke the word that healed you, that pulled you back from the brink of death.</verse>
<verse>So thank GOD for his marvelous love, for his miracle mercy to the children he loves;</verse>
<verse>Offer thanksgiving sacrifices, tell the world what he's done--sing it out!</verse>
<verse>Some of you set sail in big ships; you put to sea to do business in faraway ports.</verse>
<verse>Out at sea you saw GOD in action, saw his breathtaking ways with the ocean:</verse>
<verse>With a word he called up the wind--an ocean storm, towering waves!</verse>
<verse>You shot high in the sky, then the bottom dropped out; your hearts were stuck in your throats.</verse>
<verse>You were spun like a top, you reeled like a drunk, you didn't know which end was up.</verse>
<verse>Then you called out to GOD in your desperate condition; he got you out in the nick of time.</verse>
<verse>He quieted the wind down to a whisper, put a muzzle on all the big waves.</verse>
<verse>And you were so glad when the storm died down, and he led you safely back to harbor.</verse>
<verse>So thank GOD for his marvelous love, for his miracle mercy to the children he loves.</verse>
<verse>Lift high your praises when the people assemble, shout Hallelujah when the elders meet!</verse>
<verse>GOD turned rivers into wasteland, springs of water into sunbaked mud;</verse>
<verse>Luscious orchards became alkali flats because of the evil of the people who lived there.</verse>
<verse>Then he changed wasteland into fresh pools of water, arid earth into springs of water,</verse>
<verse>Brought in the hungry and settled them there; they moved in--what a great place to live!</verse>
<verse>They sowed the fields, they planted vineyards, they reaped a bountiful harvest.</verse>
<verse>He blessed them and they prospered greatly; their herds of cattle never decreased.</verse>
<verse>But abuse and evil and trouble declined</verse>
<verse>as he heaped scorn on princes and sent them away. He gave the poor a safe place to live,</verse>
<verse>treated their clans like well-cared-for sheep.</verse>
<verse>Good people see this and are glad; bad people are speechless, stopped in their tracks.</verse>
<verse>If you are really wise, you'll think this over--it's time you appreciated GOD's deep love. A David prayer</verse>
</chapter>