<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Psalms" book_id="19" n="118">
<verse>Thank GOD because he's good, because his love never quits.</verse>
<verse>Tell the world, Israel, "His love never quits."</verse>
<verse>And you, clan of Aaron, tell the world, "His love never quits."</verse>
<verse>And you who fear GOD, join in, "His love never quits."</verse>
<verse>Pushed to the wall, I called to GOD; from the wide open spaces, he answered.</verse>
<verse>GOD's now at my side and I'm not afraid; who would dare lay a hand on me?</verse>
<verse>GOD's my strong champion; I flick off my enemies like flies.</verse>
<verse>Far better to take refuge in GOD than trust in people;</verse>
<verse>Far better to take refuge in GOD than trust in celebrities.</verse>
<verse>Hemmed in by barbarians, in GOD's name I rubbed their faces in the dirt;</verse>
<verse>Hemmed in and with no way out, in GOD's name I rubbed their faces in the dirt;</verse>
<verse>Like swarming bees, like wild prairie fire, they hemmed me in; in GOD's name I rubbed their faces in the dirt.</verse>
<verse>I was right on the cliff-edge, ready to fall, when GOD grabbed and held me.</verse>
<verse>GOD's my strength, he's also my song, and now he's my salvation.</verse>
<verse>Hear the shouts, hear the triumph songs in the camp of the saved? "The hand of GOD has turned the tide!</verse>
<verse>The hand of GOD is raised in victory! The hand of GOD has turned the tide!"</verse>
<verse>I didn't die. I lived! And now I'm telling the world what GOD did.</verse>
<verse>GOD tested me, he pushed me hard, but he didn't hand me over to Death.</verse>
<verse>Swing wide the city gates--the righteous gates! I'll walk right through and thank GOD!</verse>
<verse>This Temple Gate belongs to GOD, so the victors can enter and praise.</verse>
<verse>Thank you for responding to me; you've truly become my salvation!</verse>
<verse>The stone the masons discarded as flawed is now the capstone!</verse>
<verse>This is GOD's work. We rub our eyes--we can hardly believe it!</verse>
<verse>This is the very day GOD acted--let's celebrate and be festive!</verse>
<verse>Salvation now, GOD. Salvation now! Oh yes, GOD-a free and full life!</verse>
<verse>Blessed are you who enter in GOD's name--from GOD's house we bless you!</verse>
<verse>GOD is God, he has bathed us in light. Festoon the shrine with garlands, hang colored banners above the altar!</verse>
<verse>You're my God, and I thank you. O my God, I lift high your praise.</verse>
<verse>Thank GOD-he's so good. His love never quits! is</verse>
</chapter>