<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Psalms" book-id="19" n="119">
<verse>You're blessed when you stay on course, walking steadily on the road revealed by GOD.</verse>
<verse>You're blessed when you follow his directions, doing your best to find him.</verse>
<verse>That's right--you don't go off on your own; you walk straight along the road he set.</verse>
<verse>You, GOD, prescribed the right way to live; now you expect us to live it.</verse>
<verse>Oh, that my steps might be steady, keeping to the course you set;</verse>
<verse>Then I'd never have any regrets in comparing my life with your counsel.</verse>
<verse>I thank you for speaking straight from your heart; I learn the pattern of your righteous ways.</verse>
<verse>I'm going to do what you tell me to do; don't ever walk off and leave me. [JC]</verse>
<verse>How can a young person live a clean life? By carefully reading the map of your Word.</verse>
<verse>I'm single-minded in pursuit of you; don't let me miss the road signs you've posted.</verse>
<verse>I've banked your promises in the vault of my heart so I won't sin myself bankrupt.</verse>
<verse>Be blessed, GOD; train me in your ways of wise living.</verse>
<verse>I'll transfer to my lips all the counsel that comes from your mouth;</verse>
<verse>I delight far more in what you tell me about living than in gathering a pile of riches.</verse>
<verse>I ponder every morsel of wisdom from you, I attentively watch how you've done it.</verse>
<verse>I relish everything you've told me of life, I won't forget a word of it. [JC]</verse>
<verse>Be generous with me and I'll live a full life; not for a minute will I take my eyes off your road.</verse>
<verse>Open my eyes so I can see what you show me of your miracle-wonders.</verse>
<verse>I'm a stranger in these parts; give me clear directions.</verse>
<verse>My soul is starved and hungry, ravenous!- insatiable for your nourishing commands.</verse>
<verse>And those who think they know so much, ignoring everything you tell them--let them have it!</verse>
<verse>Don't let them mock and humiliate me; I've been careful to do just what you said.</verse>
<verse>While bad neighbors maliciously gossip about me, I'm absorbed in pondering your wise counsel.</verse>
<verse>Yes, your sayings on life are what give me delight; I listen to them as to good neighbors! [JC]</verse>
<verse>I'm feeling terrible--I couldn't feel worse! Get me on my feet again. You promised, remember?</verse>
<verse>When I told my story, you responded; train me well in your deep wisdom.</verse>
<verse>Help me understand these things inside and out so I can ponder your miracle-wonders.</verse>
<verse>My sad life's dilapidated, a falling-down barn; build me up again by your Word.</verse>
<verse>Barricade the road that goes Nowhere; grace me with your clear revelation.</verse>
<verse>I choose the true road to Somewhere, I post your road signs at every curve and corner.</verse>
<verse>I grasp and cling to whatever you tell me; GOD, don't let me down!</verse>
<verse>I'll run the course you lay out for me if you'll just show me how. [JC]</verse>
<verse>GOD, teach me lessons for living so I can stay the course.</verse>
<verse>Give me insight so I can do what you tell me--my whole life one long, obedient response.</verse>
<verse>Guide me down the road of your commandments; I love traveling this freeway!</verse>
<verse>Give me a bent for your words of wisdom, and not for piling up loot.</verse>
<verse>Divert my eyes from toys and trinkets, invigorate me on the pilgrim way.</verse>
<verse>Affirm your promises to me--promises made to all who fear you.</verse>
<verse>Deflect the harsh words of my critics--but what you say is always so good.</verse>
<verse>See how hungry I am for your counsel; preserve my life through your righteous ways! [JC]</verse>
<verse>Let your love, GOD, shape my life with salvation, exactly as you promised;</verse>
<verse>Then I'll be able to stand up to mockery because I trusted your Word.</verse>
<verse>Don't ever deprive me of truth, not ever--your commandments are what I depend on.</verse>
<verse>Oh, I'll guard with my life what you've revealed to me, guard it now, guard it ever;</verse>
<verse>And I'll stride freely through wide open spaces as I look for your truth and your wisdom;</verse>
<verse>Then I'll tell the world what I find, speak out boldly in public, unembarrassed.</verse>
<verse>I cherish your commandments--oh, how I love them!-</verse>
<verse>relishing every fragment of your counsel. [JC]</verse>
<verse>Remember what you said to me, your servant--I hang on to these words for dear life!</verse>
<verse>These words hold me up in bad times; yes, your promises rejuvenate me.</verse>
<verse>The insolent ridicule me without mercy, but I don't budge from your revelation.</verse>
<verse>I watch for your ancient landmark words, and know I'm on the right track.</verse>
<verse>But when I see the wicked ignore your directions, I'm beside myself with anger.</verse>
<verse>I set your instructions to music and sing them as I walk this pilgrim way.</verse>
<verse>I meditate on your name all night, GOD, treasuring your revelation, O GOD.</verse>
<verse>Still, I walk through a rain of derision because I live by your Word and counsel. [JC]</verse>
<verse>Because you have satisfied me, GOD, I promise to do everything you say.</verse>
<verse>I beg you from the bottom of my heart: smile, be gracious to me just as you promised.</verse>
<verse>When I took a long, careful look at your ways, I got my feet back on the trail you blazed.</verse>
<verse>I was up at once, didn't drag my feet, was quick to follow your orders.</verse>
<verse>The wicked hemmed me in--there was no way out--but not for a minute did I forget your plan for me.</verse>
<verse>I get up in the middle of the night to thank you; your decisions are so right, so true--I can't wait till morning!</verse>
<verse>I'm a friend and companion of all who fear you, of those committed to living by your rules.</verse>
<verse>Your love, GOD, fills the earth! Train me to live by your counsel. [JC]</verse>
<verse>Be good to your servant, GOD; be as good as your Word.</verse>
<verse>Train me in good common sense; I'm thoroughly committed to living your way.</verse>
<verse>Before I learned to answer you, I wandered all over the place, but now I'm in step with your Word.</verse>
<verse>You are good, and the source of good; train me in your goodness.</verse>
<verse>The godless spread lies about me, but I focus my attention on what you are saying;</verse>
<verse>They're bland as a bucket of lard, while I dance to the tune of your revelation.</verse>
<verse>My troubles turned out all for the best--they forced me to learn from your textbook.</verse>
<verse>Truth from your mouth means more to me than striking it rich in a gold mine. [JC]</verse>
<verse>With your very own hands you formed me; now breathe your wisdom over me so I can understand you.</verse>
<verse>When they see me waiting, expecting your Word, those who fear you will take heart and be glad.</verse>
<verse>I can see now, GOD, that your decisions are right; your testing has taught me what's true and right.</verse>
<verse>Oh, love me--and right now!-hold me tight! just the way you promised.</verse>
<verse>Now comfort me so I can live, really live; your revelation is the tune I dance to.</verse>
<verse>Let the fast-talking tricksters be exposed as frauds; they tried to sell me a bill of goods, but I kept my mind fixed on your counsel.</verse>
<verse>Let those who fear you turn to me for evidence of your wise guidance.</verse>
<verse>And let me live whole and holy, soul and body, so I can always walk with my head held high. [JC]</verse>
<verse>I'm homesick--longing for your salvation; I'm waiting for your word of hope.</verse>
<verse>My eyes grow heavy watching for some sign of your promise; how long must I wait for your comfort?</verse>
<verse>There's smoke in my eyes--they burn and water, but I keep a steady gaze on the instructions you post.</verse>
<verse>How long do I have to put up with all this? How long till you haul my tormentors into court?</verse>
<verse>The arrogant godless try to throw me off track, ignorant as they are of God and his ways.</verse>
<verse>Everything you command is a sure thing, but they harass me with lies. Help!</verse>
<verse>They've pushed and pushed--they never let up--but I haven't relaxed my grip on your counsel.</verse>
<verse>In your great love revive me so I can alertly obey your every word. [JC]</verse>
<verse>What you say goes, GOD, and stays, as permanent as the heavens.</verse>
<verse>Your truth never goes out of fashion; it's as up--to-date as the earth when the sun comes up.</verse>
<verse>Your Word and truth are dependable as ever; that's what you ordered--you set the earth going.</verse>
<verse>If your revelation hadn't delighted me so, I would have given up when the hard times came.</verse>
<verse>But I'll never forget the advice you gave me; you saved my life with those wise words.</verse>
<verse>Save me! I'm all yours. I look high and low for your words of wisdom.</verse>
<verse>The wicked lie in ambush to destroy me, but I'm only concerned with your plans for me.</verse>
<verse>I see the limits to everything human, but the horizons can't contain your commands! [JC]</verse>
<verse>Oh, how I love all you've revealed; I reverently ponder it all the day long.</verse>
<verse>Your commands give me an edge on my enemies; they never become obsolete.</verse>
<verse>I've even become smarter than my teachers since I've pondered and absorbed your counsel.</verse>
<verse>I've become wiser than the wise old sages simply by doing what you tell me.</verse>
<verse>I watch my step, avoiding the ditches and ruts of evil so I can spend all my time keeping your Word.</verse>
<verse>I never make detours from the route you laid out; you gave me such good directions.</verse>
<verse>Your words are so choice, so tasty; I prefer them to the best home cooking.</verse>
<verse>With your instruction, I understand life; that's why I hate false propaganda. [JC]</verse>
<verse>By your words I can see where I'm going; they throw a beam of light on my dark path.</verse>
<verse>I've committed myself and I'll never turn back from living by your righteous order.</verse>
<verse>Everything's falling apart on me, GOD; put me together again with your Word.</verse>
<verse>Festoon me with your finest sayings, GOD; teach me your holy rules.</verse>
<verse>My life is as close as my own hands, but I don't forget what you have revealed.</verse>
<verse>The wicked do their best to throw me off track, but I don't swerve an inch from your course.</verse>
<verse>I inherited your book on living; it's mine forever--what a gift! And how happy it makes me!</verse>
<verse>I concentrate on doing exactly what you say--I always have and always will. [JC]</verse>
<verse>I hate the two-faced, but I love your clear-cut revelation.</verse>
<verse>You're my place of quiet retreat; I wait for your Word to renew me.</verse>
<verse>Get out of my life, evildoers, so I can keep my God's commands.</verse>
<verse>Take my side as you promised; I'll live then for sure. Don't disappoint all my grand hopes.</verse>
<verse>Stick with me and I'll be all right; I'll give total allegiance to your definitions of life.</verse>
<verse>Expose all who drift away from your sayings; their casual idolatry is lethal.</verse>
<verse>You reject earth's wicked as so much rubbish; therefore I lovingly embrace everything you say.</verse>
<verse>I shiver in awe before you; your decisions leave me speechless with reverence. [JC]</verse>
<verse>I stood up for justice and the right; don't leave me to the mercy of my oppressors.</verse>
<verse>Take the side of your servant, good God; don't let the godless take advantage of me.</verse>
<verse>I can't keep my eyes open any longer, waiting for you to keep your promise to set everything right.</verse>
<verse>Let your love dictate how you deal with me; teach me from your textbook on life.</verse>
<verse>I'm your servant--help me understand what that means, the inner meaning of your instructions.</verse>
<verse>It's time to act, GOD; they've made a shambles of your revelation!</verse>
<verse>Yea-Saying God, I love what you command, I love it better than gold and gemstones;</verse>
<verse>Yea-Saying God, I honor everything you tell me, I despise every deceitful detour. [JC]</verse>
<verse>Every word you give me is a miracle word--how could I help but obey?</verse>
<verse>Break open your words, let the light shine out, let ordinary people see the meaning.</verse>
<verse>Mouth open and panting, I wanted your commands more than anything.</verse>
<verse>Turn my way, look kindly on me, as you always do to those who personally love you.</verse>
<verse>Steady my steps with your Word of promise so nothing malign gets the better of me.</verse>
<verse>Rescue me from the grip of bad men and women so I can live life your way.</verse>
<verse>Smile on me, your servant; teach me the right way to live.</verse>
<verse>I cry rivers of tears because nobody's living by your book! [JC]</verse>
<verse>You are right and you do right, GOD; your decisions are right on target.</verse>
<verse>You rightly instruct us in how to live ever faithful to you.</verse>
<verse>My rivals nearly did me in, they persistently ignored your commandments.</verse>
<verse>Your promise has been tested through and through, and I, your servant, love it dearly.</verse>
<verse>I'm too young to be important, but I don't forget what you tell me.</verse>
<verse>Your righteousness is eternally right, your revelation is the only truth.</verse>
<verse>Even though troubles came down on me hard, your commands always gave me delight.</verse>
<verse>The way you tell me to live is always right; help me understand it so I can live to the fullest. [JC]</verse>
<verse>I call out at the top of my lungs, "GOD! Answer! I'll do whatever you say."</verse>
<verse>I called to you, "Save me so I can carry out all your instructions."</verse>
<verse>I was up before sunrise, crying for help, hoping for a word from you.</verse>
<verse>I stayed awake all night, prayerfully pondering your promise.</verse>
<verse>In your love, listen to me; in your justice, GOD, keep me alive.</verse>
<verse>As those out to get me come closer and closer, they go farther and farther from the truth you reveal;</verse>
<verse>But you're the closest of all to me, GOD, and all your judgments true.</verse>
<verse>I've known all along from the evidence of your words that you meant them to last forever. [JC]</verse>
<verse>Take a good look at my trouble, and help me--I haven't forgotten your revelation.</verse>
<verse>Take my side and get me out of this; give me back my life, just as you promised.</verse>
<verse>"Salvation" is only gibberish to the wicked because they've never looked it up in your dictionary.</verse>
<verse>Your mercies, GOD, run into the billions; following your guidelines, revive me.</verse>
<verse>My antagonists are too many to count, but I don't swerve from the directions you gave.</verse>
<verse>I took one look at the quitters and was filled with loathing; they walked away from your promises so casually!</verse>
<verse>Take note of how I love what you tell me; out of your life of love, prolong my life.</verse>
<verse>Your words all add up to the sum total: Truth. Your righteous decisions are eternal. [JC]</verse>
<verse>I've been slandered unmercifully by the politicians, but my awe at your words keeps me stable.</verse>
<verse>I'm ecstatic over what you say, like one who strikes it rich.</verse>
<verse>I hate lies--can't stand them!- but I love what you have revealed.</verse>
<verse>Seven times each day I stop and shout praises for the way you keep everything running right.</verse>
<verse>For those who love what you reveal, everything fits--no stumbling around in the dark for them.</verse>
<verse>I wait expectantly for your salvation; GOD, I do what you tell me.</verse>
<verse>My soul guards and keeps all your instructions--oh, how much I love them!</verse>
<verse>I follow your directions, abide by your counsel; my life's an open book before you. [JC]</verse>
<verse>Let my cry come right into your presence, GOD; provide me with the insight that comes only from your Word.</verse>
<verse>Give my request your personal attention, rescue me on the terms of your promise.</verse>
<verse>Let praise cascade off my lips; after all, you've taught me the truth about life!</verse>
<verse>And let your promises ring from my tongue; every order you've given is right.</verse>
<verse>Put your hand out and steady me since I've chosen to live by your counsel.</verse>
<verse>I'm homesick, GOD, for your salvation; I love it when you show yourself!</verse>
<verse>Invigorate my soul so I can praise you well, use your decrees to put iron in my soul.</verse>
<verse>And should I wander off like a lost sheep--seek me! I'll recognize the sound of your voice.</verse>
</chapter>