<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Psalms" book_id="19" n="136">
<verse>Thank GOD! He deserves your thanks. His love never quits.</verse>
<verse>Thank the God of all gods, His love never quits.</verse>
<verse>Thank the Lord of all lords. His love never quits.</verse>
<verse>Thank the miracle-working God, His love never quits.</verse>
<verse>The God whose skill formed the cosmos, His love never quits.</verse>
<verse>The God who laid out earth on ocean foundations, His love never quits.</verse>
<verse>The God who filled the skies with light, His love never quits.</verse>
<verse>The sun to watch over the day, His love never quits.</verse>
<verse>Moon and stars as guardians of the night, His love never quits.</verse>
<verse>The God who struck down the Egyptian firstborn, His love never quits.</verse>
<verse>And rescued Israel from Egypt's oppression, His love never quits.</verse>
<verse>Took Israel in hand with his powerful hand, His love never quits.</verse>
<verse>Split the Red Sea right in half, His love never quits.</verse>
<verse>Led Israel right through the middle, His love never quits.</verse>
<verse>Dumped Pharaoh and his army in the sea, His love never quits.</verse>
<verse>The God who marched his people through the desert, His love never quits.</verse>
<verse>Smashed huge kingdoms right and left, His love never quits.</verse>
<verse>Struck down the famous kings, His love never quits.</verse>
<verse>Struck Sihon the Amorite king, His love never quits.</verse>
<verse>Struck Og the Bashanite king, His love never quits.</verse>
<verse>Then distributed their land as booty, His love never quits.</verse>
<verse>Handed the land over to Israel. His love never quits.</verse>
<verse>God remembered us when we were down, His love never quits.</verse>
<verse>Rescued us from the trampling boot, His love never quits.</verse>
<verse>Takes care of everyone in time of need. His love never quits.</verse>
<verse>Thank God, who did it all! His love never quits!</verse>
</chapter>