<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Psalms" book-id="19" n="139">
<verse>GOD, investigate my life; get all the facts firsthand.</verse>
<verse>I'm an open book to you; even from a distance, you know what I'm thinking.</verse>
<verse>You know when I leave and when I get back; I'm never out of your sight.</verse>
<verse>You know everything I'm going to say before I start the first sentence.</verse>
<verse>I look behind me and you're there, then up ahead and you're there, too--your reassuring presence, coming and going.</verse>
<verse>This is too much, too wonderful--I can't take it all in!</verse>
<verse>Is there anyplace I can go to avoid your Spirit? to be out of your sight?</verse>
<verse>If I climb to the sky, you're there! If I go underground, you're there!</verse>
<verse>If I flew on morning's wings to the far western horizon,</verse>
<verse>You'd find me in a minute--you're already there waiting!</verse>
<verse>Then I said to myself, "Oh, he even sees me in the dark! At night I'm immersed in the light!"</verse>
<verse>It's a fact: darkness isn't dark to you; night and day, darkness and light, they're all the same to you.</verse>
<verse>Oh yes, you shaped me first inside, then out; you formed me in my mother's womb.</verse>
<verse>I thank you, High God--you're breathtaking! Body and soul, I am marvelously made! I worship in adoration--what a creation!</verse>
<verse>You know me inside and out, you know every bone in my body; You know exactly how I was made, bit by bit, how I was sculpted from nothing into something.</verse>
<verse>Like an open book, you watched me grow from conception to birth; all the stages of my life were spread out before you, The days of my life all prepared before I'd even lived one day.</verse>
<verse>Your thoughts--how rare, how beautiful! God, I'll never comprehend them!</verse>
<verse>I couldn't even begin to count them--any more than I could count the sand of the sea. Oh, let me rise in the morning and live always with you!</verse>
<verse>And please, God, do away with wickedness for good! And you murderers--out of here!-</verse>
<verse>all the men and women who belittle you, God, infatuated with cheap god-imitations.</verse>
<verse>See how I hate those who hate you, GOD, see how I loathe all this godless arrogance;</verse>
<verse>I hate it with pure, unadulterated hatred. Your enemies are my enemies!</verse>
<verse>Investigate my life, O God, find out everything about me; Cross-examine and test me, get a clear picture of what I'm about;</verse>
<verse>See for yourself whether I've done anything wrong--then guide me on the road to eternal life.</verse>
</chapter>