<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Psalms" book_id="19" n="145">
<verse>I lift you high in praise, my God, O my King! and I'll bless your name into eternity.</verse>
<verse>I'll bless you every day, and keep it up from now to eternity.</verse>
<verse>GOD is magnificent; he can never be praised enough. There are no boundaries to his greatness.</verse>
<verse>Generation after generation stands in awe of your work; each one tells stories of your mighty acts.</verse>
<verse>Your beauty and splendor have everyone talking; I compose songs on your wonders.</verse>
<verse>Your marvelous doings are headline news; I could write a book full of the details of your greatness.</verse>
<verse>The fame of your goodness spreads across the country; your righteousness is on everyone's lips.</verse>
<verse>GOD is all mercy and grace--not quick to anger, is rich in love.</verse>
<verse>GOD is good to one and all; everything he does is suffused with grace.</verse>
<verse>Creation and creatures applaud you, GOD;</verse>
<verse>your holy people bless you. They talk about the glories of your rule, they exclaim over your splendor,</verse>
<verse>Letting the world know of your power for good, the lavish splendor of your kingdom.</verse>
<verse>Your kingdom is a kingdom eternal; you never get voted out of office. GOD always does what he says, and is gracious in everything he does.</verse>
<verse>GOD gives a hand to those down on their luck, gives a fresh start to those ready to quit.</verse>
<verse>All eyes are on you, expectant; you give them their meals on time.</verse>
<verse>Generous to a fault, you lavish your favor on all creatures.</verse>
<verse>Everything GOD does is right--the trademark on all his works is love.</verse>
<verse>GOD's there, listening for all who pray, for all who pray and mean it.</verse>
<verse>He does what's best for those who fear him--hears them call out, and saves them.</verse>
<verse>GOD sticks by all who love him, but it's all over for those who don't.</verse>
<verse>My mouth is filled with GOD's praise. Let everything living bless him, bless his holy name from now to eternity! le</verse>
</chapter>