<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Psalms" book-id="19" n="22">
<verse>God, God... my God! Why did you dump me miles from nowhere?</verse>
<verse>Doubled up with pain, I call to God all the day long. No answer. Nothing. I keep at it all night, tossing and turning.</verse>
<verse>And you! Are you indifferent, above it all, leaning back on the cushions of Israel's praise?</verse>
<verse>We know you were there for our parents:</verse>
<verse>they cried for your help and you gave it; they trusted and lived a good life.</verse>
<verse>And here I am, a nothing--an earthworm, something to step on, to squash.</verse>
<verse>Everyone pokes fun at me; they make faces at me, they shake their heads:</verse>
<verse>"Let's see how GOD handles this one; since God likes him so much, let him help him!"</verse>
<verse>And to think you were midwife at my birth, setting me at my mother's breasts!</verse>
<verse>When I left the womb you cradled me; since the moment of birth you've been my God.</verse>
<verse>Then you moved far away and trouble moved in next-door. I need a neighbor.</verse>
<verse>Herds of bulls come at me, the raging bulls stampede,</verse>
<verse>Horns lowered, nostrils flaring, like a herd of buffalo on the move.</verse>
<verse>I'm a bucket kicked over and spilled, every joint in my body has been pulled apart. My heart is a blob of melted wax in my gut.</verse>
<verse>I'm dry as a bone, my tongue black and swollen. They have laid me out for burial in the dirt.</verse>
<verse>Now packs of wild dogs come at me; thugs gang up on me. They pin me down hand and foot,</verse>
<verse>and lock me in a cage--a bag Of bones in a cage, stared at by every passerby.</verse>
<verse>They take my wallet and the shirt off my back, and then throw dice for my clothes.</verse>
<verse>You, GOD-don't put off my rescue! Hurry and help me!</verse>
<verse>Don't let them cut my throat; don't let those mongrels devour me.</verse>
<verse>If you don't show up soon, I'm done for--gored by the bulls, meat for the lions.</verse>
<verse>Here's the story I'll tell my friends when they come to worship, and punctuate it with Hallelujahs:</verse>
<verse>Shout Hallelujah, you God--worshipers; give glory, you sons of Jacob; adore him, you daughters of Israel.</verse>
<verse>He has never let you down, never looked the other way when you were being kicked around. He has never wandered off to do his own thing; he has been right there, listening.</verse>
<verse>Here in this great gathering for worship I have discovered this praise--life. And I'll do what I promised right here in front of the God--worshipers.</verse>
<verse>Down-and-outers sit at GOD's table and eat their fill. Everyone on the hunt for God is here, praising him. "Live it up, from head to toe. Don't ever quit!"</verse>
<verse>From the four corners of the earth people are coming to their senses, are running back to GOD. Long-lost families are falling on their faces before him.</verse>
<verse>GOD has taken charge; from now on he has the last word.</verse>
<verse>All the power-mongers are before him -worshiping! All the poor and powerless, too -worshiping! Along with those who never got it together -worshiping!</verse>
<verse>Our children and their children will get in on this As the word is passed along from parent to child.</verse>
<verse>Babies not yet conceived will hear the good news--that God does what he says.</verse>
</chapter>