<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Psalms" book_id="19" n="25">
<verse>My head is high, GOD, held high;</verse>
<verse>I'm looking to you, GOD; No hangdog skulking for me.</verse>
<verse>I've thrown in my lot with you; You won't embarrass me, will you? Or let my enemies get the best of me? Don't embarrass any of us Who went out on a limb for you. It's the traitors who should be humiliated.</verse>
<verse>Show me how you work, GOD; School me in your ways.</verse>
<verse>Take me by the hand; Lead me down the path of truth. You are my Savior, aren't you?</verse>
<verse>Mark the milestones of your mercy and love, GOD; Rebuild the ancient landmarks!</verse>
<verse>Forget that I sowed wild oats; Mark me with your sign of love. Plan only the best for me, GOD!</verse>
<verse>GOD is fair and just; He corrects the misdirected, Sends them in the right direction.</verse>
<verse>He gives the rejects his hand, And leads them step-by-step.</verse>
<verse>From now on every road you travel Will take you to GOD. Follow the Covenant signs; Read the charted directions.</verse>
<verse>Keep up your reputation, GOD; Forgive my bad life; It's been a very bad life.</verse>
<verse>My question: What are God--worshipers like? Your answer: Arrows aimed at God's bull's-eye.</verse>
<verse>They settle down in a promising place; Their kids inherit a prosperous farm.</verse>
<verse>God--friendship is for God--worshipers; They are the ones he confides in.</verse>
<verse>If I keep my eyes on GOD, I won't trip over my own feet.</verse>
<verse>Look at me and help me! I'm all alone and in big trouble.</verse>
<verse>My heart and kidneys are fighting each other; Call a truce to this civil war.</verse>
<verse>Take a hard look at my life of hard labor, Then lift this ton of sin.</verse>
<verse>Do you see how many people Have it in for me? How viciously they hate me?</verse>
<verse>Keep watch over me and keep me out of trouble; Don't let me down when I run to you.</verse>
<verse>Use all your skill to put me together; I wait to see your finished product.</verse>
<verse>GOD, give your people a break From this run of bad luck.</verse>
</chapter>