<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Psalms" book_id="19" n="31">
<verse>I run to you, GOD; I run for dear life. Don't let me down! Take me seriously this time!</verse>
<verse>Get down on my level and listen, and please--no procrastination! Your granite cave a hiding place, your high cliff aerie a place of safety.</verse>
<verse>You're my cave to hide in, my cliff to climb. Be my safe leader, be my true mountain guide.</verse>
<verse>Free me from hidden traps; I want to hide in you.</verse>
<verse>I've put my life in your hands. You won't drop me, you'll never let me down.</verse>
<verse>I hate all this silly religion, but you, GOD, I trust.</verse>
<verse>I'm leaping and singing in the circle of your love; you saw my pain, you disarmed my tormentors,</verse>
<verse>You didn't leave me in their clutches but gave me room to breathe.</verse>
<verse>Be kind to me, GOD- I'm in deep, deep trouble again. I've cried my eyes out; I feel hollow inside.</verse>
<verse>My life leaks away, groan by groan; my years fade out in sighs. My troubles have worn me out, turned my bones to powder.</verse>
<verse>To my enemies I'm a monster; I'm ridiculed by the neighbors. My friends are horrified; they cross the street to avoid me.</verse>
<verse>They want to blot me from memory, forget me like a corpse in a grave, discard me like a broken dish in the trash.</verse>
<verse>The street-talk gossip has me "criminally insane"! Behind locked doors they plot how to ruin me for good.</verse>
<verse>Desperate, I throw myself on you: you are my God!</verse>
<verse>Hour by hour I place my days in your hand, safe from the hands out to get me.</verse>
<verse>Warm me, your servant, with a smile; save me because you love me.</verse>
<verse>Don't embarrass me by not showing up; I've given you plenty of notice. Embarrass the wicked, stand them up, leave them stupidly shaking their heads as they drift down to hell.</verse>
<verse>Gag those loudmouthed liars who heckle me, your follower, with jeers and catcalls.</verse>
<verse>What a stack of blessing you have piled up for those who worship you, Ready and waiting for all who run to you to escape an unkind world.</verse>
<verse>You hide them safely away from the opposition. As you slam the door on those oily, mocking faces, you silence the poisonous gossip.</verse>
<verse>Blessed GOD! His love is the wonder of the world. Trapped by a siege,</verse>
<verse>I panicked. "Out of sight, out of mind," I said. But you heard me say it, you heard and listened.</verse>
<verse>Love GOD, all you saints; GOD takes care of all who stay close to him, But he pays back in full those arrogant enough to go it alone.</verse>
<verse>Be brave. Be strong. Don't give up. Expect GOD to get here soon.</verse>
</chapter>