<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Psalms" book-id="19" n="33">
<verse>Good people, cheer GOD! Right-living people sound best when praising.</verse>
<verse>Use guitars to reinforce your Hallelujahs! Play his praise on a grand piano!</verse>
<verse>Invent your own new song to him; give him a trumpet fanfare.</verse>
<verse>For GOD's Word is solid to the core; everything he makes is sound inside and out.</verse>
<verse>He loves it when everything fits, when his world is in plumb-line true. Earth is drenched in GOD's affectionate satisfaction.</verse>
<verse>The skies were made by GOD's command; he breathed the word and the stars popped out.</verse>
<verse>He scooped Sea into his jug, put Ocean in his keg.</verse>
<verse>Earth-creatures, bow before GOD; world-dwellers--down on your knees!</verse>
<verse>Here's why: he spoke and there it was, in place the moment he said so.</verse>
<verse>GOD takes the wind out of Babel pretense, he shoots down the world's power-schemes.</verse>
<verse>GOD's plan for the world stands up, all his designs are made to last.</verse>
<verse>Blessed is the country with GOD for God; blessed are the people he's put in his will.</verse>
<verse>From high in the skies GOD looks around, he sees all Adam's brood.</verse>
<verse>From where he sits he overlooks all us earth-dwellers.</verse>
<verse>He has shaped each person in turn; now he watches everything we do.</verse>
<verse>No king succeeds with a big army alone, no warrior wins by brute strength.</verse>
<verse>Horsepower is not the answer; no one gets by on muscle alone.</verse>
<verse>Watch this: God's eye is on those who respect him, the ones who are looking for his love.</verse>
<verse>He's ready to come to their rescue in bad times; in lean times he keeps body and soul together.</verse>
<verse>We're depending on GOD; he's everything we need.</verse>
<verse>What's more, our hearts brim with joy since we've taken for our own his holy name.</verse>
<verse>Love us, GOD, with all you've got--that's what we're depending on.</verse>
</chapter>