<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Psalms" book_id="19" n="34">
<verse>I bless GOD every chance I get; my lungs expand with his praise.</verse>
<verse>I live and breathe GOD; if things aren't going well, hear this and be happy:</verse>
<verse>Join me in spreading the news; together let's get the word out.</verse>
<verse>GOD met me more than halfway, he freed me from my anxious fears.</verse>
<verse>Look at him; give him your warmest smile. Never hide your feelings from him.</verse>
<verse>When I was desperate, I called out, and GOD got me out of a tight spot.</verse>
<verse>GOD's angel sets up a circle of protection around us while we pray.</verse>
<verse>Open your mouth and taste, open your eyes and see--how good GOD is. Blessed are you who run to him.</verse>
<verse>Worship GOD if you want the best; worship opens doors to all his goodness.</verse>
<verse>Young lions on the prowl get hungry, but GOD-seekers are full of God.</verse>
<verse>Come, children, listen closely; I'll give you a lesson in GOD worship.</verse>
<verse>Who out there has a lust for life? Can't wait each day to come upon beauty?</verse>
<verse>Guard your tongue from profanity, and no more lying through your teeth.</verse>
<verse>Turn your back on sin; do something good. Embrace peace--don't let it get away!</verse>
<verse>GOD keeps an eye on his friends, his ears pick up every moan and groan.</verse>
<verse>GOD won't put up with rebels; he'll cull them from the pack.</verse>
<verse>Is anyone crying for help? GOD is listening, ready to rescue you.</verse>
<verse>If your heart is broken, you'll find GOD right there; if you're kicked in the gut, he'll help you catch your breath.</verse>
<verse>Disciples so often get into trouble; still, GOD is there every time.</verse>
<verse>He's your bodyguard, shielding every bone; not even a finger gets broken.</verse>
<verse>The wicked commit slow suicide; they waste their lives hating the good.</verse>
<verse>GOD pays for each slave's freedom; no one who runs to him loses out.</verse>
</chapter>