<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Psalms" book-id="19" n="35">
<verse>Harass these hecklers, GOD, punch these bullies in the nose.</verse>
<verse>Grab a weapon, anything at hand; stand up for me!</verse>
<verse>Get ready to throw the spear, aim the javelin, at the people who are out to get me. Reassure me; let me hear you say, "I'll save you."</verse>
<verse>When those thugs try to knife me in the back, make them look foolish. Frustrate all those who are plotting my downfall.</verse>
<verse>Make them like cinders in a high wind, with GOD's angel working the bellows.</verse>
<verse>Make their road lightless and mud-slick, with GOD's angel on their tails.</verse>
<verse>Out of sheer cussedness they set a trap to catch me; for no good reason they dug a ditch to stop me.</verse>
<verse>Surprise them with your ambush--catch them in the very trap they set, the disaster they planned for me.</verse>
<verse>But let me run loose and free, celebrating GOD's great work,</verse>
<verse>Every bone in my body laughing, singing, "GOD, there's no one like you. You put the down--and-out on their feet and protect the unprotected from bullies!"</verse>
<verse>Hostile accusers appear out of nowhere, they stand up and badger me.</verse>
<verse>They pay me back misery for mercy, leaving my soul empty.</verse>
<verse>When they were sick, I dressed in black; instead of eating, I prayed.</verse>
<verse>My prayers were like lead in my gut, like I'd lost my best friend, my brother. I paced, distraught as a motherless child, hunched and heavyhearted.</verse>
<verse>But when I was down they threw a party! All the nameless riffraff of the town came chanting insults about me.</verse>
<verse>Like barbarians desecrating a shrine, they destroyed my reputation.</verse>
<verse>GOD, how long are you going to stand there doing nothing? Save me from their brutalities; everything I've got is being thrown to the lions.</verse>
<verse>I will give you full credit when everyone gathers for worship; When the people turn out in force I will say my Hallelujahs.</verse>
<verse>Don't let these liars, my enemies, have a party at my expense, Those who hate me for no reason, winking and rolling their eyes.</verse>
<verse>No good is going to come from that crowd; They spend all their time cooking up gossip against those who mind their own business.</verse>
<verse>They open their mouths in ugly grins, Mocking, "Ha-ha, ha-ha, thought you'd get away with it? We've caught you hands down!"</verse>
<verse>Don't you see what they're doing, GOD? You're not going to let them Get by with it, are you? Not going to walk off without doing something, are you?</verse>
<verse>Please get up--wake up! Tend to my case. My God, my Lord--my life is on the line.</verse>
<verse>Do what you think is right, GOD, my God, but don't make me pay for their good time.</verse>
<verse>Don't let them say to themselves, "Ha-ha, we got what we wanted." Don't let them say, "We've chewed him up and spit him out."</verse>
<verse>Let those who are being hilarious at my expense Be made to look ridiculous. Make them wear donkey's ears; Pin them with the donkey's tail, who made themselves so high and mighty!</verse>
<verse>But those who want the best for me, Let them have the last word--a glad shout!- and say, over and over and over, "GOD is great--everything works together for good for his servant."</verse>
<verse>I'll tell the world how great and good you are, I'll shout Hallelujah all day, every day.</verse>
</chapter>