<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Psalms" book-id="19" n="37">
<verse>Don't bother your head with braggarts or wish you could succeed like the wicked.</verse>
<verse>In no time they'll shrivel like grass clippings and wilt like cut flowers in the sun.</verse>
<verse>Get insurance with GOD and do a good deed, settle down and stick to your last.</verse>
<verse>Keep company with GOD, get in on the best.</verse>
<verse>Open up before GOD, keep nothing back; he'll do whatever needs to be done:</verse>
<verse>He'll validate your life in the clear light of day and stamp you with approval at high noon.</verse>
<verse>Quiet down before GOD, be prayerful before him. Don't bother with those who climb the ladder, who elbow their way to the top.</verse>
<verse>Bridle your anger, trash your wrath, cool your pipes--it only makes things worse.</verse>
<verse>Before long the crooks will be bankrupt; GOD-investors will soon own the store.</verse>
<verse>Before you know it, the wicked will have had it; you'll stare at his once famous place and--nothing!</verse>
<verse>Down-to-earth people will move in and take over, relishing a huge bonanza.</verse>
<verse>Bad guys have it in for the good guys, obsessed with doing them in.</verse>
<verse>But GOD isn't losing any sleep; to him they're a joke with no punch line.</verse>
<verse>Bullies brandish their swords, pull back on their bows with a flourish. They're out to beat up on the harmless, or mug that nice man out walking his dog.</verse>
<verse>A banana peel lands them flat on their faces--slapstick figures in a moral circus.</verse>
<verse>Less is more and more is less. One righteous will outclass fifty wicked,</verse>
<verse>For the wicked are moral weaklings but the righteous are GOD-strong.</verse>
<verse>GOD keeps track of the decent folk; what they do won't soon be forgotten.</verse>
<verse>In hard times, they'll hold their heads high; when the shelves are bare, they'll be full.</verse>
<verse>God--despisers have had it; GOD's enemies are finished--Stripped bare like vineyards at harvest time, vanished like smoke in thin air.</verse>
<verse>Wicked borrows and never returns; Righteous gives and gives.</verse>
<verse>Generous gets it all in the end; Stingy is cut off at the pass.</verse>
<verse>Stalwart walks in step with GOD; his path blazed by GOD, he's happy.</verse>
<verse>If he stumbles, he's not down for long; GOD has a grip on his hand.</verse>
<verse>I once was young, now I'm a graybeard--not once have I seen an abandoned believer, or his kids out roaming the streets.</verse>
<verse>Every day he's out giving and lending, his children making him proud.</verse>
<verse>Turn your back on evil, work for the good and don't quit.</verse>
<verse>GOD loves this kind of thing, never turns away from his friends. Live this way and you've got it made, but bad eggs will be tossed out.</verse>
<verse>The good get planted on good land and put down healthy roots.</verse>
<verse>Righteous chews on wisdom like a dog on a bone, rolls virtue around on his tongue.</verse>
<verse>His heart pumps God's Word like blood through his veins; his feet are as sure as a cat's.</verse>
<verse>Wicked sets a watch for Righteous, he's out for the kill.</verse>
<verse>GOD, alert, is also on watch--Wicked won't hurt a hair of his head.</verse>
<verse>Wait passionately for GOD, don't leave the path. He'll give you your place in the sun while you watch the wicked lose it.</verse>
<verse>I saw Wicked bloated like a toad, croaking pretentious nonsense.</verse>
<verse>The next time I looked there was nothing--a punctured bladder, vapid and limp.</verse>
<verse>Keep your eye on the healthy soul, scrutinize the straight life; There's a future in strenuous wholeness.</verse>
<verse>But the willful will soon be discarded; insolent souls are on a dead-end street.</verse>
<verse>The spacious, free life is from GOD, it's also protected and safe.</verse>
<verse>GOD-strengthened, we're delivered from evil--when we run to him, he saves us.</verse>
</chapter>