<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Psalms" book_id="19" n="38">
<verse>Take a deep breath, GOD; calm down--don't be so hasty with your punishing rod.</verse>
<verse>Your sharp-pointed arrows of rebuke draw blood; my backside smarts from your caning.</verse>
<verse>I've lost twenty pounds in two months because of your accusation. My bones are brittle as dry sticks because of my sin.</verse>
<verse>I'm swamped by my bad behavior, collapsed under gunnysacks of guilt.</verse>
<verse>The cuts in my flesh stink and grow maggots because I've lived so badly.</verse>
<verse>And now I'm flat on my face feeling sorry for myself morning to night.</verse>
<verse>All my insides are on fire, my body is a wreck.</verse>
<verse>I'm on my last legs; I've had it--my life is a vomit of groans.</verse>
<verse>Lord, my longings are sitting in plain sight, my groans an old story to you.</verse>
<verse>My heart's about to break; I'm a burned-out case. Cataracts blind me to God and good;</verse>
<verse>old friends avoid me like the plague. My cousins never visit, my neighbors stab me in the back.</verse>
<verse>My competitors blacken my name, devoutly they pray for my ruin.</verse>
<verse>But I'm deaf and mute to it all, ears shut, mouth shut.</verse>
<verse>I don't hear a word they say, don't speak a word in response.</verse>
<verse>What I do, GOD, is wait for you, wait for my Lord, my God--you will answer!</verse>
<verse>I wait and pray so they won't laugh me off, won't smugly strut off when I stumble.</verse>
<verse>I'm on the edge of losing it--the pain in my gut keeps burning.</verse>
<verse>I'm ready to tell my story of failure, I'm no longer smug in my sin.</verse>
<verse>My enemies are alive and in action, a lynch mob after my neck.</verse>
<verse>I give out good and get back evil from God--haters who can't stand a God--lover.</verse>
<verse>Don't dump me, GOD; my God, don't stand me up.</verse>
<verse>Hurry and help me; I want some wide-open space in my life!</verse>
</chapter>