<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Psalms" book_id="19" n="40">
<verse>I waited and waited and waited for GOD. At last he looked; finally he listened.</verse>
<verse>He lifted me out of the ditch, pulled me from deep mud. He stood me up on a solid rock to make sure I wouldn't slip.</verse>
<verse>He taught me how to sing the latest God--song, a praise--song to our God. More and more people are seeing this: they enter the mystery, abandoning themselves to GOD.</verse>
<verse>Blessed are you who give yourselves over to GOD, turn your backs on the world's "sure thing," ignore what the world worships;</verse>
<verse>The world's a huge stockpile of GOD-wonders and God--thoughts. Nothing and no one comes close to you! I start talking about you, telling what I know, and quickly run out of words. Neither numbers nor words account for you.</verse>
<verse>Doing something for you, bringing something to you--that's not what you're after. Being religious, acting pious--that's not what you're asking for. You've opened my ears so I can listen.</verse>
<verse>So I answered, "I'm coming. I read in your letter what you wrote about me,</verse>
<verse>And I'm coming to the party you're throwing for me." That's when God's Word entered my life, became part of my very being.</verse>
<verse>I've preached you to the whole congregation, I've kept back nothing, GOD-you know that.</verse>
<verse>I didn't keep the news of your ways a secret, didn't keep it to myself. I told it all, how dependable you are, how thorough. I didn't hold back pieces of love and truth For myself alone. I told it all, let the congregation know the whole story.</verse>
<verse>Now GOD, don't hold out on me, don't hold back your passion. Your love and truth are all that keeps me together.</verse>
<verse>When troubles ganged up on me, a mob of sins past counting, I was so swamped by guilt I couldn't see my way clear. More guilt in my heart than hair on my head, so heavy the guilt that my heart gave out.</verse>
<verse>Soften up, GOD, and intervene; hurry and get me some help,</verse>
<verse>So those who are trying to kidnap my soul will be embarrassed and lose face, So anyone who gets a kick out of making me miserable will be heckled and disgraced,</verse>
<verse>So those who pray for my ruin will be booed and jeered without mercy.</verse>
<verse>But all who are hunting for you--oh, let them sing and be happy. Let those who know what you're all about tell the world you're great and not quitting.</verse>
<verse>And me? I'm a mess. I'm nothing and have nothing: make something of me. You can do it; you've got what it takes--but God, don't put it off.</verse>
</chapter>