<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Psalms" book_id="19" n="44">
<verse>We've been hearing about this, God, all our lives. Our fathers told us the stories their fathers told them,</verse>
<verse>How single-handedly you weeded out the godless from the fields and planted us, How you sent those people packing but gave us a fresh start.</verse>
<verse>We didn't fight for this land; we didn't work for it--it was a gift! You gave it, smiling as you gave it, delighting as you gave it.</verse>
<verse>You're my King, O God--command victories for Jacob!</verse>
<verse>With your help we'll wipe out our enemies, in your name we'll stomp them to dust.</verse>
<verse>I don't trust in weapons; my sword won't save me--</verse>
<verse>But it's you, you who saved us from the enemy; you made those who hate us lose face.</verse>
<verse>All day we parade God's praise--we thank you by name over and over.</verse>
<verse>But now you've walked off and left us, you've disgraced us and won't fight for us.</verse>
<verse>You made us turn tail and run; those who hate us have cleaned us out.</verse>
<verse>You delivered us as sheep to the butcher, you scattered us to the four winds.</verse>
<verse>You sold your people at a discount--you made nothing on the sale.</verse>
<verse>You made people on the street, urchins, poke fun and call us names.</verse>
<verse>You made us a joke among the godless, a cheap joke among the rabble.</verse>
<verse>Every day I'm up against it, my nose rubbed in my shame--</verse>
<verse>Gossip and ridicule fill the air, people out to get me crowd the street.</verse>
<verse>All this came down on us, and we've done nothing to deserve it. We never betrayed your Covenant:</verse>
<verse>our hearts were never false, our feet never left your path.</verse>
<verse>Do we deserve torture in a den of jackals? or lockup in a black hole?</verse>
<verse>If we had forgotten to pray to our God or made fools of ourselves with store-bought gods,</verse>
<verse>Wouldn't God have figured this out? We can't hide things from him.</verse>
<verse>No, you decided to make us martyrs, lambs assigned for sacrifice each day.</verse>
<verse>Get up, GOD! Are you going to sleep all day? Wake up! Don't you care what happens to us?</verse>
<verse>Why do you bury your face in the pillow? Why pretend things are just fine with us?</verse>
<verse>And here we are--flat on our faces in the dirt, held down with a boot on our necks.</verse>
<verse>Get up and come to our rescue. If you love us so much, Help us! A wedding song of the sons of Korah</verse>
</chapter>