<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Psalms" book_id="19" n="49">
<verse>Listen, everyone, listen--earth-dwellers, don't miss this.</verse>
<verse>All you haves and have-nots, All together now: listen.</verse>
<verse>I set plainspoken wisdom before you, my heart-seasoned understandings of life.</verse>
<verse>I fine-tuned my ear to the sayings of the wise, I solve life's riddle with the help of a harp.</verse>
<verse>So why should I fear in bad times, hemmed in by enemy malice,</verse>
<verse>Shoved around by bullies, demeaned by the arrogant rich?</verse>
<verse>Really! There's no such thing as self-rescue, pulling yourself up by your bootstraps.</verse>
<verse>The cost of rescue is beyond our means, and even then it doesn't guarantee</verse>
<verse>Life forever, or insurance against the Black Hole.</verse>
<verse>Anyone can see that the brightest and best die, wiped out right along with fools and dunces.</verse>
<verse>They leave all their prowess behind, move into their new home, The Coffin, The cemetery their permanent address. And to think they named counties after themselves!</verse>
<verse>We aren't immortal. We don't last long. Like our dogs, we age and weaken. And die.</verse>
<verse>This is what happens to those who live for the moment, who only look out for themselves:</verse>
<verse>Death herds them like sheep straight to hell; they disappear down the gullet of the grave; They waste away to nothing--nothing left but a marker in a cemetery.</verse>
<verse>But me? God snatches me from the clutch of death, he reaches down and grabs me.</verse>
<verse>So don't be impressed with those who get rich and pile up fame and fortune.</verse>
<verse>They can't take it with them; fame and fortune all get left behind.</verse>
<verse>Just when they think they've arrived and folks praise them because they've made good,</verse>
<verse>They enter the family burial plot where they'll never see sunshine again.</verse>
<verse>We aren't immortal. We don't last long. Like our dogs, we age and weaken. And die. An Asaph psalm</verse>
</chapter>