<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Psalms" book_id="19" n="50">
<verse>The God of gods--it's GOD!-speaks out, shouts, "Earth!" welcomes the sun in the east, farewells the disappearing sun in the west.</verse>
<verse>From the dazzle of Zion, God blazes into view.</verse>
<verse>Our God makes his entrance, he's not shy in his coming. Starbursts of fireworks precede him.</verse>
<verse>He summons heaven and earth as a jury, he's taking his people to court:</verse>
<verse>"Round up my saints who swore on the Bible their loyalty to me."</verse>
<verse>The whole cosmos attests to the fairness of this court, that here God is judge.</verse>
<verse>"Are you listening, dear people? I'm getting ready to speak; Israel, I'm about ready to bring you to trial. This is God, your God, speaking to you.</verse>
<verse>I don't find fault with your acts of worship, the frequent burnt sacrifices you offer.</verse>
<verse>But why should I want your blue-ribbon bull, or more and more goats from your herds?</verse>
<verse>Every creature in the forest is mine, the wild animals on all the mountains.</verse>
<verse>I know every mountain bird by name; the scampering field mice are my friends.</verse>
<verse>If I get hungry, do you think I'd tell you? All creation and its bounty are mine.</verse>
<verse>Do you think I feast on venison? or drink draughts of goats' blood?</verse>
<verse>Spread for me a banquet of praise, serve High God a feast of kept promises,</verse>
<verse>And call for help when you're in trouble--I'll help you, and you'll honor me."</verse>
<verse>Next, God calls up the wicked: "What are you up to, quoting my laws, talking like we are good friends?</verse>
<verse>You never answer the door when I call; you treat my words like garbage.</verse>
<verse>If you find a thief, you make him your buddy; adulterers are your friends of choice.</verse>
<verse>Your mouth drools filth; lying is a serious art form with you.</verse>
<verse>You stab your own brother in the back, rip off your little sister.</verse>
<verse>I kept a quiet patience while you did these things; you thought I went along with your game. I'm calling you on the carpet, now, laying your wickedness out in plain sight.</verse>
<verse>"Time's up for playing fast and loose with me. I'm ready to pass sentence, and there's no help in sight!</verse>
<verse>It's the praising life that honors me. As soon as you set your foot on the Way, I'll show you my salvation."</verse>
</chapter>