<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Psalms" book_id="19" n="55">
<verse>Open your ears, God, to my prayer; don't pretend you don't hear me knocking.</verse>
<verse>Come close and whisper your answer. I really need you. I shudder</verse>
<verse>at the mean voice, quail before the evil eye, As they pile on the guilt, stockpile angry slander.</verse>
<verse>My insides are turned inside out; specters of death have me down.</verse>
<verse>I shake with fear, I shudder from head to foot.</verse>
<verse>"Who will give me wings," I ask--"wings like a dove?" Get me out of here on dove wings;</verse>
<verse>I want some peace and quiet. I want a walk in the country,</verse>
<verse>I want a cabin in the woods. I'm desperate for a change from rage and stormy weather.</verse>
<verse>Come down hard, Lord--slit their tongues. I'm appalled how they've split the city Into rival gangs prowling the alleys</verse>
<verse>Day and night spoiling for a fight, trash piled in the streets,</verse>
<verse>Even shopkeepers gouging and cheating in broad daylight.</verse>
<verse>This isn't the neighborhood bully mocking me--I could take that. This isn't a foreign devil spitting invective--I could tune that out.</verse>
<verse>It's you! We grew up together! You! My best friend!</verse>
<verse>Those long hours of leisure as we walked arm in arm, God a third party to our conversation.</verse>
<verse>Haul my betrayers off alive to hell--let them experience the horror, let them feel every desolate detail of a damned life.</verse>
<verse>I call to God; GOD will help me.</verse>
<verse>At dusk, dawn, and noon I sigh deep sighs--he hears, he rescues.</verse>
<verse>My life is well and whole, secure in the middle of danger Even while thousands are lined up against me.</verse>
<verse>God hears it all, and from his judge's bench puts them in their place. But, set in their ways, they won't change; they pay him no mind.</verse>
<verse>And this, my best friend, betrayed his best friends; his life betrayed his word.</verse>
<verse>All my life I've been charmed by his speech, never dreaming he'd turn on me. His words, which were music to my ears, turned to daggers in my heart.</verse>
<verse>Pile your troubles on GOD's shoulders--he'll carry your load, he'll help you out. He'll never let good people topple into ruin.</verse>
<verse>But you, God, will throw the others into a muddy bog, Cut the lifespan of assassins and traitors in half. And I trust in you.</verse>
</chapter>