<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Psalms" book-id="19" n="66">
<verse>All together now--applause for God!</verse>
<verse>Sing songs to the tune of his glory, set glory to the rhythms of his praise.</verse>
<verse>Say of God, "We've never seen anything like him!" When your enemies see you in action, they slink off like scolded dogs.</verse>
<verse>The whole earth falls to its knees--it worships you, sings to you, can't stop enjoying your name and fame.</verse>
<verse>Take a good look at God's wonders--they'll take your breath away.</verse>
<verse>He converted sea to dry land; travelers crossed the river on foot. Now isn't that cause for a song?</verse>
<verse>Ever sovereign in his high tower, he keeps his eye on the godless nations. Rebels don't dare raise a finger against him.</verse>
<verse>Bless our God, O peoples! Give him a thunderous welcome!</verse>
<verse>Didn't he set us on the road to life? Didn't he keep us out of the ditch?</verse>
<verse>He trained us first, passed us like silver through refining fires,</verse>
<verse>Brought us into hardscrabble country, pushed us to our very limit,</verse>
<verse>Road-tested us inside and out, took us to hell and back; Finally he brought us to this well-watered place.</verse>
<verse>I'm bringing my prizes and presents to your house. I'm doing what I said I'd do,</verse>
<verse>What I solemnly swore I'd do that day when I was in so much trouble:</verse>
<verse>The choicest cuts of meat for the sacrificial meal; Even the fragrance of roasted lamb is like a meal! Or make it an ox garnished with goat meat!</verse>
<verse>All believers, come here and listen, let me tell you what God did for me.</verse>
<verse>I called out to him with my mouth, my tongue shaped the sounds of music.</verse>
<verse>If I had been cozy with evil, the Lord would never have listened.</verse>
<verse>But he most surely did listen, he came on the double when he heard my prayer.</verse>
<verse>Blessed be God: he didn't turn a deaf ear, he stayed with me, loyal in his love.</verse>
</chapter>