<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Psalms" book_id="19" n="68">
<verse>Up with God! Down with his enemies! Adversaries, run for the hills!</verse>
<verse>Gone like a puff of smoke, like a blob of wax in the fire--one look at God and the wicked vanish.</verse>
<verse>When the righteous see God in action they'll laugh, they'll sing, they'll laugh and sing for joy.</verse>
<verse>Sing hymns to God; all heaven, sing out; clear the way for the coming of Cloud-Rider. Enjoy GOD, cheer when you see him!</verse>
<verse>Father of orphans, champion of widows, is God in his holy house.</verse>
<verse>God makes homes for the homeless, leads prisoners to freedom, but leaves rebels to rot in hell.</verse>
<verse>God, when you took the lead with your people, when you marched out into the wild,</verse>
<verse>Earth shook, sky broke out in a sweat; God was on the march. Even Sinai trembled at the sight of God on the move, at the sight of Israel's God.</verse>
<verse>You pour out rain in buckets, O God; thorn and cactus become an oasis</verse>
<verse>For your people to camp in and enjoy. You set them up in business; they went from rags to riches.</verse>
<verse>The Lord gave the word; thousands called out the good news:</verse>
<verse>"Kings of the armies are on the run, on the run!"</verse>
<verse>While housewives, safe and sound back home, divide up the plunder, the plunder of Canaanite silver and gold.</verse>
<verse>On that day that Shaddai scattered the kings, snow fell on Black Mountain.</verse>
<verse>You huge mountains, Bashan mountains, mighty mountains, dragon mountains.</verse>
<verse>All you mountains not chosen, sulk now, and feel sorry for yourselves, For this is the mountain God has chosen to live on; he'll rule from this mountain forever.</verse>
<verse>The chariots of God, twice ten thousand, and thousands more besides, The Lord in the lead, riding down Sinai--straight to the Holy Place!</verse>
<verse>You climbed to the High Place, captives in tow, your arms full of booty from rebels, And now you sit there in state, GOD, sovereign GOD!</verse>
<verse>Blessed be the Lord--day after day he carries us along.</verse>
<verse>He's our Savior, our God, oh yes! He's God--for--us, he's God--who-saves-us. Lord GOD knows all death's ins and outs.</verse>
<verse>What's more, he made heads roll, split the skulls of the enemy As he marched out of heaven,</verse>
<verse>saying, "I tied up the Dragon in knots, put a muzzle on the Deep Blue Sea."</verse>
<verse>You can wade through your enemies' blood, and your dogs taste of your enemies from your boots.</verse>
<verse>See God on parade to the sanctuary, my God, my King on the march!</verse>
<verse>Singers out front, the band behind, maidens in the middle with castanets.</verse>
<verse>The whole choir blesses God. Like a fountain of praise, Israel blesses GOD.</verse>
<verse>Look--little Benjamin's out front and leading Princes of Judah in their royal robes, princes of Zebulon, princes of Naphtali.</verse>
<verse>Parade your power, O God, the power, O God, that made us what we are.</verse>
<verse>Your temple, High God, is Jerusalem; kings bring gifts to you.</verse>
<verse>Rebuke that old crocodile, Egypt, with her herd of wild bulls and calves, Rapacious in her lust for silver, crushing peoples, spoiling for a fight.</verse>
<verse>Let Egyptian traders bring blue cloth and Cush come running to God, her hands outstretched.</verse>
<verse>Sing, O kings of the earth! Sing praises to the Lord!</verse>
<verse>There he is: Sky-Rider, striding the ancient skies. Listen--he's calling in thunder, rumbling, rolling thunder.</verse>
<verse>Call out "Bravo!" to God, the High God of Israel. His splendor and strength rise huge as thunderheads.</verse>
<verse>A terrible beauty, O God, streams from your sanctuary. It's Israel's strong God! He gives power and might to his people! O you, his people--bless God!</verse>
</chapter>