<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Psalms" book-id="19" n="69">
<verse>God, God, save me! I'm in over my head,</verse>
<verse>Quicksand under me, swamp water over me; I'm going down for the third time.</verse>
<verse>I'm hoarse from calling for help, Bleary-eyed from searching the sky for God.</verse>
<verse>I've got more enemies than hairs on my head; Sneaks and liars are out to knife me in the back. What I never stole Must I now give back?</verse>
<verse>God, you know every sin I've committed; My life's a wide-open book before you.</verse>
<verse>Don't let those who look to you in hope Be discouraged by what happens to me, Dear Lord! GOD of the armies! Don't let those out looking for you Come to a dead end by following me--Please, dear God of Israel!</verse>
<verse>Because of you I look like an idiot, I walk around ashamed to show my face.</verse>
<verse>My brothers shun me like a bum off the street; My family treats me like an unwanted guest.</verse>
<verse>I love you more than I can say. Because I'm madly in love with you, They blame me for everything they dislike about you.</verse>
<verse>When I poured myself out in prayer and fasting, All it got me was more contempt.</verse>
<verse>When I put on a sad face, They treated me like a clown.</verse>
<verse>Now drunks and gluttons Make up drinking songs about me.</verse>
<verse>And me? I pray. GOD, it's time for a break! God, answer in love! Answer with your sure salvation!</verse>
<verse>Rescue me from the swamp, Don't let me go under for good, Pull me out of the clutch of the enemy; This whirlpool is sucking me down.</verse>
<verse>Don't let the swamp be my grave, the Black Hole Swallow me, its jaws clenched around me.</verse>
<verse>Now answer me, GOD, because you love me; Let me see your great mercy full-face.</verse>
<verse>Don't look the other way; your servant can't take it. I'm in trouble. Answer right now!</verse>
<verse>Come close, God; get me out of here. Rescue me from this deathtrap.</verse>
<verse>You know how they kick me around--Pin on me the donkey's ears, the dunce's cap.</verse>
<verse>I'm broken by their taunts, Flat on my face, reduced to a nothing. I looked in vain for one friendly face. Not one. I couldn't find one shoulder to cry on.</verse>
<verse>They put poison in my soup, Vinegar in my drink.</verse>
<verse>Let their supper be bait in a trap that snaps shut; May their best friends be trappers who'll skin them alive.</verse>
<verse>Make them become blind as bats, Give them the shakes from morning to night.</verse>
<verse>Let them know what you think of them, Blast them with your red-hot anger.</verse>
<verse>Burn down their houses, Leave them desolate with nobody at home.</verse>
<verse>They gossiped about the one you disciplined, Made up stories about anyone wounded by God.</verse>
<verse>Pile on the guilt, Don't let them off the hook.</verse>
<verse>Strike their names from the list of the living; No rock-carved honor for them among the righteous.</verse>
<verse>I'm hurt and in pain; Give me space for healing, and mountain air.</verse>
<verse>Let me shout God's name with a praising song, Let me tell his greatness in a prayer of thanks.</verse>
<verse>For GOD, this is better than oxen on the altar, Far better than blue-ribbon bulls.</verse>
<verse>The poor in spirit see and are glad--Oh, you God--seekers, take heart!</verse>
<verse>For GOD listens to the poor, He doesn't walk out on the wretched.</verse>
<verse>You heavens, praise him; praise him, earth; Also ocean and all things that swim in it.</verse>
<verse>For God is out to help Zion, Rebuilding the wrecked towns of Judah. Guess who will live there--The proud owners of the land?</verse>
<verse>No, the children of his servants will get it, The lovers of his name will live in it. A David prayer</verse>
</chapter>