<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Psalms" book_id="19" n="71">
<verse>I run for dear life to GOD, I'll never live to regret it.</verse>
<verse>Do what you do so well: get me out of this mess and up on my feet. Put your ear to the ground and listen, give me space for salvation.</verse>
<verse>Be a guest room where I can retreat; you said your door was always open! You're my salvation--my vast, granite fortress.</verse>
<verse>My God, free me from the grip of Wicked, from the clutch of Bad and Bully.</verse>
<verse>You keep me going when times are tough--my bedrock, GOD, since my childhood.</verse>
<verse>I've hung on you from the day of my birth, the day you took me from the cradle; I'll never run out of praise.</verse>
<verse>Many gasp in alarm when they see me, but you take me in stride.</verse>
<verse>Just as each day brims with your beauty, my mouth brims with praise.</verse>
<verse>But don't turn me out to pasture when I'm old or put me on the shelf when I can't pull my weight.</verse>
<verse>My enemies are talking behind my back, watching for their chance to knife me.</verse>
<verse>The gossip is: "God has abandoned him. Pounce on him now; no one will help him."</verse>
<verse>God, don't just watch from the sidelines. Come on! Run to my side!</verse>
<verse>My accusers--make them lose face. Those out to get me--make them look Like idiots,</verse>
<verse>while I stretch out, reaching for you, and daily add praise to praise.</verse>
<verse>I'll write the book on your righteousness, talk up your salvation the livelong day, never run out of good things to write or say.</verse>
<verse>I come in the power of the Lord GOD, I post signs marking his right--of-way.</verse>
<verse>You got me when I was an unformed youth, God, and taught me everything I know. Now I'm telling the world your wonders;</verse>
<verse>I'll keep at it until I'm old and gray. God, don't walk off and leave me until I get out the news Of your strong right arm to this world, news of your power to the world yet to come,</verse>
<verse>Your famous and righteous ways, O God. God, you've done it all! Who is quite like you?</verse>
<verse>You, who made me stare trouble in the face, Turn me around; Now let me look life in the face. I've been to the bottom; Bring me up,</verse>
<verse>streaming with honors; turn to me, be tender to me,</verse>
<verse>And I'll take up the lute and thank you to the tune of your faithfulness, God. I'll make music for you on a harp, Holy One of Israel.</verse>
<verse>When I open up in song to you, I let out lungsful of praise, my rescued life a song.</verse>
<verse>All day long I'm chanting about you and your righteous ways, While those who tried to do me in slink off looking ashamed. A Solomon psalm</verse>
</chapter>