<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Psalms" book_id="19" n="72">
<verse>Give the gift of wise rule to the king, O God, the gift of just rule to the crown prince.</verse>
<verse>May he judge your people rightly, be honorable to your meek and lowly.</verse>
<verse>Let the mountains give exuberant witness; shape the hills with the contours of right living.</verse>
<verse>Please stand up for the poor, help the children of the needy, come down hard on the cruel tyrants.</verse>
<verse>Outlast the sun, outlive the moon--age after age after age.</verse>
<verse>Be rainfall on cut grass, earth-refreshing rain showers.</verse>
<verse>Let righteousness burst into blossom and peace abound until the moon fades to nothing.</verse>
<verse>Rule from sea to sea, from the River to the Rim.</verse>
<verse>Foes will fall on their knees before God, his enemies lick the dust.</verse>
<verse>Kings remote and legendary will pay homage, kings rich and resplendent will turn over their wealth.</verse>
<verse>All kings will fall down and worship, and godless nations sign up to serve him,</verse>
<verse>Because he rescues the poor at the first sign of need, the destitute who have run out of luck.</verse>
<verse>He opens a place in his heart for the down--and-out, he restores the wretched of the earth.</verse>
<verse>He frees them from tyranny and torture--when they bleed, he bleeds; when they die, he dies.</verse>
<verse>And live! Oh, let him live! Deck him out in Sheba gold. Offer prayers unceasing to him, bless him from morning to night.</verse>
<verse>Fields of golden grain in the land, cresting the mountains in wild exuberance, Cornucopias of praise, praises springing from the city like grass from the earth.</verse>
<verse>May he never be forgotten, his fame shine on like sunshine. May all godless people enter his circle of blessing and bless the One who blessed them.</verse>
<verse>Blessed GOD, Israel's God, the one and only wonder-working God!</verse>
<verse>Blessed always his blazing glory! All earth brims with his glory.</verse>
<verse>Yes and Yes and Yes. An Asaph psalm</verse>
</chapter>