<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Psalms" book-id="19" n="73">
<verse>No doubt about it! God is good--good to good people, good to the good--hearted.</verse>
<verse>But I nearly missed it, missed seeing his goodness.</verse>
<verse>I was looking the other way, looking up to the people</verse>
<verse>At the top, envying the wicked who have it made,</verse>
<verse>Who have nothing to worry about, not a care in the whole wide world.</verse>
<verse>Pretentious with arrogance, they wear the latest fashions in violence,</verse>
<verse>Pampered and overfed, decked out in silk bows of silliness.</verse>
<verse>They jeer, using words to kill; they bully their way with words.</verse>
<verse>They're full of hot air, loudmouths disturbing the peace.</verse>
<verse>People actually listen to them--can you believe it? Like thirsty puppies, they lap up their words.</verse>
<verse>What's going on here? Is God out to lunch? Nobody's tending the store.</verse>
<verse>The wicked get by with everything; they have it made, piling up riches</verse>
<verse>I've been stupid to play by the rules; what has it gotten me?</verse>
<verse>A long run of bad luck, that's what--a slap in the face every time I walk out the door.</verse>
<verse>If I'd have given in and talked like this, I would have betrayed your dear children.</verse>
<verse>Still, when I tried to figure it out, all I got was a splitting headache...</verse>
<verse>Until I entered the sanctuary of God. Then I saw the whole picture:</verse>
<verse>The slippery road you've put them on, with a final crash in a ditch of delusions.</verse>
<verse>In the blink of an eye, disaster! A blind curve in the dark, and--nightmare!</verse>
<verse>We wake up and rub our eyes.... Nothing. There's nothing to them. And there never was.</verse>
<verse>When I was beleaguered and bitter, totally consumed by envy,</verse>
<verse>I was totally ignorant, a dumb ox in your very presence.</verse>
<verse>I'm still in your presence, but you've taken my hand.</verse>
<verse>You wisely and tenderly lead me, and then you bless me.</verse>
<verse>You're all I want in heaven! You're all I want on earth!</verse>
<verse>When my skin sags and my bones get brittle, GOD is rock-firm and faithful.</verse>
<verse>Look! Those who left you are falling apart! Deserters, they'll never be heard from again.</verse>
<verse>But I'm in the very presence of God--oh, how refreshing it is! I've made Lord GOD my home. God, I'm telling the world what you do! An Asaph psalm</verse>
</chapter>