<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Psalms" book_id="19" n="74">
<verse>You walked off and left us, and never looked back. God, how could you do that? We're your very own sheep; how can you stomp off in anger?</verse>
<verse>Refresh your memory of us--you bought us a long time ago. Your most precious tribe--you paid a good price for us! Your very own Mount Zion--you actually lived here once!</verse>
<verse>Come and visit the site of disaster, see how they've wrecked the sanctuary.</verse>
<verse>While your people were at worship, your enemies barged in, brawling and scrawling graffiti.</verse>
<verse>They set fire to the porch; axes swinging, they chopped up the woodwork,</verse>
<verse>Beat down the doors with sledgehammers, then split them into kindling.</verse>
<verse>They burned your holy place to the ground, violated the place of worship.</verse>
<verse>They said to themselves, "We'll wipe them all out," and burned down all the places of worship.</verse>
<verse>There's not a sign or symbol of God in sight, nor anyone to speak in his name, no one who knows what's going on.</verse>
<verse>How long, God, will barbarians blaspheme, enemies curse and get by with it?</verse>
<verse>Why don't you do something? How long are you going to sit there with your hands folded in your lap?</verse>
<verse>God is my King from the very start; he works salvation in the womb of the earth.</verse>
<verse>With one blow you split the sea in two, you made mincemeat of the dragon Tannin.</verse>
<verse>You lopped off the heads of Leviathan, then served them up in a stew for the animals.</verse>
<verse>With your finger you opened up springs and creeks, and dried up the wild floodwaters.</verse>
<verse>You own the day, you own the night; you put stars and sun in place.</verse>
<verse>You laid out the four corners of earth, shaped the seasons of summer and winter.</verse>
<verse>Mark and remember, GOD, all the enemy taunts, each idiot desecration.</verse>
<verse>Don't throw your lambs to the wolves; after all we've been through, don't forget us.</verse>
<verse>Remember your promises; the city is in darkness, the countryside violent.</verse>
<verse>Don't leave the victims to rot in the street; make them a choir that sings your praises.</verse>
<verse>On your feet, O God--stand up for yourself! Do you hear what they're saying about you, all the vile obscenities?</verse>
<verse>Don't tune out their malicious filth, the brawling invective that never lets up. An Asaph psalm</verse>
</chapter>