<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Psalms" book_id="19" n="77">
<verse>I yell out to my God, I yell with all my might, I yell at the top of my lungs. He listens.</verse>
<verse>I found myself in trouble and went looking for my Lord; my life was an open wound that wouldn't heal. When friends said, "Everything will turn out all right," I didn't believe a word they said.</verse>
<verse>I remember God--and shake my head. I bow my head--then wring my hands.</verse>
<verse>I'm awake all night--not a wink of sleep; I can't even say what's bothering me.</verse>
<verse>I go over the days one by one, I ponder the years gone by.</verse>
<verse>I strum my lute all through the night, wondering how to get my life together.</verse>
<verse>Will the Lord walk off and leave us for good? Will he never smile again?</verse>
<verse>Is his love worn threadbare? Has his salvation promise burned out?</verse>
<verse>Has God forgotten his manners? Has he angrily stalked off and left us?</verse>
<verse>"Just my luck," I said. "The High God goes out of business just the moment I need him."</verse>
<verse>Once again I'll go over what GOD has done, lay out on the table the ancient wonders;</verse>
<verse>I'll ponder all the things you've accomplished, and give a long, loving look at your acts.</verse>
<verse>O God! Your way is holy! No god is great like God!</verse>
<verse>You're the God who makes things happen; you showed everyone what you can do--</verse>
<verse>You pulled your people out of the worst kind of trouble, rescued the children of Jacob and Joseph.</verse>
<verse>Ocean saw you in action, God, saw you and trembled with fear; Deep Ocean was scared to death.</verse>
<verse>Clouds belched buckets of rain, Sky exploded with thunder, your arrows flashing this way and that.</verse>
<verse>From Whirlwind came your thundering voice, Lightning exposed the world, Earth reeled and rocked.</verse>
<verse>You strode right through Ocean, walked straight through roaring Ocean, but nobody saw you come or go.</verse>
<verse>Hidden in the hands of Moses and Aaron, You led your people like a flock of sheep. An Asaph psalm</verse>
</chapter>