<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Psalms" book-id="19" n="78">
<verse>Listen, dear friends, to God's truth, bend your ears to what I tell you.</verse>
<verse>I'm chewing on the morsel of a proverb; I'll let you in on the sweet old truths,</verse>
<verse>Stories we heard from our fathers, counsel we learned at our mother's knee.</verse>
<verse>We're not keeping this to ourselves, we're passing it along to the next generation--GOD's fame and fortune, the marvelous things he has done.</verse>
<verse>He planted a witness in Jacob, set his Word firmly in Israel, Then commanded our parents to teach it to their children</verse>
<verse>So the next generation would know, and all the generations to come--Know the truth and tell the stories so their children</verse>
<verse>can trust in God, Never forget the works of God but keep his commands to the letter.</verse>
<verse>Heaven forbid they should be like their parents, bullheaded and bad, A fickle and faithless bunch who never stayed true to God.</verse>
<verse>The Ephraimites, armed to the teeth, ran off when the battle began.</verse>
<verse>They were cowards to God's Covenant, refused to walk by his Word.</verse>
<verse>They forgot what he had done--marvels he'd done right before their eyes.</verse>
<verse>He performed miracles in plain sight of their parents in Egypt, out on the fields of Zoan.</verse>
<verse>He split the Sea and they walked right through it; he piled the waters to the right and the left.</verse>
<verse>He led them by day with a cloud, led them all the night long with a fiery torch.</verse>
<verse>He split rocks in the wilderness, gave them all they could drink from underground springs;</verse>
<verse>He made creeks flow out from sheer rock, and water pour out like a river.</verse>
<verse>All they did was sin even more, rebel in the desert against the High God.</verse>
<verse>They tried to get their own way with God, clamored for favors, for special attention.</verse>
<verse>They whined like spoiled children, "Why can't God give us a decent meal in this desert?</verse>
<verse>Sure, he struck the rock and the water flowed, creeks cascaded from the rock. But how about some fresh-baked bread? How about a nice cut of meat?"</verse>
<verse>When GOD heard that, he was furious--his anger flared against Jacob, he lost his temper with Israel.</verse>
<verse>It was clear they didn't believe God, had no intention of trusting in his help.</verse>
<verse>But God helped them anyway, commanded the clouds and gave orders that opened the gates of heaven.</verse>
<verse>He rained down showers of manna to eat, he gave them the Bread of Heaven.</verse>
<verse>They ate the bread of the mighty angels; he sent them all the food they could eat.</verse>
<verse>He let East Wind break loose from the skies, gave a strong push to South Wind.</verse>
<verse>This time it was birds that rained down--succulent birds, an abundance of birds.</verse>
<verse>He aimed them right for the center of their camp; all round their tents there were birds.</verse>
<verse>They ate and had their fill; he handed them everything they craved on a platter.</verse>
<verse>But their greed knew no bounds; they stuffed their mouths with more and more.</verse>
<verse>Finally, God was fed up, his anger erupted--he cut down their brightest and best, he laid low Israel's finest young men.</verse>
<verse>And--can you believe it?-they kept right on sinning; all those wonders and they still wouldn't believe!</verse>
<verse>So their lives dribbled off to nothing--nothing to show for their lives but a ghost town.</verse>
<verse>When he cut them down, they came running for help; they turned and pled for mercy.</verse>
<verse>They gave witness that God was their rock, that High God was their redeemer,</verse>
<verse>But they didn't mean a word of it; they lied through their teeth the whole time.</verse>
<verse>They could not have cared less about him, wanted nothing to do with his Covenant.</verse>
<verse>And God? Compassionate! Forgave the sin! Didn't destroy! Over and over he reined in his anger, restrained his considerable wrath.</verse>
<verse>He knew what they were made of; he knew there wasn't much to them,</verse>
<verse>How often in the desert they had spurned him, tried his patience in those wilderness years.</verse>
<verse>Time and again they pushed him to the limit, provoked Israel's Holy God.</verse>
<verse>How quickly they forgot what he'd done, forgot their day of rescue from the enemy,</verse>
<verse>When he did miracles in Egypt, wonders on the plain of Zoan.</verse>
<verse>He turned the River and its streams to blood--not a drop of water fit to drink.</verse>
<verse>He sent flies, which ate them alive, and frogs, which bedeviled them.</verse>
<verse>He turned their harvest over to caterpillars, everything they had worked for to the locusts.</verse>
<verse>He flattened their grapevines with hail; a killing frost ruined their orchards.</verse>
<verse>He pounded their cattle with hail, let thunderbolts loose on their herds.</verse>
<verse>His anger flared, a wild firestorm of havoc, An advance guard of disease-carrying angels</verse>
<verse>to clear the ground, preparing the way before him. He didn't spare those people, he let the plague rage through their lives.</verse>
<verse>He killed all the Egyptian firstborns, lusty infants, offspring of Ham's virility.</verse>
<verse>Then he led his people out like sheep, took his flock safely through the wilderness.</verse>
<verse>He took good care of them; they had nothing to fear. The Sea took care of their enemies for good.</verse>
<verse>He brought them into his holy land, this mountain he claimed for his own.</verse>
<verse>He scattered everyone who got in their way; he staked out an inheritance for them--the tribes of Israel all had their own places.</verse>
<verse>But they kept on giving him a hard time, rebelled against God, the High God, refused to do anything he told them.</verse>
<verse>They were worse, if that's possible, than their parents: traitors--crooked as a corkscrew.</verse>
<verse>Their pagan orgies provoked God's anger, their obscene idolatries broke his heart.</verse>
<verse>When God heard their carryings-on, he was furious; he posted a huge No over Israel.</verse>
<verse>He walked off and left Shiloh empty, abandoned the shrine where he had met with Israel.</verse>
<verse>He let his pride and joy go to the dogs, turned his back on the pride of his life.</verse>
<verse>He turned them loose on fields of battle; angry, he let them fend for themselves.</verse>
<verse>Their young men went to war and never came back; their young women waited in vain.</verse>
<verse>Their priests were massacred, and their widows never shed a tear.</verse>
<verse>Suddenly the Lord was up on his feet like someone roused from deep sleep, shouting like a drunken warrior.</verse>
<verse>He hit his enemies hard, sent them running, yelping, not daring to look back.</verse>
<verse>He disqualified Joseph as leader, told Ephraim he didn't have what it takes,</verse>
<verse>And chose the Tribe of Judah instead, Mount Zion, which he loves so much.</verse>
<verse>He built his sanctuary there, resplendent, solid and lasting as the earth itself.</verse>
<verse>Then he chose David, his servant, handpicked him from his work in the sheep pens.</verse>
<verse>One day he was caring for the ewes and their lambs, the next day God had him shepherding Jacob, his people Israel, his prize possession.</verse>
<verse>His good heart made him a good shepherd; he guided the people wisely and well. An Asaph psalm</verse>
</chapter>