<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Psalms" book_id="19" n="80">
<verse>Listen, Shepherd, Israel's Shepherd--get all your Joseph sheep together. Throw beams of light from your dazzling throne</verse>
<verse>So Ephraim, Benjamin, and Manasseh can see where they're going. Get out of bed--you've slept long enough! Come on the run before it's too late.</verse>
<verse>God, come back! Smile your blessing smile: That will be our salvation.</verse>
<verse>GOD, God of the angel armies, how long will you smolder like a sleeping volcano while your people call for fire and brimstone?</verse>
<verse>You put us on a diet of tears, bucket after bucket of salty tears to drink.</verse>
<verse>You make us look ridiculous to our friends; our enemies poke fun day after day.</verse>
<verse>God of the angel armies, come back! Smile your blessing smile: That will be our salvation.</verse>
<verse>Remember how you brought a young vine from Egypt, cleared out the brambles and briers and planted your very own vineyard?</verse>
<verse>You prepared the good earth, you planted her roots deep; the vineyard filled the land.</verse>
<verse>Your vine soared high and shaded the mountains, even dwarfing the giant cedars.</verse>
<verse>Your vine ranged west to the Sea, east to the River.</verse>
<verse>So why do you no longer protect your vine? Trespassers pick its grapes at will;</verse>
<verse>Wild pigs crash through and crush it, and the mice nibble away at what's left.</verse>
<verse>God of the angel armies, turn our way! Take a good look at what's happened and attend to this vine.</verse>
<verse>Care for what you once tenderly planted--the vine you raised from a shoot.</verse>
<verse>And those who dared to set it on fire--give them a look that will kill!</verse>
<verse>Then take the hand of your once-favorite child, the child you raised to adulthood.</verse>
<verse>We will never turn our back on you; breathe life into our lungs so we can shout your name!</verse>
<verse>GOD, God of the angel armies, come back! Smile your blessing smile: That will be our salvation. An Asaph psalm</verse>
</chapter>