<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Psalms" book-id="19" n="89">
<verse>Your love, GOD, is my song, and I'll sing it! I'm forever telling everyone how faithful you are.</verse>
<verse>I'll never quit telling the story of your love--how you built the cosmos and guaranteed everything in it. Your love has always been our lives' foundation, your fidelity has been the roof over our world.</verse>
<verse>You once said, "I joined forces with my chosen leader, I pledged my word to my servant, David, saying,</verse>
<verse>"Everyone descending from you is guaranteed life; I'll make your rule as solid and lasting as rock.'"</verse>
<verse>GOD! Let the cosmos praise your wonderful ways, the choir of holy angels sing anthems to your faithful ways!</verse>
<verse>Search high and low, scan skies and land, you'll find nothing and no one quite like GOD.</verse>
<verse>The holy angels are in awe before him; he looms immense and august over everyone around him.</verse>
<verse>GOD of the Angel Armies, who is like you, powerful and faithful from every angle?</verse>
<verse>You put the arrogant ocean in its place and calm its waves when they turn unruly.</verse>
<verse>You gave that old hag Egypt the back of your hand, you brushed off your enemies with a flick of your wrist.</verse>
<verse>You own the cosmos--you made everything in it, everything from atom to archangel.</verse>
<verse>You positioned the North and South Poles; the mountains Tabor and Hermon sing duets to you.</verse>
<verse>With your well-muscled arm and your grip of steel--nobody trifles with you!</verse>
<verse>The Right and Justice are the roots of your rule; Love and Truth are its fruits.</verse>
<verse>Blessed are the people who know the passwords of praise, who shout on parade in the bright presence of GOD.</verse>
<verse>Delighted, they dance all day long; they know who you are, what you do--they can't keep it quiet!</verse>
<verse>Your vibrant beauty has gotten inside us--you've been so good to us! We're walking on air!</verse>
<verse>All we are and have we owe to GOD, Holy God of Israel, our King!</verse>
<verse>A long time ago you spoke in a vision, you spoke to your faithful beloved: "I've crowned a hero, I chose the best I could find;</verse>
<verse>I found David, my servant, poured holy oil on his head,</verse>
<verse>And I'll keep my hand steadily on him, yes, I'll stick with him through thick and thin.</verse>
<verse>No enemy will get the best of him, no scoundrel will do him in.</verse>
<verse>I'll weed out all who oppose him, I'll clean out all who hate him.</verse>
<verse>I'm with him for good and I'll love him forever; I've set him on high--he's riding high!</verse>
<verse>I've put Ocean in his one hand, River in the other;</verse>
<verse>he'll call out, "Oh, my Father--my God, my Rock of Salvation!'</verse>
<verse>Yes, I'm setting him apart as the First of the royal line, High King over all of earth's kings.</verse>
<verse>I'll preserve him eternally in my love, I'll faithfully do all I so solemnly promised.</verse>
<verse>I'll guarantee his family tree and underwrite his rule.</verse>
<verse>If his children refuse to do what I tell them, if they refuse to walk in the way I show them,</verse>
<verse>If they spit on the directions I give them and tear up the rules I post for them</verse>
<verse>-I'll rub their faces in the dirt of their rebellion and make them face the music.</verse>
<verse>But I'll never throw them out, never abandon or disown them.</verse>
<verse>Do you think I'd withdraw my holy promise? or take back words I'd already spoken?</verse>
<verse>I've given my word, my whole and holy word; do you think I would lie to David?</verse>
<verse>His family tree is here for good, his sovereignty as sure as the sun,</verse>
<verse>Dependable as the phases of the moon, inescapable as weather."</verse>
<verse>But GOD, you did walk off and leave us, you lost your temper with the one you anointed.</verse>
<verse>You tore up the promise you made to your servant, you stomped his crown in the mud.</verse>
<verse>You blasted his home to kingdom come, reduced his city to a pile of rubble</verse>
<verse>Picked clean by wayfaring strangers, a joke to all the neighbors.</verse>
<verse>You declared a holiday for all his enemies, and they're celebrating for all they're worth.</verse>
<verse>Angry, you opposed him in battle, refused to fight on his side;</verse>
<verse>You robbed him of his splendor, humiliated this warrior, ground his kingly honor in the dirt.</verse>
<verse>You took the best years of his life and left him an impotent, ruined husk.</verse>
<verse>How long do we put up with this, GOD? Are you gone for good? Will you hold this grudge forever?</verse>
<verse>Remember my sorrow and how short life is. Did you create men and women for nothing but this?</verse>
<verse>We'll see death soon enough. Everyone does. And there's no back door out of hell.</verse>
<verse>So where is the love you're so famous for, Lord? What happened to your promise to David?</verse>
<verse>Take a good look at your servant, dear Lord; I'm the butt of the jokes of all nations,</verse>
<verse>The taunting jokes of your enemies, GOD, as they dog the steps of your dear anointed.</verse>
<verse>Blessed be GOD forever and always! Yes. Oh, yes. A prayer of Moses, man of God</verse>
</chapter>