<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Psalms" book_id="19" n="9">
<verse>I'm thanking you, GOD, from a full heart, I'm writing the book on your wonders.</verse>
<verse>I'm whistling, laughing, and jumping for joy; I'm singing your song, High God.</verse>
<verse>The day my enemies turned tail and ran, they stumbled on you and fell on their faces.</verse>
<verse>You took over and set everything right; when I needed you, you were there, taking charge.</verse>
<verse>You blow the whistle on godless nations; you throw dirty players out of the game, wipe their names right off the roster.</verse>
<verse>Enemies disappear from the sidelines, their reputation trashed, their names erased from the halls of fame.</verse>
<verse>GOD holds the high center, he sees and sets the world's mess right.</verse>
<verse>He decides what is right for us earthlings, gives people their just deserts.</verse>
<verse>GOD's a safe-house for the battered, a sanctuary during bad times.</verse>
<verse>The moment you arrive, you relax; you're never sorry you knocked.</verse>
<verse>Sing your songs to Zion--dwelling GOD, tell his stories to everyone you meet:</verse>
<verse>How he tracks down killers yet keeps his eye on us, registers every whimper and moan.</verse>
<verse>Be kind to me, GOD; I've been kicked around long enough. Once you've pulled me back from the gates of death,</verse>
<verse>I'll write the book on Hallelujahs; on the corner of Main and First I'll hold a street meeting; I'll be the song leader; we'll fill the air with salvation songs.</verse>
<verse>They're trapped, those godless countries, in the very snares they set, Their feet all tangled in the net they spread.</verse>
<verse>They have no excuse; the way God works is well-known. The cunning machinery made by the wicked has maimed their own hands.</verse>
<verse>The wicked bought a one--way ticket to hell.</verse>
<verse>No longer will the poor be nameless--no more humiliation for the humble.</verse>
<verse>Up, GOD! Aren't you fed up with their empty strutting? Expose these grand pretensions!</verse>
<verse>Shake them up, GOD! Show them how silly they look.</verse>
</chapter>