<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Psalms" book-id="19" n="94">
<verse>GOD, put an end to evil; avenging God, show your colors!</verse>
<verse>Judge of the earth, take your stand; throw the book at the arrogant.</verse>
<verse>GOD, the wicked get away with murder--how long will you let this go on?</verse>
<verse>They brag and boast and crow about their crimes!</verse>
<verse>They walk all over your people, GOD, exploit and abuse your precious people.</verse>
<verse>They take out anyone who gets in their way; if they can't use them, they kill them.</verse>
<verse>They think, "GOD isn't looking, Jacob's God is out to lunch."</verse>
<verse>Well, think again, you idiots, fools--how long before you get smart?</verse>
<verse>Do you think Ear-Maker doesn't hear, Eye-Shaper doesn't see?</verse>
<verse>Do you think the trainer of nations doesn't correct, the teacher of Adam doesn't know?</verse>
<verse>GOD knows, all right--knows your stupidity, sees your shallowness.</verse>
<verse>How blessed the man you train, GOD, the woman you instruct in your Word,</verse>
<verse>Providing a circle of quiet within the clamor of evil, while a jail is being built for the wicked.</verse>
<verse>GOD will never walk away from his people, never desert his precious people.</verse>
<verse>Rest assured that justice is on its way and every good heart put right.</verse>
<verse>Who stood up for me against the wicked? Who took my side against evil workers?</verse>
<verse>If GOD hadn't been there for me, I never would have made it.</verse>
<verse>The minute I said, "I'm slipping, I'm falling," your love, GOD, took hold and held me fast.</verse>
<verse>When I was upset and beside myself, you calmed me down and cheered me up.</verse>
<verse>Can Misrule have anything in common with you? Can Troublemaker pretend to be on your side?</verse>
<verse>They ganged up on good people, plotted behind the backs of the innocent.</verse>
<verse>But GOD became my hideout, God was my high mountain retreat,</verse>
<verse>Then boomeranged their evil back on them: for their evil ways he wiped them out, our GOD cleaned them out for good.</verse>
</chapter>