<chapter translation="NASB" testament="New" book="1 Corinthians" book_id="46" n="11">
<verse>Be imitators of me, just as I also am of Christ.</verse>
<verse>Now I praise you because you remember me in everything and hold firmly to the traditions, just as I delivered them to you.</verse>
<verse>But I want you to understand that Christ is the head of every man, and the man is the head of a woman, and God is the head of Christ.</verse>
<verse>Every man who has something on his head while praying or prophesying disgraces his head.</verse>
<verse>But every woman who has her head uncovered while praying or prophesying disgraces her head, for she is one and the same as the woman whose head is shaved.</verse>
<verse>For if a woman does not cover her head, let her also have her hair cut off; but if it is disgraceful for a woman to have her hair cut off or her head shaved, let her cover her head.</verse>
<verse>For a man ought not to have his head covered, since he is the image and glory of God; but the woman is the glory of man.</verse>
<verse>For man does not originate from woman, but woman from man;</verse>
<verse>for indeed man was not created for the woman's sake, but woman for the man's sake.</verse>
<verse>Therefore the woman ought to have a symbol of authority on her head, because of the angels.</verse>
<verse>However, in the Lord, neither is woman independent of man, nor is man independent of woman.</verse>
<verse>For as the woman originates from the man, so also the man has his birth through the woman; and all things originate from God.</verse>
<verse>Judge for yourselves: is it proper for a woman to pray to God with her head uncovered?</verse>
<verse>Does not even nature itself teach you that if a man has long hair, it is a dishonor to him,</verse>
<verse>but if a woman has long hair, it is a glory to her? For her hair is given to her for a covering.</verse>
<verse>But if one is inclined to be contentious, we have no other practice, nor have the churches of God.</verse>
<verse>But in giving this instruction, I do not praise you, because you come together not for the better but for the worse.</verse>
<verse>For, in the first place, when you come together as a church, I hear that divisions exist among you; and in part I believe it.</verse>
<verse>For there must also be factions among you, so that those who are approved may become evident among you.</verse>
<verse>Therefore when you meet together, it is not to eat the Lord's Supper,</verse>
<verse>for in your eating each one takes his own supper first; and one is hungry and another is drunk.</verse>
<verse>What! Do you not have houses in which to eat and drink? Or do you despise the church of God and shame those who have nothing? What shall I say to you? Shall I praise you? In this I will not praise you.</verse>
<verse>For I received from the Lord that which I also delivered to you, that the Lord Jesus in the night in which He was betrayed took bread;</verse>
<verse>and when He had given thanks, He broke it and said, "This is My body, which is for you; do this in remembrance of Me."</verse>
<verse>In the same way He took the cup also after supper, saying, "This cup is the new covenant in My blood; do this, as often as you drink it, in remembrance of Me."</verse>
<verse>For as often as you eat this bread and drink the cup, you proclaim the Lord's death until He comes.</verse>
<verse>Therefore whoever eats the bread or drinks the cup of the Lord in an unworthy manner, shall be guilty of the body and the blood of the Lord.</verse>
<verse>But a man must examine himself, and in so doing he is to eat of the bread and drink of the cup.</verse>
<verse>For he who eats and drinks, eats and drinks judgment to himself if he does not judge the body rightly.</verse>
<verse>For this reason many among you are weak and sick, and a number sleep.</verse>
<verse>But if we judged ourselves rightly, we would not be judged.</verse>
<verse>But when we are judged, we are disciplined by the Lord so that we will not be condemned along with the world.</verse>
<verse>So then, my brethren, when you come together to eat, wait for one another.</verse>
<verse>If anyone is hungry, let him eat at home, so that you will not come together for judgment. The remaining matters I will arrange when I come.</verse>
</chapter>