<chapter translation="NASB" testament="New" book="1 Corinthians" book_id="46" n="14">
<verse>Pursue love, yet desire earnestly spiritual gifts, but especially that you may prophesy.</verse>
<verse>For one who speaks in a tongue does not speak to men but to God; for no one understands, but in his spirit he speaks mysteries.</verse>
<verse>But one who prophesies speaks to men for edification and exhortation and consolation.</verse>
<verse>One who speaks in a tongue edifies himself; but one who prophesies edifies the church.</verse>
<verse>Now I wish that you all spoke in tongues, but even more that you would prophesy; and greater is one who prophesies than one who speaks in tongues, unless he interprets, so that the church may receive edifying.</verse>
<verse>But now, brethren, if I come to you speaking in tongues, what will I profit you unless I speak to you either by way of revelation or of knowledge or of prophecy or of teaching?</verse>
<verse>Yet even lifeless things, either flute or harp, in producing a sound, if they do not produce a distinction in the tones, how will it be known what is played on the flute or on the harp?</verse>
<verse>For if the bugle produces an indistinct sound, who will prepare himself for battle?</verse>
<verse>So also you, unless you utter by the tongue speech that is clear, how will it be known what is spoken? For you will be speaking into the air.</verse>
<verse>There are, perhaps, a great many kinds of languages in the world, and no kind is without meaning.</verse>
<verse>If then I do not know the meaning of the language, I will be to the one who speaks a barbarian, and the one who speaks will be a barbarian to me.</verse>
<verse>So also you, since you are zealous of spiritual gifts, seek to abound for the edification of the church.</verse>
<verse>Therefore let one who speaks in a tongue pray that he may interpret.</verse>
<verse>For if I pray in a tongue, my spirit prays, but my mind is unfruitful.</verse>
<verse>What is the outcome then? I will pray with the spirit and I will pray with the mind also; I will sing with the spirit and I will sing with the mind also.</verse>
<verse>Otherwise if you bless in the spirit only, how will the one who fills the place of the ungifted say the "Amen" at your giving of thanks, since he does not know what you are saying?</verse>
<verse>For you are giving thanks well enough, but the other person is not edified.</verse>
<verse>I thank God, I speak in tongues more than you all;</verse>
<verse>however, in the church I desire to speak five words with my mind so that I may instruct others also, rather than ten thousand words in a tongue.</verse>
<verse>Brethren, do not be children in your thinking; yet in evil be infants, but in your thinking be mature.</verse>
<verse>In the Law it is written, "BY MEN OF STRANGE TONGUES AND BY THE LIPS OF STRANGERS I WILL SPEAK TO THIS PEOPLE, AND EVEN SO THEY WILL NOT LISTEN TO ME," says the Lord.</verse>
<verse>So then tongues are for a sign, not to those who believe but to unbelievers; but prophecy is for a sign, not to unbelievers but to those who believe.</verse>
<verse>Therefore if the whole church assembles together and all speak in tongues, and ungifted men or unbelievers enter, will they not say that you are mad?</verse>
<verse>But if all prophesy, and an unbeliever or an ungifted man enters, he is convicted by all, he is called to account by all;</verse>
<verse>the secrets of his heart are disclosed; and so he will fall on his face and worship God, declaring that God is certainly among you.</verse>
<verse>What is the outcome then, brethren? When you assemble, each one has a psalm, has a teaching, has a revelation, has a tongue, has an interpretation. Let all things be done for edification.</verse>
<verse>If anyone speaks in a tongue, it should be by two or at the most three, and each in turn, and one must interpret;</verse>
<verse>but if there is no interpreter, he must keep silent in the church; and let him speak to himself and to God.</verse>
<verse>Let two or three prophets speak, and let the others pass judgment.</verse>
<verse>But if a revelation is made to another who is seated, the first one must keep silent.</verse>
<verse>For you can all prophesy one by one, so that all may learn and all may be exhorted;</verse>
<verse>and the spirits of prophets are subject to prophets;</verse>
<verse>for God is not a God of confusion but of peace, as in all the churches of the saints.</verse>
<verse>The women are to keep silent in the churches; for they are not permitted to speak, but are to subject themselves, just as the Law also says.</verse>
<verse>If they desire to learn anything, let them ask their own husbands at home; for it is improper for a woman to speak in church.</verse>
<verse>Was it from you that the word of God first went forth? Or has it come to you only?</verse>
<verse>If anyone thinks he is a prophet or spiritual, let him recognize that the things which I write to you are the Lord's commandment.</verse>
<verse>But if anyone does not recognize this, he is not recognized.</verse>
<verse>Therefore, my brethren, desire earnestly to prophesy, and do not forbid to speak in tongues.</verse>
<verse>But all things must be done properly and in an orderly manner.</verse>
</chapter>