<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Zechariah" book-id="38" n="6">
<verse>Once again I looked up--another strange sight! Four chariots charging out from between two mountains. The mountains were bronze.</verse>
<verse>The first chariot was drawn by red horses, the second chariot by black horses,</verse>
<verse>the third chariot by white horses, and the fourth chariot by dappled horses. All the horses were powerful.</verse>
<verse>I asked the Messenger-Angel, "Sir, what's the meaning here?"</verse>
<verse>The angel answered, "These are the four winds of heaven, which originate with the Master of the whole earth.</verse>
<verse>The black horses are headed north with the white ones right after them. The dappled horses are headed south."</verse>
<verse>The powerful horses galloped out, bursting with energy, eager to patrol through the earth. The Messenger-Angel commanded: "On your way! Survey the earth!" and they were off in every direction.</verse>
<verse>Then he called to me and said, "Look at them go! The ones going north are conveying a sense of my Spirit, serene and secure. No more trouble from that direction."</verse>
<verse>Then this Message from GOD came to me:</verse>
<verse>"Take up a collection from the exiles. Target Heldai, Tobiah, and Jedaiah. They've just arrived from Babylon. You'll find them at the home of Josiah son of Zephaniah.</verse>
<verse>Collect silver and gold from them and fashion crowns. Place one on the head of Joshua son of Jehozadak, the high priest,</verse>
<verse>and give him this message: A Message from GOD-of-the-Angel-Armies. Be alert. We have a man here whose name is Branch. He will branch out from where he is and build the Temple of GOD.</verse>
<verse>Yes, he's the one. He'll build the Temple of GOD. Then he'll assume the role of royalty, take his place on the throne and rule--a priest sitting on the throne!-showing that king and priest can coexist in harmony.'</verse>
<verse>"The other crown will be in the Temple of GOD as a symbol of royalty, under the custodial care of Helem, Tobiah, Jedaiah, and Hen son of Zephaniah.</verse>
<verse>"People will come from faraway places to pitch in and rebuild the Temple of GOD. This will confirm that GOD-of-the-Angel-Armies did, in fact, send me to you. All this follows as you put your minds to a life of responsive obedience to the voice of your GOD."</verse>
</chapter>