<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Zechariah" book_id="38" n="8">
<verse>And then these Messages from GOD-of-the-Angel-Armies: A Message from GOD-of-the-Angel-Armies:</verse>
<verse>"I am zealous for Zion--I care! I'm angry about Zion--I'm involved!" [JC] GOD's Message:</verse>
<verse>"I've come back to Zion, I've moved back to Jerusalem. Jerusalem's new names will be Truth City, and Mountain of GOD-of-the-Angel-Armies, and Mount Holiness." [JC]</verse>
<verse>A Message from GOD-of-the-Angel-Armies: "Old men and old women will come back to Jerusalem, sit on benches on the streets and spin tales, move around safely with their canes--a good city to grow old in.</verse>
<verse>And boys and girls will fill the public parks, laughing and playing--a good city to grow up in." [JC]</verse>
<verse>A Message from GOD-of-the-Angel-Armies: "Do the problems of returning and rebuilding by just a few survivors seem too much? But is anything too much for me? Not if I have my say." [JC]</verse>
<verse>A Message from God-of-the-Angel-Armies: "I'll collect my people from countries to the east and countries to the west.</verse>
<verse>I'll bring them back and move them into Jerusalem. They'll be my people and I'll be their God. I'll stick with them and do right by them." [JC] A Message from GOD-of-the-Angel-Armies:</verse>
<verse>"Get a grip on things. Hold tight, you who are listening to what I say through the preaching of the prophets. The Temple of GOD-of-the-Angel-Armies has been reestablished. The Temple is being rebuilt.</verse>
<verse>We've come through a hard time: You worked for a pittance and were lucky to get that; the streets were dangerous; you could never let down your guard; I had turned the world into an armed camp.</verse>
<verse>"But things have changed. I'm taking the side of my core of surviving people:</verse>
<verse>Sowing and harvesting will resume, Vines will grow grapes, Gardens will flourish, Dew and rain will make everything green. "My core survivors will get everything they need--and more.</verse>
<verse>You've gotten a reputation as a bad-news people, you people of Judah and Israel, but I'm coming to save you. From now on, you're the good-news people. Don't be afraid. Keep a firm grip on what I'm doing."</verse>
<verse>A Message from GOD-of-the-Angel-Armies: "In the same way that I decided to punish you when your ancestors made me angry, and didn't pull my punches,</verse>
<verse>at this time I've decided to bless Jerusalem and the country of Judah. Don't be afraid.</verse>
<verse>And now here's what I want you to do: Tell the truth, the whole truth, when you speak. Do the right thing by one another, both personally and in your courts.</verse>
<verse>Don't cook up plans to take unfair advantage of others. Don't do or say what isn't so. I hate all that stuff. Keep your lives simple and honest." Decree of GOD. [JC]</verse>
<verse>Again I received a Message from GOD-of-the-Angel-Armies:</verse>
<verse>"The days of mourning set for the fourth, fifth, seventh, and tenth months will be turned into days of feasting for Judah--celebration and holiday. Embrace truth! Love peace!" [JC]</verse>
<verse>A Message from GOD-of-the-Angel-Armies: "People and their leaders will come from all over to see what's going on.</verse>
<verse>The leaders will confer with one another: "Shouldn't we try to get in on this? Get in on GOD's blessings? Pray to GOD-of-the-Angel-Armies? What's keeping us? Let's go!'</verse>
<verse>"Lots of people, powerful nations--they'll come to Jerusalem looking for what they can get from GOD-of-the-Angel-Armies, looking to get a blessing from GOD." [JC]</verse>
<verse>A Message from GOD-of-the-Angel-Armies: "At that time, ten men speaking a variety of languages will grab the sleeve of one Jew, hold tight, and say, "Let us go with you. We've heard that God is with you.'"</verse>
</chapter>