<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Jeremiah" book-id="24" n="14">
<verse>That which came as the word of the LORD to Jeremiah in regard to the drought:</verse>
<verse>"Judah mourns And her gates languish; They sit on the ground in mourning, And the cry of Jerusalem has ascended.</verse>
<verse>"Their nobles have sent their servants for water; They have come to the cisterns and found no water. They have returned with their vessels empty; They have been put to shame and humiliated, And they cover their heads.</verse>
<verse>"Because the ground is cracked, For there has been no rain on the land; The farmers have been put to shame, They have covered their heads.</verse>
<verse>"For even the doe in the field has given birth only to abandon her young, Because there is no grass.</verse>
<verse>"The wild donkeys stand on the bare heights; They pant for air like jackals, Their eyes fail For there is no vegetation.</verse>
<verse>"Although our iniquities testify against us, O LORD, act for Your name's sake! Truly our apostasies have been many, We have sinned against You.</verse>
<verse>"O Hope of Israel, Its Savior in time of distress, Why are You like a stranger in the land Or like a traveler who has pitched his tent for the night?</verse>
<verse>"Why are You like a man dismayed, Like a mighty man who cannot save? Yet You are in our midst, O LORD, And we are called by Your name; Do not forsake us!"</verse>
<verse>Thus says the LORD to this people, "Even so they have loved to wander; they have not kept their feet in check. Therefore the LORD does not accept them; now He will remember their iniquity and call their sins to account."</verse>
<verse>So the LORD said to me, "Do not pray for the welfare of this people.</verse>
<verse>"When they fast, I am not going to listen to their cry; and when they offer burnt offering and grain offering, I am not going to accept them. Rather I am going to make an end of them by the sword, famine and pestilence."</verse>
<verse>But, "Ah, Lord GOD!" I said, "Look, the prophets are telling them, 'You will not see the sword nor will you have famine, but I will give you lasting peace in this place.'"</verse>
<verse>Then the LORD said to me, "The prophets are prophesying falsehood in My name. I have neither sent them nor commanded them nor spoken to them; they are prophesying to you a false vision, divination, futility and the deception of their own minds.</verse>
<verse>"Therefore thus says the LORD concerning the prophets who are prophesying in My name, although it was not I who sent them--yet they keep saying, 'There will be no sword or famine in this land'--by sword and famine those prophets shall meet their end!</verse>
<verse>"The people also to whom they are prophesying will be thrown out into the streets of Jerusalem because of the famine and the sword; and there will be no one to bury them--neither them, nor their wives, nor their sons, nor their daughters--for I will pour out their own wickedness on them.</verse>
<verse>"You will say this word to them, 'Let my eyes flow down with tears night and day, And let them not cease; For the virgin daughter of my people has been crushed with a mighty blow, With a sorely infected wound.</verse>
<verse>'If I go out to the country, Behold, those slain with the sword! Or if I enter the city, Behold, diseases of famine! For both prophet and priest Have gone roving about in the land that they do not know.'"</verse>
<verse>Have You completely rejected Judah? Or have You loathed Zion? Why have You stricken us so that we are beyond healing? We waited for peace, but nothing good came; And for a time of healing, but behold, terror!</verse>
<verse>We know our wickedness, O LORD, The iniquity of our fathers, for we have sinned against You.</verse>
<verse>Do not despise us, for Your own name's sake; Do not disgrace the throne of Your glory; Remember and do not annul Your covenant with us.</verse>
<verse>Are there any among the idols of the nations who give rain? Or can the heavens grant showers? Is it not You, O LORD our God? Therefore we hope in You, For You are the one who has done all these things.</verse>
</chapter>