<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Jeremiah" book_id="24" n="20">
<verse>When Pashhur the priest, the son of Immer, who was chief officer in the house of the LORD, heard Jeremiah prophesying these things,</verse>
<verse>Pashhur had Jeremiah the prophet beaten and put him in the stocks that were at the upper Benjamin Gate, which was by the house of the LORD.</verse>
<verse>On the next day, when Pashhur released Jeremiah from the stocks, Jeremiah said to him, "Pashhur is not the name the LORD has called you, but rather Magor-missabib.</verse>
<verse>"For thus says the LORD, 'Behold, I am going to make you a terror to yourself and to all your friends; and while your eyes look on, they will fall by the sword of their enemies. So I will give over all Judah to the hand of the king of Babylon, and he will carry them away as exiles to Babylon and will slay them with the sword.</verse>
<verse>'I will also give over all the wealth of this city, all its produce and all its costly things; even all the treasures of the kings of Judah I will give over to the hand of their enemies, and they will plunder them, take them away and bring them to Babylon.</verse>
<verse>'And you, Pashhur, and all who live in your house will go into captivity; and you will enter Babylon, and there you will die and there you will be buried, you and all your friends to whom you have falsely prophesied.'"</verse>
<verse>O LORD, You have deceived me and I was deceived; You have overcome me and prevailed. I have become a laughingstock all day long; Everyone mocks me.</verse>
<verse>For each time I speak, I cry aloud; I proclaim violence and destruction, Because for me the word of the LORD has resulted In reproach and derision all day long.</verse>
<verse>But if I say, "I will not remember Him Or speak anymore in His name," Then in my heart it becomes like a burning fire Shut up in my bones; And I am weary of holding it in, And I cannot endure it.</verse>
<verse>For I have heard the whispering of many, "Terror on every side! Denounce him; yes, let us denounce him!" All my trusted friends, Watching for my fall, say: "Perhaps he will be deceived, so that we may prevail against him And take our revenge on him."</verse>
<verse>But the LORD is with me like a dread champion; Therefore my persecutors will stumble and not prevail. They will be utterly ashamed, because they have failed, With an everlasting disgrace that will not be forgotten.</verse>
<verse>Yet, O LORD of hosts, You who test the righteous, Who see the mind and the heart; Let me see Your vengeance on them; For to You I have set forth my cause.</verse>
<verse>Sing to the LORD, praise the LORD! For He has delivered the soul of the needy one From the hand of evildoers.</verse>
<verse>Cursed be the day when I was born; Let the day not be blessed when my mother bore me!</verse>
<verse>Cursed be the man who brought the news To my father, saying, "A baby boy has been born to you!" And made him very happy.</verse>
<verse>But let that man be like the cities Which the LORD overthrew without relenting, And let him hear an outcry in the morning And a shout of alarm at noon;</verse>
<verse>Because he did not kill me before birth, So that my mother would have been my grave, And her womb ever pregnant.</verse>
<verse>Why did I ever come forth from the womb To look on trouble and sorrow, So that my days have been spent in shame?</verse>
</chapter>