<?xml version="1.0"?>
<chapter translation="KJV" testament="Old" book="Proverbs" n="18" book_id="20">
      <verse>Through desire a man, having separated himself, seeketh <supplied>and</supplied> intermeddleth with all wisdom.
</verse><verse>A fool hath no delight in understanding, but that his heart may discover itself.
</verse><verse>When the wicked cometh, <supplied>then</supplied> cometh also contempt, and with ignominy reproach.
</verse><verse>The words of a man&#x2019;s mouth <supplied>are as</supplied> deep waters, <supplied>and</supplied> the wellspring of wisdom <supplied>as</supplied> a flowing brook.
</verse><verse><supplied>It is</supplied> not good to accept the person of the wicked, to overthrow the righteous in judgment.
</verse><verse>A fool&#x2019;s lips enter into contention, and his mouth calleth for strokes.
</verse><verse>A fool&#x2019;s mouth <supplied>is</supplied> his destruction, and his lips <supplied>are</supplied> the snare of his soul.
</verse><verse>The words of a talebearer <supplied>are</supplied> as wounds, and they go down into the innermost parts of the belly.
</verse><verse>He also that is slothful in his work is brother to him that is a great waster.
</verse><verse>The name of the LORD <supplied>is</supplied> a strong tower: the righteous runneth into it, and is safe.
</verse><verse>The rich man&#x2019;s wealth <supplied>is</supplied> his strong city, and as an high wall in his own conceit.
</verse><verse>Before destruction the heart of man is haughty, and before honour <supplied>is</supplied> humility.
</verse><verse>He that answereth a matter before he heareth <supplied>it,</supplied> it <supplied>is</supplied> folly and shame unto him.
</verse><verse>The spirit of a man will sustain his infirmity; but a wounded spirit who can bear?
</verse><verse>The heart of the prudent getteth knowledge; and the ear of the wise seeketh knowledge.
</verse><verse>A man&#x2019;s gift maketh room for him, and bringeth him before great men.
</verse><verse><supplied>He that is</supplied> first in his own cause <supplied>seemeth</supplied> just; but his neighbour cometh and searcheth him.
</verse><verse>The lot causeth contentions to cease, and parteth between the mighty.
</verse><verse>A brother offended <supplied>is harder to be won</supplied> than a strong city: and <supplied>their</supplied> contentions <supplied>are</supplied> like the bars of a castle.
</verse><verse>A man&#x2019;s belly shall be satisfied with the fruit of his mouth; <supplied>and</supplied> with the increase of his lips shall he be filled.
</verse><verse>Death and life <supplied>are</supplied> in the power of the tongue: and they that love it shall eat the fruit thereof.
</verse><verse><supplied>Whoso</supplied> findeth a wife findeth a good <supplied>thing,</supplied> and obtaineth favour of the LORD.
</verse><verse>The poor useth intreaties; but the rich answereth roughly.
</verse><verse>A man <supplied>that hath</supplied> friends must shew himself friendly: and there is a friend <supplied>that</supplied> sticketh closer than a brother.
     
      </verse>
      </chapter>
