<?xml version="1.0"?>
<chapter translation="KJV" testament="Old" book="Proverbs" n="4" book_id="20">
      <verse>Hear, ye children, the instruction of a father, and attend to know understanding.
</verse><verse>For I give you good doctrine, forsake ye not my law.
</verse><verse>For I was my father&#x2019;s son, tender and only <supplied>beloved</supplied> in the sight of my mother.
</verse><verse>He taught me also, and said unto me, Let thine heart retain my words: keep my commandments, and live.
</verse><verse>Get wisdom, get understanding: forget <supplied>it</supplied> not; neither decline from the words of my mouth.
</verse><verse>Forsake her not, and she shall preserve thee: love her, and she shall keep thee.
</verse><verse>Wisdom <supplied>is</supplied> the principal thing; <supplied>therefore</supplied> get wisdom: and with all thy getting get understanding.
</verse><verse>Exalt her, and she shall promote thee: she shall bring thee to honour, when thou dost embrace her.
</verse><verse>She shall give to thine head an ornament of grace: a crown of glory shall she deliver to thee.
</verse><verse>Hear, O my son, and receive my sayings; and the years of thy life shall be many.
</verse><verse>I have taught thee in the way of wisdom; I have led thee in right paths.
</verse><verse>When thou goest, thy steps shall not be straitened; and when thou runnest, thou shalt not stumble.
</verse><verse>Take fast hold of instruction; let <supplied>her</supplied> not go: keep her; for she <supplied>is</supplied> thy life.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>Enter not into the path of the wicked, and go not in the way of evil <supplied>men. </supplied></verse><verse>Avoid it, pass not by it, turn from it, and pass away.
</verse><verse>For they sleep not, except they have done mischief; and their sleep is taken away, unless they cause <supplied>some</supplied> to fall.
</verse><verse>For they eat the bread of wickedness, and drink the wine of violence.
</verse><verse>But the path of the just <supplied>is</supplied> as the shining light, that shineth more and more unto the perfect day.
</verse><verse>The way of the wicked <supplied>is</supplied> as darkness: they know not at what they stumble.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>My son, attend to my words; incline thine ear unto my sayings.
</verse><verse>Let them not depart from thine eyes; keep them in the midst of thine heart.
</verse><verse>For they <supplied>are</supplied> life unto those that find them, and health to all their flesh.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>Keep thy heart with all diligence; for out of it <supplied>are</supplied> the issues of life.
</verse><verse>Put away from thee a froward mouth, and perverse lips put far from thee.
</verse><verse>Let thine eyes look right on, and let thine eyelids look straight before thee.
</verse><verse>Ponder the path of thy feet, and let all thy ways be established.
</verse><verse>Turn not to the right hand nor to the left: remove thy foot from evil.
     
      </verse>
      </chapter>
