<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Daniel" book-id="27" n="12">
<verse>That's when Michael, the great angel-prince, champion of your people, will step in. It will be a time of trouble, the worst trouble the world has ever seen. But your people will be saved from the trouble, every last one found written in the Book.</verse>
<verse>Many who have been long dead and buried will wake up, some to eternal life, others to eternal shame.</verse>
<verse>Men and women who have lived wisely and well will shine brilliantly, like the cloudless, star-strewn night skies. And those who put others on the right path to life will glow like stars forever.</verse>
<verse>This is a confidential report, Daniel, for your eyes and ears only. Keep it secret. Put the book under lock and key until the end. In the interim there is going to be a lot of frantic running around, trying to figure out what's going on.' [JC]</verse>
<verse>"As I, Daniel, took all this in, two figures appeared, one standing on this bank of the river and one on the other bank.</verse>
<verse>One of them asked a third man who was dressed in linen and who straddled the river, "How long is this astonishing story to go on?'</verse>
<verse>"The man dressed in linen, who straddled the river, raised both hands to the skies. I heard him solemnly swear by the Eternal One that it would be a time, two times, and half a time, that when the oppressor of the holy people was brought down the story would be complete.</verse>
<verse>"I heard all this plainly enough, but I didn't understand it. So I asked, "Master, can you explain this to me?'</verse>
<verse>Go on about your business, Daniel,' he said. "The message is confidential and under lock and key until the end, until things are about to be wrapped up.</verse>
<verse>The populace will be washed clean and made like new. But the wicked will just keep on being wicked, without a clue about what is happening. Those who live wisely and well will understand what's going on.' [JC]</verse>
<verse>"From the time that the daily worship is banished from the Temple and the obscene desecration is set up in its place, there will be 1,290 days.</verse>
<verse>"Blessed are those who patiently make it through the 1,335 days.</verse>
<verse>"And you? Go about your business without fretting or worrying. Relax. When it's all over, you will be on your feet to receive your reward."</verse>
</chapter>