<chapter translation="MSG" testament="New" book="Hebrews" book-id="58" n="2">
<verse>It's crucial that we keep a firm grip on what we've heard so that we don't drift off.</verse>
<verse>If the old message delivered by the angels was valid and nobody got away with anything,</verse>
<verse>do you think we can risk neglecting this latest message, this magnificent salvation? First of all, it was delivered in person by the Master, then accurately passed on to us by those who heard it from him.</verse>
<verse>All the while God was validating it with gifts through the Holy Spirit, all sorts of signs and miracles, as he saw fit.</verse>
<verse>God didn't put angels in charge of this business of salvation that we're dealing with here.</verse>
<verse>It says in Scripture, What is man and woman that you bother with them; why take a second look their way?</verse>
<verse>You made them not quite as high as angels, bright with Eden's dawn light;</verse>
<verse>Then you put them in charge of your entire handcrafted world. When God put them in charge of everything, nothing was excluded. But we don't see it yet, don't see everything under human jurisdiction.</verse>
<verse>What we do see is Jesus, made "not quite as high as angels," and then, through the experience of death, crowned so much higher than any angel, with a glory "bright with Eden's dawn light." In that death, by God's grace, he fully experienced death in every person's place.</verse>
<verse>It makes good sense that the God who got everything started and keeps everything going now completes the work by making the Salvation Pioneer perfect through suffering as he leads all these people to glory.</verse>
<verse>Since the One who saves and those who are saved have a common origin, Jesus doesn't hesitate to treat them as family,</verse>
<verse>saying, I'll tell my good friends, my brothers and sisters, all I know	about you; I'll join them in worship and praise to you.</verse>
<verse>Again, he puts himself in the same family circle when he says, Even I live by placing my trust in God. And yet again, I'm here with the children God gave me.</verse>
<verse>Since the children are made of flesh and blood, it's logical that the Savior took on flesh and blood in order to rescue them by his death. By embracing death, taking it into himself, he destroyed the Devil's hold on death</verse>
<verse>and freed all who cower through life, scared to death of death.</verse>
<verse>It's obvious, of course, that he didn't go to all this trouble for angels. It was for people like us, children of Abraham.</verse>
<verse>That's why he had to enter into every detail of human life. Then, when he came before God as high priest to get rid of the people's sins,</verse>
<verse>he would have already experienced it all himself--all the pain, all the testing--and would be able to help where help was needed.</verse>
</chapter>