<chapter translation="MSG" testament="New" book="Hebrews" book-id="58" n="3">
<verse>So, my dear Christian friends, companions in following this call to the heights, take a good hard look at Jesus. He's the centerpiece of everything we believe,</verse>
<verse>faithful in everything God gave him to do. Moses was also faithful,</verse>
<verse>but Jesus gets far more honor. A builder is more valuable than a building any day.</verse>
<verse>Every house has a builder, but the Builder behind them all is God.</verse>
<verse>Moses did a good job in God's house, but it was all servant work, getting things ready for what was to come.</verse>
<verse>Christ as Son is in charge of the house. Now, if we can only keep a firm grip on this bold confidence, we're the house!</verse>
<verse>That's why the Holy Spirit says, Today, please listen;</verse>
<verse>don't turn a deaf ear as in "the bitter uprising," that time of wilderness testing!</verse>
<verse>Even though they watched me at work for forty years, your ancestors refused to let me do it my way; over and over they tried my patience.</verse>
<verse>And I was provoked, oh, so provoked! I said, "They'll never keep their minds on God; they refuse to walk down my road."</verse>
<verse>Exasperated, I vowed, "They'll never get where they're going, never be able to sit down and rest."</verse>
<verse>So watch your step, friends. Make sure there's no evil unbelief lying around that will trip you up and throw you off course, diverting you from the living God.</verse>
<verse>For as long as it's still God's Today, keep each other on your toes so sin doesn't slow down your reflexes.</verse>
<verse>If we can only keep our grip on the sure thing we started out with, we're in this with Christ for the long haul.</verse>
<verse>These words keep ringing in our ears: Today, please listen; don't turn a deaf ear as in the bitter uprising.</verse>
<verse>For who were the people who turned a deaf ear? Weren't they the very ones Moses led out of Egypt?</verse>
<verse>And who was God provoked with for forty years? Wasn't it those who turned a deaf ear and ended up corpses in the wilderness?</verse>
<verse>And when he swore that they'd never get where they were going, wasn't he talking to the ones who turned a deaf ear?</verse>
<verse>They never got there because they never listened, never believed.</verse>
</chapter>