<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Genesis" book_id="1" n="15">
<verse>After this, the word of the LORD came to Abram in a vision: "Do not be afraid, Abram. I am your shield, your very great reward. "</verse>
<verse>But Abram said, "O Sovereign LORD, what can you give me since I remain childless and the one who will inherit my estate is Eliezer of Damascus?"</verse>
<verse>And Abram said, "You have given me no children; so a servant in my household will be my heir."</verse>
<verse>Then the word of the LORD came to him: "This man will not be your heir, but a son coming from your own body will be your heir."</verse>
<verse>He took him outside and said, "Look up at the heavens and count the stars-if indeed you can count them." Then he said to him, "So shall your offspring be."</verse>
<verse>Abram believed the LORD, and he credited it to him as righteousness.</verse>
<verse>He also said to him, "I am the LORD, who brought you out of Ur of the Chaldeans to give you this land to take possession of it."</verse>
<verse>But Abram said, "O Sovereign LORD, how can I know that I will gain possession of it?"</verse>
<verse>So the LORD said to him, "Bring me a heifer, a goat and a ram, each three years old, along with a dove and a young pigeon."</verse>
<verse>Abram brought all these to him, cut them in two and arranged the halves opposite each other; the birds, however, he did not cut in half.</verse>
<verse>Then birds of prey came down on the carcasses, but Abram drove them away.</verse>
<verse>As the sun was setting, Abram fell into a deep sleep, and a thick and dreadful darkness came over him.</verse>
<verse>Then the LORD said to him, "Know for certain that your descendants will be strangers in a country not their own, and they will be enslaved and mistreated four hundred years.</verse>
<verse>But I will punish the nation they serve as slaves, and afterward they will come out with great possessions.</verse>
<verse>You, however, will go to your fathers in peace and be buried at a good old age.</verse>
<verse>In the fourth generation your descendants will come back here, for the sin of the Amorites has not yet reached its full measure."</verse>
<verse>When the sun had set and darkness had fallen, a smoking firepot with a blazing torch appeared and passed between the pieces.</verse>
<verse>On that day the LORD made a covenant with Abram and said, "To your descendants I give this land, from the river of Egypt to the great river, the Euphrates-</verse>
<verse>the land of the Kenites, Kenizzites, Kadmonites,</verse>
<verse>Hittites, Perizzites, Rephaites,</verse>
<verse>Amorites, Canaanites, Girgashites and Jebusites."</verse>
</chapter>