<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Genesis" book-id="1" n="20">
<verse>Now Abraham moved on from there into the region of the Negev and lived between Kadesh and Shur. For a while he stayed in Gerar,</verse>
<verse>and there Abraham said of his wife Sarah, "She is my sister." Then Abimelech king of Gerar sent for Sarah and took her.</verse>
<verse>But God came to Abimelech in a dream one night and said to him, "You are as good as dead because of the woman you have taken; she is a married woman."</verse>
<verse>Now Abimelech had not gone near her, so he said, "Lord, will you destroy an innocent nation?</verse>
<verse>Did he not say to me, 'She is my sister,' and didn't she also say, 'He is my brother'? I have done this with a clear conscience and clean hands."</verse>
<verse>Then God said to him in the dream, "Yes, I know you did this with a clear conscience, and so I have kept you from sinning against me. That is why I did not let you touch her.</verse>
<verse>Now return the man's wife, for he is a prophet, and he will pray for you and you will live. But if you do not return her, you may be sure that you and all yours will die."</verse>
<verse>Early the next morning Abimelech summoned all his officials, and when he told them all that had happened, they were very much afraid.</verse>
<verse>Then Abimelech called Abraham in and said, "What have you done to us? How have I wronged you that you have brought such great guilt upon me and my kingdom? You have done things to me that should not be done."</verse>
<verse>And Abimelech asked Abraham, "What was your reason for doing this?"</verse>
<verse>Abraham replied, "I said to myself, 'There is surely no fear of God in this place, and they will kill me because of my wife.'</verse>
<verse>Besides, she really is my sister, the daughter of my father though not of my mother; and she became my wife.</verse>
<verse>And when God had me wander from my father's household, I said to her, 'This is how you can show your love to me: Everywhere we go, say of me, "He is my brother."'"</verse>
<verse>Then Abimelech brought sheep and cattle and male and female slaves and gave them to Abraham, and he returned Sarah his wife to him.</verse>
<verse>And Abimelech said, "My land is before you; live wherever you like."</verse>
<verse>To Sarah he said, "I am giving your brother a thousand shekels of silver. This is to cover the offense against you before all who are with you; you are completely vindicated."</verse>
<verse>Then Abraham prayed to God, and God healed Abimelech, his wife and his slave girls so they could have children again,</verse>
<verse>for the LORD had closed up every womb in Abimelech's household because of Abraham's wife Sarah.</verse>
</chapter>