<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Genesis" book_id="1" n="25">
<verse>Abraham took another wife, whose name was Keturah.</verse>
<verse>She bore him Zimran, Jokshan, Medan, Midian, Ishbak and Shuah.</verse>
<verse>Jokshan was the father of Sheba and Dedan; the descendants of Dedan were the Asshurites, the Letushites and the Leummites.</verse>
<verse>The sons of Midian were Ephah, Epher, Hanoch, Abida and Eldaah. All these were descendants of Keturah.</verse>
<verse>Abraham left everything he owned to Isaac.</verse>
<verse>But while he was still living, he gave gifts to the sons of his concubines and sent them away from his son Isaac to the land of the east.</verse>
<verse>Altogether, Abraham lived a hundred and seventy-five years.</verse>
<verse>Then Abraham breathed his last and died at a good old age, an old man and full of years; and he was gathered to his people.</verse>
<verse>His sons Isaac and Ishmael buried him in the cave of Machpelah near Mamre, in the field of Ephron son of Zohar the Hittite,</verse>
<verse>the field Abraham had bought from the Hittites. There Abraham was buried with his wife Sarah.</verse>
<verse>After Abraham's death, God blessed his son Isaac, who then lived near Beer Lahai Roi.</verse>
<verse>This is the account of Abraham's son Ishmael, whom Sarah's maidservant, Hagar the Egyptian, bore to Abraham.</verse>
<verse>These are the names of the sons of Ishmael, listed in the order of their birth: Nebaioth the firstborn of Ishmael, Kedar, Adbeel, Mibsam,</verse>
<verse>Mishma, Dumah, Massa,</verse>
<verse>Hadad, Tema, Jetur, Naphish and Kedemah.</verse>
<verse>These were the sons of Ishmael, and these are the names of the twelve tribal rulers according to their settlements and camps.</verse>
<verse>Altogether, Ishmael lived a hundred and thirty-seven years. He breathed his last and died, and he was gathered to his people.</verse>
<verse>His descendants settled in the area from Havilah to Shur, near the border of Egypt, as you go toward Asshur. And they lived in hostility toward all their brothers.</verse>
<verse>This is the account of Abraham's son Isaac. Abraham became the father of Isaac,</verse>
<verse>and Isaac was forty years old when he married Rebekah daughter of Bethuel the Aramean from Paddan Aram and sister of Laban the Aramean.</verse>
<verse>Isaac prayed to the LORD on behalf of his wife, because she was barren. The LORD answered his prayer, and his wife Rebekah became pregnant.</verse>
<verse>The babies jostled each other within her, and she said, "Why is this happening to me?" So she went to inquire of the LORD.</verse>
<verse>The LORD said to her, "Two nations are in your womb, and two peoples from within you will be separated; one people will be stronger than the other, and the older will serve the younger."</verse>
<verse>When the time came for her to give birth, there were twin boys in her womb.</verse>
<verse>The first to come out was red, and his whole body was like a hairy garment; so they named him Esau.</verse>
<verse>After this, his brother came out, with his hand grasping Esau's heel; so he was named Jacob. Isaac was sixty years old when Rebekah gave birth to them.</verse>
<verse>The boys grew up, and Esau became a skillful hunter, a man of the open country, while Jacob was a quiet man, staying among the tents.</verse>
<verse>Isaac, who had a taste for wild game, loved Esau, but Rebekah loved Jacob.</verse>
<verse>Once when Jacob was cooking some stew, Esau came in from the open country, famished.</verse>
<verse>He said to Jacob, "Quick, let me have some of that red stew! I'm famished!" (That is why he was also called Edom. )</verse>
<verse>Jacob replied, "First sell me your birthright."</verse>
<verse>"Look, I am about to die," Esau said. "What good is the birthright to me?"</verse>
<verse>But Jacob said, "Swear to me first." So he swore an oath to him, selling his birthright to Jacob.</verse>
<verse>Then Jacob gave Esau some bread and some lentil stew. He ate and drank, and then got up and left. So Esau despised his birthright.</verse>
</chapter>