<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Genesis" book_id="1" n="6">
<verse>When men began to increase in number on the earth and daughters were born to them,</verse>
<verse>the sons of God saw that the daughters of men were beautiful, and they married any of them they chose.</verse>
<verse>Then the LORD said, "My Spirit will not contend with man forever, for he is mortal; his days will be a hundred and twenty years."</verse>
<verse>The Nephilim were on the earth in those days-and also afterward-when the sons of God went to the daughters of men and had children by them. They were the heroes of old, men of renown.</verse>
<verse>The LORD saw how great man's wickedness on the earth had become, and that every inclination of the thoughts of his heart was only evil all the time.</verse>
<verse>The LORD was grieved that he had made man on the earth, and his heart was filled with pain.</verse>
<verse>So the LORD said, "I will wipe mankind, whom I have created, from the face of the earth-men and animals, and creatures that move along the ground, and birds of the air-for I am grieved that I have made them."</verse>
<verse>But Noah found favor in the eyes of the LORD.</verse>
<verse>This is the account of Noah. Noah was a righteous man, blameless among the people of his time, and he walked with God.</verse>
<verse>Noah had three sons: Shem, Ham and Japheth.</verse>
<verse>Now the earth was corrupt in God's sight and was full of violence.</verse>
<verse>God saw how corrupt the earth had become, for all the people on earth had corrupted their ways.</verse>
<verse>So God said to Noah, "I am going to put an end to all people, for the earth is filled with violence because of them. I am surely going to destroy both them and the earth.</verse>
<verse>So make yourself an ark of cypress wood; make rooms in it and coat it with pitch inside and out.</verse>
<verse>This is how you are to build it: The ark is to be 450 feet long, 75 feet wide and 45 feet high.</verse>
<verse>Make a roof for it and finish the ark to within 18 inches of the top. Put a door in the side of the ark and make lower, middle and upper decks.</verse>
<verse>I am going to bring floodwaters on the earth to destroy all life under the heavens, every creature that has the breath of life in it. Everything on earth will perish.</verse>
<verse>But I will establish my covenant with you, and you will enter the ark-you and your sons and your wife and your sons' wives with you.</verse>
<verse>You are to bring into the ark two of all living creatures, male and female, to keep them alive with you.</verse>
<verse>Two of every kind of bird, of every kind of animal and of every kind of creature that moves along the ground will come to you to be kept alive.</verse>
<verse>You are to take every kind of food that is to be eaten and store it away as food for you and for them."</verse>
<verse>Noah did everything just as God commanded him.</verse>
</chapter>