<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Micah" book-id="33" n="2">
<verse>Woe to those who scheme iniquity, Who work out evil on their beds! When morning comes, they do it, For it is in the power of their hands.</verse>
<verse>They covet fields and then seize them, And houses, and take them away. They rob a man and his house, A man and his inheritance.</verse>
<verse>Therefore thus says the LORD, "Behold, I am planning against this family a calamity From which you cannot remove your necks; And you will not walk haughtily, For it will be an evil time.</verse>
<verse>"On that day they will take up against you a taunt And utter a bitter lamentation and say, 'We are completely destroyed! He exchanges the portion of my people; How He removes it from me! To the apostate He apportions our fields.'</verse>
<verse>"Therefore you will have no one stretching a measuring line For you by lot in the assembly of the LORD.</verse>
<verse>'Do not speak out,' so they speak out. But if they do not speak out concerning these things, Reproaches will not be turned back.</verse>
<verse>"Is it being said, O house of Jacob: 'Is the Spirit of the LORD impatient? Are these His doings?' Do not My words do good To the one walking uprightly?</verse>
<verse>"Recently My people have arisen as an enemy--You strip the robe off the garment From unsuspecting passers-by, From those returned from war.</verse>
<verse>"The women of My people you evict, Each one from her pleasant house. From her children you take My splendor forever.</verse>
<verse>"Arise and go, For this is no place of rest Because of the uncleanness that brings on destruction, A painful destruction.</verse>
<verse>"If a man walking after wind and falsehood Had told lies and said, 'I will speak out to you concerning wine and liquor,' He would be spokesman to this people.</verse>
<verse>"I will surely assemble all of you, Jacob, I will surely gather the remnant of Israel. I will put them together like sheep in the fold; Like a flock in the midst of its pasture They will be noisy with men.</verse>
<verse>"The breaker goes up before them; They break out, pass through the gate and go out by it. So their king goes on before them, And the LORD at their head."</verse>
</chapter>