<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Psalms" book_id="19" n="10">
<verse>Why, O LORD, do you stand far off? Why do you hide yourself in times of trouble?</verse>
<verse>In his arrogance the wicked man hunts down the weak, who are caught in the schemes he devises.</verse>
<verse>He boasts of the cravings of his heart; he blesses the greedy and reviles the LORD.</verse>
<verse>In his pride the wicked does not seek him; in all his thoughts there is no room for God.</verse>
<verse>His ways are always prosperous; he is haughty and your laws are far from him; he sneers at all his enemies.</verse>
<verse>He says to himself, "Nothing will shake me; I'll always be happy and never have trouble."</verse>
<verse>His mouth is full of curses and lies and threats; trouble and evil are under his tongue.</verse>
<verse>He lies in wait near the villages; from ambush he murders the innocent, watching in secret for his victims.</verse>
<verse>He lies in wait like a lion in cover; he lies in wait to catch the helpless; he catches the helpless and drags them off in his net.</verse>
<verse>His victims are crushed, they collapse; they fall under his strength.</verse>
<verse>He says to himself, "God has forgotten; he covers his face and never sees."</verse>
<verse>Arise, LORD! Lift up your hand, O God. Do not forget the helpless.</verse>
<verse>Why does the wicked man revile God? Why does he say to himself, "He won't call me to account"?</verse>
<verse>But you, O God, do see trouble and grief; you consider it to take it in hand. The victim commits himself to you; you are the helper of the fatherless.</verse>
<verse>Break the arm of the wicked and evil man; call him to account for his wickedness that would not be found out.</verse>
<verse>The LORD is King for ever and ever; the nations will perish from his land.</verse>
<verse>You hear, O LORD, the desire of the afflicted; you encourage them, and you listen to their cry,</verse>
<verse>defending the fatherless and the oppressed, in order that man, who is of the earth, may terrify no more.</verse>
</chapter>