<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Psalms" book_id="19" n="102">
<verse>Hear my prayer, O LORD; let my cry for help come to you.</verse>
<verse>Do not hide your face from me when I am in distress. Turn your ear to me; when I call, answer me quickly.</verse>
<verse>For my days vanish like smoke; my bones burn like glowing embers.</verse>
<verse>My heart is blighted and withered like grass; I forget to eat my food.</verse>
<verse>Because of my loud groaning I am reduced to skin and bones.</verse>
<verse>I am like a desert owl, like an owl among the ruins.</verse>
<verse>I lie awake; I have become like a bird alone on a roof.</verse>
<verse>All day long my enemies taunt me; those who rail against me use my name as a curse.</verse>
<verse>For I eat ashes as my food and mingle my drink with tears</verse>
<verse>because of your great wrath, for you have taken me up and thrown me aside.</verse>
<verse>My days are like the evening shadow; I wither away like grass.</verse>
<verse>But you, O LORD, sit enthroned forever; your renown endures through all generations.</verse>
<verse>You will arise and have compassion on Zion, for it is time to show favor to her; the appointed time has come.</verse>
<verse>For her stones are dear to your servants; her very dust moves them to pity.</verse>
<verse>The nations will fear the name of the LORD, all the kings of the earth will revere your glory.</verse>
<verse>For the LORD will rebuild Zion and appear in his glory.</verse>
<verse>He will respond to the prayer of the destitute; he will not despise their plea.</verse>
<verse>Let this be written for a future generation, that a people not yet created may praise the LORD:</verse>
<verse>"The LORD looked down from his sanctuary on high, from heaven he viewed the earth,</verse>
<verse>to hear the groans of the prisoners and release those condemned to death."</verse>
<verse>So the name of the LORD will be declared in Zion and his praise in Jerusalem</verse>
<verse>when the peoples and the kingdoms assemble to worship the LORD.</verse>
<verse>In the course of my life he broke my strength; he cut short my days.</verse>
<verse>So I said: "Do not take me away, O my God, in the midst of my days; your years go on through all generations.</verse>
<verse>In the beginning you laid the foundations of the earth, and the heavens are the work of your hands.</verse>
<verse>They will perish, but you remain; they will all wear out like a garment. Like clothing you will change them and they will be discarded.</verse>
<verse>But you remain the same, and your years will never end.</verse>
<verse>The children of your servants will live in your presence; their descendants will be established before you."</verse>
</chapter>