<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Psalms" book-id="19" n="104">
<verse>Praise the LORD, O my soul. O LORD my God, you are very great; you are clothed with splendor and majesty.</verse>
<verse>He wraps himself in light as with a garment; he stretches out the heavens like a tent</verse>
<verse>and lays the beams of his upper chambers on their waters. He makes the clouds his chariot and rides on the wings of the wind.</verse>
<verse>He makes winds his messengers, flames of fire his servants.</verse>
<verse>He set the earth on its foundations; it can never be moved.</verse>
<verse>You covered it with the deep as with a garment; the waters stood above the mountains.</verse>
<verse>But at your rebuke the waters fled, at the sound of your thunder they took to flight;</verse>
<verse>they flowed over the mountains, they went down into the valleys, to the place you assigned for them.</verse>
<verse>You set a boundary they cannot cross; never again will they cover the earth.</verse>
<verse>He makes springs pour water into the ravines; it flows between the mountains.</verse>
<verse>They give water to all the beasts of the field; the wild donkeys quench their thirst.</verse>
<verse>The birds of the air nest by the waters; they sing among the branches.</verse>
<verse>He waters the mountains from his upper chambers; the earth is satisfied by the fruit of his work.</verse>
<verse>He makes grass grow for the cattle, and plants for man to cultivate- bringing forth food from the earth:</verse>
<verse>wine that gladdens the heart of man, oil to make his face shine, and bread that sustains his heart.</verse>
<verse>The trees of the LORD are well watered, the cedars of Lebanon that he planted.</verse>
<verse>There the birds make their nests; the stork has its home in the pine trees.</verse>
<verse>The high mountains belong to the wild goats; the crags are a refuge for the coneys.</verse>
<verse>The moon marks off the seasons, and the sun knows when to go down.</verse>
<verse>You bring darkness, it becomes night, and all the beasts of the forest prowl.</verse>
<verse>The lions roar for their prey and seek their food from God.</verse>
<verse>The sun rises, and they steal away; they return and lie down in their dens.</verse>
<verse>Then man goes out to his work, to his labor until evening.</verse>
<verse>How many are your works, O LORD! In wisdom you made them all; the earth is full of your creatures.</verse>
<verse>There is the sea, vast and spacious, teeming with creatures beyond number- living things both large and small.</verse>
<verse>There the ships go to and fro, and the leviathan, which you formed to frolic there.</verse>
<verse>These all look to you to give them their food at the proper time.</verse>
<verse>When you give it to them, they gather it up; when you open your hand, they are satisfied with good things.</verse>
<verse>When you hide your face, they are terrified; when you take away their breath, they die and return to the dust.</verse>
<verse>When you send your Spirit, they are created, and you renew the face of the earth.</verse>
<verse>May the glory of the LORD endure forever; may the LORD rejoice in his works-</verse>
<verse>he who looks at the earth, and it trembles, who touches the mountains, and they smoke.</verse>
<verse>I will sing to the LORD all my life; I will sing praise to my God as long as I live.</verse>
<verse>May my meditation be pleasing to him, as I rejoice in the LORD.</verse>
<verse>But may sinners vanish from the earth and the wicked be no more. Praise the LORD, O my soul. Praise the LORD.</verse>
</chapter>