<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Psalms" book-id="19" n="105">
<verse>Give thanks to the LORD, call on his name; make known among the nations what he has done.</verse>
<verse>Sing to him, sing praise to him; tell of all his wonderful acts.</verse>
<verse>Glory in his holy name; let the hearts of those who seek the LORD rejoice.</verse>
<verse>Look to the LORD and his strength; seek his face always.</verse>
<verse>Remember the wonders he has done, his miracles, and the judgments he pronounced,</verse>
<verse>O descendants of Abraham his servant, O sons of Jacob, his chosen ones.</verse>
<verse>He is the LORD our God; his judgments are in all the earth.</verse>
<verse>He remembers his covenant forever, the word he commanded, for a thousand generations,</verse>
<verse>the covenant he made with Abraham, the oath he swore to Isaac.</verse>
<verse>He confirmed it to Jacob as a decree, to Israel as an everlasting covenant:</verse>
<verse>"To you I will give the land of Canaan as the portion you will inherit."</verse>
<verse>When they were but few in number, few indeed, and strangers in it,</verse>
<verse>they wandered from nation to nation, from one kingdom to another.</verse>
<verse>He allowed no one to oppress them; for their sake he rebuked kings:</verse>
<verse>"Do not touch my anointed ones; do my prophets no harm."</verse>
<verse>He called down famine on the land and destroyed all their supplies of food;</verse>
<verse>and he sent a man before them- Joseph, sold as a slave.</verse>
<verse>They bruised his feet with shackles, his neck was put in irons,</verse>
<verse>till what he foretold came to pass, till the word of the LORD proved him true.</verse>
<verse>The king sent and released him, the ruler of peoples set him free.</verse>
<verse>He made him master of his household, ruler over all he possessed,</verse>
<verse>to instruct his princes as he pleased and teach his elders wisdom.</verse>
<verse>Then Israel entered Egypt; Jacob lived as an alien in the land of Ham.</verse>
<verse>The LORD made his people very fruitful; he made them too numerous for their foes,</verse>
<verse>whose hearts he turned to hate his people, to conspire against his servants.</verse>
<verse>He sent Moses his servant, and Aaron, whom he had chosen.</verse>
<verse>They performed his miraculous signs among them, his wonders in the land of Ham.</verse>
<verse>He sent darkness and made the land dark- for had they not rebelled against his words?</verse>
<verse>He turned their waters into blood, causing their fish to die.</verse>
<verse>Their land teemed with frogs, which went up into the bedrooms of their rulers.</verse>
<verse>He spoke, and there came swarms of flies, and gnats throughout their country.</verse>
<verse>He turned their rain into hail, with lightning throughout their land;</verse>
<verse>he struck down their vines and fig trees and shattered the trees of their country.</verse>
<verse>He spoke, and the locusts came, grasshoppers without number;</verse>
<verse>they ate up every green thing in their land, ate up the produce of their soil.</verse>
<verse>Then he struck down all the firstborn in their land, the firstfruits of all their manhood.</verse>
<verse>He brought out Israel, laden with silver and gold, and from among their tribes no one faltered.</verse>
<verse>Egypt was glad when they left, because dread of Israel had fallen on them.</verse>
<verse>He spread out a cloud as a covering, and a fire to give light at night.</verse>
<verse>They asked, and he brought them quail and satisfied them with the bread of heaven.</verse>
<verse>He opened the rock, and water gushed out; like a river it flowed in the desert.</verse>
<verse>For he remembered his holy promise given to his servant Abraham.</verse>
<verse>He brought out his people with rejoicing, his chosen ones with shouts of joy;</verse>
<verse>he gave them the lands of the nations, and they fell heir to what others had toiled for-</verse>
<verse>that they might keep his precepts and observe his laws. Praise the LORD.</verse>
</chapter>