<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Psalms" book-id="19" n="106">
<verse>Praise the LORD. Give thanks to the LORD, for he is good; his love endures forever.</verse>
<verse>Who can proclaim the mighty acts of the LORD or fully declare his praise?</verse>
<verse>Blessed are they who maintain justice, who constantly do what is right.</verse>
<verse>Remember me, O LORD, when you show favor to your people, come to my aid when you save them,</verse>
<verse>that I may enjoy the prosperity of your chosen ones, that I may share in the joy of your nation and join your inheritance in giving praise.</verse>
<verse>We have sinned, even as our fathers did; we have done wrong and acted wickedly.</verse>
<verse>When our fathers were in Egypt, they gave no thought to your miracles; they did not remember your many kindnesses, and they rebelled by the sea, the Red Sea.</verse>
<verse>Yet he saved them for his name's sake, to make his mighty power known.</verse>
<verse>He rebuked the Red Sea, and it dried up; he led them through the depths as through a desert.</verse>
<verse>He saved them from the hand of the foe; from the hand of the enemy he redeemed them.</verse>
<verse>The waters covered their adversaries; not one of them survived.</verse>
<verse>Then they believed his promises and sang his praise.</verse>
<verse>But they soon forgot what he had done and did not wait for his counsel.</verse>
<verse>In the desert they gave in to their craving; in the wasteland they put God to the test.</verse>
<verse>So he gave them what they asked for, but sent a wasting disease upon them.</verse>
<verse>In the camp they grew envious of Moses and of Aaron, who was consecrated to the LORD.</verse>
<verse>The earth opened up and swallowed Dathan; it buried the company of Abiram.</verse>
<verse>Fire blazed among their followers; a flame consumed the wicked.</verse>
<verse>At Horeb they made a calf and worshiped an idol cast from metal.</verse>
<verse>They exchanged their Glory for an image of a bull, which eats grass.</verse>
<verse>They forgot the God who saved them, who had done great things in Egypt,</verse>
<verse>miracles in the land of Ham and awesome deeds by the Red Sea.</verse>
<verse>So he said he would destroy them- had not Moses, his chosen one, stood in the breach before him to keep his wrath from destroying them.</verse>
<verse>Then they despised the pleasant land; they did not believe his promise.</verse>
<verse>They grumbled in their tents and did not obey the LORD.</verse>
<verse>So he swore to them with uplifted hand that he would make them fall in the desert,</verse>
<verse>make their descendants fall among the nations and scatter them throughout the lands.</verse>
<verse>They yoked themselves to the Baal of Peor and ate sacrifices offered to lifeless gods;</verse>
<verse>they provoked the LORD to anger by their wicked deeds, and a plague broke out among them.</verse>
<verse>But Phinehas stood up and intervened, and the plague was checked.</verse>
<verse>This was credited to him as righteousness for endless generations to come.</verse>
<verse>By the waters of Meribah they angered the LORD, and trouble came to Moses because of them;</verse>
<verse>for they rebelled against the Spirit of God, and rash words came from Moses' lips.</verse>
<verse>They did not destroy the peoples as the LORD had commanded them,</verse>
<verse>but they mingled with the nations and adopted their customs.</verse>
<verse>They worshiped their idols, which became a snare to them.</verse>
<verse>They sacrificed their sons and their daughters to demons.</verse>
<verse>They shed innocent blood, the blood of their sons and daughters, whom they sacrificed to the idols of Canaan, and the land was desecrated by their blood.</verse>
<verse>They defiled themselves by what they did; by their deeds they prostituted themselves.</verse>
<verse>Therefore the LORD was angry with his people and abhorred his inheritance.</verse>
<verse>He handed them over to the nations, and their foes ruled over them.</verse>
<verse>Their enemies oppressed them and subjected them to their power.</verse>
<verse>Many times he delivered them, but they were bent on rebellion and they wasted away in their sin.</verse>
<verse>But he took note of their distress when he heard their cry;</verse>
<verse>for their sake he remembered his covenant and out of his great love he relented.</verse>
<verse>He caused them to be pitied by all who held them captive.</verse>
<verse>Save us, O LORD our God, and gather us from the nations, that we may give thanks to your holy name and glory in your praise.</verse>
<verse>Praise be to the LORD, the God of Israel, from everlasting to everlasting. Let all the people say, "Amen!" Praise the LORD.</verse>
</chapter>