<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Psalms" book-id="19" n="107">
<verse>Give thanks to the LORD, for he is good; his love endures forever.</verse>
<verse>Let the redeemed of the LORD say this- those he redeemed from the hand of the foe,</verse>
<verse>those he gathered from the lands, from east and west, from north and south.</verse>
<verse>Some wandered in desert wastelands, finding no way to a city where they could settle.</verse>
<verse>They were hungry and thirsty, and their lives ebbed away.</verse>
<verse>Then they cried out to the LORD in their trouble, and he delivered them from their distress.</verse>
<verse>He led them by a straight way to a city where they could settle.</verse>
<verse>Let them give thanks to the LORD for his unfailing love and his wonderful deeds for men,</verse>
<verse>for he satisfies the thirsty and fills the hungry with good things.</verse>
<verse>Some sat in darkness and the deepest gloom, prisoners suffering in iron chains,</verse>
<verse>for they had rebelled against the words of God and despised the counsel of the Most High.</verse>
<verse>So he subjected them to bitter labor; they stumbled, and there was no one to help.</verse>
<verse>Then they cried to the LORD in their trouble, and he saved them from their distress.</verse>
<verse>He brought them out of darkness and the deepest gloom and broke away their chains.</verse>
<verse>Let them give thanks to the LORD for his unfailing love and his wonderful deeds for men,</verse>
<verse>for he breaks down gates of bronze and cuts through bars of iron.</verse>
<verse>Some became fools through their rebellious ways and suffered affliction because of their iniquities.</verse>
<verse>They loathed all food and drew near the gates of death.</verse>
<verse>Then they cried to the LORD in their trouble, and he saved them from their distress.</verse>
<verse>He sent forth his word and healed them; he rescued them from the grave.</verse>
<verse>Let them give thanks to the LORD for his unfailing love and his wonderful deeds for men.</verse>
<verse>Let them sacrifice thank offerings and tell of his works with songs of joy.</verse>
<verse>Others went out on the sea in ships; they were merchants on the mighty waters.</verse>
<verse>They saw the works of the LORD, his wonderful deeds in the deep.</verse>
<verse>For he spoke and stirred up a tempest that lifted high the waves.</verse>
<verse>They mounted up to the heavens and went down to the depths; in their peril their courage melted away.</verse>
<verse>They reeled and staggered like drunken men; they were at their wits' end.</verse>
<verse>Then they cried out to the LORD in their trouble, and he brought them out of their distress.</verse>
<verse>He stilled the storm to a whisper; the waves of the sea were hushed.</verse>
<verse>They were glad when it grew calm, and he guided them to their desired haven.</verse>
<verse>Let them give thanks to the LORD for his unfailing love and his wonderful deeds for men.</verse>
<verse>Let them exalt him in the assembly of the people and praise him in the council of the elders.</verse>
<verse>He turned rivers into a desert, flowing springs into thirsty ground,</verse>
<verse>and fruitful land into a salt waste, because of the wickedness of those who lived there.</verse>
<verse>He turned the desert into pools of water and the parched ground into flowing springs;</verse>
<verse>there he brought the hungry to live, and they founded a city where they could settle.</verse>
<verse>They sowed fields and planted vineyards that yielded a fruitful harvest;</verse>
<verse>he blessed them, and their numbers greatly increased, and he did not let their herds diminish.</verse>
<verse>Then their numbers decreased, and they were humbled by oppression, calamity and sorrow;</verse>
<verse>he who pours contempt on nobles made them wander in a trackless waste.</verse>
<verse>But he lifted the needy out of their affliction and increased their families like flocks.</verse>
<verse>The upright see and rejoice, but all the wicked shut their mouths.</verse>
<verse>Whoever is wise, let him heed these things and consider the great love of the LORD.</verse>
</chapter>