<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Psalms" book-id="19" n="119">
<verse>Blessed are they whose ways are blameless, who walk according to the law of the LORD.</verse>
<verse>Blessed are they who keep his statutes and seek him with all their heart.</verse>
<verse>They do nothing wrong; they walk in his ways.</verse>
<verse>You have laid down precepts that are to be fully obeyed.</verse>
<verse>Oh, that my ways were steadfast in obeying your decrees!</verse>
<verse>Then I would not be put to shame when I consider all your commands.</verse>
<verse>I will praise you with an upright heart as I learn your righteous laws.</verse>
<verse>I will obey your decrees; do not utterly forsake me.</verse>
<verse>How can a young man keep his way pure? By living according to your word.</verse>
<verse>I seek you with all my heart; do not let me stray from your commands.</verse>
<verse>I have hidden your word in my heart that I might not sin against you.</verse>
<verse>Praise be to you, O LORD; teach me your decrees.</verse>
<verse>With my lips I recount all the laws that come from your mouth.</verse>
<verse>I rejoice in following your statutes as one rejoices in great riches.</verse>
<verse>I meditate on your precepts and consider your ways.</verse>
<verse>I delight in your decrees; I will not neglect your word.</verse>
<verse>Do good to your servant, and I will live; I will obey your word.</verse>
<verse>Open my eyes that I may see wonderful things in your law.</verse>
<verse>I am a stranger on earth; do not hide your commands from me.</verse>
<verse>My soul is consumed with longing for your laws at all times.</verse>
<verse>You rebuke the arrogant, who are cursed and who stray from your commands.</verse>
<verse>Remove from me scorn and contempt, for I keep your statutes.</verse>
<verse>Though rulers sit together and slander me, your servant will meditate on your decrees.</verse>
<verse>Your statutes are my delight; they are my counselors.</verse>
<verse>I am laid low in the dust; preserve my life according to your word.</verse>
<verse>I recounted my ways and you answered me; teach me your decrees.</verse>
<verse>Let me understand the teaching of your precepts; then I will meditate on your wonders.</verse>
<verse>My soul is weary with sorrow; strengthen me according to your word.</verse>
<verse>Keep me from deceitful ways; be gracious to me through your law.</verse>
<verse>I have chosen the way of truth; I have set my heart on your laws.</verse>
<verse>I hold fast to your statutes, O LORD; do not let me be put to shame.</verse>
<verse>I run in the path of your commands, for you have set my heart free.</verse>
<verse>Teach me, O LORD, to follow your decrees; then I will keep them to the end.</verse>
<verse>Give me understanding, and I will keep your law and obey it with all my heart.</verse>
<verse>Direct me in the path of your commands, for there I find delight.</verse>
<verse>Turn my heart toward your statutes and not toward selfish gain.</verse>
<verse>Turn my eyes away from worthless things; preserve my life according to your word.</verse>
<verse>Fulfill your promise to your servant, so that you may be feared.</verse>
<verse>Take away the disgrace I dread, for your laws are good.</verse>
<verse>How I long for your precepts! Preserve my life in your righteousness.</verse>
<verse>May your unfailing love come to me, O LORD, your salvation according to your promise;</verse>
<verse>then I will answer the one who taunts me, for I trust in your word.</verse>
<verse>Do not snatch the word of truth from my mouth, for I have put my hope in your laws.</verse>
<verse>I will always obey your law, for ever and ever.</verse>
<verse>I will walk about in freedom, for I have sought out your precepts.</verse>
<verse>I will speak of your statutes before kings and will not be put to shame,</verse>
<verse>for I delight in your commands because I love them.</verse>
<verse>I lift up my hands to your commands, which I love, and I meditate on your decrees.</verse>
<verse>Remember your word to your servant, for you have given me hope.</verse>
<verse>My comfort in my suffering is this: Your promise preserves my life.</verse>
<verse>The arrogant mock me without restraint, but I do not turn from your law.</verse>
<verse>I remember your ancient laws, O LORD, and I find comfort in them.</verse>
<verse>Indignation grips me because of the wicked, who have forsaken your law.</verse>
<verse>Your decrees are the theme of my song wherever I lodge.</verse>
<verse>In the night I remember your name, O LORD, and I will keep your law.</verse>
<verse>This has been my practice: I obey your precepts.</verse>
<verse>You are my portion, O LORD; I have promised to obey your words.</verse>
<verse>I have sought your face with all my heart; be gracious to me according to your promise.</verse>
<verse>I have considered my ways and have turned my steps to your statutes.</verse>
<verse>I will hasten and not delay to obey your commands.</verse>
<verse>Though the wicked bind me with ropes, I will not forget your law.</verse>
<verse>At midnight I rise to give you thanks for your righteous laws.</verse>
<verse>I am a friend to all who fear you, to all who follow your precepts.</verse>
<verse>The earth is filled with your love, O LORD; teach me your decrees.</verse>
<verse>Do good to your servant according to your word, O LORD.</verse>
<verse>Teach me knowledge and good judgment, for I believe in your commands.</verse>
<verse>Before I was afflicted I went astray, but now I obey your word.</verse>
<verse>You are good, and what you do is good; teach me your decrees.</verse>
<verse>Though the arrogant have smeared me with lies, I keep your precepts with all my heart.</verse>
<verse>Their hearts are callous and unfeeling, but I delight in your law.</verse>
<verse>It was good for me to be afflicted so that I might learn your decrees.</verse>
<verse>The law from your mouth is more precious to me than thousands of pieces of silver and gold.</verse>
<verse>Your hands made me and formed me; give me understanding to learn your commands.</verse>
<verse>May those who fear you rejoice when they see me, for I have put my hope in your word.</verse>
<verse>I know, O LORD, that your laws are righteous, and in faithfulness you have afflicted me.</verse>
<verse>May your unfailing love be my comfort, according to your promise to your servant.</verse>
<verse>Let your compassion come to me that I may live, for your law is my delight.</verse>
<verse>May the arrogant be put to shame for wronging me without cause; but I will meditate on your precepts.</verse>
<verse>May those who fear you turn to me, those who understand your statutes.</verse>
<verse>May my heart be blameless toward your decrees, that I may not be put to shame.</verse>
<verse>My soul faints with longing for your salvation, but I have put my hope in your word.</verse>
<verse>My eyes fail, looking for your promise; I say, "When will you comfort me?"</verse>
<verse>Though I am like a wineskin in the smoke, I do not forget your decrees.</verse>
<verse>How long must your servant wait? When will you punish my persecutors?</verse>
<verse>The arrogant dig pitfalls for me, contrary to your law.</verse>
<verse>All your commands are trustworthy; help me, for men persecute me without cause.</verse>
<verse>They almost wiped me from the earth, but I have not forsaken your precepts.</verse>
<verse>Preserve my life according to your love, and I will obey the statutes of your mouth.</verse>
<verse>Your word, O LORD, is eternal; it stands firm in the heavens.</verse>
<verse>Your faithfulness continues through all generations; you established the earth, and it endures.</verse>
<verse>Your laws endure to this day, for all things serve you.</verse>
<verse>If your law had not been my delight, I would have perished in my affliction.</verse>
<verse>I will never forget your precepts, for by them you have preserved my life.</verse>
<verse>Save me, for I am yours; I have sought out your precepts.</verse>
<verse>The wicked are waiting to destroy me, but I will ponder your statutes.</verse>
<verse>To all perfection I see a limit; but your commands are boundless.</verse>
<verse>Oh, how I love your law! I meditate on it all day long.</verse>
<verse>Your commands make me wiser than my enemies, for they are ever with me.</verse>
<verse>I have more insight than all my teachers, for I meditate on your statutes.</verse>
<verse>I have more understanding than the elders, for I obey your precepts.</verse>
<verse>I have kept my feet from every evil path so that I might obey your word.</verse>
<verse>I have not departed from your laws, for you yourself have taught me.</verse>
<verse>How sweet are your words to my taste, sweeter than honey to my mouth!</verse>
<verse>I gain understanding from your precepts; therefore I hate every wrong path.</verse>
<verse>Your word is a lamp to my feet and a light for my path.</verse>
<verse>I have taken an oath and confirmed it, that I will follow your righteous laws.</verse>
<verse>I have suffered much; preserve my life, O LORD, according to your word.</verse>
<verse>Accept, O LORD, the willing praise of my mouth, and teach me your laws.</verse>
<verse>Though I constantly take my life in my hands, I will not forget your law.</verse>
<verse>The wicked have set a snare for me, but I have not strayed from your precepts.</verse>
<verse>Your statutes are my heritage forever; they are the joy of my heart.</verse>
<verse>My heart is set on keeping your decrees to the very end.</verse>
<verse>I hate double-minded men, but I love your law.</verse>
<verse>You are my refuge and my shield; I have put my hope in your word.</verse>
<verse>Away from me, you evildoers, that I may keep the commands of my God!</verse>
<verse>Sustain me according to your promise, and I will live; do not let my hopes be dashed.</verse>
<verse>Uphold me, and I will be delivered; I will always have regard for your decrees.</verse>
<verse>You reject all who stray from your decrees, for their deceitfulness is in vain.</verse>
<verse>All the wicked of the earth you discard like dross; therefore I love your statutes.</verse>
<verse>My flesh trembles in fear of you; I stand in awe of your laws.</verse>
<verse>I have done what is righteous and just; do not leave me to my oppressors.</verse>
<verse>Ensure your servant's well-being; let not the arrogant oppress me.</verse>
<verse>My eyes fail, looking for your salvation, looking for your righteous promise.</verse>
<verse>Deal with your servant according to your love and teach me your decrees.</verse>
<verse>I am your servant; give me discernment that I may understand your statutes.</verse>
<verse>It is time for you to act, O LORD; your law is being broken.</verse>
<verse>Because I love your commands more than gold, more than pure gold,</verse>
<verse>and because I consider all your precepts right, I hate every wrong path.</verse>
<verse>Your statutes are wonderful; therefore I obey them.</verse>
<verse>The unfolding of your words gives light; it gives understanding to the simple.</verse>
<verse>I open my mouth and pant, longing for your commands.</verse>
<verse>Turn to me and have mercy on me, as you always do to those who love your name.</verse>
<verse>Direct my footsteps according to your word; let no sin rule over me.</verse>
<verse>Redeem me from the oppression of men, that I may obey your precepts.</verse>
<verse>Make your face shine upon your servant and teach me your decrees.</verse>
<verse>Streams of tears flow from my eyes, for your law is not obeyed.</verse>
<verse>Righteous are you, O LORD, and your laws are right.</verse>
<verse>The statutes you have laid down are righteous; they are fully trustworthy.</verse>
<verse>My zeal wears me out, for my enemies ignore your words.</verse>
<verse>Your promises have been thoroughly tested, and your servant loves them.</verse>
<verse>Though I am lowly and despised, I do not forget your precepts.</verse>
<verse>Your righteousness is everlasting and your law is true.</verse>
<verse>Trouble and distress have come upon me, but your commands are my delight.</verse>
<verse>Your statutes are forever right; give me understanding that I may live.</verse>
<verse>I call with all my heart; answer me, O LORD, and I will obey your decrees.</verse>
<verse>I call out to you; save me and I will keep your statutes.</verse>
<verse>I rise before dawn and cry for help; I have put my hope in your word.</verse>
<verse>My eyes stay open through the watches of the night, that I may meditate on your promises.</verse>
<verse>Hear my voice in accordance with your love; preserve my life, O LORD, according to your laws.</verse>
<verse>Those who devise wicked schemes are near, but they are far from your law.</verse>
<verse>Yet you are near, O LORD, and all your commands are true.</verse>
<verse>Long ago I learned from your statutes that you established them to last forever.</verse>
<verse>Look upon my suffering and deliver me, for I have not forgotten your law.</verse>
<verse>Defend my cause and redeem me; preserve my life according to your promise.</verse>
<verse>Salvation is far from the wicked, for they do not seek out your decrees.</verse>
<verse>Your compassion is great, O LORD; preserve my life according to your laws.</verse>
<verse>Many are the foes who persecute me, but I have not turned from your statutes.</verse>
<verse>I look on the faithless with loathing, for they do not obey your word.</verse>
<verse>See how I love your precepts; preserve my life, O LORD, according to your love.</verse>
<verse>All your words are true; all your righteous laws are eternal.</verse>
<verse>Rulers persecute me without cause, but my heart trembles at your word.</verse>
<verse>I rejoice in your promise like one who finds great spoil.</verse>
<verse>I hate and abhor falsehood but I love your law.</verse>
<verse>Seven times a day I praise you for your righteous laws.</verse>
<verse>Great peace have they who love your law, and nothing can make them stumble.</verse>
<verse>I wait for your salvation, O LORD, and I follow your commands.</verse>
<verse>I obey your statutes, for I love them greatly.</verse>
<verse>I obey your precepts and your statutes, for all my ways are known to you.</verse>
<verse>May my cry come before you, O LORD; give me understanding according to your word.</verse>
<verse>May my supplication come before you; deliver me according to your promise.</verse>
<verse>May my lips overflow with praise, for you teach me your decrees.</verse>
<verse>May my tongue sing of your word, for all your commands are righteous.</verse>
<verse>May your hand be ready to help me, for I have chosen your precepts.</verse>
<verse>I long for your salvation, O LORD, and your law is my delight.</verse>
<verse>Let me live that I may praise you, and may your laws sustain me.</verse>
<verse>I have strayed like a lost sheep. Seek your servant, for I have not forgotten your commands.</verse>
</chapter>