<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Psalms" book_id="19" n="135">
<verse>Praise the LORD. Praise the name of the LORD; praise him, you servants of the LORD,</verse>
<verse>you who minister in the house of the LORD, in the courts of the house of our God.</verse>
<verse>Praise the LORD, for the LORD is good; sing praise to his name, for that is pleasant.</verse>
<verse>For the LORD has chosen Jacob to be his own, Israel to be his treasured possession.</verse>
<verse>I know that the LORD is great, that our Lord is greater than all gods.</verse>
<verse>The LORD does whatever pleases him, in the heavens and on the earth, in the seas and all their depths.</verse>
<verse>He makes clouds rise from the ends of the earth; he sends lightning with the rain and brings out the wind from his storehouses.</verse>
<verse>He struck down the firstborn of Egypt, the firstborn of men and animals.</verse>
<verse>He sent his signs and wonders into your midst, O Egypt, against Pharaoh and all his servants.</verse>
<verse>He struck down many nations and killed mighty kings-</verse>
<verse>Sihon king of the Amorites, Og king of Bashan and all the kings of Canaan-</verse>
<verse>and he gave their land as an inheritance, an inheritance to his people Israel.</verse>
<verse>Your name, O LORD, endures forever, your renown, O LORD, through all generations.</verse>
<verse>For the LORD will vindicate his people and have compassion on his servants.</verse>
<verse>The idols of the nations are silver and gold, made by the hands of men.</verse>
<verse>They have mouths, but cannot speak, eyes, but they cannot see;</verse>
<verse>they have ears, but cannot hear, nor is there breath in their mouths.</verse>
<verse>Those who make them will be like them, and so will all who trust in them.</verse>
<verse>O house of Israel, praise the LORD; O house of Aaron, praise the LORD;</verse>
<verse>O house of Levi, praise the LORD; you who fear him, praise the LORD.</verse>
<verse>Praise be to the LORD from Zion, to him who dwells in Jerusalem. Praise the LORD.</verse>
</chapter>