<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Psalms" book_id="19" n="136">
<verse>Give thanks to the LORD, for he is good. His love endures forever.</verse>
<verse>Give thanks to the God of gods. His love endures forever.</verse>
<verse>Give thanks to the Lord of lords: His love endures forever.</verse>
<verse>to him who alone does great wonders, His love endures forever.</verse>
<verse>who by his understanding made the heavens, His love endures forever.</verse>
<verse>who spread out the earth upon the waters, His love endures forever.</verse>
<verse>who made the great lights- His love endures forever.</verse>
<verse>the sun to govern the day, His love endures forever.</verse>
<verse>the moon and stars to govern the night; His love endures forever.</verse>
<verse>to him who struck down the firstborn of Egypt His love endures forever.</verse>
<verse>and brought Israel out from among them His love endures forever.</verse>
<verse>with a mighty hand and outstretched arm; His love endures forever.</verse>
<verse>to him who divided the Red Sea asunder His love endures forever.</verse>
<verse>and brought Israel through the midst of it, His love endures forever.</verse>
<verse>but swept Pharaoh and his army into the Red Sea; His love endures forever.</verse>
<verse>to him who led his people through the desert, His love endures forever.</verse>
<verse>who struck down great kings, His love endures forever.</verse>
<verse>and killed mighty kings- His love endures forever.</verse>
<verse>Sihon king of the Amorites His love endures forever.</verse>
<verse>and Og king of Bashan- His love endures forever.</verse>
<verse>and gave their land as an inheritance, His love endures forever.</verse>
<verse>an inheritance to his servant Israel; His love endures forever.</verse>
<verse>to the One who remembered us in our low estate His love endures forever.</verse>
<verse>and freed us from our enemies, His love endures forever.</verse>
<verse>and who gives food to every creature. His love endures forever.</verse>
<verse>Give thanks to the God of heaven. His love endures forever.</verse>
</chapter>