<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Psalms" book-id="19" n="22">
<verse>My God, my God, why have you forsaken me? Why are you so far from saving me, so far from the words of my groaning?</verse>
<verse>O my God, I cry out by day, but you do not answer, by night, and am not silent.</verse>
<verse>Yet you are enthroned as the Holy One; you are the praise of Israel.</verse>
<verse>In you our fathers put their trust; they trusted and you delivered them.</verse>
<verse>They cried to you and were saved; in you they trusted and were not disappointed.</verse>
<verse>But I am a worm and not a man, scorned by men and despised by the people.</verse>
<verse>All who see me mock me; they hurl insults, shaking their heads:</verse>
<verse>"He trusts in the LORD; let the LORD rescue him. Let him deliver him, since he delights in him."</verse>
<verse>Yet you brought me out of the womb; you made me trust in you even at my mother's breast.</verse>
<verse>From birth I was cast upon you; from my mother's womb you have been my God.</verse>
<verse>Do not be far from me, for trouble is near and there is no one to help.</verse>
<verse>Many bulls surround me; strong bulls of Bashan encircle me.</verse>
<verse>Roaring lions tearing their prey open their mouths wide against me.</verse>
<verse>I am poured out like water, and all my bones are out of joint. My heart has turned to wax; it has melted away within me.</verse>
<verse>My strength is dried up like a potsherd, and my tongue sticks to the roof of my mouth; you lay me in the dust of death.</verse>
<verse>Dogs have surrounded me; a band of evil men has encircled me, they have pierced my hands and my feet.</verse>
<verse>I can count all my bones; people stare and gloat over me.</verse>
<verse>They divide my garments among them and cast lots for my clothing.</verse>
<verse>But you, O LORD, be not far off; O my Strength, come quickly to help me.</verse>
<verse>Deliver my life from the sword, my precious life from the power of the dogs.</verse>
<verse>Rescue me from the mouth of the lions; save me from the horns of the wild oxen.</verse>
<verse>I will declare your name to my brothers; in the congregation I will praise you.</verse>
<verse>You who fear the LORD, praise him! All you descendants of Jacob, honor him! Revere him, all you descendants of Israel!</verse>
<verse>For he has not despised or disdained the suffering of the afflicted one; he has not hidden his face from him but has listened to his cry for help.</verse>
<verse>From you comes the theme of my praise in the great assembly; before those who fear you will I fulfill my vows.</verse>
<verse>The poor will eat and be satisfied; they who seek the LORD will praise him- may your hearts live forever!</verse>
<verse>All the ends of the earth will remember and turn to the LORD, and all the families of the nations will bow down before him,</verse>
<verse>for dominion belongs to the LORD and he rules over the nations.</verse>
<verse>All the rich of the earth will feast and worship; all who go down to the dust will kneel before him- those who cannot keep themselves alive.</verse>
<verse>Posterity will serve him; future generations will be told about the Lord.</verse>
<verse>They will proclaim his righteousness to a people yet unborn- for he has done it.</verse>
</chapter>