<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Psalms" book_id="19" n="25">
<verse>To you, O LORD, I lift up my soul;</verse>
<verse>in you I trust, O my God. Do not let me be put to shame, nor let my enemies triumph over me.</verse>
<verse>No one whose hope is in you will ever be put to shame, but they will be put to shame who are treacherous without excuse.</verse>
<verse>Show me your ways, O LORD, teach me your paths;</verse>
<verse>guide me in your truth and teach me, for you are God my Savior, and my hope is in you all day long.</verse>
<verse>Remember, O LORD, your great mercy and love, for they are from of old.</verse>
<verse>Remember not the sins of my youth and my rebellious ways; according to your love remember me, for you are good, O LORD.</verse>
<verse>Good and upright is the LORD; therefore he instructs sinners in his ways.</verse>
<verse>He guides the humble in what is right and teaches them his way.</verse>
<verse>All the ways of the LORD are loving and faithful for those who keep the demands of his covenant.</verse>
<verse>For the sake of your name, O LORD, forgive my iniquity, though it is great.</verse>
<verse>Who, then, is the man that fears the LORD? He will instruct him in the way chosen for him.</verse>
<verse>He will spend his days in prosperity, and his descendants will inherit the land.</verse>
<verse>The LORD confides in those who fear him; he makes his covenant known to them.</verse>
<verse>My eyes are ever on the LORD, for only he will release my feet from the snare.</verse>
<verse>Turn to me and be gracious to me, for I am lonely and afflicted.</verse>
<verse>The troubles of my heart have multiplied; free me from my anguish.</verse>
<verse>Look upon my affliction and my distress and take away all my sins.</verse>
<verse>See how my enemies have increased and how fiercely they hate me!</verse>
<verse>Guard my life and rescue me; let me not be put to shame, for I take refuge in you.</verse>
<verse>May integrity and uprightness protect me, because my hope is in you.</verse>
<verse>Redeem Israel, O God, from all their troubles!</verse>
</chapter>