<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Psalms" book_id="19" n="31">
<verse>In you, O LORD, I have taken refuge; let me never be put to shame; deliver me in your righteousness.</verse>
<verse>Turn your ear to me, come quickly to my rescue; be my rock of refuge, a strong fortress to save me.</verse>
<verse>Since you are my rock and my fortress, for the sake of your name lead and guide me.</verse>
<verse>Free me from the trap that is set for me, for you are my refuge.</verse>
<verse>Into your hands I commit my spirit; redeem me, O LORD, the God of truth.</verse>
<verse>I hate those who cling to worthless idols; I trust in the LORD.</verse>
<verse>I will be glad and rejoice in your love, for you saw my affliction and knew the anguish of my soul.</verse>
<verse>You have not handed me over to the enemy but have set my feet in a spacious place.</verse>
<verse>Be merciful to me, O LORD, for I am in distress; my eyes grow weak with sorrow, my soul and my body with grief.</verse>
<verse>My life is consumed by anguish and my years by groaning; my strength fails because of my affliction, and my bones grow weak.</verse>
<verse>Because of all my enemies, I am the utter contempt of my neighbors; I am a dread to my friends- those who see me on the street flee from me.</verse>
<verse>I am forgotten by them as though I were dead; I have become like broken pottery.</verse>
<verse>For I hear the slander of many; there is terror on every side; they conspire against me and plot to take my life.</verse>
<verse>But I trust in you, O LORD; I say, "You are my God."</verse>
<verse>My times are in your hands; deliver me from my enemies and from those who pursue me.</verse>
<verse>Let your face shine on your servant; save me in your unfailing love.</verse>
<verse>Let me not be put to shame, O LORD, for I have cried out to you; but let the wicked be put to shame and lie silent in the grave.</verse>
<verse>Let their lying lips be silenced, for with pride and contempt they speak arrogantly against the righteous.</verse>
<verse>How great is your goodness, which you have stored up for those who fear you, which you bestow in the sight of men on those who take refuge in you.</verse>
<verse>In the shelter of your presence you hide them from the intrigues of men; in your dwelling you keep them safe from accusing tongues.</verse>
<verse>Praise be to the LORD, for he showed his wonderful love to me when I was in a besieged city.</verse>
<verse>In my alarm I said, "I am cut off from your sight!" Yet you heard my cry for mercy when I called to you for help.</verse>
<verse>Love the LORD, all his saints! The LORD preserves the faithful, but the proud he pays back in full.</verse>
<verse>Be strong and take heart, all you who hope in the LORD.</verse>
</chapter>