<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Psalms" book_id="19" n="33">
<verse>Sing joyfully to the LORD, you righteous; it is fitting for the upright to praise him.</verse>
<verse>Praise the LORD with the harp; make music to him on the ten-stringed lyre.</verse>
<verse>Sing to him a new song; play skillfully, and shout for joy.</verse>
<verse>For the word of the LORD is right and true; he is faithful in all he does.</verse>
<verse>The LORD loves righteousness and justice; the earth is full of his unfailing love.</verse>
<verse>By the word of the LORD were the heavens made, their starry host by the breath of his mouth.</verse>
<verse>He gathers the waters of the sea into jars; he puts the deep into storehouses.</verse>
<verse>Let all the earth fear the LORD; let all the people of the world revere him.</verse>
<verse>For he spoke, and it came to be; he commanded, and it stood firm.</verse>
<verse>The LORD foils the plans of the nations; he thwarts the purposes of the peoples.</verse>
<verse>But the plans of the LORD stand firm forever, the purposes of his heart through all generations.</verse>
<verse>Blessed is the nation whose God is the LORD, the people he chose for his inheritance.</verse>
<verse>From heaven the LORD looks down and sees all mankind;</verse>
<verse>from his dwelling place he watches all who live on earth-</verse>
<verse>he who forms the hearts of all, who considers everything they do.</verse>
<verse>No king is saved by the size of his army; no warrior escapes by his great strength.</verse>
<verse>A horse is a vain hope for deliverance; despite all its great strength it cannot save.</verse>
<verse>But the eyes of the LORD are on those who fear him, on those whose hope is in his unfailing love,</verse>
<verse>to deliver them from death and keep them alive in famine.</verse>
<verse>We wait in hope for the LORD; he is our help and our shield.</verse>
<verse>In him our hearts rejoice, for we trust in his holy name.</verse>
<verse>May your unfailing love rest upon us, O LORD, even as we put our hope in you.</verse>
</chapter>