<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Psalms" book_id="19" n="34">
<verse>I will extol the LORD at all times; his praise will always be on my lips.</verse>
<verse>My soul will boast in the LORD; let the afflicted hear and rejoice.</verse>
<verse>Glorify the LORD with me; let us exalt his name together.</verse>
<verse>I sought the LORD, and he answered me; he delivered me from all my fears.</verse>
<verse>Those who look to him are radiant; their faces are never covered with shame.</verse>
<verse>This poor man called, and the LORD heard him; he saved him out of all his troubles.</verse>
<verse>The angel of the LORD encamps around those who fear him, and he delivers them.</verse>
<verse>Taste and see that the LORD is good; blessed is the man who takes refuge in him.</verse>
<verse>Fear the LORD, you his saints, for those who fear him lack nothing.</verse>
<verse>The lions may grow weak and hungry, but those who seek the LORD lack no good thing.</verse>
<verse>Come, my children, listen to me; I will teach you the fear of the LORD.</verse>
<verse>Whoever of you loves life and desires to see many good days,</verse>
<verse>keep your tongue from evil and your lips from speaking lies.</verse>
<verse>Turn from evil and do good; seek peace and pursue it.</verse>
<verse>The eyes of the LORD are on the righteous and his ears are attentive to their cry;</verse>
<verse>the face of the LORD is against those who do evil, to cut off the memory of them from the earth.</verse>
<verse>The righteous cry out, and the LORD hears them; he delivers them from all their troubles.</verse>
<verse>The LORD is close to the brokenhearted and saves those who are crushed in spirit.</verse>
<verse>A righteous man may have many troubles, but the LORD delivers him from them all;</verse>
<verse>he protects all his bones, not one of them will be broken.</verse>
<verse>Evil will slay the wicked; the foes of the righteous will be condemned.</verse>
<verse>The LORD redeems his servants; no one will be condemned who takes refuge in him.</verse>
</chapter>