<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Psalms" book_id="19" n="35">
<verse>Contend, O LORD, with those who contend with me; fight against those who fight against me.</verse>
<verse>Take up shield and buckler; arise and come to my aid.</verse>
<verse>Brandish spear and javelin against those who pursue me. Say to my soul, "I am your salvation."</verse>
<verse>May those who seek my life be disgraced and put to shame; may those who plot my ruin be turned back in dismay.</verse>
<verse>May they be like chaff before the wind, with the angel of the LORD driving them away;</verse>
<verse>may their path be dark and slippery, with the angel of the LORD pursuing them.</verse>
<verse>Since they hid their net for me without cause and without cause dug a pit for me,</verse>
<verse>may ruin overtake them by surprise- may the net they hid entangle them, may they fall into the pit, to their ruin.</verse>
<verse>Then my soul will rejoice in the LORD and delight in his salvation.</verse>
<verse>My whole being will exclaim, "Who is like you, O LORD? You rescue the poor from those too strong for them, the poor and needy from those who rob them."</verse>
<verse>Ruthless witnesses come forward; they question me on things I know nothing about.</verse>
<verse>They repay me evil for good and leave my soul forlorn.</verse>
<verse>Yet when they were ill, I put on sackcloth and humbled myself with fasting. When my prayers returned to me unanswered,</verse>
<verse>I went about mourning as though for my friend or brother. I bowed my head in grief as though weeping for my mother.</verse>
<verse>But when I stumbled, they gathered in glee; attackers gathered against me when I was unaware. They slandered me without ceasing.</verse>
<verse>Like the ungodly they maliciously mocked; they gnashed their teeth at me.</verse>
<verse>O Lord, how long will you look on? Rescue my life from their ravages, my precious life from these lions.</verse>
<verse>I will give you thanks in the great assembly; among throngs of people I will praise you.</verse>
<verse>Let not those gloat over me who are my enemies without cause; let not those who hate me without reason maliciously wink the eye.</verse>
<verse>They do not speak peaceably, but devise false accusations against those who live quietly in the land.</verse>
<verse>They gape at me and say, "Aha! Aha! With our own eyes we have seen it."</verse>
<verse>O LORD, you have seen this; be not silent. Do not be far from me, O Lord.</verse>
<verse>Awake, and rise to my defense! Contend for me, my God and Lord.</verse>
<verse>Vindicate me in your righteousness, O LORD my God; do not let them gloat over me.</verse>
<verse>Do not let them think, "Aha, just what we wanted!" or say, "We have swallowed him up."</verse>
<verse>May all who gloat over my distress be put to shame and confusion; may all who exalt themselves over me be clothed with shame and disgrace.</verse>
<verse>May those who delight in my vindication shout for joy and gladness; may they always say, "The LORD be exalted, who delights in the well-being of his servant."</verse>
<verse>My tongue will speak of your righteousness and of your praises all day long.</verse>
</chapter>