<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Psalms" book_id="19" n="37">
<verse>Do not fret because of evil men or be envious of those who do wrong;</verse>
<verse>for like the grass they will soon wither, like green plants they will soon die away.</verse>
<verse>Trust in the LORD and do good; dwell in the land and enjoy safe pasture.</verse>
<verse>Delight yourself in the LORD and he will give you the desires of your heart.</verse>
<verse>Commit your way to the LORD; trust in him and he will do this:</verse>
<verse>He will make your righteousness shine like the dawn, the justice of your cause like the noonday sun.</verse>
<verse>Be still before the LORD and wait patiently for him; do not fret when men succeed in their ways, when they carry out their wicked schemes.</verse>
<verse>Refrain from anger and turn from wrath; do not fret-it leads only to evil.</verse>
<verse>For evil men will be cut off, but those who hope in the LORD will inherit the land.</verse>
<verse>A little while, and the wicked will be no more; though you look for them, they will not be found.</verse>
<verse>But the meek will inherit the land and enjoy great peace.</verse>
<verse>The wicked plot against the righteous and gnash their teeth at them;</verse>
<verse>but the Lord laughs at the wicked, for he knows their day is coming.</verse>
<verse>The wicked draw the sword and bend the bow to bring down the poor and needy, to slay those whose ways are upright.</verse>
<verse>But their swords will pierce their own hearts, and their bows will be broken.</verse>
<verse>Better the little that the righteous have than the wealth of many wicked;</verse>
<verse>for the power of the wicked will be broken, but the LORD upholds the righteous.</verse>
<verse>The days of the blameless are known to the LORD, and their inheritance will endure forever.</verse>
<verse>In times of disaster they will not wither; in days of famine they will enjoy plenty.</verse>
<verse>But the wicked will perish: The LORD's enemies will be like the beauty of the fields, they will vanish-vanish like smoke.</verse>
<verse>The wicked borrow and do not repay, but the righteous give generously;</verse>
<verse>those the LORD blesses will inherit the land, but those he curses will be cut off.</verse>
<verse>If the LORD delights in a man's way, he makes his steps firm;</verse>
<verse>though he stumble, he will not fall, for the LORD upholds him with his hand.</verse>
<verse>I was young and now I am old, yet I have never seen the righteous forsaken or their children begging bread.</verse>
<verse>They are always generous and lend freely; their children will be blessed.</verse>
<verse>Turn from evil and do good; then you will dwell in the land forever.</verse>
<verse>For the LORD loves the just and will not forsake his faithful ones. They will be protected forever, but the offspring of the wicked will be cut off;</verse>
<verse>the righteous will inherit the land and dwell in it forever.</verse>
<verse>The mouth of the righteous man utters wisdom, and his tongue speaks what is just.</verse>
<verse>The law of his God is in his heart; his feet do not slip.</verse>
<verse>The wicked lie in wait for the righteous, seeking their very lives;</verse>
<verse>but the LORD will not leave them in their power or let them be condemned when brought to trial.</verse>
<verse>Wait for the LORD and keep his way. He will exalt you to inherit the land; when the wicked are cut off, you will see it.</verse>
<verse>I have seen a wicked and ruthless man flourishing like a green tree in its native soil,</verse>
<verse>but he soon passed away and was no more; though I looked for him, he could not be found.</verse>
<verse>Consider the blameless, observe the upright; there is a future for the man of peace.</verse>
<verse>But all sinners will be destroyed; the future of the wicked will be cut off.</verse>
<verse>The salvation of the righteous comes from the LORD; he is their stronghold in time of trouble.</verse>
<verse>The LORD helps them and delivers them; he delivers them from the wicked and saves them, because they take refuge in him.</verse>
</chapter>