<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Psalms" book_id="19" n="38">
<verse>O LORD, do not rebuke me in your anger or discipline me in your wrath.</verse>
<verse>For your arrows have pierced me, and your hand has come down upon me.</verse>
<verse>Because of your wrath there is no health in my body; my bones have no soundness because of my sin.</verse>
<verse>My guilt has overwhelmed me like a burden too heavy to bear.</verse>
<verse>My wounds fester and are loathsome because of my sinful folly.</verse>
<verse>I am bowed down and brought very low; all day long I go about mourning.</verse>
<verse>My back is filled with searing pain; there is no health in my body.</verse>
<verse>I am feeble and utterly crushed; I groan in anguish of heart.</verse>
<verse>All my longings lie open before you, O Lord; my sighing is not hidden from you.</verse>
<verse>My heart pounds, my strength fails me; even the light has gone from my eyes.</verse>
<verse>My friends and companions avoid me because of my wounds; my neighbors stay far away.</verse>
<verse>Those who seek my life set their traps, those who would harm me talk of my ruin; all day long they plot deception.</verse>
<verse>I am like a deaf man, who cannot hear, like a mute, who cannot open his mouth;</verse>
<verse>I have become like a man who does not hear, whose mouth can offer no reply.</verse>
<verse>I wait for you, O LORD; you will answer, O Lord my God.</verse>
<verse>For I said, "Do not let them gloat or exalt themselves over me when my foot slips."</verse>
<verse>For I am about to fall, and my pain is ever with me.</verse>
<verse>I confess my iniquity; I am troubled by my sin.</verse>
<verse>Many are those who are my vigorous enemies; those who hate me without reason are numerous.</verse>
<verse>Those who repay my good with evil slander me when I pursue what is good.</verse>
<verse>O LORD, do not forsake me; be not far from me, O my God.</verse>
<verse>Come quickly to help me, O Lord my Savior.</verse>
</chapter>