<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Psalms" book_id="19" n="40">
<verse>I waited patiently for the LORD; he turned to me and heard my cry.</verse>
<verse>He lifted me out of the slimy pit, out of the mud and mire; he set my feet on a rock and gave me a firm place to stand.</verse>
<verse>He put a new song in my mouth, a hymn of praise to our God. Many will see and fear and put their trust in the LORD.</verse>
<verse>Blessed is the man who makes the LORD his trust, who does not look to the proud, to those who turn aside to false gods.</verse>
<verse>Many, O LORD my God, are the wonders you have done. The things you planned for us no one can recount to you; were I to speak and tell of them, they would be too many to declare.</verse>
<verse>Sacrifice and offering you did not desire, but my ears you have pierced,; burnt offerings and sin offerings you did not require.</verse>
<verse>Then I said, "Here I am, I have come- it is written about me in the scroll.</verse>
<verse>I desire to do your will, O my God; your law is within my heart."</verse>
<verse>I proclaim righteousness in the great assembly; I do not seal my lips, as you know, O LORD.</verse>
<verse>I do not hide your righteousness in my heart; I speak of your faithfulness and salvation. I do not conceal your love and your truth from the great assembly.</verse>
<verse>Do not withhold your mercy from me, O LORD; may your love and your truth always protect me.</verse>
<verse>For troubles without number surround me; my sins have overtaken me, and I cannot see. They are more than the hairs of my head, and my heart fails within me.</verse>
<verse>Be pleased, O LORD, to save me; O LORD, come quickly to help me.</verse>
<verse>May all who seek to take my life be put to shame and confusion; may all who desire my ruin be turned back in disgrace.</verse>
<verse>May those who say to me, "Aha! Aha!" be appalled at their own shame.</verse>
<verse>But may all who seek you rejoice and be glad in you; may those who love your salvation always say, "The LORD be exalted!"</verse>
<verse>Yet I am poor and needy; may the Lord think of me. You are my help and my deliverer; O my God, do not delay.</verse>
</chapter>