<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Psalms" book_id="19" n="45">
<verse>My heart is stirred by a noble theme as I recite my verses for the king; my tongue is the pen of a skillful writer.</verse>
<verse>You are the most excellent of men and your lips have been anointed with grace, since God has blessed you forever.</verse>
<verse>Gird your sword upon your side, O mighty one; clothe yourself with splendor and majesty.</verse>
<verse>In your majesty ride forth victoriously in behalf of truth, humility and righteousness; let your right hand display awesome deeds.</verse>
<verse>Let your sharp arrows pierce the hearts of the king's enemies; let the nations fall beneath your feet.</verse>
<verse>Your throne, O God, will last for ever and ever; a scepter of justice will be the scepter of your kingdom.</verse>
<verse>You love righteousness and hate wickedness; therefore God, your God, has set you above your companions by anointing you with the oil of joy.</verse>
<verse>All your robes are fragrant with myrrh and aloes and cassia; from palaces adorned with ivory the music of the strings makes you glad.</verse>
<verse>Daughters of kings are among your honored women; at your right hand is the royal bride in gold of Ophir.</verse>
<verse>Listen, O daughter, consider and give ear: Forget your people and your father's house.</verse>
<verse>The king is enthralled by your beauty; honor him, for he is your lord.</verse>
<verse>The Daughter of Tyre will come with a gift, men of wealth will seek your favor.</verse>
<verse>All glorious is the princess within her chamber; her gown is interwoven with gold.</verse>
<verse>In embroidered garments she is led to the king; her virgin companions follow her and are brought to you.</verse>
<verse>They are led in with joy and gladness; they enter the palace of the king.</verse>
<verse>Your sons will take the place of your fathers; you will make them princes throughout the land.</verse>
<verse>I will perpetuate your memory through all generations; therefore the nations will praise you for ever and ever.</verse>
</chapter>