<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Psalms" book-id="19" n="49">
<verse>Hear this, all you peoples; listen, all who live in this world,</verse>
<verse>both low and high, rich and poor alike:</verse>
<verse>My mouth will speak words of wisdom; the utterance from my heart will give understanding.</verse>
<verse>I will turn my ear to a proverb; with the harp I will expound my riddle:</verse>
<verse>Why should I fear when evil days come, when wicked deceivers surround me-</verse>
<verse>those who trust in their wealth and boast of their great riches?</verse>
<verse>No man can redeem the life of another or give to God a ransom for him-</verse>
<verse>the ransom for a life is costly, no payment is ever enough-</verse>
<verse>that he should live on forever and not see decay.</verse>
<verse>For all can see that wise men die; the foolish and the senseless alike perish and leave their wealth to others.</verse>
<verse>Their tombs will remain their houses forever, their dwellings for endless generations, though they had named lands after themselves.</verse>
<verse>But man, despite his riches, does not endure; he is like the beasts that perish.</verse>
<verse>This is the fate of those who trust in themselves, and of their followers, who approve their sayings. Selah</verse>
<verse>Like sheep they are destined for the grave, and death will feed on them. The upright will rule over them in the morning; their forms will decay in the grave, far from their princely mansions.</verse>
<verse>But God will redeem my life from the grave; he will surely take me to himself. Selah</verse>
<verse>Do not be overawed when a man grows rich, when the splendor of his house increases;</verse>
<verse>for he will take nothing with him when he dies, his splendor will not descend with him.</verse>
<verse>Though while he lived he counted himself blessed- and men praise you when you prosper-</verse>
<verse>he will join the generation of his fathers, who will never see the light of life.</verse>
<verse>A man who has riches without understanding is like the beasts that perish.</verse>
</chapter>