<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Psalms" book-id="19" n="50">
<verse>The Mighty One, God, the LORD, speaks and summons the earth from the rising of the sun to the place where it sets.</verse>
<verse>From Zion, perfect in beauty, God shines forth.</verse>
<verse>Our God comes and will not be silent; a fire devours before him, and around him a tempest rages.</verse>
<verse>He summons the heavens above, and the earth, that he may judge his people:</verse>
<verse>"Gather to me my consecrated ones, who made a covenant with me by sacrifice."</verse>
<verse>And the heavens proclaim his righteousness, for God himself is judge. Selah</verse>
<verse>"Hear, O my people, and I will speak, O Israel, and I will testify against you: I am God, your God.</verse>
<verse>I do not rebuke you for your sacrifices or your burnt offerings, which are ever before me.</verse>
<verse>I have no need of a bull from your stall or of goats from your pens,</verse>
<verse>for every animal of the forest is mine, and the cattle on a thousand hills.</verse>
<verse>I know every bird in the mountains, and the creatures of the field are mine.</verse>
<verse>If I were hungry I would not tell you, for the world is mine, and all that is in it.</verse>
<verse>Do I eat the flesh of bulls or drink the blood of goats?</verse>
<verse>Sacrifice thank offerings to God, fulfill your vows to the Most High,</verse>
<verse>and call upon me in the day of trouble; I will deliver you, and you will honor me."</verse>
<verse>But to the wicked, God says: "What right have you to recite my laws or take my covenant on your lips?</verse>
<verse>You hate my instruction and cast my words behind you.</verse>
<verse>When you see a thief, you join with him; you throw in your lot with adulterers.</verse>
<verse>You use your mouth for evil and harness your tongue to deceit.</verse>
<verse>You speak continually against your brother and slander your own mother's son.</verse>
<verse>These things you have done and I kept silent; you thought I was altogether like you. But I will rebuke you and accuse you to your face.</verse>
<verse>"Consider this, you who forget God, or I will tear you to pieces, with none to rescue:</verse>
<verse>He who sacrifices thank offerings honors me, and he prepares the way so that I may show him the salvation of God."</verse>
</chapter>