<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Psalms" book_id="19" n="55">
<verse>Listen to my prayer, O God, do not ignore my plea;</verse>
<verse>hear me and answer me. My thoughts trouble me and I am distraught</verse>
<verse>at the voice of the enemy, at the stares of the wicked; for they bring down suffering upon me and revile me in their anger.</verse>
<verse>My heart is in anguish within me; the terrors of death assail me.</verse>
<verse>Fear and trembling have beset me; horror has overwhelmed me.</verse>
<verse>I said, "Oh, that I had the wings of a dove! I would fly away and be at rest-</verse>
<verse>I would flee far away and stay in the desert; Selah</verse>
<verse>I would hurry to my place of shelter, far from the tempest and storm."</verse>
<verse>Confuse the wicked, O Lord, confound their speech, for I see violence and strife in the city.</verse>
<verse>Day and night they prowl about on its walls; malice and abuse are within it.</verse>
<verse>Destructive forces are at work in the city; threats and lies never leave its streets.</verse>
<verse>If an enemy were insulting me, I could endure it; if a foe were raising himself against me, I could hide from him.</verse>
<verse>But it is you, a man like myself, my companion, my close friend,</verse>
<verse>with whom I once enjoyed sweet fellowship as we walked with the throng at the house of God.</verse>
<verse>Let death take my enemies by surprise; let them go down alive to the grave, for evil finds lodging among them.</verse>
<verse>But I call to God, and the LORD saves me.</verse>
<verse>Evening, morning and noon I cry out in distress, and he hears my voice.</verse>
<verse>He ransoms me unharmed from the battle waged against me, even though many oppose me.</verse>
<verse>God, who is enthroned forever, will hear them and afflict them- Selah men who never change their ways and have no fear of God.</verse>
<verse>My companion attacks his friends; he violates his covenant.</verse>
<verse>His speech is smooth as butter, yet war is in his heart; his words are more soothing than oil, yet they are drawn swords.</verse>
<verse>Cast your cares on the LORD and he will sustain you; he will never let the righteous fall.</verse>
<verse>But you, O God, will bring down the wicked into the pit of corruption; bloodthirsty and deceitful men will not live out half their days. But as for me, I trust in you.</verse>
</chapter>