<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Psalms" book_id="19" n="68">
<verse>May God arise, may his enemies be scattered; may his foes flee before him.</verse>
<verse>As smoke is blown away by the wind, may you blow them away; as wax melts before the fire, may the wicked perish before God.</verse>
<verse>But may the righteous be glad and rejoice before God; may they be happy and joyful.</verse>
<verse>Sing to God, sing praise to his name, extol him who rides on the clouds - his name is the LORD - and rejoice before him.</verse>
<verse>A father to the fatherless, a defender of widows, is God in his holy dwelling.</verse>
<verse>God sets the lonely in families, he leads forth the prisoners with singing; but the rebellious live in a sun-scorched land.</verse>
<verse>When you went out before your people, O God, when you marched through the wasteland, Selah</verse>
<verse>the earth shook, the heavens poured down rain, before God, the One of Sinai, before God, the God of Israel.</verse>
<verse>You gave abundant showers, O God; you refreshed your weary inheritance.</verse>
<verse>Your people settled in it, and from your bounty, O God, you provided for the poor.</verse>
<verse>The Lord announced the word, and great was the company of those who proclaimed it:</verse>
<verse>"Kings and armies flee in haste; in the camps men divide the plunder.</verse>
<verse>Even while you sleep among the campfires, the wings of my dove are sheathed with silver, its feathers with shining gold."</verse>
<verse>When the Almighty scattered the kings in the land, it was like snow fallen on Zalmon.</verse>
<verse>The mountains of Bashan are majestic mountains; rugged are the mountains of Bashan.</verse>
<verse>Why gaze in envy, O rugged mountains, at the mountain where God chooses to reign, where the LORD himself will dwell forever?</verse>
<verse>The chariots of God are tens of thousands and thousands of thousands; the Lord has come from Sinai into his sanctuary.</verse>
<verse>When you ascended on high, you led captives in your train; you received gifts from men, even from the rebellious- that you, O LORD God, might dwell there.</verse>
<verse>Praise be to the Lord, to God our Savior, who daily bears our burdens. Selah</verse>
<verse>Our God is a God who saves; from the Sovereign LORD comes escape from death.</verse>
<verse>Surely God will crush the heads of his enemies, the hairy crowns of those who go on in their sins.</verse>
<verse>The Lord says, "I will bring them from Bashan; I will bring them from the depths of the sea,</verse>
<verse>that you may plunge your feet in the blood of your foes, while the tongues of your dogs have their share."</verse>
<verse>Your procession has come into view, O God, the procession of my God and King into the sanctuary.</verse>
<verse>In front are the singers, after them the musicians; with them are the maidens playing tambourines.</verse>
<verse>Praise God in the great congregation; praise the LORD in the assembly of Israel.</verse>
<verse>There is the little tribe of Benjamin, leading them, there the great throng of Judah's princes, and there the princes of Zebulun and of Naphtali.</verse>
<verse>Summon your power, O God; show us your strength, O God, as you have done before.</verse>
<verse>Because of your temple at Jerusalem kings will bring you gifts.</verse>
<verse>Rebuke the beast among the reeds, the herd of bulls among the calves of the nations. Humbled, may it bring bars of silver. Scatter the nations who delight in war.</verse>
<verse>Envoys will come from Egypt; Cush will submit herself to God.</verse>
<verse>Sing to God, O kingdoms of the earth, sing praise to the Lord, Selah</verse>
<verse>to him who rides the ancient skies above, who thunders with mighty voice.</verse>
<verse>Proclaim the power of God, whose majesty is over Israel, whose power is in the skies.</verse>
<verse>You are awesome, O God, in your sanctuary; the God of Israel gives power and strength to his people. Praise be to God!</verse>
</chapter>