<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Psalms" book-id="19" n="69">
<verse>Save me, O God, for the waters have come up to my neck.</verse>
<verse>I sink in the miry depths, where there is no foothold. I have come into the deep waters; the floods engulf me.</verse>
<verse>I am worn out calling for help; my throat is parched. My eyes fail, looking for my God.</verse>
<verse>Those who hate me without reason outnumber the hairs of my head; many are my enemies without cause, those who seek to destroy me. I am forced to restore what I did not steal.</verse>
<verse>You know my folly, O God; my guilt is not hidden from you.</verse>
<verse>May those who hope in you not be disgraced because of me, O Lord, the LORD Almighty; may those who seek you not be put to shame because of me, O God of Israel.</verse>
<verse>For I endure scorn for your sake, and shame covers my face.</verse>
<verse>I am a stranger to my brothers, an alien to my own mother's sons;</verse>
<verse>for zeal for your house consumes me, and the insults of those who insult you fall on me.</verse>
<verse>When I weep and fast, I must endure scorn;</verse>
<verse>when I put on sackcloth, people make sport of me.</verse>
<verse>Those who sit at the gate mock me, and I am the song of the drunkards.</verse>
<verse>But I pray to you, O LORD, in the time of your favor; in your great love, O God, answer me with your sure salvation.</verse>
<verse>Rescue me from the mire, do not let me sink; deliver me from those who hate me, from the deep waters.</verse>
<verse>Do not let the floodwaters engulf me or the depths swallow me up or the pit close its mouth over me.</verse>
<verse>Answer me, O LORD, out of the goodness of your love; in your great mercy turn to me.</verse>
<verse>Do not hide your face from your servant; answer me quickly, for I am in trouble.</verse>
<verse>Come near and rescue me; redeem me because of my foes.</verse>
<verse>You know how I am scorned, disgraced and shamed; all my enemies are before you.</verse>
<verse>Scorn has broken my heart and has left me helpless; I looked for sympathy, but there was none, for comforters, but I found none.</verse>
<verse>They put gall in my food and gave me vinegar for my thirst.</verse>
<verse>May the table set before them become a snare; may it become retribution and a trap.</verse>
<verse>May their eyes be darkened so they cannot see, and their backs be bent forever.</verse>
<verse>Pour out your wrath on them; let your fierce anger overtake them.</verse>
<verse>May their place be deserted; let there be no one to dwell in their tents.</verse>
<verse>For they persecute those you wound and talk about the pain of those you hurt.</verse>
<verse>Charge them with crime upon crime; do not let them share in your salvation.</verse>
<verse>May they be blotted out of the book of life and not be listed with the righteous.</verse>
<verse>I am in pain and distress; may your salvation, O God, protect me.</verse>
<verse>I will praise God's name in song and glorify him with thanksgiving.</verse>
<verse>This will please the LORD more than an ox, more than a bull with its horns and hoofs.</verse>
<verse>The poor will see and be glad- you who seek God, may your hearts live!</verse>
<verse>The LORD hears the needy and does not despise his captive people.</verse>
<verse>Let heaven and earth praise him, the seas and all that move in them,</verse>
<verse>for God will save Zion and rebuild the cities of Judah. Then people will settle there and possess it;</verse>
<verse>the children of his servants will inherit it, and those who love his name will dwell there.</verse>
</chapter>