<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Psalms" book_id="19" n="71">
<verse>In you, O LORD, I have taken refuge; let me never be put to shame.</verse>
<verse>Rescue me and deliver me in your righteousness; turn your ear to me and save me.</verse>
<verse>Be my rock of refuge, to which I can always go; give the command to save me, for you are my rock and my fortress.</verse>
<verse>Deliver me, O my God, from the hand of the wicked, from the grasp of evil and cruel men.</verse>
<verse>For you have been my hope, O Sovereign LORD, my confidence since my youth.</verse>
<verse>From birth I have relied on you; you brought me forth from my mother's womb. I will ever praise you.</verse>
<verse>I have become like a portent to many, but you are my strong refuge.</verse>
<verse>My mouth is filled with your praise, declaring your splendor all day long.</verse>
<verse>Do not cast me away when I am old; do not forsake me when my strength is gone.</verse>
<verse>For my enemies speak against me; those who wait to kill me conspire together.</verse>
<verse>They say, "God has forsaken him; pursue him and seize him, for no one will rescue him."</verse>
<verse>Be not far from me, O God; come quickly, O my God, to help me.</verse>
<verse>May my accusers perish in shame; may those who want to harm me be covered with scorn and disgrace.</verse>
<verse>But as for me, I will always have hope; I will praise you more and more.</verse>
<verse>My mouth will tell of your righteousness, of your salvation all day long, though I know not its measure.</verse>
<verse>I will come and proclaim your mighty acts, O Sovereign LORD; I will proclaim your righteousness, yours alone.</verse>
<verse>Since my youth, O God, you have taught me, and to this day I declare your marvelous deeds.</verse>
<verse>Even when I am old and gray, do not forsake me, O God, till I declare your power to the next generation, your might to all who are to come.</verse>
<verse>Your righteousness reaches to the skies, O God, you who have done great things. Who, O God, is like you?</verse>
<verse>Though you have made me see troubles, many and bitter, you will restore my life again; from the depths of the earth you will again bring me up.</verse>
<verse>You will increase my honor and comfort me once again.</verse>
<verse>I will praise you with the harp for your faithfulness, O my God; I will sing praise to you with the lyre, O Holy One of Israel.</verse>
<verse>My lips will shout for joy when I sing praise to you- I, whom you have redeemed.</verse>
<verse>My tongue will tell of your righteous acts all day long, for those who wanted to harm me have been put to shame and confusion.</verse>
</chapter>