<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Psalms" book_id="19" n="73">
<verse>A psalm of Asaph. Surely God is good to Israel, to those who are pure in heart.</verse>
<verse>But as for me, my feet had almost slipped; I had nearly lost my foothold.</verse>
<verse>For I envied the arrogant when I saw the prosperity of the wicked.</verse>
<verse>They have no struggles; their bodies are healthy and strong.</verse>
<verse>They are free from the burdens common to man; they are not plagued by human ills.</verse>
<verse>Therefore pride is their necklace; they clothe themselves with violence.</verse>
<verse>From their callous hearts comes iniquity; the evil conceits of their minds know no limits.</verse>
<verse>They scoff, and speak with malice; in their arrogance they threaten oppression.</verse>
<verse>Their mouths lay claim to heaven, and their tongues take possession of the earth.</verse>
<verse>Therefore their people turn to them and drink up waters in abundance.</verse>
<verse>They say, "How can God know? Does the Most High have knowledge?"</verse>
<verse>This is what the wicked are like- always carefree, they increase in wealth.</verse>
<verse>Surely in vain have I kept my heart pure; in vain have I washed my hands in innocence.</verse>
<verse>All day long I have been plagued; I have been punished every morning.</verse>
<verse>If I had said, "I will speak thus," I would have betrayed your children.</verse>
<verse>When I tried to understand all this, it was oppressive to me</verse>
<verse>till I entered the sanctuary of God; then I understood their final destiny.</verse>
<verse>Surely you place them on slippery ground; you cast them down to ruin.</verse>
<verse>How suddenly are they destroyed, completely swept away by terrors!</verse>
<verse>As a dream when one awakes, so when you arise, O Lord, you will despise them as fantasies.</verse>
<verse>When my heart was grieved and my spirit embittered,</verse>
<verse>I was senseless and ignorant; I was a brute beast before you.</verse>
<verse>Yet I am always with you; you hold me by my right hand.</verse>
<verse>You guide me with your counsel, and afterward you will take me into glory.</verse>
<verse>Whom have I in heaven but you? And earth has nothing I desire besides you.</verse>
<verse>My flesh and my heart may fail, but God is the strength of my heart and my portion forever.</verse>
<verse>Those who are far from you will perish; you destroy all who are unfaithful to you.</verse>
<verse>But as for me, it is good to be near God. I have made the Sovereign LORD my refuge; I will tell of all your deeds.</verse>
</chapter>