<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Psalms" book_id="19" n="74">
<verse>Why have you rejected us forever, O God? Why does your anger smolder against the sheep of your pasture?</verse>
<verse>Remember the people you purchased of old, the tribe of your inheritance, whom you redeemed- Mount Zion, where you dwelt.</verse>
<verse>Turn your steps toward these everlasting ruins, all this destruction the enemy has brought on the sanctuary.</verse>
<verse>Your foes roared in the place where you met with us; they set up their standards as signs.</verse>
<verse>They behaved like men wielding axes to cut through a thicket of trees.</verse>
<verse>They smashed all the carved paneling with their axes and hatchets.</verse>
<verse>They burned your sanctuary to the ground; they defiled the dwelling place of your Name.</verse>
<verse>They said in their hearts, "We will crush them completely!" They burned every place where God was worshiped in the land.</verse>
<verse>We are given no miraculous signs; no prophets are left, and none of us knows how long this will be.</verse>
<verse>How long will the enemy mock you, O God? Will the foe revile your name forever?</verse>
<verse>Why do you hold back your hand, your right hand? Take it from the folds of your garment and destroy them!</verse>
<verse>But you, O God, are my king from of old; you bring salvation upon the earth.</verse>
<verse>It was you who split open the sea by your power; you broke the heads of the monster in the waters.</verse>
<verse>It was you who crushed the heads of Leviathan and gave him as food to the creatures of the desert.</verse>
<verse>It was you who opened up springs and streams; you dried up the ever flowing rivers.</verse>
<verse>The day is yours, and yours also the night; you established the sun and moon.</verse>
<verse>It was you who set all the boundaries of the earth; you made both summer and winter.</verse>
<verse>Remember how the enemy has mocked you, O LORD, how foolish people have reviled your name.</verse>
<verse>Do not hand over the life of your dove to wild beasts; do not forget the lives of your afflicted people forever.</verse>
<verse>Have regard for your covenant, because haunts of violence fill the dark places of the land.</verse>
<verse>Do not let the oppressed retreat in disgrace; may the poor and needy praise your name.</verse>
<verse>Rise up, O God, and defend your cause; remember how fools mock you all day long.</verse>
<verse>Do not ignore the clamor of your adversaries, the uproar of your enemies, which rises continually.</verse>
</chapter>