<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Psalms" book-id="19" n="78">
<verse>O my people, hear my teaching; listen to the words of my mouth.</verse>
<verse>I will open my mouth in parables, I will utter hidden things, things from of old-</verse>
<verse>what we have heard and known, what our fathers have told us.</verse>
<verse>We will not hide them from their children; we will tell the next generation the praiseworthy deeds of the LORD, his power, and the wonders he has done.</verse>
<verse>He decreed statutes for Jacob and established the law in Israel, which he commanded our forefathers to teach their children,</verse>
<verse>so the next generation would know them, even the children yet to be born, and they in turn would tell their children.</verse>
<verse>Then they would put their trust in God and would not forget his deeds but would keep his commands.</verse>
<verse>They would not be like their forefathers- a stubborn and rebellious generation, whose hearts were not loyal to God, whose spirits were not faithful to him.</verse>
<verse>The men of Ephraim, though armed with bows, turned back on the day of battle;</verse>
<verse>they did not keep God's covenant and refused to live by his law.</verse>
<verse>They forgot what he had done, the wonders he had shown them.</verse>
<verse>He did miracles in the sight of their fathers in the land of Egypt, in the region of Zoan.</verse>
<verse>He divided the sea and led them through; he made the water stand firm like a wall.</verse>
<verse>He guided them with the cloud by day and with light from the fire all night.</verse>
<verse>He split the rocks in the desert and gave them water as abundant as the seas;</verse>
<verse>he brought streams out of a rocky crag and made water flow down like rivers.</verse>
<verse>But they continued to sin against him, rebelling in the desert against the Most High.</verse>
<verse>They willfully put God to the test by demanding the food they craved.</verse>
<verse>They spoke against God, saying, "Can God spread a table in the desert?</verse>
<verse>When he struck the rock, water gushed out, and streams flowed abundantly. But can he also give us food? Can he supply meat for his people?"</verse>
<verse>When the LORD heard them, he was very angry; his fire broke out against Jacob, and his wrath rose against Israel,</verse>
<verse>for they did not believe in God or trust in his deliverance.</verse>
<verse>Yet he gave a command to the skies above and opened the doors of the heavens;</verse>
<verse>he rained down manna for the people to eat, he gave them the grain of heaven.</verse>
<verse>Men ate the bread of angels; he sent them all the food they could eat.</verse>
<verse>He let loose the east wind from the heavens and led forth the south wind by his power.</verse>
<verse>He rained meat down on them like dust, flying birds like sand on the seashore.</verse>
<verse>He made them come down inside their camp, all around their tents.</verse>
<verse>They ate till they had more than enough, for he had given them what they craved.</verse>
<verse>But before they turned from the food they craved, even while it was still in their mouths,</verse>
<verse>God's anger rose against them; he put to death the sturdiest among them, cutting down the young men of Israel.</verse>
<verse>In spite of all this, they kept on sinning; in spite of his wonders, they did not believe.</verse>
<verse>So he ended their days in futility and their years in terror.</verse>
<verse>Whenever God slew them, they would seek him; they eagerly turned to him again.</verse>
<verse>They remembered that God was their Rock, that God Most High was their Redeemer.</verse>
<verse>But then they would flatter him with their mouths, lying to him with their tongues;</verse>
<verse>their hearts were not loyal to him, they were not faithful to his covenant.</verse>
<verse>Yet he was merciful; he forgave their iniquities and did not destroy them. Time after time he restrained his anger and did not stir up his full wrath.</verse>
<verse>He remembered that they were but flesh, a passing breeze that does not return.</verse>
<verse>How often they rebelled against him in the desert and grieved him in the wasteland!</verse>
<verse>Again and again they put God to the test; they vexed the Holy One of Israel.</verse>
<verse>They did not remember his power- the day he redeemed them from the oppressor,</verse>
<verse>the day he displayed his miraculous signs in Egypt, his wonders in the region of Zoan.</verse>
<verse>He turned their rivers to blood; they could not drink from their streams.</verse>
<verse>He sent swarms of flies that devoured them, and frogs that devastated them.</verse>
<verse>He gave their crops to the grasshopper, their produce to the locust.</verse>
<verse>He destroyed their vines with hail and their sycamore-figs with sleet.</verse>
<verse>He gave over their cattle to the hail, their livestock to bolts of lightning.</verse>
<verse>He unleashed against them his hot anger, his wrath, indignation and hostility- a band of destroying angels.</verse>
<verse>He prepared a path for his anger; he did not spare them from death but gave them over to the plague.</verse>
<verse>He struck down all the firstborn of Egypt, the firstfruits of manhood in the tents of Ham.</verse>
<verse>But he brought his people out like a flock; he led them like sheep through the desert.</verse>
<verse>He guided them safely, so they were unafraid; but the sea engulfed their enemies.</verse>
<verse>Thus he brought them to the border of his holy land, to the hill country his right hand had taken.</verse>
<verse>He drove out nations before them and allotted their lands to them as an inheritance; he settled the tribes of Israel in their homes.</verse>
<verse>But they put God to the test and rebelled against the Most High; they did not keep his statutes.</verse>
<verse>Like their fathers they were disloyal and faithless, as unreliable as a faulty bow.</verse>
<verse>They angered him with their high places; they aroused his jealousy with their idols.</verse>
<verse>When God heard them, he was very angry; he rejected Israel completely.</verse>
<verse>He abandoned the tabernacle of Shiloh, the tent he had set up among men.</verse>
<verse>He sent the ark of his might into captivity, his splendor into the hands of the enemy.</verse>
<verse>He gave his people over to the sword; he was very angry with his inheritance.</verse>
<verse>Fire consumed their young men, and their maidens had no wedding songs;</verse>
<verse>their priests were put to the sword, and their widows could not weep.</verse>
<verse>Then the Lord awoke as from sleep, as a man wakes from the stupor of wine.</verse>
<verse>He beat back his enemies; he put them to everlasting shame.</verse>
<verse>Then he rejected the tents of Joseph, he did not choose the tribe of Ephraim;</verse>
<verse>but he chose the tribe of Judah, Mount Zion, which he loved.</verse>
<verse>He built his sanctuary like the heights, like the earth that he established forever.</verse>
<verse>He chose David his servant and took him from the sheep pens;</verse>
<verse>from tending the sheep he brought him to be the shepherd of his people Jacob, of Israel his inheritance.</verse>
<verse>And David shepherded them with integrity of heart; with skillful hands he led them.</verse>
</chapter>