<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Psalms" book-id="19" n="89">
<verse>I will sing of the LORD's great love forever; with my mouth I will make your faithfulness known through all generations.</verse>
<verse>I will declare that your love stands firm forever, that you established your faithfulness in heaven itself.</verse>
<verse>You said, "I have made a covenant with my chosen one, I have sworn to David my servant,</verse>
<verse>'I will establish your line forever and make your throne firm through all generations.'" Selah</verse>
<verse>The heavens praise your wonders, O LORD, your faithfulness too, in the assembly of the holy ones.</verse>
<verse>For who in the skies above can compare with the LORD? Who is like the LORD among the heavenly beings?</verse>
<verse>In the council of the holy ones God is greatly feared; he is more awesome than all who surround him.</verse>
<verse>O LORD God Almighty, who is like you? You are mighty, O LORD, and your faithfulness surrounds you.</verse>
<verse>You rule over the surging sea; when its waves mount up, you still them.</verse>
<verse>You crushed Rahab like one of the slain; with your strong arm you scattered your enemies.</verse>
<verse>The heavens are yours, and yours also the earth; you founded the world and all that is in it.</verse>
<verse>You created the north and the south; Tabor and Hermon sing for joy at your name.</verse>
<verse>Your arm is endued with power; your hand is strong, your right hand exalted.</verse>
<verse>Righteousness and justice are the foundation of your throne; love and faithfulness go before you.</verse>
<verse>Blessed are those who have learned to acclaim you, who walk in the light of your presence, O LORD.</verse>
<verse>They rejoice in your name all day long; they exult in your righteousness.</verse>
<verse>For you are their glory and strength, and by your favor you exalt our horn.</verse>
<verse>Indeed, our shield belongs to the LORD, our king to the Holy One of Israel.</verse>
<verse>Once you spoke in a vision, to your faithful people you said: "I have bestowed strength on a warrior; I have exalted a young man from among the people.</verse>
<verse>I have found David my servant; with my sacred oil I have anointed him.</verse>
<verse>My hand will sustain him; surely my arm will strengthen him.</verse>
<verse>No enemy will subject him to tribute; no wicked man will oppress him.</verse>
<verse>I will crush his foes before him and strike down his adversaries.</verse>
<verse>My faithful love will be with him, and through my name his horn will be exalted.</verse>
<verse>I will set his hand over the sea, his right hand over the rivers.</verse>
<verse>He will call out to me, 'You are my Father, my God, the Rock my Savior.'</verse>
<verse>I will also appoint him my firstborn, the most exalted of the kings of the earth.</verse>
<verse>I will maintain my love to him forever, and my covenant with him will never fail.</verse>
<verse>I will establish his line forever, his throne as long as the heavens endure.</verse>
<verse>"If his sons forsake my law and do not follow my statutes,</verse>
<verse>if they violate my decrees and fail to keep my commands,</verse>
<verse>I will punish their sin with the rod, their iniquity with flogging;</verse>
<verse>but I will not take my love from him, nor will I ever betray my faithfulness.</verse>
<verse>I will not violate my covenant or alter what my lips have uttered.</verse>
<verse>Once for all, I have sworn by my holiness- and I will not lie to David-</verse>
<verse>that his line will continue forever and his throne endure before me like the sun;</verse>
<verse>it will be established forever like the moon, the faithful witness in the sky." Selah</verse>
<verse>But you have rejected, you have spurned, you have been very angry with your anointed one.</verse>
<verse>You have renounced the covenant with your servant and have defiled his crown in the dust.</verse>
<verse>You have broken through all his walls and reduced his strongholds to ruins.</verse>
<verse>All who pass by have plundered him; he has become the scorn of his neighbors.</verse>
<verse>You have exalted the right hand of his foes; you have made all his enemies rejoice.</verse>
<verse>You have turned back the edge of his sword and have not supported him in battle.</verse>
<verse>You have put an end to his splendor and cast his throne to the ground.</verse>
<verse>You have cut short the days of his youth; you have covered him with a mantle of shame. Selah</verse>
<verse>How long, O LORD? Will you hide yourself forever? How long will your wrath burn like fire?</verse>
<verse>Remember how fleeting is my life. For what futility you have created all men!</verse>
<verse>What man can live and not see death, or save himself from the power of the grave? Selah</verse>
<verse>O Lord, where is your former great love, which in your faithfulness you swore to David?</verse>
<verse>Remember, Lord, how your servant has been mocked, how I bear in my heart the taunts of all the nations,</verse>
<verse>the taunts with which your enemies have mocked, O LORD, with which they have mocked every step of your anointed one.</verse>
<verse>Praise be to the LORD forever! Amen and Amen. BOOK IV Psalms 90-106</verse>
</chapter>