<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Psalms" book_id="19" n="9">
<verse>I will praise you, O LORD, with all my heart; I will tell of all your wonders.</verse>
<verse>I will be glad and rejoice in you; I will sing praise to your name, O Most High.</verse>
<verse>My enemies turn back; they stumble and perish before you.</verse>
<verse>For you have upheld my right and my cause; you have sat on your throne, judging righteously.</verse>
<verse>You have rebuked the nations and destroyed the wicked; you have blotted out their name for ever and ever.</verse>
<verse>Endless ruin has overtaken the enemy, you have uprooted their cities; even the memory of them has perished.</verse>
<verse>The LORD reigns forever; he has established his throne for judgment.</verse>
<verse>He will judge the world in righteousness; he will govern the peoples with justice.</verse>
<verse>The LORD is a refuge for the oppressed, a stronghold in times of trouble.</verse>
<verse>Those who know your name will trust in you, for you, LORD, have never forsaken those who seek you.</verse>
<verse>Sing praises to the LORD, enthroned in Zion; proclaim among the nations what he has done.</verse>
<verse>For he who avenges blood remembers; he does not ignore the cry of the afflicted.</verse>
<verse>O LORD, see how my enemies persecute me! Have mercy and lift me up from the gates of death,</verse>
<verse>that I may declare your praises in the gates of the Daughter of Zion and there rejoice in your salvation.</verse>
<verse>The nations have fallen into the pit they have dug; their feet are caught in the net they have hidden.</verse>
<verse>The LORD is known by his justice; the wicked are ensnared by the work of their hands. Higgaion. Selah</verse>
<verse>The wicked return to the grave, all the nations that forget God.</verse>
<verse>But the needy will not always be forgotten, nor the hope of the afflicted ever perish.</verse>
<verse>Arise, O LORD, let not man triumph; let the nations be judged in your presence.</verse>
<verse>Strike them with terror, O LORD; let the nations know they are but men. Selah</verse>
</chapter>