<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="Psalms" book_id="19" n="94">
<verse>O LORD, the God who avenges, O God who avenges, shine forth.</verse>
<verse>Rise up, O Judge of the earth; pay back to the proud what they deserve.</verse>
<verse>How long will the wicked, O LORD, how long will the wicked be jubilant?</verse>
<verse>They pour out arrogant words; all the evildoers are full of boasting.</verse>
<verse>They crush your people, O LORD; they oppress your inheritance.</verse>
<verse>They slay the widow and the alien; they murder the fatherless.</verse>
<verse>They say, "The LORD does not see; the God of Jacob pays no heed."</verse>
<verse>Take heed, you senseless ones among the people; you fools, when will you become wise?</verse>
<verse>Does he who implanted the ear not hear? Does he who formed the eye not see?</verse>
<verse>Does he who disciplines nations not punish? Does he who teaches man lack knowledge?</verse>
<verse>The LORD knows the thoughts of man; he knows that they are futile.</verse>
<verse>Blessed is the man you discipline, O LORD, the man you teach from your law;</verse>
<verse>you grant him relief from days of trouble, till a pit is dug for the wicked.</verse>
<verse>For the LORD will not reject his people; he will never forsake his inheritance.</verse>
<verse>Judgment will again be founded on righteousness, and all the upright in heart will follow it.</verse>
<verse>Who will rise up for me against the wicked? Who will take a stand for me against evildoers?</verse>
<verse>Unless the LORD had given me help, I would soon have dwelt in the silence of death.</verse>
<verse>When I said, "My foot is slipping," your love, O LORD, supported me.</verse>
<verse>When anxiety was great within me, your consolation brought joy to my soul.</verse>
<verse>Can a corrupt throne be allied with you- one that brings on misery by its decrees?</verse>
<verse>They band together against the righteous and condemn the innocent to death.</verse>
<verse>But the LORD has become my fortress, and my God the rock in whom I take refuge.</verse>
<verse>He will repay them for their sins and destroy them for their wickedness; the LORD our God will destroy them.</verse>
</chapter>