<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Song of Solomon" book-id="22" n="1">
<verse>The Song of Songs, which is Solomon's.</verse>
<verse>"May he kiss me with the kisses of his mouth! For your love is better than wine.</verse>
<verse>"Your oils have a pleasing fragrance, Your name is like purified oil; Therefore the maidens love you.</verse>
<verse>"Draw me after you and let us run together! The king has brought me into his chambers. We will rejoice in you and be glad; We will extol your love more than wine. Rightly do they love you."</verse>
<verse>"I am black but lovely, O daughters of Jerusalem, Like the tents of Kedar, Like the curtains of Solomon.</verse>
<verse>"Do not stare at me because I am swarthy, For the sun has burned me. My mother's sons were angry with me; They made me caretaker of the vineyards, But I have not taken care of my own vineyard.</verse>
<verse>"Tell me, O you whom my soul loves, Where do you pasture your flock, Where do you make it lie down at noon? For why should I be like one who veils herself Beside the flocks of your companions?"</verse>
<verse>"If you yourself do not know, Most beautiful among women, Go forth on the trail of the flock And pasture your young goats By the tents of the shepherds.</verse>
<verse>"To me, my darling, you are like My mare among the chariots of Pharaoh.</verse>
<verse>"Your cheeks are lovely with ornaments, Your neck with strings of beads."</verse>
<verse>"We will make for you ornaments of gold With beads of silver."</verse>
<verse>"While the king was at his table, My perfume gave forth its fragrance.</verse>
<verse>"My beloved is to me a pouch of myrrh Which lies all night between my breasts.</verse>
<verse>"My beloved is to me a cluster of henna blossoms In the vineyards of Engedi."</verse>
<verse>"How beautiful you are, my darling, How beautiful you are! Your eyes are like doves."</verse>
<verse>"How handsome you are, my beloved, And so pleasant! Indeed, our couch is luxuriant!</verse>
<verse>"The beams of our houses are cedars, Our rafters, cypresses.</verse>
</chapter>