<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Song of Solomon" book-id="22" n="2">
<verse>"I am the rose of Sharon, The lily of the valleys."</verse>
<verse>"Like a lily among the thorns, So is my darling among the maidens."</verse>
<verse>"Like an apple tree among the trees of the forest, So is my beloved among the young men. In his shade I took great delight and sat down, And his fruit was sweet to my taste.</verse>
<verse>"He has brought me to his banquet hall, And his banner over me is love.</verse>
<verse>"Sustain me with raisin cakes, Refresh me with apples, Because I am lovesick.</verse>
<verse>"Let his left hand be under my head And his right hand embrace me."</verse>
<verse>"I adjure you, O daughters of Jerusalem, By the gazelles or by the hinds of the field, That you do not arouse or awaken my love Until she pleases."</verse>
<verse>"Listen! My beloved! Behold, he is coming, Climbing on the mountains, Leaping on the hills!</verse>
<verse>"My beloved is like a gazelle or a young stag. Behold, he is standing behind our wall, He is looking through the windows, He is peering through the lattice.</verse>
<verse>"My beloved responded and said to me, 'Arise, my darling, my beautiful one, And come along.</verse>
<verse>'For behold, the winter is past, The rain is over and gone.</verse>
<verse>'The flowers have already appeared in the land; The time has arrived for pruning the vines, And the voice of the turtledove has been heard in our land.</verse>
<verse>'The fig tree has ripened its figs, And the vines in blossom have given forth their fragrance. Arise, my darling, my beautiful one, And come along!'"</verse>
<verse>"O my dove, in the clefts of the rock, In the secret place of the steep pathway, Let me see your form, Let me hear your voice; For your voice is sweet, And your form is lovely."</verse>
<verse>"Catch the foxes for us, The little foxes that are ruining the vineyards, While our vineyards are in blossom."</verse>
<verse>"My beloved is mine, and I am his; He pastures his flock among the lilies.</verse>
<verse>"Until the cool of the day when the shadows flee away, Turn, my beloved, and be like a gazelle Or a young stag on the mountains of Bether."</verse>
</chapter>