<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Song of Solomon" book-id="22" n="5">
<verse>"I have come into my garden, my sister, my bride; I have gathered my myrrh along with my balsam. I have eaten my honeycomb and my honey; I have drunk my wine and my milk. Eat, friends; Drink and imbibe deeply, O lovers."</verse>
<verse>"I was asleep but my heart was awake. A voice! My beloved was knocking: 'Open to me, my sister, my darling, My dove, my perfect one! For my head is drenched with dew, My locks with the damp of the night.'</verse>
<verse>"I have taken off my dress, How can I put it on again? I have washed my feet, How can I dirty them again?</verse>
<verse>"My beloved extended his hand through the opening, And my feelings were aroused for him.</verse>
<verse>"I arose to open to my beloved; And my hands dripped with myrrh, And my fingers with liquid myrrh, On the handles of the bolt.</verse>
<verse>"I opened to my beloved, But my beloved had turned away and had gone! My heart went out to him as he spoke. I searched for him but I did not find him; I called him but he did not answer me.</verse>
<verse>"The watchmen who make the rounds in the city found me, They struck me and wounded me; The guardsmen of the walls took away my shawl from me.</verse>
<verse>"I adjure you, O daughters of Jerusalem, If you find my beloved, As to what you will tell him: For I am lovesick."</verse>
<verse>"What kind of beloved is your beloved, O most beautiful among women? What kind of beloved is your beloved, That thus you adjure us?"</verse>
<verse>"My beloved is dazzling and ruddy, Outstanding among ten thousand.</verse>
<verse>"His head is like gold, pure gold; His locks are like clusters of dates And black as a raven.</verse>
<verse>"His eyes are like doves Beside streams of water, Bathed in milk, And reposed in their setting.</verse>
<verse>"His cheeks are like a bed of balsam, Banks of sweet-scented herbs; His lips are lilies Dripping with liquid myrrh.</verse>
<verse>"His hands are rods of gold Set with beryl; His abdomen is carved ivory Inlaid with sapphires.</verse>
<verse>"His legs are pillars of alabaster Set on pedestals of pure gold; His appearance is like Lebanon Choice as the cedars.</verse>
<verse>"His mouth is full of sweetness. And he is wholly desirable. This is my beloved and this is my friend, O daughters of Jerusalem."</verse>
</chapter>