<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Song of Solomon" book-id="22" n="8">
<verse>"Oh that you were like a brother to me Who nursed at my mother's breasts. If I found you outdoors, I would kiss you; No one would despise me, either.</verse>
<verse>"I would lead you and bring you Into the house of my mother, who used to instruct me; I would give you spiced wine to drink from the juice of my pomegranates.</verse>
<verse>"Let his left hand be under my head And his right hand embrace me."</verse>
<verse>"I want you to swear, O daughters of Jerusalem, Do not arouse or awaken my love Until she pleases."</verse>
<verse>"Who is this coming up from the wilderness Leaning on her beloved? Beneath the apple tree I awakened you; There your mother was in labor with you, There she was in labor and gave you birth.</verse>
<verse>"Put me like a seal over your heart, Like a seal on your arm. For love is as strong as death, Jealousy is as severe as Sheol; Its flashes are flashes of fire, The very flame of the LORD.</verse>
<verse>"Many waters cannot quench love, Nor will rivers overflow it; If a man were to give all the riches of his house for love, It would be utterly despised."</verse>
<verse>"We have a little sister, And she has no breasts; What shall we do for our sister On the day when she is spoken for?</verse>
<verse>"If she is a wall, We will build on her a battlement of silver; But if she is a door, We will barricade her with planks of cedar."</verse>
<verse>"I was a wall, and my breasts were like towers; Then I became in his eyes as one who finds peace.</verse>
<verse>"Solomon had a vineyard at Baal-hamon; He entrusted the vineyard to caretakers. Each one was to bring a thousand shekels of silver for its fruit.</verse>
<verse>"My very own vineyard is at my disposal; The thousand shekels are for you, Solomon, And two hundred are for those who take care of its fruit."</verse>
<verse>"O you who sit in the gardens, My companions are listening for your voice--Let me hear it!"</verse>
<verse>"Hurry, my beloved, And be like a gazelle or a young stag On the mountains of spices."</verse>
</chapter>