<?xml version="1.0"?>
<chapter translation="KJV" testament="New" book="1 John" n="5" book_id="62">
      <verse>Whosoever believeth that Jesus is the Christ is born of God: and every one that loveth him that begat loveth him also that is begotten of him.
</verse><verse>By this we know that we love the children of God, when we love God, and keep his commandments.
</verse><verse>For this is the love of God, that we keep his commandments: and his commandments are not grievous.
</verse><verse>For whatsoever is born of God overcometh the world: and this is the victory that overcometh the world, <supplied>even</supplied> our faith.
</verse><verse>Who is he that overcometh the world, but he that believeth that Jesus is the Son of God?
</verse><verse>This is he that came by water and blood, <supplied>even</supplied> Jesus Christ; not by water only, but by water and blood. And it is the Spirit that beareth witness, because the Spirit is truth.
</verse><verse>For there are three that bear record in heaven, the Father, the Word, and the Holy Ghost: and these three are one.
</verse><verse>And there are three that bear witness in earth, the spirit, and the water, and the blood: and these three agree in one.
</verse><verse>If we receive the witness of men, the witness of God is greater: for this is the witness of God which he hath testified of his Son.
</verse><verse>He that believeth on the Son of God hath the witness in himself: he that believeth not God hath made him a liar; because he believeth not the record that God gave of his Son.
</verse><verse>And this is the record, that God hath given to us eternal life, and this life is in his Son.
</verse><verse>He that hath the Son hath life; <supplied>and</supplied> he that hath not the Son of God hath not life.
</verse><verse>These things have I written unto you that believe on the name of the Son of God; that ye may know that ye have eternal life, and that ye may believe on the name of the Son of God.
</verse><verse>And this is the confidence that we have in him, that, if we ask any thing according to his will, he heareth us:
</verse><verse>And if we know that he hear us, whatsoever we ask, we know that we have the petitions that we desired of him.
</verse><verse>If any man see his brother sin a sin <supplied>which is</supplied> not unto death, he shall ask, and he shall give him life for them that sin not unto death. There is a sin unto death: I do not say that he shall pray for it.
</verse><verse>All unrighteousness is sin: and there is a sin not unto death.
</verse><verse>We know that whosoever is born of God sinneth not; but he that is begotten of God keepeth himself, and that wicked one toucheth him not.
</verse><verse>And we know that we are of God, and the whole world lieth in wickedness.
</verse><verse><supplied>And</supplied> we know that the Son of God is come, and hath given us an understanding, that we may know him that is true, and we are in him that is true, <supplied>even</supplied> in his Son Jesus Christ. This is the true God, and eternal life.
</verse><verse>Little children, keep yourselves from idols. Amen.
     
     
      </verse>
      </chapter>
