<chapter translation="NASB" testament="New" book="1 John" book_id="62" n="5">
<verse>Whoever believes that Jesus is the Christ is born of God, and whoever loves the Father loves the child born of Him.</verse>
<verse>By this we know that we love the children of God, when we love God and observe His commandments.</verse>
<verse>For this is the love of God, that we keep His commandments; and His commandments are not burdensome.</verse>
<verse>For whatever is born of God overcomes the world; and this is the victory that has overcome the world--our faith.</verse>
<verse>Who is the one who overcomes the world, but he who believes that Jesus is the Son of God?</verse>
<verse>This is the One who came by water and blood, Jesus Christ; not with the water only, but with the water and with the blood. It is the Spirit who testifies, because the Spirit is the truth.</verse>
<verse>For there are three that testify:</verse>
<verse>the Spirit and the water and the blood; and the three are in agreement.</verse>
<verse>If we receive the testimony of men, the testimony of God is greater; for the testimony of God is this, that He has testified concerning His Son.</verse>
<verse>The one who believes in the Son of God has the testimony in himself; the one who does not believe God has made Him a liar, because he has not believed in the testimony that God has given concerning His Son.</verse>
<verse>And the testimony is this, that God has given us eternal life, and this life is in His Son.</verse>
<verse>He who has the Son has the life; he who does not have the Son of God does not have the life.</verse>
<verse>These things I have written to you who believe in the name of the Son of God, so that you may know that you have eternal life.</verse>
<verse>This is the confidence which we have before Him, that, if we ask anything according to His will, He hears us.</verse>
<verse>And if we know that He hears us in whatever we ask, we know that we have the requests which we have asked from Him.</verse>
<verse>If anyone sees his brother committing a sin not leading to death, he shall ask and God will for him give life to those who commit sin not leading to death. There is a sin leading to death; I do not say that he should make request for this.</verse>
<verse>All unrighteousness is sin, and there is a sin not leading to death.</verse>
<verse>We know that no one who is born of God sins; but He who was born of God keeps him, and the evil one does not touch him.</verse>
<verse>We know that we are of God, and that the whole world lies in the power of the evil one.</verse>
<verse>And we know that the Son of God has come, and has given us understanding so that we may know Him who is true; and we are in Him who is true, in His Son Jesus Christ. This is the true God and eternal life.</verse>
<verse>Little children, guard yourselves from idols.</verse>
</chapter>