<chapter translation="NIV" testament="New" book="Ephesians" book_id="49" n="3">
<verse>For this reason I, Paul, the prisoner of Christ Jesus for the sake of you Gentiles--</verse>
<verse>Surely you have heard about the administration of God's grace that was given to me for you,</verse>
<verse>that is, the mystery made known to me by revelation, as I have already written briefly.</verse>
<verse>In reading this, then, you will be able to understand my insight into the mystery of Christ,</verse>
<verse>which was not made known to men in other generations as it has now been revealed by the Spirit to God's holy apostles and prophets.</verse>
<verse>This mystery is that through the gospel the Gentiles are heirs together with Israel, members together of one body, and sharers together in the promise in Christ Jesus.</verse>
<verse>I became a servant of this gospel by the gift of God's grace given me through the working of his power.</verse>
<verse>Although I am less than the least of all God's people, this grace was given me: to preach to the Gentiles the unsearchable riches of Christ,</verse>
<verse>and to make plain to everyone the administration of this mystery, which for ages past was kept hidden in God, who created all things.</verse>
<verse>His intent was that now, through the church, the manifold wisdom of God should be made known to the rulers and authorities in the heavenly realms,</verse>
<verse>according to his eternal purpose which he accomplished in Christ Jesus our Lord.</verse>
<verse>In him and through faith in him we may approach God with freedom and confidence.</verse>
<verse>I ask you, therefore, not to be discouraged because of my sufferings for you, which are your glory.</verse>
<verse>For this reason I kneel before the Father,</verse>
<verse>from whom his whole family in heaven and on earth derives its name.</verse>
<verse>I pray that out of his glorious riches he may strengthen you with power through his Spirit in your inner being,</verse>
<verse>so that Christ may dwell in your hearts through faith. And I pray that you, being rooted and established in love,</verse>
<verse>may have power, together with all the saints, to grasp how wide and long and high and deep is the love of Christ,</verse>
<verse>and to know this love that surpasses knowledge--that you may be filled to the measure of all the fullness of God.</verse>
<verse>Now to him who is able to do immeasurably more than all we ask or imagine, according to his power that is at work within us,</verse>
<verse>to him be glory in the church and in Christ Jesus throughout all generations, for ever and ever! Amen.</verse>
</chapter>