<chapter translation="NIV" testament="New" book="Ephesians" book-id="49" n="5">
<verse>Be imitators of God, therefore, as dearly loved children</verse>
<verse>and live a life of love, just as Christ loved us and gave himself up for us as a fragrant offering and sacrifice to God.</verse>
<verse>But among you there must not be even a hint of sexual immorality, or of any kind of impurity, or of greed, because these are improper for God's holy people.</verse>
<verse>Nor should there be obscenity, foolish talk or coarse joking, which are out of place, but rather thanksgiving.</verse>
<verse>For of this you can be sure: No immoral, impure or greedy person--such a man is an idolater--has any inheritance in the kingdom of Christ and of God.</verse>
<verse>Let no one deceive you with empty words, for because of such things God's wrath comes on those who are disobedient.</verse>
<verse>Therefore do not be partners with them.</verse>
<verse>For you were once darkness, but now you are light in the Lord. Live as children of light</verse>
<verse>(for the fruit of the light consists in all goodness, righteousness and truth)</verse>
<verse>and find out what pleases the Lord.</verse>
<verse>Have nothing to do with the fruitless deeds of darkness, but rather expose them.</verse>
<verse>For it is shameful even to mention what the disobedient do in secret.</verse>
<verse>But everything exposed by the light becomes visible,</verse>
<verse>for it is light that makes everything visible. This is why it is said: "Wake up, O sleeper, rise from the dead, and Christ will shine on you."</verse>
<verse>Be very careful, then, how you live--not as unwise but as wise,</verse>
<verse>making the most of every opportunity, because the days are evil.</verse>
<verse>Therefore do not be foolish, but understand what the Lord's will is.</verse>
<verse>Do not get drunk on wine, which leads to debauchery. Instead, be filled with the Spirit.</verse>
<verse>Speak to one another with psalms, hymns and spiritual songs. Sing and make music in your heart to the Lord,</verse>
<verse>always giving thanks to God the Father for everything, in the name of our Lord Jesus Christ.</verse>
<verse>Submit to one another out of reverence for Christ.</verse>
<verse>Wives, submit to your husbands as to the Lord.</verse>
<verse>For the husband is the head of the wife as Christ is the head of the church, his body, of which he is the Savior.</verse>
<verse>Now as the church submits to Christ, so also wives should submit to their husbands in everything.</verse>
<verse>Husbands, love your wives, just as Christ loved the church and gave himself up for her</verse>
<verse>to make her holy, cleansing her by the washing with water through the word,</verse>
<verse>and to present her to himself as a radiant church, without stain or wrinkle or any other blemish, but holy and blameless.</verse>
<verse>In this same way, husbands ought to love their wives as their own bodies. He who loves his wife loves himself.</verse>
<verse>After all, no one ever hated his own body, but he feeds and cares for it, just as Christ does the church--</verse>
<verse>for we are members of his body.</verse>
<verse>"For this reason a man will leave his father and mother and be united to his wife, and the two will become one flesh."</verse>
<verse>This is a profound mystery--but I am talking about Christ and the church.</verse>
<verse>However, each one of you also must love his wife as he loves himself, and the wife must respect her husband.</verse>
</chapter>