<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Esther" book-id="17" n="5">
<verse>Three days later Esther dressed in her royal robes and took up a position in the inner court of the palace in front of the king's throne room. The king was on his throne facing the entrance.</verse>
<verse>When he noticed Queen Esther standing in the court, he was pleased to see her; the king extended the gold scepter in his hand. Esther approached and touched the tip of the scepter.</verse>
<verse>The king asked, "And what's your desire, Queen Esther? What do you want? Ask and it's yours--even if it's half my kingdom!"</verse>
<verse>"If it please the king," said Esther, "let the king come with Haman to a dinner I've prepared for him."</verse>
<verse>"Get Haman at once," said the king, "so we can go to dinner with Esther." So the king and Haman joined Esther at the dinner she had arranged.</verse>
<verse>As they were drinking the wine, the king said, "Now, what is it you want? Half of my kingdom isn't too much to ask! Just ask."</verse>
<verse>Esther answered, "Here's what I want.</verse>
<verse>If the king favors me and is pleased to do what I desire and ask, let the king and Haman come again tomorrow to the dinner that I will fix for them. Then I'll give a straight answer to the king's question." W+</verse>
<verse>Haman left the palace that day happy, beaming. And then he saw Mordecai sitting at the King's Gate ignoring him, oblivious to him. Haman was furious with Mordecai.</verse>
<verse>But he held himself in and went on home. He got his friends together with his wife Zeresh</verse>
<verse>and started bragging about how much money he had, his many sons, all the times the king had honored him, and his promotion to the highest position in the government.</verse>
<verse>"On top of all that," Haman continued, "Queen Esther invited me to a private dinner she gave for the king, just the three of us. And she's invited me to another one tomorrow.</verse>
<verse>But I can't enjoy any of it when I see Mordecai the Jew sitting at the King's Gate."</verse>
<verse>His wife Zeresh and all his friends said, "Build a gallows seventy-five feet high. First thing in the morning speak with the king; get him to order Mordecai hanged on it. Then happily go with the king to dinner." Haman liked that. He had the gallows built. [JC]</verse>
</chapter>