<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="1 Chronicles" book-id="13" n="1">
<verse>Adam, Seth, Enosh,</verse>
<verse>Kenan, Mahalalel, Jared,</verse>
<verse>Enoch, Methuselah, Lamech, Noah.</verse>
<verse>The sons of Noah: Shem, Ham and Japheth. The Japhethites</verse>
<verse>The sons of Japheth: Gomer, Magog, Madai, Javan, Tubal, Meshech and Tiras.</verse>
<verse>The sons of Gomer: Ashkenaz, Riphath and Togarmah.</verse>
<verse>The sons of Javan: Elishah, Tarshish, the Kittim and the Rodanim. The Hamites</verse>
<verse>The sons of Ham: Cush, Mizraim, Put and Canaan.</verse>
<verse>The sons of Cush: Seba, Havilah, Sabta, Raamah and Sabteca. The sons of Raamah: Sheba and Dedan.</verse>
<verse>Cush was the father of Nimrod, who grew to be a mighty warrior on earth.</verse>
<verse>Mizraim was the father of the Ludites, Anamites, Lehabites, Naphtuhites,</verse>
<verse>Pathrusites, Casluhites (from whom the Philistines came) and Caphtorites.</verse>
<verse>Canaan was the father of Sidon his firstborn, and of the Hittites,</verse>
<verse>Jebusites, Amorites, Girgashites,</verse>
<verse>Hivites, Arkites, Sinites,</verse>
<verse>Arvadites, Zemarites and Hamathites. The Semites</verse>
<verse>The sons of Shem: Elam, Asshur, Arphaxad, Lud and Aram. The sons of Aram: Uz, Hul, Gether and Meshech.</verse>
<verse>Arphaxad was the father of Shelah, and Shelah the father of Eber.</verse>
<verse>Two sons were born to Eber: One was named Peleg, because in his time the earth was divided; his brother was named Joktan.</verse>
<verse>Joktan was the father of Almodad, Sheleph, Hazarmaveth, Jerah,</verse>
<verse>Hadoram, Uzal, Diklah,</verse>
<verse>Obal, Abimael, Sheba,</verse>
<verse>Ophir, Havilah and Jobab. All these were sons of Joktan.</verse>
<verse>Shem, Arphaxad, Shelah,</verse>
<verse>Eber, Peleg, Reu,</verse>
<verse>Serug, Nahor, Terah</verse>
<verse>and Abram (that is, Abraham).</verse>
<verse>The sons of Abraham: Isaac and Ishmael. Descendants of Hagar</verse>
<verse>These were their descendants: Nebaioth the firstborn of Ishmael, Kedar, Adbeel, Mibsam,</verse>
<verse>Mishma, Dumah, Massa, Hadad, Tema,</verse>
<verse>Jetur, Naphish and Kedemah. These were the sons of Ishmael. Descendants of Keturah</verse>
<verse>The sons born to Keturah, Abraham's concubine: Zimran, Jokshan, Medan, Midian, Ishbak and Shuah. The sons of Jokshan: Sheba and Dedan.</verse>
<verse>The sons of Midian: Ephah, Epher, Hanoch, Abida and Eldaah. All these were descendants of Keturah. Descendants of Sarah</verse>
<verse>Abraham was the father of Isaac. The sons of Isaac: Esau and Israel.</verse>
<verse>The sons of Esau: Eliphaz, Reuel, Jeush, Jalam and Korah.</verse>
<verse>The sons of Eliphaz: Teman, Omar, Zepho, Gatam and Kenaz; by Timna: Amalek.</verse>
<verse>The sons of Reuel: Nahath, Zerah, Shammah and Mizzah. The People of Seir in Edom</verse>
<verse>The sons of Seir: Lotan, Shobal, Zibeon, Anah, Dishon, Ezer and Dishan.</verse>
<verse>The sons of Lotan: Hori and Homam. Timna was Lotan's sister.</verse>
<verse>The sons of Shobal: Alvan, Manahath, Ebal, Shepho and Onam. The sons of Zibeon: Aiah and Anah.</verse>
<verse>The son of Anah: Dishon. The sons of Dishon: Hemdan, Eshban, Ithran and Keran.</verse>
<verse>The sons of Ezer: Bilhan, Zaavan and Akan. The sons of Dishan: Uz and Aran. The Rulers of Edom</verse>
<verse>These were the kings who reigned in Edom before any Israelite king reigned: Bela son of Beor, whose city was named Dinhabah.</verse>
<verse>When Bela died, Jobab son of Zerah from Bozrah succeeded him as king.</verse>
<verse>When Jobab died, Husham from the land of the Temanites succeeded him as king.</verse>
<verse>When Husham died, Hadad son of Bedad, who defeated Midian in the country of Moab, succeeded him as king. His city was named Avith.</verse>
<verse>When Hadad died, Samlah from Masrekah succeeded him as king.</verse>
<verse>When Samlah died, Shaul from Rehoboth on the river succeeded him as king.</verse>
<verse>When Shaul died, Baal-Hanan son of Acbor succeeded him as king.</verse>
<verse>When Baal-Hanan died, Hadad succeeded him as king. His city was named Pau, and his wife's name was Mehetabel daughter of Matred, the daughter of Me-Zahab.</verse>
<verse>Hadad also died. The chiefs of Edom were: Timna, Alvah, Jetheth,</verse>
<verse>Oholibamah, Elah, Pinon,</verse>
<verse>Kenaz, Teman, Mibzar,</verse>
<verse>Magdiel and Iram. These were the chiefs of Edom.</verse>
</chapter>