<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="1 Chronicles" book-id="13" n="2">
<verse>These were the sons of Israel: Reuben, Simeon, Levi, Judah, Issachar, Zebulun,</verse>
<verse>Dan, Joseph, Benjamin, Naphtali, Gad and Asher.</verse>
<verse>The sons of Judah: Er, Onan and Shelah. These three were born to him by a Canaanite woman, the daughter of Shua. Er, Judah's firstborn, was wicked in the LORD's sight; so the LORD put him to death.</verse>
<verse>Tamar, Judah's daughter-in-law, bore him Perez and Zerah. Judah had five sons in all.</verse>
<verse>The sons of Perez: Hezron and Hamul.</verse>
<verse>The sons of Zerah: Zimri, Ethan, Heman, Calcol and Darda -five in all.</verse>
<verse>The son of Carmi: Achar, who brought trouble on Israel by violating the ban on taking devoted things.</verse>
<verse>The son of Ethan: Azariah.</verse>
<verse>The sons born to Hezron were: Jerahmeel, Ram and Caleb. From Ram Son of Hezron</verse>
<verse>Ram was the father of Amminadab, and Amminadab the father of Nahshon, the leader of the people of Judah.</verse>
<verse>Nahshon was the father of Salmon, Salmon the father of Boaz,</verse>
<verse>Boaz the father of Obed and Obed the father of Jesse.</verse>
<verse>Jesse was the father of Eliab his firstborn; the second son was Abinadab, the third Shimea,</verse>
<verse>the fourth Nethanel, the fifth Raddai,</verse>
<verse>the sixth Ozem and the seventh David.</verse>
<verse>Their sisters were Zeruiah and Abigail. Zeruiah's three sons were Abishai, Joab and Asahel.</verse>
<verse>Abigail was the mother of Amasa, whose father was Jether the Ishmaelite. Caleb Son of Hezron</verse>
<verse>Caleb son of Hezron had children by his wife Azubah (and by Jerioth). These were her sons: Jesher, Shobab and Ardon.</verse>
<verse>When Azubah died, Caleb married Ephrath, who bore him Hur.</verse>
<verse>Hur was the father of Uri, and Uri the father of Bezalel.</verse>
<verse>Later, Hezron lay with the daughter of Makir the father of Gilead (he had married her when he was sixty years old), and she bore him Segub.</verse>
<verse>Segub was the father of Jair, who controlled twenty-three towns in Gilead.</verse>
<verse>(But Geshur and Aram captured Havvoth Jair, as well as Kenath with its surrounding settlements-sixty towns.) All these were descendants of Makir the father of Gilead.</verse>
<verse>After Hezron died in Caleb Ephrathah, Abijah the wife of Hezron bore him Ashhur the father of Tekoa. Jerahmeel Son of Hezron</verse>
<verse>The sons of Jerahmeel the firstborn of Hezron: Ram his firstborn, Bunah, Oren, Ozem and Ahijah.</verse>
<verse>Jerahmeel had another wife, whose name was Atarah; she was the mother of Onam.</verse>
<verse>The sons of Ram the firstborn of Jerahmeel: Maaz, Jamin and Eker.</verse>
<verse>The sons of Onam: Shammai and Jada. The sons of Shammai: Nadab and Abishur.</verse>
<verse>Abishur's wife was named Abihail, who bore him Ahban and Molid.</verse>
<verse>The sons of Nadab: Seled and Appaim. Seled died without children.</verse>
<verse>The son of Appaim: Ishi, who was the father of Sheshan. Sheshan was the father of Ahlai.</verse>
<verse>The sons of Jada, Shammai's brother: Jether and Jonathan. Jether died without children.</verse>
<verse>The sons of Jonathan: Peleth and Zaza. These were the descendants of Jerahmeel.</verse>
<verse>Sheshan had no sons-only daughters. He had an Egyptian servant named Jarha.</verse>
<verse>Sheshan gave his daughter in marriage to his servant Jarha, and she bore him Attai.</verse>
<verse>Attai was the father of Nathan, Nathan the father of Zabad,</verse>
<verse>Zabad the father of Ephlal, Ephlal the father of Obed,</verse>
<verse>Obed the father of Jehu, Jehu the father of Azariah,</verse>
<verse>Azariah the father of Helez, Helez the father of Eleasah,</verse>
<verse>Eleasah the father of Sismai, Sismai the father of Shallum,</verse>
<verse>Shallum the father of Jekamiah, and Jekamiah the father of Elishama. The Clans of Caleb</verse>
<verse>The sons of Caleb the brother of Jerahmeel: Mesha his firstborn, who was the father of Ziph, and his son Mareshah, who was the father of Hebron.</verse>
<verse>The sons of Hebron: Korah, Tappuah, Rekem and Shema.</verse>
<verse>Shema was the father of Raham, and Raham the father of Jorkeam. Rekem was the father of Shammai.</verse>
<verse>The son of Shammai was Maon, and Maon was the father of Beth Zur.</verse>
<verse>Caleb's concubine Ephah was the mother of Haran, Moza and Gazez. Haran was the father of Gazez.</verse>
<verse>The sons of Jahdai: Regem, Jotham, Geshan, Pelet, Ephah and Shaaph.</verse>
<verse>Caleb's concubine Maacah was the mother of Sheber and Tirhanah.</verse>
<verse>She also gave birth to Shaaph the father of Madmannah and to Sheva the father of Macbenah and Gibea. Caleb's daughter was Acsah.</verse>
<verse>These were the descendants of Caleb. The sons of Hur the firstborn of Ephrathah: Shobal the father of Kiriath Jearim,</verse>
<verse>Salma the father of Bethlehem, and Hareph the father of Beth Gader.</verse>
<verse>The descendants of Shobal the father of Kiriath Jearim were: Haroeh, half the Manahathites,</verse>
<verse>and the clans of Kiriath Jearim: the Ithrites, Puthites, Shumathites and Mishraites. From these descended the Zorathites and Eshtaolites.</verse>
<verse>The descendants of Salma: Bethlehem, the Netophathites, Atroth Beth Joab, half the Manahathites, the Zorites,</verse>
<verse>and the clans of scribes who lived at Jabez: the Tirathites, Shimeathites and Sucathites. These are the Kenites who came from Hammath, the father of the house of Recab.</verse>
</chapter>