<chapter translation="NIV" testament="Old" book="1 Chronicles" book-id="13" n="8">
<verse>Benjamin was the father of Bela his firstborn, Ashbel the second son, Aharah the third,</verse>
<verse>Nohah the fourth and Rapha the fifth.</verse>
<verse>The sons of Bela were: Addar, Gera, Abihud,</verse>
<verse>Abishua, Naaman, Ahoah,</verse>
<verse>Gera, Shephuphan and Huram.</verse>
<verse>These were the descendants of Ehud, who were heads of families of those living in Geba and were deported to Manahath:</verse>
<verse>Naaman, Ahijah, and Gera, who deported them and who was the father of Uzza and Ahihud.</verse>
<verse>Sons were born to Shaharaim in Moab after he had divorced his wives Hushim and Baara.</verse>
<verse>By his wife Hodesh he had Jobab, Zibia, Mesha, Malcam,</verse>
<verse>Jeuz, Sakia and Mirmah. These were his sons, heads of families.</verse>
<verse>By Hushim he had Abitub and Elpaal.</verse>
<verse>The sons of Elpaal: Eber, Misham, Shemed (who built Ono and Lod with its surrounding villages),</verse>
<verse>and Beriah and Shema, who were heads of families of those living in Aijalon and who drove out the inhabitants of Gath.</verse>
<verse>Ahio, Shashak, Jeremoth,</verse>
<verse>Zebadiah, Arad, Eder,</verse>
<verse>Michael, Ishpah and Joha were the sons of Beriah.</verse>
<verse>Zebadiah, Meshullam, Hizki, Heber,</verse>
<verse>Ishmerai, Izliah and Jobab were the sons of Elpaal.</verse>
<verse>Jakim, Zicri, Zabdi,</verse>
<verse>Elienai, Zillethai, Eliel,</verse>
<verse>Adaiah, Beraiah and Shimrath were the sons of Shimei.</verse>
<verse>Ishpan, Eber, Eliel,</verse>
<verse>Abdon, Zicri, Hanan,</verse>
<verse>Hananiah, Elam, Anthothijah,</verse>
<verse>Iphdeiah and Penuel were the sons of Shashak.</verse>
<verse>Shamsherai, Shehariah, Athaliah,</verse>
<verse>Jaareshiah, Elijah and Zicri were the sons of Jeroham.</verse>
<verse>All these were heads of families, chiefs as listed in their genealogy, and they lived in Jerusalem.</verse>
<verse>Jeiel the father of Gibeon lived in Gibeon. His wife's name was Maacah,</verse>
<verse>and his firstborn son was Abdon, followed by Zur, Kish, Baal, Ner, Nadab,</verse>
<verse>Gedor, Ahio, Zeker</verse>
<verse>and Mikloth, who was the father of Shimeah. They too lived near their relatives in Jerusalem.</verse>
<verse>Ner was the father of Kish, Kish the father of Saul, and Saul the father of Jonathan, Malki-Shua, Abinadab and Esh-Baal.</verse>
<verse>The son of Jonathan: Merib-Baal, who was the father of Micah.</verse>
<verse>The sons of Micah: Pithon, Melech, Tarea and Ahaz.</verse>
<verse>Ahaz was the father of Jehoaddah, Jehoaddah was the father of Alemeth, Azmaveth and Zimri, and Zimri was the father of Moza.</verse>
<verse>Moza was the father of Binea; Raphah was his son, Eleasah his son and Azel his son.</verse>
<verse>Azel had six sons, and these were their names: Azrikam, Bokeru, Ishmael, Sheariah, Obadiah and Hanan. All these were the sons of Azel.</verse>
<verse>The sons of his brother Eshek: Ulam his firstborn, Jeush the second son and Eliphelet the third.</verse>
<verse>The sons of Ulam were brave warriors who could handle the bow. They had many sons and grandsons-150 in all. All these were the descendants of Benjamin.</verse>
</chapter>