<?xml version="1.0"?>
<chapter translation="KJV" testament="Old" book="2 Samuel" n="18">
      <verse>And David numbered the people that <supplied>were</supplied> with him, and set captains of thousands and captains of hundreds over them.
</verse><verse>And David sent forth a third part of the people under the hand of Joab, and a third part under the hand of Abishai the son of Zeruiah, Joab&#x2019;s brother, and a third part under the hand of Ittai the Gittite. And the king said unto the people, I
will surely go forth with you myself also.
</verse><verse>But the people answered, Thou shalt not go forth: for if we flee away, they will not care for us; neither if half of us die, will they care for us: but now <supplied>thou art</supplied> worth ten thousand of us: therefore now <supplied>it is</supplied> better that thou
succour us out of the city.
</verse><verse>And the king said unto them, What seemeth you best I will do. And the king stood by the gate side, and all the people came out by hundreds and by thousands.
</verse><verse>And the king commanded Joab and Abishai and Ittai, saying, <supplied>Deal</supplied> gently for my sake with the young man, <supplied>even</supplied> with Absalom. And all the people heard when the king gave all the captains charge concerning Absalom.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>So the people went out into the field against Israel: and the battle was in the wood of Ephraim;
</verse><verse>Where the people of Israel were slain before the servants of David, and there was there a great slaughter that day of twenty thousand <supplied>men. </supplied></verse><verse>For the battle was there scattered over the face of all the country: and the wood devoured
more people that day than the sword devoured.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>And Absalom met the servants of David. And Absalom rode upon a mule, and the mule went under the thick boughs of a great oak, and his head caught hold of the oak, and he was taken up between the heaven and the earth; and the mule that
<supplied>was</supplied> under him went away.
</verse><verse>And a certain man saw it, and told Joab, and said, Behold, I saw Absalom hanged in an oak.
</verse><verse>And Joab said unto the man that told him, And, behold, thou sawest <supplied>him,</supplied> and why didst thou not smite him there to the ground? and I would have given thee ten <supplied>shekels</supplied> of silver, and a girdle.
</verse><verse>And the man said unto Joab, Though I should receive a thousand <supplied>shekels</supplied> of silver in mine hand, yet would I not put forth mine hand against the king&#x2019;s son: for in our hearing the king charged thee and Abishai and Ittai, saying, Beware
that none <supplied>touch</supplied> the young man Absalom.
</verse><verse>Otherwise I should have wrought falsehood against mine own life: for there is no matter hid from the king, and thou thyself wouldest have set thyself against <supplied>me. </supplied></verse><verse>Then said Joab, I may not tarry thus with thee. And he took three
darts in his hand, and thrust them through the heart of Absalom, while he <supplied>was</supplied> yet alive in the midst of the oak.
</verse><verse>And ten young men that bare Joab&#x2019;s armour compassed about and smote Absalom, and slew him.
</verse><verse>And Joab blew the trumpet, and the people returned from pursuing after Israel: for Joab held back the people.
</verse><verse>And they took Absalom, and cast him into a great pit in the wood, and laid a very great heap of stones upon him: and all Israel fled every one to his tent.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>Now Absalom in his lifetime had taken and reared up for himself a pillar, which <supplied>is</supplied> in the king&#x2019;s dale: for he said, I have no son to keep my name in remembrance: and he called the pillar after his own name: and it is called unto this
day, Absalom&#x2019;s place.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>Then said Ahimaaz the son of Zadok, Let me now run, and bear the king tidings, how that the LORD hath avenged him of his enemies.
</verse><verse>And Joab said unto him, Thou shalt not bear tidings this day, but thou shalt bear tidings another day: but this day thou shalt bear no tidings, because the king&#x2019;s son is dead.
</verse><verse>Then said Joab to Cushi, Go tell the king what thou hast seen. And Cushi bowed himself unto Joab, and ran.
</verse><verse>Then said Ahimaaz the son of Zadok yet again to Joab, But howsoever, let me, I pray thee, also run after Cushi. And Joab said, Wherefore wilt thou run, my son, seeing that thou hast no tidings ready?
</verse><verse>But howsoever, <supplied>said he,</supplied> let me run. And he said unto him, Run. Then Ahimaaz ran by the way of the plain, and overran Cushi.
</verse><verse>And David sat between the two gates: and the watchman went up to the roof over the gate unto the wall, and lifted up his eyes, and looked, and behold a man running alone.
</verse><verse>And the watchman cried, and told the king. And the king said, If he <supplied>be</supplied> alone, <supplied>there is</supplied> tidings in his mouth. And he came apace, and drew near.
</verse><verse>And the watchman saw another man running: and the watchman called unto the porter, and said, Behold <supplied>another</supplied> man running alone. And the king said, He also bringeth tidings.
</verse><verse>And the watchman said, Me thinketh the running of the foremost is like the running of Ahimaaz the son of Zadok. And the king said, He <supplied>is</supplied> a good man, and cometh with good tidings.
</verse><verse>And Ahimaaz called, and said unto the king, All is well. And he fell down to the earth upon his face before the king, and said, Blessed <supplied>be</supplied> the LORD thy God, which hath delivered up the men that lifted up their hand against my lord the
king.
</verse><verse>And the king said, Is the young man Absalom safe? And Ahimaaz answered, When Joab sent the king&#x2019;s servant, and <supplied>me</supplied> thy servant, I saw a great tumult, but I knew not what <supplied>it was. </supplied></verse><verse>And the king said <supplied>unto him,</supplied> Turn
aside, <supplied>and</supplied> stand here. And he turned aside, and stood still.
</verse><verse>And, behold, Cushi came; and Cushi said, Tidings, my lord the king: for the LORD hath avenged thee this day of all them that rose up against thee.
</verse><verse>And the king said unto Cushi, Is the young man Absalom safe? And Cushi answered, The enemies of my lord the king, and all that rise against thee to do <supplied>thee</supplied> hurt, be as <supplied>that</supplied> young man <supplied>is.</supplied>
     
      </verse>
      <verse>And the king was much moved, and went up to the chamber over the gate, and wept: and as he went, thus he said, O my son Absalom, my son, my son Absalom! would God I had died for thee, O Absalom, my son, my son!
     
      </verse>
      </chapter>
