<chapter translation="NIV" testament="New" book="James" book_id="59" n="2">
<verse>My brothers, as believers in our glorious Lord Jesus Christ, don't show favoritism.</verse>
<verse>Suppose a man comes into your meeting wearing a gold ring and fine clothes, and a poor man in shabby clothes also comes in.</verse>
<verse>If you show special attention to the man wearing fine clothes and say, "Here's a good seat for you," but say to the poor man, "You stand there" or "Sit on the floor by my feet,"</verse>
<verse>have you not discriminated among yourselves and become judges with evil thoughts?</verse>
<verse>Listen, my dear brothers: Has not God chosen those who are poor in the eyes of the world to be rich in faith and to inherit the kingdom he promised those who love him?</verse>
<verse>But you have insulted the poor. Is it not the rich who are exploiting you? Are they not the ones who are dragging you into court?</verse>
<verse>Are they not the ones who are slandering the noble name of him to whom you belong?</verse>
<verse>If you really keep the royal law found in Scripture, "Love your neighbor as yourself," you are doing right.</verse>
<verse>But if you show favoritism, you sin and are convicted by the law as lawbreakers.</verse>
<verse>For whoever keeps the whole law and yet stumbles at just one point is guilty of breaking all of it.</verse>
<verse>For he who said, "Do not commit adultery," also said, "Do not murder." If you do not commit adultery but do commit murder, you have become a lawbreaker.</verse>
<verse>Speak and act as those who are going to be judged by the law that gives freedom,</verse>
<verse>because judgment without mercy will be shown to anyone who has not been merciful. Mercy triumphs over judgment!</verse>
<verse>What good is it, my brothers, if a man claims to have faith but has no deeds? Can such faith save him?</verse>
<verse>Suppose a brother or sister is without clothes and daily food.</verse>
<verse>If one of you says to him, "Go, I wish you well; keep warm and well fed," but does nothing about his physical needs, what good is it?</verse>
<verse>In the same way, faith by itself, if it is not accompanied by action, is dead.</verse>
<verse>But someone will say, "You have faith; I have deeds." Show me your faith without deeds, and I will show you my faith by what I do.</verse>
<verse>You believe that there is one God. Good! Even the demons believe that--and shudder.</verse>
<verse>You foolish man, do you want evidence that faith without deeds is useless?</verse>
<verse>Was not our ancestor Abraham considered righteous for what he did when he offered his son Isaac on the altar?</verse>
<verse>You see that his faith and his actions were working together, and his faith was made complete by what he did.</verse>
<verse>And the scripture was fulfilled that says, "Abraham believed God, and it was credited to him as righteousness," and he was called God's friend.</verse>
<verse>You see that a person is justified by what he does and not by faith alone.</verse>
<verse>In the same way, was not even Rahab the prostitute considered righteous for what she did when she gave lodging to the spies and sent them off in a different direction?</verse>
<verse>As the body without the spirit is dead, so faith without deeds is dead.</verse>
</chapter>