<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Judges" book-id="7" n="13">
<verse>And then the People of Israel were back at it again, doing what was evil in GOD's sight. GOD put them under the domination of the Philistines for forty years.</verse>
<verse>At that time there was a man named Manoah from Zorah from the tribe of Dan. His wife was barren and childless.</verse>
<verse>The angel of God appeared to her and told her, "I know that you are barren and childless, but you're going to become pregnant and bear a son.</verse>
<verse>But take much care: Drink no wine or beer; eat nothing ritually unclean.</verse>
<verse>You are, in fact, pregnant right now, carrying a son. No razor will touch his head--the boy will be GOD's Nazirite from the moment of his birth. He will launch the deliverance from Philistine oppression."</verse>
<verse>The woman went to her husband and said, "A man of God came to me. He looked like the angel of God--terror laced with glory! I didn't ask him where he was from and he didn't tell me his name,</verse>
<verse>but he told me, 'You're pregnant. You're going to give birth to a son. Don't drink any wine or beer and eat nothing ritually unclean. The boy will be God's Nazirite from the moment of birth to the day of his death.'"</verse>
<verse>Manoah prayed to GOD: "Master, let the man of God you sent come to us again and teach us how to raise this boy who is to be born."</verse>
<verse>God listened to Manoah. God's angel came again to the woman. She was sitting in the field; her husband Manoah wasn't there with her.</verse>
<verse>She jumped to her feet and ran and told her husband: "He's back! The man who came to me that day!"</verse>
<verse>Manoah got up and, following his wife, came to the man. He said to him, "Are you the man who spoke to my wife?" He said, "I am."</verse>
<verse>Manoah said, "So. When what you say comes true, what do you have to tell us about this boy and his work?"</verse>
<verse>The angel of God said to Manoah,</verse>
<verse>"Keep in mind everything I told the woman. Eat nothing that comes from the vine: Drink no wine or beer; eat no ritually unclean foods. She's to observe everything I commanded her."</verse>
<verse>Manoah said to the angel of God, "Please, stay with us a little longer; we'll prepare a meal for you--a young goat."</verse>
<verse>GOD's angel said to Manoah, "Even if I stay, I won't eat your food. But if you want to prepare a Whole-Burnt-Offering for GOD, go ahead--offer it!" Manoah had no idea that he was talking to the angel of God.</verse>
<verse>Then Manoah asked the angel of God, "What's your name? When your words come true, we'd like to honor you."</verse>
<verse>The angel of GOD said, "What's this? You ask for my name? You wouldn't understand--it's sheer wonder."</verse>
<verse>So Manoah took the kid and the Grain-Offering and sacrificed them on a rock altar to GOD who works wonders.</verse>
<verse>As the flames leapt up from the altar to heaven, GOD's angel also ascended in the altar flames. When Manoah and his wife saw this, they fell facedown to the ground.</verse>
<verse>Manoah and his wife never saw the angel of GOD again. Only then did Manoah realize that this was GOD's angel.</verse>
<verse>He said to his wife, "We're as good as dead! We've looked on God!"</verse>
<verse>But his wife said, "If GOD were planning to kill us, he wouldn't have accepted our Whole-Burnt-Offering and Grain-Offering, or revealed all these things to us--given us this birth announcement."</verse>
<verse>The woman gave birth to a son. They named him Samson. The boy grew and GOD blessed him.</verse>
<verse>The Spirit of GOD began working in him while he was staying at a Danite camp between Zorah and Eshtaol. [JC]</verse>
</chapter>