<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="Judges" book-id="7" n="3">
<verse>These are the nations that GOD left there, using them to test the Israelites who had no experience in the Canaanite wars.</verse>
<verse>He did it to train the descendants of Israel, the ones who had no battle experience, in the art of war.</verse>
<verse>He left the five Philistine tyrants, all the Canaanites, the Sidonians, and the Hivites living on Mount Lebanon from Mount Baal Hermon to Hamath's Pass.</verse>
<verse>They were there to test Israel and see whether they would obey GOD's commands that were given to their parents through Moses.</verse>
<verse>But the People of Israel made themselves at home among the Canaanites, Hittites, Amorites, Perizzites, Hivites, and Jebusites.</verse>
<verse>They married their daughters and gave their own daughters to their sons in marriage. And they worshiped their gods.</verse>
<verse>The People of Israel did evil in GOD's sight. They forgot their GOD and worshiped the Baal gods and Asherah goddesses.</verse>
<verse>GOD's hot anger blazed against Israel. He sold them off to Cushan-Rishathaim king of Aram Naharaim. The People of Israel were in servitude to Cushan-Rishathaim for eight years.</verse>
<verse>The People of Israel cried out to GOD and GOD raised up a savior who rescued them: Caleb's nephew Othniel, son of his younger brother Kenaz.The Spirit of GOD came on him and he rallied Israel. He went out to war and GOD gave him Cushan-Rishathaim king of Aram Naharaim. Othniel made short work of him.</verse>
<verse/>
<verse>The land was quiet for forty years. Then Othniel son of Kenaz died.</verse>
<verse>But the People of Israel went back to doing evil in GOD's sight. So GOD made Eglon king of Moab a power against Israel because they did evil in GOD's sight.</verse>
<verse>He recruited the Ammonites and Amalekites and went out and struck Israel. They took the City of Palms.</verse>
<verse>The People of Israel were in servitude to Eglon fourteen years.</verse>
<verse>The People of Israel cried out to GOD and GOD raised up for them a savior, Ehud son of Gera, a Benjaminite. He was left-handed. The People of Israel sent tribute by him to Eglon king of Moab.</verse>
<verse>Ehud made himself a short two-edged sword and strapped it on his right thigh under his clothes.</verse>
<verse>He presented the tribute to Eglon king of Moab. Eglon was grossly fat.</verse>
<verse>After Ehud finished presenting the tribute, he went a little way with the men who had carried it.</verse>
<verse>But when he got as far as the stone images near Gilgal, he went back and said, "I have a private message for you, O king." The king told his servants, "Leave." They all left.</verse>
<verse>Ehud approached him--the king was now quite alone in his cool rooftop room--and said, "I have a word of God for you." Eglon stood up from his throne.</verse>
<verse>Ehud reached with his left hand and took his sword from his right thigh and plunged it into the king's big belly.</verse>
<verse>Not only the blade but the hilt went in. The fat closed in over it so he couldn't pull it out.</verse>
<verse>Ehud slipped out by way of the porch and shut and locked the doors of the rooftop room behind him.</verse>
<verse>Then he was gone. When the servants came, they saw with surprise that the doors to the rooftop room were locked. They said, "He's probably relieving himself in the restroom."</verse>
<verse>They waited. And then they worried--no one was coming out of those locked doors. Finally, they got a key and unlocked them. There was their master, fallen on the floor, dead!</verse>
<verse>While they were standing around wondering what to do, Ehud was long gone. He got past the stone images and escaped to Seirah.</verse>
<verse>When he got there, he sounded the trumpet on Mount Ephraim. The People of Israel came down from the hills and joined him. He took his place at their head.</verse>
<verse>He said, "Follow me, for GOD has given your enemies--yes, Moab!-to you." They went down after him and secured the fords of the Jordan against the Moabites. They let no one cross over.</verse>
<verse>At that time, they struck down about ten companies of Moabites, all of them well-fed and robust. Not one escaped.</verse>
<verse>That day Moab was subdued under the hand of Israel. The land was quiet for eighty years.</verse>
<verse>Shamgar son of Anath came after Ehud. Using a cattle prod, he killed six hundred Philistines single-handed. He too saved Israel.</verse>
</chapter>