<?xml version="1.0"?>
<chapter translation="KJV" testament="Old" book="Isaiah" n="1" book-id="23">
     
      <verse>The vision of Isaiah the son of Amoz, which he saw concerning Judah and Jerusalem in the days of Uzziah, Jotham, Ahaz, <supplied>and</supplied> Hezekiah, kings of Judah.
</verse><verse>Hear, O heavens, and give ear, O earth: for the LORD hath spoken, I have nourished and brought up children, and they have rebelled against me.
</verse><verse>The ox knoweth his owner, and the ass his master&#x2019;s crib: <supplied>but</supplied> Israel doth not know, my people doth not consider.
</verse><verse>Ah sinful nation, a people laden with iniquity, a seed of evildoers, children that are corrupters: they have forsaken the LORD, they have provoked the Holy One of Israel unto anger, they are gone away backward.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>Why should ye be stricken any more? ye will revolt more and more: the whole head is sick, and the whole heart faint.
</verse><verse>From the sole of the foot even unto the head <supplied>there is</supplied> no soundness in it; <supplied>but</supplied> wounds, and bruises, and putrifying sores: they have not been closed, neither bound up, neither mollified with ointment.
</verse><verse>Your country <supplied>is</supplied> desolate, your cities <supplied>are</supplied> burned with fire: your land, strangers devour it in your presence, and <supplied>it is</supplied> desolate, as overthrown by strangers.
</verse><verse>And the daughter of Zion is left as a cottage in a vineyard, as a lodge in a garden of cucumbers, as a besieged city.
</verse><verse>Except the LORD of hosts had left unto us a very small remnant, we should have been as Sodom, <supplied>and</supplied> we should have been like unto Gomorrah.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>Hear the word of the LORD, ye rulers of Sodom; give ear unto the law of our God, ye people of Gomorrah.
</verse><verse>To what purpose <supplied>is</supplied> the multitude of your sacrifices unto me? saith the LORD: I am full of the burnt offerings of rams, and the fat of fed beasts; and I delight not in the blood of bullocks, or of lambs, or of he goats.
</verse><verse>When ye come to appear before me, who hath required this at your hand, to tread my courts?
</verse><verse>Bring no more vain oblations; incense is an abomination unto me; the new moons and sabbaths, the calling of assemblies, I cannot away with; <supplied>it is</supplied> iniquity, even the solemn meeting.
</verse><verse>Your new moons and your appointed feasts my soul hateth: they are a trouble unto me; I am weary to bear <supplied>them. </supplied></verse><verse>And when ye spread forth your hands, I will hide mine eyes from you: yea, when ye make many prayers, I will not hear:
your hands are full of blood.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>Wash you, make you clean; put away the evil of your doings from before mine eyes; cease to do evil;
</verse><verse>Learn to do well; seek judgment, relieve the oppressed, judge the fatherless, plead for the widow.
</verse><verse>Come now, and let us reason together, saith the LORD: though your sins be as scarlet, they shall be as white as snow; though they be red like crimson, they shall be as wool.
</verse><verse>If ye be willing and obedient, ye shall eat the good of the land:
</verse><verse>But if ye refuse and rebel, ye shall be devoured with the sword: for the mouth of the LORD hath spoken <supplied>it.</supplied>
     
      </verse>
      <verse>How is the faithful city become an harlot! it was full of judgment; righteousness lodged in it; but now murderers.
</verse><verse>Thy silver is become dross, thy wine mixed with water:
</verse><verse>Thy princes <supplied>are</supplied> rebellious, and companions of thieves: every one loveth gifts, and followeth after rewards: they judge not the fatherless, neither doth the cause of the widow come unto them.
</verse><verse>Therefore saith the Lord, the LORD of hosts, the mighty One of Israel, Ah, I will ease me of mine adversaries, and avenge me of mine enemies:
     
      </verse>
      <verse>And I will turn my hand upon thee, and purely purge away thy dross, and take away all thy tin:
</verse><verse>And I will restore thy judges as at the first, and thy counsellors as at the beginning: afterward thou shalt be called, The city of righteousness, the faithful city.
</verse><verse>Zion shall be redeemed with judgment, and her converts with righteousness.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>And the destruction of the transgressors and of the sinners <supplied>shall be</supplied> together, and they that forsake the LORD shall be consumed.
</verse><verse>For they shall be ashamed of the oaks which ye have desired, and ye shall be confounded for the gardens that ye have chosen.
</verse><verse>For ye shall be as an oak whose leaf fadeth, and as a garden that hath no water.
</verse><verse>And the strong shall be as tow, and the maker of it as a spark, and they shall both burn together, and none shall quench <supplied>them.</supplied>
     
      </verse>
      </chapter>
