<?xml version="1.0"?>
<chapter translation="KJV" testament="Old" book="Isaiah" n="44" book-id="23">
      <verse>Yet now hear, O Jacob my servant; and Israel, whom I have chosen:
</verse><verse>Thus saith the LORD that made thee, and formed thee from the womb, <supplied>which</supplied> will help thee; Fear not, O Jacob, my servant; and thou, Jesurun, whom I have chosen.
</verse><verse>For I will pour water upon him that is thirsty, and floods upon the dry ground: I will pour my spirit upon thy seed, and my blessing upon thine offspring:
</verse><verse>And they shall spring up as among the grass, as willows by the water courses.
</verse><verse>One shall say, I <supplied>am</supplied> the LORD&#x2019;S; and another shall call <supplied>himself</supplied> by the name of Jacob; and another shall subscribe <supplied>with</supplied> his hand unto the LORD, and surname <supplied>himself</supplied> by the name of Israel.
</verse><verse>Thus saith the LORD the King of Israel, and his redeemer the LORD of hosts; I <supplied>am</supplied> the first, and I <supplied>am</supplied> the last; and beside me <supplied>there is</supplied> no God.
</verse><verse>And who, as I, shall call, and shall declare it, and set it in order for me, since I appointed the ancient people? and the things that are coming, and shall come, let them shew unto them.
</verse><verse>Fear ye not, neither be afraid: have not I told thee from that time, and have declared <supplied>it?</supplied> ye <supplied>are</supplied> even my witnesses. Is there a God beside me? yea, <supplied>there is</supplied> no God; I know not <supplied>any.</supplied>
     
      </verse>
      <verse>They that make a graven image <supplied>are</supplied> all of them vanity; and their delectable things shall not profit; and they <supplied>are</supplied> their own witnesses; they see not, nor know; that they may be ashamed.
</verse><verse>Who hath formed a god, or molten a graven image <supplied>that</supplied> is profitable for nothing?
</verse><verse>Behold, all his fellows shall be ashamed: and the workmen, they <supplied>are</supplied> of men: let them all be gathered together, let them stand up; <supplied>yet</supplied> they shall fear, <supplied>and</supplied> they shall be ashamed together.
</verse><verse>The smith with the tongs both worketh in the coals, and fashioneth it with hammers, and worketh it with the strength of his arms: yea, he is hungry, and his strength faileth: he drinketh no water, and is faint.
</verse><verse>The carpenter stretcheth out <supplied>his</supplied> rule; he marketh it out with a line; he fitteth it with planes, and he marketh it out with the compass, and maketh it after the figure of a man, according to the beauty of a man; that it may remain in
the house.
</verse><verse>He heweth him down cedars, and taketh the cypress and the oak, which he strengtheneth for himself among the trees of the forest: he planteth an ash, and the rain doth nourish <supplied>it. </supplied></verse><verse>Then shall it be for a man to burn: for he will
take thereof, and warm himself; yea, he kindleth <supplied>it,</supplied> and baketh bread; yea, he maketh a god, and worshippeth <supplied>it;</supplied> he maketh it a graven image, and falleth down thereto.
</verse><verse>He burneth part thereof in the fire; with part thereof he eateth flesh; he roasteth roast, and is satisfied: yea, he warmeth <supplied>himself,</supplied> and saith, Aha, I am warm, I have seen the fire:
</verse><verse>And the residue thereof he maketh a god, <supplied>even</supplied> his graven image: he falleth down unto it, and worshippeth <supplied>it,</supplied> and prayeth unto it, and saith, Deliver me; for thou <supplied>art</supplied> my god.
</verse><verse>They have not known nor understood: for he hath shut their eyes, that they cannot see; <supplied>and</supplied> their hearts, that they cannot understand.
</verse><verse>And none considereth in his heart, neither <supplied>is there</supplied> knowledge nor understanding to say, I have burned part of it in the fire; yea, also I have baked bread upon the coals thereof; I have roasted flesh, and eaten <supplied>it:</supplied> and shall I
make the residue thereof an abomination? shall I fall down to the stock of a tree?
</verse><verse>He feedeth on ashes: a deceived heart hath turned him aside, that he cannot deliver his soul, nor say, <supplied>Is there</supplied> not a lie in my right hand?
     
      </verse>
      <verse>Remember these, O Jacob and Israel; for thou <supplied>art</supplied> my servant: I have formed thee; thou <supplied>art</supplied> my servant: O Israel, thou shalt not be forgotten of me.
</verse><verse>I have blotted out, as a thick cloud, thy transgressions, and, as a cloud, thy sins: return unto me; for I have redeemed thee.
</verse><verse>Sing, O ye heavens; for the LORD hath done <supplied>it:</supplied> shout, ye lower parts of the earth: break forth into singing, ye mountains, O forest, and every tree therein: for the LORD hath redeemed Jacob, and glorified himself in Israel.
</verse><verse>Thus saith the LORD, thy redeemer, and he that formed thee from the womb, I <supplied>am</supplied> the LORD that maketh all <supplied>things;</supplied> that stretcheth forth the heavens alone; that spreadeth abroad the earth by myself;
</verse><verse>That frustrateth the tokens of the liars, and maketh diviners mad; that turneth wise <supplied>men</supplied> backward, and maketh their knowledge foolish;
</verse><verse>That confirmeth the word of his servant, and performeth the counsel of his messengers; that saith to Jerusalem, Thou shalt be inhabited; and to the cities of Judah, Ye shall be built, and I will raise up the decayed places thereof:
</verse><verse>That saith to the deep, Be dry, and I will dry up thy rivers:
</verse><verse>That saith of Cyrus, <supplied>He is</supplied> my shepherd, and shall perform all my pleasure: even saying to Jerusalem, Thou shalt be built; and to the temple, Thy foundation shall be laid.
     
      </verse>
      </chapter>
