<?xml version="1.0"?>
<chapter translation="KJV" testament="Old" book="Isaiah" n="46" book_id="23">
      <verse>Bel boweth down, Nebo stoopeth, their idols were upon the beasts, and upon the cattle: your carriages <supplied>were</supplied> heavy loaden; <supplied>they are</supplied> a burden to the weary <supplied>beast. </supplied></verse><verse>They stoop, they bow down together; they could not
deliver the burden, but themselves are gone into captivity.
</verse><verse>Hearken unto me, O house of Jacob, and all the remnant of the house of Israel, which are borne <supplied>by me</supplied> from the belly, which are carried from the womb:
</verse><verse>And <supplied>even</supplied> to <supplied>your</supplied> old age I <supplied>am</supplied> he; and <supplied>even</supplied> to hoar hairs will I carry <supplied>you:</supplied> I have made, and I will bear; even I will carry, and will deliver <supplied>you.</supplied>
     
      </verse>
      <verse>To whom will ye liken me, and make <supplied>me</supplied> equal, and compare me, that we may be like?
</verse><verse>They lavish gold out of the bag, and weigh silver in the balance, <supplied>and</supplied> hire a goldsmith; and he maketh it a god: they fall down, yea, they worship.
</verse><verse>They bear him upon the shoulder, they carry him, and set him in his place, and he standeth; from his place shall he not remove: yea, <supplied>one</supplied> shall cry unto him, yet can he not answer, nor save him out of his trouble.
</verse><verse>Remember this, and shew yourselves men: bring it again to mind, O ye transgressors.
</verse><verse>Remember the former things of old: for I <supplied>am</supplied> God, and <supplied>there is</supplied> none else; <supplied>I am</supplied> God, and <supplied>there is</supplied> none like me,
</verse><verse>Declaring the end from the beginning, and from ancient times <supplied>the things</supplied> that are not <supplied>yet</supplied> done, saying, My counsel shall stand, and I will do all my pleasure:
</verse><verse>Calling a ravenous bird from the east, the man that executeth my counsel from a far country: yea, I have spoken <supplied>it,</supplied> I will also bring it to pass; I have purposed <supplied>it,</supplied> I will also do it.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>Hearken unto me, ye stouthearted, that <supplied>are</supplied> far from righteousness:
</verse><verse>I bring near my righteousness; it shall not be far off, and my salvation shall not tarry: and I will place salvation in Zion for Israel my glory.
     
      </verse>
      </chapter>
