<?xml version="1.0"?>
<chapter translation="KJV" testament="Old" book="Isaiah" n="5" book-id="23">
      <verse>Now will I sing to my wellbeloved a song of my beloved touching his vineyard. My wellbeloved hath a vineyard in a very fruitful hill:
</verse><verse>And he fenced it, and gathered out the stones thereof, and planted it with the choicest vine, and built a tower in the midst of it, and also made a winepress therein: and he looked that it should bring forth grapes, and it brought forth wild
grapes.
</verse><verse>And now, O inhabitants of Jerusalem, and men of Judah, judge, I pray you, betwixt me and my vineyard.
</verse><verse>What could have been done more to my vineyard, that I have not done in it? wherefore, when I looked that it should bring forth grapes, brought it forth wild grapes?
</verse><verse>And now go to; I will tell you what I will do to my vineyard: I will take away the hedge thereof, and it shall be eaten up; <supplied>and</supplied> break down the wall thereof, and it shall be trodden down:
</verse><verse>And I will lay it waste: it shall not be pruned, nor digged; but there shall come up briers and thorns: I will also command the clouds that they rain no rain upon it.
</verse><verse>For the vineyard of the LORD of hosts <supplied>is</supplied> the house of Israel, and the men of Judah his pleasant plant: and he looked for judgment, but behold oppression; for righteousness, but behold a cry.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>Woe unto them that join house to house, <supplied>that</supplied> lay field to field, till <supplied>there be</supplied> no place, that they may be placed alone in the midst of the earth!
</verse><verse>In mine ears <supplied>said</supplied> the LORD of hosts, Of a truth many houses shall be desolate, <supplied>even</supplied> great and fair, without inhabitant.
</verse><verse>Yea, ten acres of vineyard shall yield one bath, and the seed of an homer shall yield an ephah.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>Woe unto them that rise up early in the morning, <supplied>that</supplied> they may follow strong drink; that continue until night, <supplied>till</supplied> wine inflame them!
</verse><verse>And the harp, and the viol, the tabret, and pipe, and wine, are in their feasts: but they regard not the work of the LORD, neither consider the operation of his hands.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>Therefore my people are gone into captivity, because <supplied>they have</supplied> no knowledge: and their honourable men <supplied>are</supplied> famished, and their multitude dried up with thirst.
</verse><verse>Therefore hell hath enlarged herself, and opened her mouth without measure: and their glory, and their multitude, and their pomp, and he that rejoiceth, shall descend into it.
</verse><verse>And the mean man shall be brought down, and the mighty man shall be humbled, and the eyes of the lofty shall be humbled:
</verse><verse>But the LORD of hosts shall be exalted in judgment, and God that is holy shall be sanctified in righteousness.
</verse><verse>Then shall the lambs feed after their manner, and the waste places of the fat ones shall strangers eat.
</verse><verse>Woe unto them that draw iniquity with cords of vanity, and sin as it were with a cart rope:
</verse><verse>That say, Let him make speed, <supplied>and</supplied> hasten his work, that we may see it: and let the counsel of the Holy One of Israel draw nigh and come, that we may know <supplied>it!</supplied>
     
      </verse>
      <verse>Woe unto them that call evil good, and good evil; that put darkness for light, and light for darkness; that put bitter for sweet, and sweet for bitter!
</verse><verse>Woe unto <supplied>them that are</supplied> wise in their own eyes, and prudent in their own sight!
</verse><verse>Woe unto <supplied>them that are</supplied> mighty to drink wine, and men of strength to mingle strong drink:
</verse><verse>Which justify the wicked for reward, and take away the righteousness of the righteous from him!
</verse><verse>Therefore as the fire devoureth the stubble, and the flame consumeth the chaff, <supplied>so</supplied> their root shall be as rottenness, and their blossom shall go up as dust: because they have cast away the law of the LORD of hosts, and despised the
word of the Holy One of Israel.
</verse><verse>Therefore is the anger of the LORD kindled against his people, and he hath stretched forth his hand against them, and hath smitten them: and the hills did tremble, and their carcases <supplied>were</supplied> torn in the midst of the streets. For all this
his anger is not turned away, but his hand <supplied>is</supplied> stretched out still.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>And he will lift up an ensign to the nations from far, and will hiss unto them from the end of the earth: and, behold, they shall come with speed swiftly:
</verse><verse>None shall be weary nor stumble among them; none shall slumber nor sleep; neither shall the girdle of their loins be loosed, nor the latchet of their shoes be broken:
</verse><verse>Whose arrows <supplied>are</supplied> sharp, and all their bows bent, their horses&#x2019; hoofs shall be counted like flint, and their wheels like a whirlwind:
</verse><verse>Their roaring <supplied>shall be</supplied> like a lion, they shall roar like young lions: yea, they shall roar, and lay hold of the prey, and shall carry <supplied>it</supplied> away safe, and none shall deliver <supplied>it. </supplied></verse><verse>And in that day they shall roar
against them like the roaring of the sea: and if <supplied>one</supplied> look unto the land, behold darkness <supplied>and</supplied> sorrow, and the light is darkened in the heavens thereof.
     
      </verse>
      </chapter>
