<?xml version="1.0"?>
<chapter translation="KJV" testament="Old" book="Isaiah" n="62" book-id="23">
      <verse>For Zion&#x2019;s sake will I not hold my peace, and for Jerusalem&#x2019;s sake I will not rest, until the righteousness thereof go forth as brightness, and the salvation thereof as a lamp <supplied>that</supplied> burneth.
</verse><verse>And the Gentiles shall see thy righteousness, and all kings thy glory: and thou shalt be called by a new name, which the mouth of the LORD shall name.
</verse><verse>Thou shalt also be a crown of glory in the hand of the LORD, and a royal diadem in the hand of thy God.
</verse><verse>Thou shalt no more be termed Forsaken; neither shall thy land any more be termed Desolate: but thou shalt be called Hephzi-bah, and thy land Beulah: for the LORD delighteth in thee, and thy land shall be married.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>For <supplied>as</supplied> a young man marrieth a virgin, <supplied>so</supplied> shall thy sons marry thee: and <supplied>as</supplied> the bridegroom rejoiceth over the bride, <supplied>so</supplied> shall thy God rejoice over thee.
</verse><verse>I have set watchmen upon thy walls, O Jerusalem, <supplied>which</supplied> shall never hold their peace day nor night: ye that make mention of the LORD, keep not silence,
</verse><verse>And give him no rest, till he establish, and till he make Jerusalem a praise in the earth.
</verse><verse>The LORD hath sworn by his right hand, and by the arm of his strength, Surely I will no more give thy corn <supplied>to be</supplied> meat for thine enemies; and the sons of the stranger shall not drink thy wine, for the which thou hast laboured:
</verse><verse>But they that have gathered it shall eat it, and praise the LORD; and they that have brought it together shall drink it in the courts of my holiness.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>Go through, go through the gates; prepare ye the way of the people; cast up, cast up the highways; gather out the stones; lift up a standard for the people.
</verse><verse>Behold, the LORD hath proclaimed unto the end of the world, Say ye to the daughter of Zion, Behold, thy salvation cometh; behold, his reward <supplied>is</supplied> with him, and his work before him.
</verse><verse>And they shall call them, The holy people, The redeemed of the LORD: and thou shalt be called, Sought out, A city not forsaken.
     
      </verse>
      </chapter>
