<?xml version="1.0"?>
<chapter translation="KJV" testament="Old" book="1 Samuel" n="23" book_id="9">
      <verse>Then they told David, saying, Behold, the Philistines fight against Keilah, and they rob the threshingfloors.
</verse><verse>Therefore David enquired of the LORD, saying, Shall I go and smite these Philistines? And the LORD said unto David, Go, and smite the Philistines, and save Keilah.
</verse><verse>And David&#x2019;s men said unto him, Behold, we be afraid here in Judah: how much more then if we come to Keilah against the armies of the Philistines?
</verse><verse>Then David enquired of the LORD yet again. And the LORD answered him and said, Arise, go down to Keilah; for I will deliver the Philistines into thine hand.
</verse><verse>So David and his men went to Keilah, and fought with the Philistines, and brought away their cattle, and smote them with a great slaughter. So David saved the inhabitants of Keilah.
</verse><verse>And it came to pass, when Abiathar the son of Ahimelech fled to David to Keilah, <supplied>that</supplied> he came down <supplied>with</supplied> an ephod in his hand.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>And it was told Saul that David was come to Keilah. And Saul said, God hath delivered him into mine hand; for he is shut in, by entering into a town that hath gates and bars.
</verse><verse>And Saul called all the people together to war, to go down to Keilah, to besiege David and his men.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>And David knew that Saul secretly practised mischief against him; and he said to Abiathar the priest, Bring hither the ephod.
</verse><verse>Then said David, O LORD God of Israel, thy servant hath certainly heard that Saul seeketh to come to Keilah, to destroy the city for my sake.
</verse><verse>Will the men of Keilah deliver me up into his hand? will Saul come down, as thy servant hath heard? O LORD God of Israel, I beseech thee, tell thy servant. And the LORD said, He will come down.
</verse><verse>Then said David, Will the men of Keilah deliver me and my men into the hand of Saul? And the LORD said, They will deliver <supplied>thee</supplied> up.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>Then David and his men, <supplied>which were</supplied> about six hundred, arose and departed out of Keilah, and went whithersoever they could go. And it was told Saul that David was escaped from Keilah; and he forbare to go forth.
</verse><verse>And David abode in the wilderness in strong holds, and remained in a mountain in the wilderness of Ziph. And Saul sought him every day, but God delivered him not into his hand.
</verse><verse>And David saw that Saul was come out to seek his life: and David <supplied>was</supplied> in the wilderness of Ziph in a wood.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>And Jonathan Saul&#x2019;s son arose, and went to David into the wood, and strengthened his hand in God.
</verse><verse>And he said unto him, Fear not: for the hand of Saul my father shall not find thee; and thou shalt be king over Israel, and I shall be next unto thee; and that also Saul my father knoweth.
</verse><verse>And they two made a covenant before the LORD: and David abode in the wood, and Jonathan went to his house.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>Then came up the Ziphites to Saul to Gibeah, saying, Doth not David hide himself with us in strong holds in the wood, in the hill of Hachilah, which <supplied>is</supplied> on the south of Jeshimon?
</verse><verse>Now therefore, O king, come down according to all the desire of thy soul to come down; and our part <supplied>shall be</supplied> to deliver him into the king&#x2019;s hand.
</verse><verse>And Saul said, Blessed <supplied>be</supplied> ye of the LORD; for ye have compassion on me.
</verse><verse>Go, I pray you, prepare yet, and know and see his place where his haunt is, <supplied>and</supplied> who hath seen him there: for it is told me <supplied>that</supplied> he dealeth very subtilly.
</verse><verse>See therefore, and take knowledge of all the lurking places where he hideth himself, and come ye again to me with the certainty, and I will go with you: and it shall come to pass, if he be in the land, that I will search him out throughout all
the thousands of Judah.
</verse><verse>And they arose, and went to Ziph before Saul: but David and his men <supplied>were</supplied> in the wilderness of Maon, in the plain on the south of Jeshimon.
</verse><verse>Saul also and his men went to seek <supplied>him.</supplied> And they told David: wherefore he came down into a rock, and abode in the wilderness of Maon. And when Saul heard <supplied>that,</supplied> he pursued after David in the wilderness of Maon.
</verse><verse>And Saul went on this side of the mountain, and David and his men on that side of the mountain: and David made haste to get away for fear of Saul; for Saul and his men compassed David and his men round about to take them.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>But there came a messenger unto Saul, saying, Haste thee, and come; for the Philistines have invaded the land.
</verse><verse>Wherefore Saul returned from pursuing after David, and went against the Philistines: therefore they called that place Sela- hammahlekoth.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>And David went up from thence, and dwelt in strong holds at En-gedi.
     
      </verse>
      </chapter>
