<chapter translation="NASB" testament="New" book="Revelation" book-id="66" n="11">
<verse>Then there was given me a measuring rod like a staff; and someone said, "Get up and measure the temple of God and the altar, and those who worship in it.</verse>
<verse>"Leave out the court which is outside the temple and do not measure it, for it has been given to the nations; and they will tread under foot the holy city for forty-two months.</verse>
<verse>"And I will grant authority to my two witnesses, and they will prophesy for twelve hundred and sixty days, clothed in sackcloth."</verse>
<verse>These are the two olive trees and the two lampstands that stand before the Lord of the earth.</verse>
<verse>And if anyone wants to harm them, fire flows out of their mouth and devours their enemies; so if anyone wants to harm them, he must be killed in this way.</verse>
<verse>These have the power to shut up the sky, so that rain will not fall during the days of their prophesying; and they have power over the waters to turn them into blood, and to strike the earth with every plague, as often as they desire.</verse>
<verse>When they have finished their testimony, the beast that comes up out of the abyss will make war with them, and overcome them and kill them.</verse>
<verse>And their dead bodies will lie in the street of the great city which mystically is called Sodom and Egypt, where also their Lord was crucified.</verse>
<verse>Those from the peoples and tribes and tongues and nations will look at their dead bodies for three and a half days, and will not permit their dead bodies to be laid in a tomb.</verse>
<verse>And those who dwell on the earth will rejoice over them and celebrate; and they will send gifts to one another, because these two prophets tormented those who dwell on the earth.</verse>
<verse>But after the three and a half days, the breath of life from God came into them, and they stood on their feet; and great fear fell upon those who were watching them.</verse>
<verse>And they heard a loud voice from heaven saying to them, "Come up here." Then they went up into heaven in the cloud, and their enemies watched them.</verse>
<verse>And in that hour there was a great earthquake, and a tenth of the city fell; seven thousand people were killed in the earthquake, and the rest were terrified and gave glory to the God of heaven.</verse>
<verse>The second woe is past; behold, the third woe is coming quickly.</verse>
<verse>Then the seventh angel sounded; and there were loud voices in heaven, saying, "The kingdom of the world has become the kingdom of our Lord and of His Christ; and He will reign forever and ever."</verse>
<verse>And the twenty-four elders, who sit on their thrones before God, fell on their faces and worshiped God,</verse>
<verse>saying, "We give You thanks, O Lord God, the Almighty, who are and who were, because You have taken Your great power and have begun to reign.</verse>
<verse>"And the nations were enraged, and Your wrath came, and the time came for the dead to be judged, and the time to reward Your bond-servants the prophets and the saints and those who fear Your name, the small and the great, and to destroy those who destroy the earth."</verse>
<verse>And the temple of God which is in heaven was opened; and the ark of His covenant appeared in His temple, and there were flashes of lightning and sounds and peals of thunder and an earthquake and a great hailstorm.</verse>
</chapter>