<chapter translation="NASB" testament="New" book="Revelation" book-id="66" n="8">
<verse>When the Lamb broke the seventh seal, there was silence in heaven for about half an hour.</verse>
<verse>And I saw the seven angels who stand before God, and seven trumpets were given to them.</verse>
<verse>Another angel came and stood at the altar, holding a golden censer; and much incense was given to him, so that he might add it to the prayers of all the saints on the golden altar which was before the throne.</verse>
<verse>And the smoke of the incense, with the prayers of the saints, went up before God out of the angel's hand.</verse>
<verse>Then the angel took the censer and filled it with the fire of the altar, and threw it to the earth; and there followed peals of thunder and sounds and flashes of lightning and an earthquake.</verse>
<verse>And the seven angels who had the seven trumpets prepared themselves to sound them.</verse>
<verse>The first sounded, and there came hail and fire, mixed with blood, and they were thrown to the earth; and a third of the earth was burned up, and a third of the trees were burned up, and all the green grass was burned up.</verse>
<verse>The second angel sounded, and something like a great mountain burning with fire was thrown into the sea; and a third of the sea became blood,</verse>
<verse>and a third of the creatures which were in the sea and had life, died; and a third of the ships were destroyed.</verse>
<verse>The third angel sounded, and a great star fell from heaven, burning like a torch, and it fell on a third of the rivers and on the springs of waters.</verse>
<verse>The name of the star is called Wormwood; and a third of the waters became wormwood, and many men died from the waters, because they were made bitter.</verse>
<verse>The fourth angel sounded, and a third of the sun and a third of the moon and a third of the stars were struck, so that a third of them would be darkened and the day would not shine for a third of it, and the night in the same way.</verse>
<verse>Then I looked, and I heard an eagle flying in midheaven, saying with a loud voice, "Woe, woe, woe to those who dwell on the earth, because of the remaining blasts of the trumpet of the three angels who are about to sound!"</verse>
</chapter>