<chapter translation="NIV" testament="New" book="Revelation" book-id="66" n="4">
<verse>After this I looked, and there before me was a door standing open in heaven. And the voice I had first heard speaking to me like a trumpet said, "Come up here, and I will show you what must take place after this."</verse>
<verse>At once I was in the Spirit, and there before me was a throne in heaven with someone sitting on it.</verse>
<verse>And the one who sat there had the appearance of jasper and carnelian. A rainbow, resembling an emerald, encircled the throne.</verse>
<verse>Surrounding the throne were twenty-four other thrones, and seated on them were twenty-four elders. They were dressed in white and had crowns of gold on their heads.</verse>
<verse>From the throne came flashes of lightning, rumblings and peals of thunder. Before the throne, seven lamps were blazing. These are the seven spirits of God.</verse>
<verse>Also before the throne there was what looked like a sea of glass, clear as crystal.</verse>
<verse>In the center, around the throne, were four living creatures, and they were covered with eyes, in front and in back. The first living creature was like a lion, the second was like an ox, the third had a face like a man, the fourth was like a flying eagle.</verse>
<verse>Each of the four living creatures had six wings and was covered with eyes all around, even under his wings. Day and night they never stop saying: "Holy, holy, holy is the Lord God Almighty, who was, and is, and is to come."</verse>
<verse>Whenever the living creatures give glory, honor and thanks to him who sits on the throne and who lives for ever and ever,</verse>
<verse>the twenty-four elders fall down before him who sits on the throne, and worship him who lives for ever and ever. They lay their crowns before the throne and say:</verse>
<verse>"You are worthy, our Lord and God, to receive glory and honor and power, for you created all things, and by your will they were created and have their being."</verse>
</chapter>