<chapter translation="NASB" testament="New" book="Philippians" book-id="50" n="1">
<verse>Paul and Timothy, bond-servants of Christ Jesus, To all the saints in Christ Jesus who are in Philippi, including the overseers and deacons:</verse>
<verse>Grace to you and peace from God our Father and the Lord Jesus Christ.</verse>
<verse>I thank my God in all my remembrance of you,</verse>
<verse>always offering prayer with joy in my every prayer for you all,</verse>
<verse>in view of your participation in the gospel from the first day until now.</verse>
<verse>For I am confident of this very thing, that He who began a good work in you will perfect it until the day of Christ Jesus.</verse>
<verse>For it is only right for me to feel this way about you all, because I have you in my heart, since both in my imprisonment and in the defense and confirmation of the gospel, you all are partakers of grace with me.</verse>
<verse>For God is my witness, how I long for you all with the affection of Christ Jesus.</verse>
<verse>And this I pray, that your love may abound still more and more in real knowledge and all discernment,</verse>
<verse>so that you may approve the things that are excellent, in order to be sincere and blameless until the day of Christ;</verse>
<verse>having been filled with the fruit of righteousness which comes through Jesus Christ, to the glory and praise of God.</verse>
<verse>Now I want you to know, brethren, that my circumstances have turned out for the greater progress of the gospel,</verse>
<verse>so that my imprisonment in the cause of Christ has become well known throughout the whole praetorian guard and to everyone else,</verse>
<verse>and that most of the brethren, trusting in the Lord because of my imprisonment, have far more courage to speak the word of God without fear.</verse>
<verse>Some, to be sure, are preaching Christ even from envy and strife, but some also from good will;</verse>
<verse>the latter do it out of love, knowing that I am appointed for the defense of the gospel;</verse>
<verse>the former proclaim Christ out of selfish ambition rather than from pure motives, thinking to cause me distress in my imprisonment.</verse>
<verse>What then? Only that in every way, whether in pretense or in truth, Christ is proclaimed; and in this I rejoice. Yes, and I will rejoice,</verse>
<verse>for I know that this will turn out for my deliverance through your prayers and the provision of the Spirit of Jesus Christ,</verse>
<verse>according to my earnest expectation and hope, that I will not be put to shame in anything, but that with all boldness, Christ will even now, as always, be exalted in my body, whether by life or by death.</verse>
<verse>For to me, to live is Christ and to die is gain.</verse>
<verse>But if I am to live on in the flesh, this will mean fruitful labor for me; and I do not know which to choose.</verse>
<verse>But I am hard-pressed from both directions, having the desire to depart and be with Christ, for that is very much better;</verse>
<verse>yet to remain on in the flesh is more necessary for your sake.</verse>
<verse>Convinced of this, I know that I will remain and continue with you all for your progress and joy in the faith,</verse>
<verse>so that your proud confidence in me may abound in Christ Jesus through my coming to you again.</verse>
<verse>Only conduct yourselves in a manner worthy of the gospel of Christ, so that whether I come and see you or remain absent, I will hear of you that you are standing firm in one spirit, with one mind striving together for the faith of the gospel;</verse>
<verse>in no way alarmed by your opponents--which is a sign of destruction for them, but of salvation for you, and that too, from God.</verse>
<verse>For to you it has been granted for Christ's sake, not only to believe in Him, but also to suffer for His sake,</verse>
<verse>experiencing the same conflict which you saw in me, and now hear to be in me.</verse>
</chapter>