<chapter translation="NASB" testament="New" book="Philippians" book_id="50" n="2">
<verse>Therefore if there is any encouragement in Christ, if there is any consolation of love, if there is any fellowship of the Spirit, if any affection and compassion,</verse>
<verse>make my joy complete by being of the same mind, maintaining the same love, united in spirit, intent on one purpose.</verse>
<verse>Do nothing from selfishness or empty conceit, but with humility of mind regard one another as more important than yourselves;</verse>
<verse>do not merely look out for your own personal interests, but also for the interests of others.</verse>
<verse>Have this attitude in yourselves which was also in Christ Jesus,</verse>
<verse>who, although He existed in the form of God, did not regard equality with God a thing to be grasped,</verse>
<verse>but emptied Himself, taking the form of a bond-servant, and being made in the likeness of men.</verse>
<verse>Being found in appearance as a man, He humbled Himself by becoming obedient to the point of death, even death on a cross.</verse>
<verse>For this reason also, God highly exalted Him, and bestowed on Him the name which is above every name,</verse>
<verse>so that at the name of Jesus EVERY KNEE WILL BOW, of those who are in heaven and on earth and under the earth,</verse>
<verse>and that every tongue will confess that Jesus Christ is Lord, to the glory of God the Father.</verse>
<verse>So then, my beloved, just as you have always obeyed, not as in my presence only, but now much more in my absence, work out your salvation with fear and trembling;</verse>
<verse>for it is God who is at work in you, both to will and to work for His good pleasure.</verse>
<verse>Do all things without grumbling or disputing;</verse>
<verse>so that you will prove yourselves to be blameless and innocent, children of God above reproach in the midst of a crooked and perverse generation, among whom you appear as lights in the world,</verse>
<verse>holding fast the word of life, so that in the day of Christ I will have reason to glory because I did not run in vain nor toil in vain.</verse>
<verse>But even if I am being poured out as a drink offering upon the sacrifice and service of your faith, I rejoice and share my joy with you all.</verse>
<verse>You too, I urge you, rejoice in the same way and share your joy with me.</verse>
<verse>But I hope in the Lord Jesus to send Timothy to you shortly, so that I also may be encouraged when I learn of your condition.</verse>
<verse>For I have no one else of kindred spirit who will genuinely be concerned for your welfare.</verse>
<verse>For they all seek after their own interests, not those of Christ Jesus.</verse>
<verse>But you know of his proven worth, that he served with me in the furtherance of the gospel like a child serving his father.</verse>
<verse>Therefore I hope to send him immediately, as soon as I see how things go with me;</verse>
<verse>and I trust in the Lord that I myself also will be coming shortly.</verse>
<verse>But I thought it necessary to send to you Epaphroditus, my brother and fellow worker and fellow soldier, who is also your messenger and minister to my need;</verse>
<verse>because he was longing for you all and was distressed because you had heard that he was sick.</verse>
<verse>For indeed he was sick to the point of death, but God had mercy on him, and not on him only but also on me, so that I would not have sorrow upon sorrow.</verse>
<verse>Therefore I have sent him all the more eagerly so that when you see him again you may rejoice and I may be less concerned about you.</verse>
<verse>Receive him then in the Lord with all joy, and hold men like him in high regard;</verse>
<verse>because he came close to death for the work of Christ, risking his life to complete what was deficient in your service to me.</verse>
</chapter>