<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="1 Chronicles" book_id="13" n="1">
<verse>Adam		Seth Enosh</verse>
<verse>Kenan Mahalalel Jared</verse>
<verse>Enoch Methuselah Lamech</verse>
<verse>Noah Shem, Ham, and Japheth.</verse>
<verse>Japheth had Gomer, Magog, Madai, Javan, Tubal, Meshech, and Tiras.</verse>
<verse>Gomer had Ashkenaz, Riphath, and Togarmah.</verse>
<verse>Javan had Elisha, Tarshish, Kittim, and Rodanim.</verse>
<verse>Ham had Cush, Mizraim, Put, and Canaan.</verse>
<verse>Cush had Seba, Havilah, Sabta, Raamah, and Sabteca. Raamah had Sheba and Dedan.</verse>
<verse>Cush had Nimrod, the first great hero on earth.</verse>
<verse>Mizraim was ancestor to the Ludim, the Anamim, the Lehabim, the Naphtuhim,</verse>
<verse>the Pathrusim, the Casluhim, and the Caphtorim from whom the Philistines descended.</verse>
<verse>Canaan had Sidon (his firstborn) and Heth,</verse>
<verse>and was ancestor to the Jebusites, the Amorites, the Girgashites,</verse>
<verse>the Hivites, the Arkites, the Sinites,</verse>
<verse>the Arvadites, the Zemarites, and the Hamathites.</verse>
<verse>Shem had Elam, Asshur, Arphaxad, Lud, Aram, Uz, Hul, Gether, and Meshech.</verse>
<verse>Arphaxad had Shelah and Shelah had Eber.</verse>
<verse>Eber had two sons: Peleg (Division) because in his time the earth was divided up; his brother was Joktan.</verse>
<verse>Joktan had Almodad, Sheleph, Hazarmaveth, Jerah,</verse>
<verse>Hadoram, Uzal, Diklah,</verse>
<verse>Ebal, Abimael, Sheba,</verse>
<verse>Ophir, Havilah, and Jobab--all sons of Joktan.</verse>
<verse>The three main branches in summary: Shem, Arphaxad, Shelah,</verse>
<verse>Eber, Peleg, Reu,</verse>
<verse>Serug, Nahor, Terah,</verse>
<verse>and Abram (Abraham).</verse>
<verse>And Abraham had Isaac and Ishmael.</verse>
<verse>Abraham's family tree developed along these lines: Ishmael had Nebaioth (his firstborn), then Kedar, Adbeel, Mibsam,</verse>
<verse>Mishma, Dumah, Massa, Hadad, Tema,</verse>
<verse>Jetur, Naphish, and Kedemah--the Ishmael branch.</verse>
<verse>Keturah, Abraham's concubine, gave birth to Zimran, Jokshan, Medan, Midian, Ishbak, and Shuah. Then Jokshan had Sheba and Dedan.</verse>
<verse>And Midian had Ephah, Epher, Hanoch, Abida, and Eldaah. These made up the Keturah branch.</verse>
<verse>Abraham had Isaac, and Isaac had Esau and Israel (Jacob).</verse>
<verse>Esau had Eliphaz, Reuel, Jeush, Jalam, and Korah.</verse>
<verse>Eliphaz had Teman, Omar, Zepho, Gatam, Kenaz, Timna, and Amalek.</verse>
<verse>And Reuel had Nahath, Zerah, Shammah, and Mizzah.</verse>
<verse>Seir then had Lotan, Shobal, Zibeon, Anah, Dishon, Ezer, and Dishan.</verse>
<verse>Lotan had Hori and Homam. Timna was Lotan's sister.</verse>
<verse>Shobal had Alian, Manahath, Ebal, Shepho, and Onam. Zibeon had Aiah and Anah.</verse>
<verse>Anah had Dishon. Dishon had Hemdan, Eshban, Ithran, and Keran.</verse>
<verse>Ezer had Bilhan, Zaavan, and Akan. And Dishan had Uz and Aran.</verse>
<verse>A list of the kings who ruled in the country of Edom before Israel had a king: Bela son of Beor; his city was Dinhabah.</verse>
<verse>Bela died; Jobab son of Zerah from Bozrah was the next king.</verse>
<verse>Jobab died; Husham from the country of the Temanites was the next king.</verse>
<verse>Husham died; Hadad son of Bedad, who defeated Midian in the country of Moab, was the next king; his city was Avith.</verse>
<verse>Hadad died; Samlah from Masrekah was the next king.</verse>
<verse>Samlah died; Shaul from Rehoboth-by-the-River was the next king.</verse>
<verse>Shaul died; Baal-Hanan son of Acbor was the next king.</verse>
<verse>Baal-Hanan died; Hadad was the next king; his city was Pau and his wife was Mehetabel daughter of Matred, the daughter of Me-Zahab.</verse>
<verse>Last of all Hadad died. The chieftains of Edom after that were Chief Timna, Chief Alvah, Chief Jetheth,</verse>
<verse>Chief Oholibamah, Chief Elah, Chief Pinon,</verse>
<verse>Chief Kenaz, Chief Teman, Chief Mibzar,</verse>
<verse>Chief Magdiel, and Chief Iram. These were the chieftains of Edom.</verse>
</chapter>