<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="1 Chronicles" book_id="13" n="10">
<verse>The Philistines went to war against Israel; the Israelites ran for their lives from the Philistines but fell, slaughtered on Mount Gilboa.</verse>
<verse>The Philistines zeroed in on Saul and his sons and killed his sons Jonathan, Abinadab, and Malki-Shua.</verse>
<verse>The battle went hard against Saul--the archers found him and wounded him.</verse>
<verse>Saul said to his armor bearer, "Draw your sword and finish me off before these pagan pigs get to me and make a sport of my body." But his armor bearer, restrained by both reverence and fear, wouldn't do it. So Saul took his own sword and killed himself.</verse>
<verse>The armor bearer, panicked because Saul was dead, then killed himself.</verse>
<verse>So Saul and his three sons--all four the same day--died.</verse>
<verse>When all the Israelites in the valley saw that the army had fled and that Saul and his sons were dead, they abandoned their cities and ran off; the Philistines came and moved in.</verse>
<verse>The next day the Philistines came to plunder the dead bodies and found Saul and his sons dead on Mount Gilboa.</verse>
<verse>They stripped Saul, removed his head and his armor, and put them on exhibit throughout Philistia, reporting the victory news to their idols and the people.</verse>
<verse>Then they put Saul's armor on display in the temple of their gods and placed his skull as a trophy in the temple of their god Dagon.</verse>
<verse>The people of Jabesh Gilead heard what the Philistines had done to Saul.</verse>
<verse>All of their fighting men went into action--retrieved the bodies of Saul and his sons and brought them to Jabesh, gave them a dignified burial under the oak at Jabesh, and mourned their deaths for seven days.</verse>
<verse>Saul died in disobedience, disobedient to GOD. He didn't obey GOD's words. Instead of praying, he went to a witch to seek guidance.</verse>
<verse>Because he didn't go to GOD for help, GOD took his life and turned the kingdom over to David son of Jesse.</verse>
</chapter>