<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="1 Chronicles" book_id="13" n="2">
<verse>Israel's (that is, Jacob's) sons: Reuben, Simeon, Levi, Judah, Issachar, Zebulun,</verse>
<verse>Dan, Joseph, Benjamin, Naphtali, Gad, and Asher.</verse>
<verse>Judah had Er, Onan, and Shelah; their mother was Bathshua the Canaanite. Er, Judah's firstborn, was so bad before GOD that GOD killed him.</verse>
<verse>Judah also had Perez and Zerah by his daughter-in-law Tamar--a total of five sons.</verse>
<verse>Perez had Hezron and Hamul;</verse>
<verse>Zerah had Zimri, Ethan, Heman, Calcol, and Darda--five sons.</verse>
<verse>Carmi had Achar, who brought doom on Israel when he violated a holy ban.</verse>
<verse>Ethan's son was Azariah.</verse>
<verse>And Hezron had Jerahmeel, Ram, and Chelubai.</verse>
<verse>Ram had Amminadab and Amminadab had Nahshon, a prominent leader in the Judah family.</verse>
<verse>Nahshon had Salmon and Salmon had Boaz.</verse>
<verse>Boaz had Obed and Obed had Jesse.</verse>
<verse>Jesse's firstborn was Eliab, followed by Abinadab, Shimea,</verse>
<verse>Nethanel, Raddai,</verse>
<verse>Ozem, and finally David; David was the seventh.</verse>
<verse>Their sisters were Zeruiah and Abigail. Zeruiah gave birth to three sons: Abishai, Joab, and Asahel;</verse>
<verse>Abigail was the mother of Amasa (the father was Jether the Ishmaelite).</verse>
<verse>Caleb son of Hezron had children by his wife Azubah and also by Jerioth. Azubah's sons were Jesher, Shobab, and Ardon.</verse>
<verse>After Azubah died, Caleb married Ephrath, who gave birth to Hur.</verse>
<verse>Hur had Uri and Uri had Bezalel.</verse>
<verse>Some time later Hezron married the daughter of Makir the father of Gilead; he was sixty years old when he married her; she gave birth to Segub.</verse>
<verse>Then Segub had Jair who owned twenty-three cities in the land of Gilead.</verse>
<verse>Geshur and Aram captured the nomadic villages of Jair and Kenath and their satellite settlements--sixty towns. These all belonged to Makir the father of Gilead.</verse>
<verse>After the death of Hezron, Caleb married Ephrathah the wife of his father Hezron; she then gave birth to Ashhur the father of Tekoa.</verse>
<verse>The sons of Jerahmeel, Hezron's firstborn: Ram his firstborn, followed by Bunah, Oren, Ozem, and Ahijah.</verse>
<verse>Jerahmeel had another wife whose name was Atarah; she gave birth to Onam.</verse>
<verse>The sons of Ram, Jerahmeel's firstborn: Maaz, Jamin, and Eker.</verse>
<verse>The sons of Onam: Shammai and Jada. The sons of Shammai: Nadab and Abishur.</verse>
<verse>Abishur's wife was Abihail; she gave birth to Ahban and Molid.</verse>
<verse>Nadab had Seled and Appaim. Seled died leaving no sons.</verse>
<verse>Appaim had Ishi; Ishi had Sheshan; and Sheshan had Ahlai.</verse>
<verse>Jada, Shammai's brother, had Jether and Jonathan. Jether died leaving no sons.</verse>
<verse>Jonathan had Peleth and Zaza. This is the family tree of the sons of Jerahmeel. [JC]</verse>
<verse>Sheshan had no sons, only daughters. But Sheshan had an Egyptian servant, Jarha.</verse>
<verse>Sheshan married his daughter to Jarha and she gave birth to Attai.</verse>
<verse>Attai had Nathan, Nathan had Zabad,</verse>
<verse>Zabad had Ephlal, Ephlal had Obed,</verse>
<verse>Obed had Jehu, Jehu had Azariah,</verse>
<verse>Azariah had Helez, Helez had Eleasah,</verse>
<verse>Eleasah had Sismai, Sismai had Shallum,</verse>
<verse>Shallum had Jekamiah, and Jekamiah had Elishama. [JC]</verse>
<verse>Jerahmeel's brother Caleb had a son, his firstborn, named Mesha; Mesha had Ziph; Ziph's son was Mareshah the father of Hebron.</verse>
<verse>The sons of Hebron: Korah, Tappuah, Rekem, and Shema.</verse>
<verse>Shema had Raham the father of Jorkeam; Rekem had Shammai.</verse>
<verse>Shammai's son was Maon and Maon was the father of Beth Zur.</verse>
<verse>Caleb's concubine Ephah gave birth to Haran, Moza, and Gazez; Haran had Gazez.</verse>
<verse>The sons of Jahdai: Regem, Jotham, Geshan, Pelet, Ephah, and Shaaph.</verse>
<verse>Another concubine of Caleb, Maacah, gave birth to Sheber and Tirhanah.</verse>
<verse>She also bore Shaaph the father of Madmannah and Sheva the father of Macbenah and Gibea. Caleb's daughter was Acsah.</verse>
<verse>These made up the Caleb branch of the family tree. The sons of Hur, Ephrathah's firstborn: Shobal who had Kiriath Jearim,</verse>
<verse>Salma who had Bethlehem, and Hareph father of Beth Gader.</verse>
<verse>The family of Shobal, father of Kiriath Jearim: Haroeh, half of the population of Manahath,</verse>
<verse>the families of Kiriath Jearim, the Ithrites, the Puthites, the Shumathites, and the Mishraites. The Zorathites and Eshtaolites also came from this line.</verse>
<verse>The sons of Salma: Bethlehem, the Netophathites, Atroth Beth Joab, half of the Manahathites, the Zorites,</verse>
<verse>and the families of Sopherim who lived at Jabez--the Tirathites, the Shimeathites, and the Sucathites. They made up the Kenites who came from Hammath the father of the house of Recab.</verse>
</chapter>