<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="1 Chronicles" book-id="13" n="22">
<verse>So David declared, "From now on, this is the site for the worship of GOD; this is the place for Israel's Altar of Burnt Offering."</verse>
<verse>David ordered all the resident aliens in the land to come together; he sent them to the stone quarries to cut dressed stone to build The Temple of God.</verse>
<verse>He also stockpiled a huge quantity of iron for nails and bracings for the doors of the gates, more bronze than could be weighed,</verse>
<verse>and cedar logs past counting (the Sidonians and Tyrians shipped in huge loads of cedar logs for David).</verse>
<verse>David was thinking, "My son Solomon is too young to plan ahead for this. But the sanctuary that is to be built for GOD has to be the greatest, the talk of all the nations; so I'll get the construction materials together." That's why David prepared this huge stockpile of building materials before he died.</verse>
<verse>Then he called in Solomon his son and commanded him to build a sanctuary for the GOD of Israel.</verse>
<verse>David said to Solomon, "I wanted in the worst way to build a sanctuary to honor my GOD.</verse>
<verse>But GOD prevented me, saying, "You've killed too many people, fought too many wars. You are not the one to honor me by building a sanctuary--you've been responsible for too much killing, too much bloodshed.</verse>
<verse>But you are going to have a son and he will be a quiet and peaceful man, and I will calm his enemies down on all sides. His very name will speak peace--that is, Solomon, which means Peace--and I'll give peace and rest under his rule.</verse>
<verse>He will be the one to build a sanctuary in my honor. He'll be my royal adopted son and I'll be his father; and I'll make sure that the authority of his kingdom over Israel lasts forever.'</verse>
<verse>"So now, son, GOD be with you. GOD-speed as you build the sanctuary for your GOD, the job God has given you.</verse>
<verse>And may GOD also give you discernment and understanding when he puts you in charge of Israel so that you will rule in reverent obedience under GOD's Revelation.</verse>
<verse>That's what will make you successful, following the directions and doing the things that GOD commanded Moses for Israel. Courage! Take charge! Don't be timid; don't hold back.</verse>
<verse>Look at this--I've gone to a lot of trouble to stockpile materials for the sanctuary of GOD: 100,000 talents (3,775 tons) of gold, a million talents (37,750 tons) of silver, tons of bronze and iron--too much to weigh--and all this timber and stone. And you're free to add more.</verse>
<verse>And workers both plentiful and prepared: stonecutters, masons, carpenters, artisans in</verse>
<verse>gold and silver, bronze and iron. You're all set--get to work! And GOD-speed!"</verse>
<verse>David gave orders to all of Israel's leaders to help his son Solomon,</verse>
<verse>saying, "Isn't it obvious that your GOD is present with you; that he has given you peaceful relations with everyone around? My part in this was to put down the enemies, subdue the land to GOD and his people;</verse>
<verse>your part is to give yourselves, heart and soul, to praying to your GOD. So get moving--build the sacred house of worship to GOD! Then bring the Chest of the Covenant of GOD and all the holy furnishings for the worship of God into the sanctuary built in honor of GOD."</verse>
</chapter>