<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="1 Chronicles" book-id="13" n="3">
<verse>These are the sons that David had while he lived at Hebron: 	His firstborn was Amnon by Ahinoam of Jezreel; second, Daniel by Abigail of Carmel;</verse>
<verse>third, Absalom born of Maacah, daughter of Talmai king of Geshur; fourth, Adonijah born of Haggith;</verse>
<verse>fifth, Shephatiah born of Abital; sixth, Ithream born of his wife Eglah.</verse>
<verse>He had these six sons while he was in Hebron; he was king there for seven years and six months. He went on to be king in Jerusalem for another thirty-three years.</verse>
<verse>These are the sons he had in Jerusalem: first Shammua, then Shobab, Nathan, and Solomon. Bathsheba daughter of Ammiel was the mother of these four.</verse>
<verse>And then there were another nine sons: Ibhar, Elishua, Eliphelet,</verse>
<verse>Nogah, Nepheg, Japhia,</verse>
<verse>Elishama, Eliada, Eliphelet--</verse>
<verse>David's sons, plus Tamar their sister. There were other sons by his concubines.</verse>
<verse>In the next generation Solomon had Rehoboam, who had Abijah, who had Asa, who had Jehoshaphat,</verse>
<verse>who had Jehoram, who had Ahaziah, who had Joash,</verse>
<verse>who had Amaziah, who had Azariah, who had Jotham,</verse>
<verse>who had Ahaz, who had Hezekiah, who had Manasseh,</verse>
<verse>who had Amon, who had Josiah.</verse>
<verse>Josiah's firstborn was Johanan, followed by Jehoiakim, then Zedekiah, and finally Shallum.</verse>
<verse>Jehoiakim's sons were Jeconiah (Jehoiachin) and Zedekiah.</verse>
<verse>The sons of Jeconiah born while he was captive in Babylon: Shealtiel</verse>
<verse>, Malkiram, Pedaiah, Shenazzar, Jekamiah, Hoshama, and Nedabiah.</verse>
<verse>Pedaiah had Zerubbabel and Shimei; Zerubbabel had Meshullam and Hananiah. Shelomith was their sister.</verse>
<verse>And then five more--Hashubah, Ohel, Berekiah, Hasadiah, and Jushab-Hesed.</verse>
<verse>Hananiah's sons were Pelatiah and Jeshaiah. There were also sons of Rephaiah, sons of Arnan, sons of Obadiah, and sons of Shecaniah.</verse>
<verse>Shecaniah had Shemaiah who in his turn had Hattush, Igal, Bariah, Neariah, and Shaphat--six of them.</verse>
<verse>Neariah had three sons: Elioenai, Hizkiah, and Azrikam.</verse>
<verse>And Elioenai had seven sons: Hodaviah, Eliashib, Pelaiah, Akkub, Johanan, Delaiah, and Anani.</verse>
</chapter>