<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="1 Chronicles" book-id="13" n="7">
<verse>The sons of Issachar were Tola, Puah, Jashub, and Shimron--four sons.</verse>
<verse>The sons of Tola were Uzzi, Rephaiah, Jeriel, Jahmai, Ibsam, and Samuel--the chiefs of their families. During David's reign, the Tola family counted 22,600 warriors in their lineage.</verse>
<verse>The son of Uzzi was Izrahiah; the sons of Izrahiah were Michael, Obadiah, Joel, and Isshiah--five sons and all of them chiefs.</verse>
<verse>They counted 36,000 warriors in their lineage because they had more wives and sons than their brothers.</verse>
<verse>The extended families of Issachar accounted for 87,000 warriors--all of them listed in the family tree.</verse>
<verse>Benjamin had three sons: Bela, Beker, and Jediael.</verse>
<verse>Bela had five: Ezbon, Uzzi, Uzziel, Jerimoth, and Iri, all of them chiefs and warriors. They counted 22,034 names in their family tree.</verse>
<verse>Beker's sons were Zemirah, Joash, Eliezer, Elioenai, Omri, Jeremoth, Abijah, Anathoth, and Alemeth.</verse>
<verse>Through these chiefs their family tree listed 20,200 warriors.</verse>
<verse>Jediael's son was Bilhan and the sons of Bilhan were Jeush, Benjamin, Ehud, Kenaanah, Zethan, Tarshish, and Ahishahar</verse>
<verse>-all sons of Jediael and family chiefs; they counted 17,200 combat-ready warriors.</verse>
<verse>Shuppim and Huppim were the sons of Ir; Hushim were from the family of Aher.</verse>
<verse>The sons of Naphtali were Jahziel, Guni, Jezer, and Shallum; they are listed under the maternal line of Bilhah, their grandfather's concubine.</verse>
<verse>Manasseh's sons, born of his Aramean concubine, were Asriel and Makir the father of Gilead.</verse>
<verse>Makir got his wife from the Huppites and Shuppites. His sister's name was Maacah. Another son, Zelophehad, had only daughters.</verse>
<verse>Makir's wife Maacah bore a son whom she named Peresh; his brother's name was Sheresh and his sons were Ulam and Rakem.</verse>
<verse>Ulam's son was Bedan. This accounts for the sons of Gilead son of Makir, the son of Manasseh.</verse>
<verse>His sister Hammoleketh gave birth to Ishdod, Abiezer, and Mahlah.</verse>
<verse>The sons of Shemida were Ahian, Shechem, Likhi, and Aniam.</verse>
<verse>The sons of Ephraim were Shuthelah, Bered his son, Tahath his son, Eleadah his son, Tahath his son,</verse>
<verse>Zabad his son, Shuthelah his son, and Ezer and Elead, cattle-rustlers, killed on one of their raids by the natives of Gath.</verse>
<verse>Their father Ephraim grieved a long time and his family gathered to give him comfort.</verse>
<verse>Then he slept with his wife again. She conceived and produced a son. He named him Beriah (Unlucky), because of the bad luck that had come to his family.</verse>
<verse>His daughter was Sheerah. She built Lower and Upper Beth Horon and Uzzen Sheerah.</verse>
<verse>Rephah was Ephraim's son and also Resheph; Telah was his son, Tahan his son,</verse>
<verse>Ladan his son, Ammihud his son, Elishama his son,</verse>
<verse>Nun his son, and Joshua his son.</verse>
<verse>They occupied Bethel and the neighboring country from Naaran on the east to Gezer and its villages on the west, along with Shechem and its villages, and extending as far as Ayyah and its villages.</verse>
<verse>Stretched along the borders of Manasseh were Beth Shan, Taanach, Megiddo, and Dor, together with their satellite villages. The families descended from Joseph son of Israel lived in all these places.</verse>
<verse>The sons of Asher were Imnah, Ishvah, Ishvi, and Beriah; Serah was their sister.</verse>
<verse>The sons of Beriah were Heber and Malkiel, who had Birzaith.</verse>
<verse>Heber had Japhlet, Shomer, Hotham, and Shua their sister.</verse>
<verse>Japhlet had Pasach, Bimhal, and Ashvath.</verse>
<verse>His brother Shomer had Rohgah, Hubbah, and Aram.</verse>
<verse>His brother Helem had Zophah, Imna, Shelesh, and Amal.</verse>
<verse>Zophah had Suah, Harnepher, Shual, Beri, Imrah,</verse>
<verse>Bezer, Hod, Shamma, Shilshah, Ithran, and Beera.</verse>
<verse>Jether had Jephunneh, Pispah, and Ara.</verse>
<verse>Ulla had Arah, Hanniel, and Rizia.</verse>
<verse>These were Asher's sons, all of them responsible, excellent in character, and brave in battle--good leaders. They listed 26,000 combat-ready men in their family tree.</verse>
</chapter>