<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="1 Chronicles" book_id="13" n="8">
<verse>Benjamin's firstborn son was Bela, followed by Ashbel, Aharah,</verse>
<verse>Nohah, and Rapha--five in all.</verse>
<verse>Bela's sons were Addar, Gera, Abihud,</verse>
<verse>Abishua, Naaman, Ahoah,</verse>
<verse>Gera, Shephuphan, and Huram.</verse>
<verse>These are the families of Ehud that lived in Geba and were exiled to Manahath:</verse>
<verse>Naaman, Ahijah, and Gera, who led them to exile and had Uzza and Ahihud.</verse>
<verse>In the land of Moab, Shaharaim had children after he divorced his wives Hushim and Baara.</verse>
<verse>From his new wife Hodesh he had Jobab, Zibia, Mesha, Malcam,</verse>
<verse>Jeuz, Sakia, and Mirmah--sons who became heads of families.</verse>
<verse>From his earlier wife Hushim he had Abitub and Elpaal.</verse>
<verse>Elpaal's sons were Eber, Misham, and Shemed, who built Ono and Lod with all their villages.</verse>
<verse>Beriah and Shema were family chiefs who lived at Aijalon. They drove out the citizens of Gath.</verse>
<verse>Their brothers were Shashak and Jeremoth.</verse>
<verse>The sons of Beriah were Zebadiah, Arad, Eder,</verse>
<verse>Michael, Ishpah, and Joha.</verse>
<verse>The sons of Elpaal were Zebadiah, Meshullam, Hizki, Heber,</verse>
<verse>Ishmerai, Izliah, and Jobab.</verse>
<verse>The sons of Shimei were Jakim, Zicri, Zabdi,</verse>
<verse>Elienai, Zillethai, Eliel,</verse>
<verse>Adaiah, Beraiah, and Shimrath.</verse>
<verse>The sons of Shashak were Ishpan, Eber, Eliel,</verse>
<verse>Abdon, Zicri, Hanan,</verse>
<verse>Hananiah, Elam, Anthothijah,</verse>
<verse>Iphdeiah, and Penuel.</verse>
<verse>The sons of Jeroham were Shamsherai, Shehariah, Athaliah,</verse>
<verse>Jaareshiah, Elijah, and Zicri.</verse>
<verse>These were the chiefs of the families as listed in their family tree. They lived in Jerusalem.</verse>
<verse>Jeiel the father of Gibeon lived in Gibeon. His wife's name was Maacah.</verse>
<verse>Abdon was his firstborn son, followed by Zur, Kish, Baal, Nadab,</verse>
<verse>Gedor, Ahio, Zeker, and Mikloth.</verse>
<verse>Mikloth had Shimeah. They lived in the neighborhood of their extended families in Jerusalem.</verse>
<verse>Ner had Kish, Kish had Saul, and Saul had Jonathan, Malki-Shua, Abinadab, and Esh-Baal.</verse>
<verse>Jonathan had Merib-Baal, and Merib-Baal had Micah.</verse>
<verse>Micah's sons were Pithon, Melech, Tarea, and Ahaz.</verse>
<verse>Ahaz had Jehoaddah and Jehoaddah had Alemeth, Azmaveth, and Zimri. Zimri had Moza and</verse>
<verse>Moza had Binea. Raphah was his son, Eleasah his son, and Azel his son.</verse>
<verse>Azel had six sons named Azrikam, Bokeru, Ishmael, Sheariah, Obadiah, and Hanan.</verse>
<verse>His brother Eshek's sons were Ulam his firstborn, followed by Jeush and Eliphelet.</verse>
<verse>Ulam's sons were warriors well known as archers. They had lots of sons and grandsons--at least 150. These were all in Benjamin's family tree.</verse>
</chapter>