<chapter translation="MSG" testament="Old" book="1 Chronicles" book-id="13" n="9">
<verse>This is the complete family tree for all Israel, recorded in the Royal Annals of the Kings of Israel and Judah at the time they were exiled to Babylon because of their unbelieving and disobedient lives.</verse>
<verse>The first Israelites to return from exile to their homes and cities were the priests, the Levites, and the temple support staff.</verse>
<verse>Returning to Jerusalem from the families of Judah, Benjamin, Ephraim, and Manasseh were the following:</verse>
<verse>Uthai son of Ammihud, the son of Omri, the son of Imri, the son of Bani, from the line of Perez son of Judah;</verse>
<verse>from the Shilonites were Asaiah the firstborn and his sons;</verse>
<verse>from the family of Zerah there was Jeuel. There were 690 in the Judah group.</verse>
<verse>From the family of Benjamin were Sallu son of Meshullam, the son of Hodaviah, the son of Hassenuah,</verse>
<verse>and Ibneiah son of Jeroham, and Elah son of Uzzi, the son of Micri, and Meshullam son of Shephatiah, the son of Reuel, the son of Ibnijah.</verse>
<verse>There were 956 in the Benjamin group. All these named were heads of families.</verse>
<verse>From the company of priests there were Jedaiah; Jehoiarib; Jakin;</verse>
<verse>Azariah son of Hilkiah, the son of Meshullam, the son of Zadok, the son of Meraioth, the son of Ahitub, who was in charge of taking care of the house of God;</verse>
<verse>Adaiah son of Jeroham, the son of Pashhur, the son of Malkijah; also Maasai son of Adiel, the son of Jahzerah, the son of Meshullam, the son of Meshillemith, the son of Immer.</verse>
<verse>The priests, all of them heads of families, numbered 1,760, skilled and seasoned servants in the work of worshiping God.</verse>
<verse>From the Levites were Shemaiah son of Hasshub, the son of Azrikam, the son of Hashabiah, a Merarite;</verse>
<verse>then Bakbakkar, Heresh, Galal, Mattaniah son of Mica, the son of Zicri, the son of Asaph;</verse>
<verse>also Obadiah son of Shemaiah, the son of Galal, the son of Jeduthun; and finally Berekiah son of Asa, the son of Elkanah, who lived in the villages of the Netophathites.</verse>
<verse>The security guards were Shallum, Akkub, Talmon, Ahiman, and their brothers. Shallum was the chief</verse>
<verse>and up to now the security guard at the King's Gate on the east. They also served as security guards at the camps of Levite families.</verse>
<verse>Shallum son of Kore, the son of Ebiasaph, the son of Korah, along with his brothers in the Korahite family, were in charge of the services of worship as doorkeepers of the Tent, as their ancestors had guarded the entrance to the camp of God.</verse>
<verse>In the early days, Phinehas son of Eleazar was in charge of the security guards--God be with him!</verse>
<verse>Now Zechariah son of Meshelemiah was the security guard at the entrance of the Tent of Meeting.</verse>
<verse>The number of those who had been chosen to be security guards was 212--they were officially registered in their own camps. David and Samuel the seer handpicked them for their dependability.</verse>
<verse>They and their sons had the permanent responsibility for guarding the gates of God's house, the house of worship;</verse>
<verse>the main security guards were posted at the four entrances, east, west, north, and south;</verse>
<verse>their brothers in the villages were scheduled to give them relief weekly--the four main security guards were responsible for round-the-clock surveillance.</verse>
<verse>Being Levites, they were responsible for the security of all supplies and valuables in the house of God.</verse>
<verse>They kept watch all through the night and had the key to open the doors each morning.</verse>
<verse>Some were in charge of the articles used in The Temple worship--they counted them both when they brought them in and when they took them out.</verse>
<verse>Others were in charge of supplies in the sanctuary--flour, wine, oil, incense, and spices.</verse>
<verse>And some of the priests were assigned to mixing the oils for the perfume.</verse>
<verse>The Levite Mattithiah, the firstborn son of Shallum the Korahite, was responsible for baking the bread for the services of worship.</verse>
<verse>Some of the brothers, sons of the Kohathites, were assigned to preparing the bread set out on the table each Sabbath.</verse>
<verse>And then there were the musicians, all heads of Levite families. They had permanent living quarters in The Temple; because they were on twenty-four-hour duty,</verse>
<verse>they were exempt from all other duties. These were the heads of Levite families as designated in their family tree. They lived in Jerusalem.</verse>
<verse>Jeiel the father of Gibeon lived at Gibeon; his wife was Maacah.</verse>
<verse>His firstborn son was Abdon, followed by Zur, Kish, Baal, Ner, Nadab,</verse>
<verse>Gedor, Ahio, Zechariah, and Mikloth.</verse>
<verse>Mikloth had Shimeam. They lived in the same neighborhood as their relatives in Jerusalem.</verse>
<verse>Ner had Kish, Kish had Saul, Saul had Jonathan, Malki-Shua, Abinadab, and Esh-Baal.</verse>
<verse>Merib-Baal was the son of Jonathan and Merib-Baal had Micah.</verse>
<verse>Micah's sons were Pithon, Melech, and Tahrea.</verse>
<verse>Ahaz had Jarah, Jarah had Alemeth, Azmaveth, and Zimri; Zimri had Moza,</verse>
<verse>Moza had Binea, Rephaiah was his son, Eleasah was his son, and Azel was his son.</verse>
<verse>Azel had six sons: Azrikam, Bokeru, Ishmael, Sheariah, Obadiah, and Hanan--the sons of Azel. [JC]</verse>
</chapter>