<chapter translation="KJV" testament="Old" book="ISA" n="26">
      <verse>In that day shall this song be sung in the land of Judah; We have a strong city; salvation will <supplied>God</supplied> appoint <supplied>for</supplied> walls and bulwarks.
</verse><verse>Open ye the gates, that the righteous nation which keepeth the truth may enter in.
</verse><verse>Thou wilt keep <supplied>him</supplied> in perfect peace, <supplied>whose</supplied> mind <supplied>is</supplied> stayed <supplied>on thee:</supplied> because he trusteth in thee.
</verse><verse>Trust ye in the LORD for ever: for in the LORD JEHOVAH <supplied>is</supplied> everlasting strength:
     
      </verse>
      <verse>For he bringeth down them that dwell on high; the lofty city, he layeth it low; he layeth it low, <supplied>even</supplied> to the ground; he bringeth it <supplied>even</supplied> to the dust.
</verse><verse>The foot shall tread it down, <supplied>even</supplied> the feet of the poor, <supplied>and</supplied> the steps of the needy.
</verse><verse>The way of the just <supplied>is</supplied> uprightness: thou, most upright, dost weigh the path of the just.
</verse><verse>Yea, in the way of thy judgments, O LORD, have we waited for thee; the desire of <supplied>our</supplied> soul <supplied>is</supplied> to thy name, and to the remembrance of thee.
</verse><verse>With my soul have I desired thee in the night; yea, with my spirit within me will I seek thee early: for when thy judgments <supplied>are</supplied> in the earth, the inhabitants of the world will learn righteousness.
</verse><verse>Let favour be shewed to the wicked, <supplied>yet</supplied> will he not learn righteousness: in the land of uprightness will he deal unjustly, and will not behold the majesty of the LORD.
</verse><verse>LORD, <supplied>when</supplied> thy hand is lifted up, they will not see: <supplied>but</supplied> they shall see, and be ashamed for <supplied>their</supplied> envy at the people; yea, the fire of thine enemies shall devour them.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>LORD, thou wilt ordain peace for us: for thou also hast wrought all our works in us.
</verse><verse>O LORD our God, <supplied>other</supplied> lords besides thee have had dominion over us: <supplied>but</supplied> by thee only will we make mention of thy name.
</verse><verse><supplied>They are</supplied> dead, they shall not live; <supplied>they are</supplied> deceased, they shall not rise: therefore hast thou visited and destroyed them, and made all their memory to perish.
</verse><verse>Thou hast increased the nation, O LORD, thou hast increased the nation: thou art glorified: thou hadst removed <supplied>it</supplied> far <supplied>unto</supplied> all the ends of the earth.
</verse><verse>LORD, in trouble have they visited thee, they poured out a prayer <supplied>when</supplied> thy chastening <supplied>was</supplied> upon them.
</verse><verse>Like as a woman with child, <supplied>that</supplied> draweth near the time of her delivery, is in pain, <supplied>and</supplied> crieth out in her pangs; so have we been in thy sight, O LORD.
</verse><verse>We have been with child, we have been in pain, we have as it were brought forth wind; we have not wrought any deliverance in the earth; neither have the inhabitants of the world fallen.
</verse><verse>Thy dead <supplied>men</supplied> shall live, <supplied>together with</supplied> my dead body shall they arise. Awake and sing, ye that dwell in dust: for thy dew <supplied>is as</supplied> the dew of herbs, and the earth shall cast out the dead.
     
      </verse>
      <verse>Come, my people, enter thou into thy chambers, and shut thy doors about thee: hide thyself as it were for a little moment, until the indignation be overpast.
</verse><verse>For, behold, the LORD cometh out of his place to punish the inhabitants of the earth for their iniquity: the earth also shall disclose her blood, and shall no more cover her slain.
     
      </verse>
      </chapter>