<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Psalms" book_id="19" n="10">
<verse>Why do You stand afar off, O LORD? Why do You hide Yourself in times of trouble?</verse>
<verse>In pride the wicked hotly pursue the afflicted; Let them be caught in the plots which they have devised.</verse>
<verse>For the wicked boasts of his heart's desire, And the greedy man curses and spurns the LORD.</verse>
<verse>The wicked, in the haughtiness of his countenance, does not seek Him. All his thoughts are, "There is no God."</verse>
<verse>His ways prosper at all times; Your judgments are on high, out of his sight; As for all his adversaries, he snorts at them.</verse>
<verse>He says to himself, "I will not be moved; Throughout all generations I will not be in adversity."</verse>
<verse>His mouth is full of curses and deceit and oppression; Under his tongue is mischief and wickedness.</verse>
<verse>He sits in the lurking places of the villages; In the hiding places he kills the innocent; His eyes stealthily watch for the unfortunate.</verse>
<verse>He lurks in a hiding place as a lion in his lair; He lurks to catch the afflicted; He catches the afflicted when he draws him into his net.</verse>
<verse>He crouches, he bows down, And the unfortunate fall by his mighty ones.</verse>
<verse>He says to himself, "God has forgotten; He has hidden His face; He will never see it."</verse>
<verse>Arise, O LORD; O God, lift up Your hand. Do not forget the afflicted.</verse>
<verse>Why has the wicked spurned God? He has said to himself, "You will not require it."</verse>
<verse>You have seen it, for You have beheld mischief and vexation to take it into Your hand. The unfortunate commits himself to You; You have been the helper of the orphan.</verse>
<verse>Break the arm of the wicked and the evildoer, Seek out his wickedness until You find none.</verse>
<verse>The LORD is King forever and ever; Nations have perished from His land.</verse>
<verse>O LORD, You have heard the desire of the humble; You will strengthen their heart, You will incline Your ear</verse>
<verse>To vindicate the orphan and the oppressed, So that man who is of the earth will no longer cause terror.</verse>
</chapter>