<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Psalms" book-id="19" n="102">
<verse>Hear my prayer, O LORD! And let my cry for help come to You.</verse>
<verse>Do not hide Your face from me in the day of my distress; Incline Your ear to me; In the day when I call answer me quickly.</verse>
<verse>For my days have been consumed in smoke, And my bones have been scorched like a hearth.</verse>
<verse>My heart has been smitten like grass and has withered away, Indeed, I forget to eat my bread.</verse>
<verse>Because of the loudness of my groaning My bones cling to my flesh.</verse>
<verse>I resemble a pelican of the wilderness; I have become like an owl of the waste places.</verse>
<verse>I lie awake, I have become like a lonely bird on a housetop.</verse>
<verse>My enemies have reproached me all day long; Those who deride me have used my name as a curse.</verse>
<verse>For I have eaten ashes like bread And mingled my drink with weeping</verse>
<verse>Because of Your indignation and Your wrath, For You have lifted me up and cast me away.</verse>
<verse>My days are like a lengthened shadow, And I wither away like grass.</verse>
<verse>But You, O LORD, abide forever, And Your name to all generations.</verse>
<verse>You will arise and have compassion on Zion; For it is time to be gracious to her, For the appointed time has come.</verse>
<verse>Surely Your servants find pleasure in her stones And feel pity for her dust.</verse>
<verse>So the nations will fear the name of the LORD And all the kings of the earth Your glory.</verse>
<verse>For the LORD has built up Zion; He has appeared in His glory.</verse>
<verse>He has regarded the prayer of the destitute And has not despised their prayer.</verse>
<verse>This will be written for the generation to come, That a people yet to be created may praise the LORD.</verse>
<verse>For He looked down from His holy height; From heaven the LORD gazed upon the earth,</verse>
<verse>To hear the groaning of the prisoner, To set free those who were doomed to death,</verse>
<verse>That men may tell of the name of the LORD in Zion And His praise in Jerusalem,</verse>
<verse>When the peoples are gathered together, And the kingdoms, to serve the LORD.</verse>
<verse>He has weakened my strength in the way; He has shortened my days.</verse>
<verse>I say, "O my God, do not take me away in the midst of my days, Your years are throughout all generations.</verse>
<verse>"Of old You founded the earth, And the heavens are the work of Your hands.</verse>
<verse>"Even they will perish, but You endure; And all of them will wear out like a garment; Like clothing You will change them and they will be changed.</verse>
<verse>"But You are the same, And Your years will not come to an end.</verse>
<verse>"The children of Your servants will continue, And their descendants will be established before You."</verse>
</chapter>