<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Psalms" book-id="19" n="103">
<verse>Bless the LORD, O my soul, And all that is within me, bless His holy name.</verse>
<verse>Bless the LORD, O my soul, And forget none of His benefits;</verse>
<verse>Who pardons all your iniquities, Who heals all your diseases;</verse>
<verse>Who redeems your life from the pit, Who crowns you with lovingkindness and compassion;</verse>
<verse>Who satisfies your years with good things, So that your youth is renewed like the eagle.</verse>
<verse>The LORD performs righteous deeds And judgments for all who are oppressed.</verse>
<verse>He made known His ways to Moses, His acts to the sons of Israel.</verse>
<verse>The LORD is compassionate and gracious, Slow to anger and abounding in lovingkindness.</verse>
<verse>He will not always strive with us, Nor will He keep His anger forever.</verse>
<verse>He has not dealt with us according to our sins, Nor rewarded us according to our iniquities.</verse>
<verse>For as high as the heavens are above the earth, So great is His lovingkindness toward those who fear Him.</verse>
<verse>As far as the east is from the west, So far has He removed our transgressions from us.</verse>
<verse>Just as a father has compassion on his children, So the LORD has compassion on those who fear Him.</verse>
<verse>For He Himself knows our frame; He is mindful that we are but dust.</verse>
<verse>As for man, his days are like grass; As a flower of the field, so he flourishes.</verse>
<verse>When the wind has passed over it, it is no more, And its place acknowledges it no longer.</verse>
<verse>But the lovingkindness of the LORD is from everlasting to everlasting on those who fear Him, And His righteousness to children's children,</verse>
<verse>To those who keep His covenant And remember His precepts to do them.</verse>
<verse>The LORD has established His throne in the heavens, And His sovereignty rules over all.</verse>
<verse>Bless the LORD, you His angels, Mighty in strength, who perform His word, Obeying the voice of His word!</verse>
<verse>Bless the LORD, all you His hosts, You who serve Him, doing His will.</verse>
<verse>Bless the LORD, all you works of His, In all places of His dominion; Bless the LORD, O my soul!</verse>
</chapter>