<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Psalms" book_id="19" n="104">
<verse>Bless the LORD, O my soul! O LORD my God, You are very great; You are clothed with splendor and majesty,</verse>
<verse>Covering Yourself with light as with a cloak, Stretching out heaven like a tent curtain.</verse>
<verse>He lays the beams of His upper chambers in the waters; He makes the clouds His chariot; He walks upon the wings of the wind;</verse>
<verse>He makes the winds His messengers, Flaming fire His ministers.</verse>
<verse>He established the earth upon its foundations, So that it will not totter forever and ever.</verse>
<verse>You covered it with the deep as with a garment; The waters were standing above the mountains.</verse>
<verse>At Your rebuke they fled, At the sound of Your thunder they hurried away.</verse>
<verse>The mountains rose; the valleys sank down To the place which You established for them.</verse>
<verse>You set a boundary that they may not pass over, So that they will not return to cover the earth.</verse>
<verse>He sends forth springs in the valleys; They flow between the mountains;</verse>
<verse>They give drink to every beast of the field; The wild donkeys quench their thirst.</verse>
<verse>Beside them the birds of the heavens dwell; They lift up their voices among the branches.</verse>
<verse>He waters the mountains from His upper chambers; The earth is satisfied with the fruit of His works.</verse>
<verse>He causes the grass to grow for the cattle, And vegetation for the labor of man, So that he may bring forth food from the earth,</verse>
<verse>And wine which makes man's heart glad, So that he may make his face glisten with oil, And food which sustains man's heart.</verse>
<verse>The trees of the LORD drink their fill, The cedars of Lebanon which He planted,</verse>
<verse>Where the birds build their nests, And the stork, whose home is the fir trees.</verse>
<verse>The high mountains are for the wild goats; The cliffs are a refuge for the shephanim.</verse>
<verse>He made the moon for the seasons; The sun knows the place of its setting.</verse>
<verse>You appoint darkness and it becomes night, In which all the beasts of the forest prowl about.</verse>
<verse>The young lions roar after their prey And seek their food from God.</verse>
<verse>When the sun rises they withdraw And lie down in their dens.</verse>
<verse>Man goes forth to his work And to his labor until evening.</verse>
<verse>O LORD, how many are Your works! In wisdom You have made them all; The earth is full of Your possessions.</verse>
<verse>There is the sea, great and broad, In which are swarms without number, Animals both small and great.</verse>
<verse>There the ships move along, And Leviathan, which You have formed to sport in it.</verse>
<verse>They all wait for You To give them their food in due season.</verse>
<verse>You give to them, they gather it up; You open Your hand, they are satisfied with good.</verse>
<verse>You hide Your face, they are dismayed; You take away their spirit, they expire And return to their dust.</verse>
<verse>You send forth Your Spirit, they are created; And You renew the face of the ground.</verse>
<verse>Let the glory of the LORD endure forever; Let the LORD be glad in His works;</verse>
<verse>He looks at the earth, and it trembles; He touches the mountains, and they smoke.</verse>
<verse>I will sing to the LORD as long as I live; I will sing praise to my God while I have my being.</verse>
<verse>Let my meditation be pleasing to Him; As for me, I shall be glad in the LORD.</verse>
<verse>Let sinners be consumed from the earth And let the wicked be no more. Bless the LORD, O my soul. Praise the LORD!</verse>
</chapter>