<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Psalms" book-id="19" n="105">
<verse>Oh give thanks to the LORD, call upon His name; Make known His deeds among the peoples.</verse>
<verse>Sing to Him, sing praises to Him; Speak of all His wonders.</verse>
<verse>Glory in His holy name; Let the heart of those who seek the LORD be glad.</verse>
<verse>Seek the LORD and His strength; Seek His face continually.</verse>
<verse>Remember His wonders which He has done, His marvels and the judgments uttered by His mouth,</verse>
<verse>O seed of Abraham, His servant, O sons of Jacob, His chosen ones!</verse>
<verse>He is the LORD our God; His judgments are in all the earth.</verse>
<verse>He has remembered His covenant forever, The word which He commanded to a thousand generations,</verse>
<verse>The covenant which He made with Abraham, And His oath to Isaac.</verse>
<verse>Then He confirmed it to Jacob for a statute, To Israel as an everlasting covenant,</verse>
<verse>Saying, "To you I will give the land of Canaan As the portion of your inheritance,"</verse>
<verse>When they were only a few men in number, Very few, and strangers in it.</verse>
<verse>And they wandered about from nation to nation, From one kingdom to another people.</verse>
<verse>He permitted no man to oppress them, And He reproved kings for their sakes:</verse>
<verse>"Do not touch My anointed ones, And do My prophets no harm."</verse>
<verse>And He called for a famine upon the land; He broke the whole staff of bread.</verse>
<verse>He sent a man before them, Joseph, who was sold as a slave.</verse>
<verse>They afflicted his feet with fetters, He himself was laid in irons;</verse>
<verse>Until the time that his word came to pass, The word of the LORD tested him.</verse>
<verse>The king sent and released him, The ruler of peoples, and set him free.</verse>
<verse>He made him lord of his house And ruler over all his possessions,</verse>
<verse>To imprison his princes at will, That he might teach his elders wisdom.</verse>
<verse>Israel also came into Egypt; Thus Jacob sojourned in the land of Ham.</verse>
<verse>And He caused His people to be very fruitful, And made them stronger than their adversaries.</verse>
<verse>He turned their heart to hate His people, To deal craftily with His servants.</verse>
<verse>He sent Moses His servant, And Aaron, whom He had chosen.</verse>
<verse>They performed His wondrous acts among them, And miracles in the land of Ham.</verse>
<verse>He sent darkness and made it dark; And they did not rebel against His words.</verse>
<verse>He turned their waters into blood And caused their fish to die.</verse>
<verse>Their land swarmed with frogs Even in the chambers of their kings.</verse>
<verse>He spoke, and there came a swarm of flies And gnats in all their territory.</verse>
<verse>He gave them hail for rain, And flaming fire in their land.</verse>
<verse>He struck down their vines also and their fig trees, And shattered the trees of their territory.</verse>
<verse>He spoke, and locusts came, And young locusts, even without number,</verse>
<verse>And ate up all vegetation in their land, And ate up the fruit of their ground.</verse>
<verse>He also struck down all the firstborn in their land, The first fruits of all their vigor.</verse>
<verse>Then He brought them out with silver and gold, And among His tribes there was not one who stumbled.</verse>
<verse>Egypt was glad when they departed, For the dread of them had fallen upon them.</verse>
<verse>He spread a cloud for a covering, And fire to illumine by night.</verse>
<verse>They asked, and He brought quail, And satisfied them with the bread of heaven.</verse>
<verse>He opened the rock and water flowed out; It ran in the dry places like a river.</verse>
<verse>For He remembered His holy word With Abraham His servant;</verse>
<verse>And He brought forth His people with joy, His chosen ones with a joyful shout.</verse>
<verse>He gave them also the lands of the nations, That they might take possession of the fruit of the peoples' labor,</verse>
<verse>So that they might keep His statutes And observe His laws, Praise the LORD!</verse>
</chapter>