<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Psalms" book_id="19" n="106">
<verse>Praise the LORD! Oh give thanks to the LORD, for He is good; For His lovingkindness is everlasting.</verse>
<verse>Who can speak of the mighty deeds of the LORD, Or can show forth all His praise?</verse>
<verse>How blessed are those who keep justice, Who practice righteousness at all times!</verse>
<verse>Remember me, O LORD, in Your favor toward Your people; Visit me with Your salvation,</verse>
<verse>That I may see the prosperity of Your chosen ones, That I may rejoice in the gladness of Your nation, That I may glory with Your inheritance.</verse>
<verse>We have sinned like our fathers, We have committed iniquity, we have behaved wickedly.</verse>
<verse>Our fathers in Egypt did not understand Your wonders; They did not remember Your abundant kindnesses, But rebelled by the sea, at the Red Sea.</verse>
<verse>Nevertheless He saved them for the sake of His name, That He might make His power known.</verse>
<verse>Thus He rebuked the Red Sea and it dried up, And He led them through the deeps, as through the wilderness.</verse>
<verse>So He saved them from the hand of the one who hated them, And redeemed them from the hand of the enemy.</verse>
<verse>The waters covered their adversaries; Not one of them was left.</verse>
<verse>Then they believed His words; They sang His praise.</verse>
<verse>They quickly forgot His works; They did not wait for His counsel,</verse>
<verse>But craved intensely in the wilderness, And tempted God in the desert.</verse>
<verse>So He gave them their request, But sent a wasting disease among them.</verse>
<verse>When they became envious of Moses in the camp, And of Aaron, the holy one of the LORD,</verse>
<verse>The earth opened and swallowed up Dathan, And engulfed the company of Abiram.</verse>
<verse>And a fire blazed up in their company; The flame consumed the wicked.</verse>
<verse>They made a calf in Horeb And worshiped a molten image.</verse>
<verse>Thus they exchanged their glory For the image of an ox that eats grass.</verse>
<verse>They forgot God their Savior, Who had done great things in Egypt,</verse>
<verse>Wonders in the land of Ham And awesome things by the Red Sea.</verse>
<verse>Therefore He said that He would destroy them, Had not Moses His chosen one stood in the breach before Him, To turn away His wrath from destroying them.</verse>
<verse>Then they despised the pleasant land; They did not believe in His word,</verse>
<verse>But grumbled in their tents; They did not listen to the voice of the LORD.</verse>
<verse>Therefore He swore to them That He would cast them down in the wilderness,</verse>
<verse>And that He would cast their seed among the nations And scatter them in the lands.</verse>
<verse>They joined themselves also to Baal-peor, And ate sacrifices offered to the dead.</verse>
<verse>Thus they provoked Him to anger with their deeds, And the plague broke out among them.</verse>
<verse>Then Phinehas stood up and interposed, And so the plague was stayed.</verse>
<verse>And it was reckoned to him for righteousness, To all generations forever.</verse>
<verse>They also provoked Him to wrath at the waters of Meribah, So that it went hard with Moses on their account;</verse>
<verse>Because they were rebellious against His Spirit, He spoke rashly with his lips.</verse>
<verse>They did not destroy the peoples, As the LORD commanded them,</verse>
<verse>But they mingled with the nations And learned their practices,</verse>
<verse>And served their idols, Which became a snare to them.</verse>
<verse>They even sacrificed their sons and their daughters to the demons,</verse>
<verse>And shed innocent blood, The blood of their sons and their daughters, Whom they sacrificed to the idols of Canaan; And the land was polluted with the blood.</verse>
<verse>Thus they became unclean in their practices, And played the harlot in their deeds.</verse>
<verse>Therefore the anger of the LORD was kindled against His people And He abhorred His inheritance.</verse>
<verse>Then He gave them into the hand of the nations, And those who hated them ruled over them.</verse>
<verse>Their enemies also oppressed them, And they were subdued under their power.</verse>
<verse>Many times He would deliver them; They, however, were rebellious in their counsel, And so sank down in their iniquity.</verse>
<verse>Nevertheless He looked upon their distress When He heard their cry;</verse>
<verse>And He remembered His covenant for their sake, And relented according to the greatness of His lovingkindness.</verse>
<verse>He also made them objects of compassion In the presence of all their captors.</verse>
<verse>Save us, O LORD our God, And gather us from among the nations, To give thanks to Your holy name And glory in Your praise.</verse>
<verse>Blessed be the LORD, the God of Israel, From everlasting even to everlasting. And let all the people say, "Amen." Praise the LORD!</verse>
</chapter>