<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Psalms" book-id="19" n="107">
<verse>Oh give thanks to the LORD, for He is good, For His lovingkindness is everlasting.</verse>
<verse>Let the redeemed of the LORD say so, Whom He has redeemed from the hand of the adversary</verse>
<verse>And gathered from the lands, From the east and from the west, From the north and from the south.</verse>
<verse>They wandered in the wilderness in a desert region; They did not find a way to an inhabited city.</verse>
<verse>They were hungry and thirsty; Their soul fainted within them.</verse>
<verse>Then they cried out to the LORD in their trouble; He delivered them out of their distresses.</verse>
<verse>He led them also by a straight way, To go to an inhabited city.</verse>
<verse>Let them give thanks to the LORD for His lovingkindness, And for His wonders to the sons of men!</verse>
<verse>For He has satisfied the thirsty soul, And the hungry soul He has filled with what is good.</verse>
<verse>There were those who dwelt in darkness and in the shadow of death, Prisoners in misery and chains,</verse>
<verse>Because they had rebelled against the words of God And spurned the counsel of the Most High.</verse>
<verse>Therefore He humbled their heart with labor; They stumbled and there was none to help.</verse>
<verse>Then they cried out to the LORD in their trouble; He saved them out of their distresses.</verse>
<verse>He brought them out of darkness and the shadow of death And broke their bands apart.</verse>
<verse>Let them give thanks to the LORD for His lovingkindness, And for His wonders to the sons of men!</verse>
<verse>For He has shattered gates of bronze And cut bars of iron asunder.</verse>
<verse>Fools, because of their rebellious way, And because of their iniquities, were afflicted.</verse>
<verse>Their soul abhorred all kinds of food, And they drew near to the gates of death.</verse>
<verse>Then they cried out to the LORD in their trouble; He saved them out of their distresses.</verse>
<verse>He sent His word and healed them, And delivered them from their destructions.</verse>
<verse>Let them give thanks to the LORD for His lovingkindness, And for His wonders to the sons of men!</verse>
<verse>Let them also offer sacrifices of thanksgiving, And tell of His works with joyful singing.</verse>
<verse>Those who go down to the sea in ships, Who do business on great waters;</verse>
<verse>They have seen the works of the LORD, And His wonders in the deep.</verse>
<verse>For He spoke and raised up a stormy wind, Which lifted up the waves of the sea.</verse>
<verse>They rose up to the heavens, they went down to the depths; Their soul melted away in their misery.</verse>
<verse>They reeled and staggered like a drunken man, And were at their wits' end.</verse>
<verse>Then they cried to the LORD in their trouble, And He brought them out of their distresses.</verse>
<verse>He caused the storm to be still, So that the waves of the sea were hushed.</verse>
<verse>Then they were glad because they were quiet, So He guided them to their desired haven.</verse>
<verse>Let them give thanks to the LORD for His lovingkindness, And for His wonders to the sons of men!</verse>
<verse>Let them extol Him also in the congregation of the people, And praise Him at the seat of the elders.</verse>
<verse>He changes rivers into a wilderness And springs of water into a thirsty ground;</verse>
<verse>A fruitful land into a salt waste, Because of the wickedness of those who dwell in it.</verse>
<verse>He changes a wilderness into a pool of water And a dry land into springs of water;</verse>
<verse>And there He makes the hungry to dwell, So that they may establish an inhabited city,</verse>
<verse>And sow fields and plant vineyards, And gather a fruitful harvest.</verse>
<verse>Also He blesses them and they multiply greatly, And He does not let their cattle decrease.</verse>
<verse>When they are diminished and bowed down Through oppression, misery and sorrow,</verse>
<verse>He pours contempt upon princes And makes them wander in a pathless waste.</verse>
<verse>But He sets the needy securely on high away from affliction, And makes his families like a flock.</verse>
<verse>The upright see it and are glad; But all unrighteousness shuts its mouth.</verse>
<verse>Who is wise? Let him give heed to these things, And consider the lovingkindnesses of the LORD.</verse>
</chapter>