<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Psalms" book-id="19" n="109">
<verse>O God of my praise, Do not be silent!</verse>
<verse>For they have opened the wicked and deceitful mouth against me; They have spoken against me with a lying tongue.</verse>
<verse>They have also surrounded me with words of hatred, And fought against me without cause.</verse>
<verse>In return for my love they act as my accusers; But I am in prayer.</verse>
<verse>Thus they have repaid me evil for good And hatred for my love.</verse>
<verse>Appoint a wicked man over him, And let an accuser stand at his right hand.</verse>
<verse>When he is judged, let him come forth guilty, And let his prayer become sin.</verse>
<verse>Let his days be few; Let another take his office.</verse>
<verse>Let his children be fatherless And his wife a widow.</verse>
<verse>Let his children wander about and beg; And let them seek sustenance far from their ruined homes.</verse>
<verse>Let the creditor seize all that he has, And let strangers plunder the product of his labor.</verse>
<verse>Let there be none to extend lovingkindness to him, Nor any to be gracious to his fatherless children.</verse>
<verse>Let his posterity be cut off; In a following generation let their name be blotted out.</verse>
<verse>Let the iniquity of his fathers be remembered before the LORD, And do not let the sin of his mother be blotted out.</verse>
<verse>Let them be before the LORD continually, That He may cut off their memory from the earth;</verse>
<verse>Because he did not remember to show lovingkindness, But persecuted the afflicted and needy man, And the despondent in heart, to put them to death.</verse>
<verse>He also loved cursing, so it came to him; And he did not delight in blessing, so it was far from him.</verse>
<verse>But he clothed himself with cursing as with his garment, And it entered into his body like water And like oil into his bones.</verse>
<verse>Let it be to him as a garment with which he covers himself, And for a belt with which he constantly girds himself.</verse>
<verse>Let this be the reward of my accusers from the LORD, And of those who speak evil against my soul.</verse>
<verse>But You, O GOD, the Lord, deal kindly with me for Your name's sake; Because Your lovingkindness is good, deliver me;</verse>
<verse>For I am afflicted and needy, And my heart is wounded within me.</verse>
<verse>I am passing like a shadow when it lengthens; I am shaken off like the locust.</verse>
<verse>My knees are weak from fasting, And my flesh has grown lean, without fatness.</verse>
<verse>I also have become a reproach to them; When they see me, they wag their head.</verse>
<verse>Help me, O LORD my God; Save me according to Your lovingkindness.</verse>
<verse>And let them know that this is Your hand; You, LORD, have done it.</verse>
<verse>Let them curse, but You bless; When they arise, they shall be ashamed, But Your servant shall be glad.</verse>
<verse>Let my accusers be clothed with dishonor, And let them cover themselves with their own shame as with a robe.</verse>
<verse>With my mouth I will give thanks abundantly to the LORD; And in the midst of many I will praise Him.</verse>
<verse>For He stands at the right hand of the needy, To save him from those who judge his soul.</verse>
</chapter>