<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Psalms" book-id="19" n="118">
<verse>Give thanks to the LORD, for He is good; For His lovingkindness is everlasting.</verse>
<verse>Oh let Israel say, "His lovingkindness is everlasting."</verse>
<verse>Oh let the house of Aaron say, "His lovingkindness is everlasting."</verse>
<verse>Oh let those who fear the LORD say, "His lovingkindness is everlasting."</verse>
<verse>From my distress I called upon the LORD; The LORD answered me and set me in a large place.</verse>
<verse>The LORD is for me; I will not fear; What can man do to me?</verse>
<verse>The LORD is for me among those who help me; Therefore I will look with satisfaction on those who hate me.</verse>
<verse>It is better to take refuge in the LORD Than to trust in man.</verse>
<verse>It is better to take refuge in the LORD Than to trust in princes.</verse>
<verse>All nations surrounded me; In the name of the LORD I will surely cut them off.</verse>
<verse>They surrounded me, yes, they surrounded me; In the name of the LORD I will surely cut them off.</verse>
<verse>They surrounded me like bees; They were extinguished as a fire of thorns; In the name of the LORD I will surely cut them off.</verse>
<verse>You pushed me violently so that I was falling, But the LORD helped me.</verse>
<verse>The LORD is my strength and song, And He has become my salvation.</verse>
<verse>The sound of joyful shouting and salvation is in the tents of the righteous; The right hand of the LORD does valiantly.</verse>
<verse>The right hand of the LORD is exalted; The right hand of the LORD does valiantly.</verse>
<verse>I will not die, but live, And tell of the works of the LORD.</verse>
<verse>The LORD has disciplined me severely, But He has not given me over to death.</verse>
<verse>Open to me the gates of righteousness; I shall enter through them, I shall give thanks to the LORD.</verse>
<verse>This is the gate of the LORD; The righteous will enter through it.</verse>
<verse>I shall give thanks to You, for You have answered me, And You have become my salvation.</verse>
<verse>The stone which the builders rejected Has become the chief corner stone.</verse>
<verse>This is the LORD'S doing; It is marvelous in our eyes.</verse>
<verse>This is the day which the LORD has made; Let us rejoice and be glad in it.</verse>
<verse>O LORD, do save, we beseech You; O LORD, we beseech You, do send prosperity!</verse>
<verse>Blessed is the one who comes in the name of the LORD; We have blessed you from the house of the LORD.</verse>
<verse>The LORD is God, and He has given us light; Bind the festival sacrifice with cords to the horns of the altar.</verse>
<verse>You are my God, and I give thanks to You; You are my God, I extol You.</verse>
<verse>Give thanks to the LORD, for He is good; For His lovingkindness is everlasting.</verse>
</chapter>