<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Psalms" book-id="19" n="119">
<verse>How blessed are those whose way is blameless, Who walk in the law of the LORD.</verse>
<verse>How blessed are those who observe His testimonies, Who seek Him with all their heart.</verse>
<verse>They also do no unrighteousness; They walk in His ways.</verse>
<verse>You have ordained Your precepts, That we should keep them diligently.</verse>
<verse>Oh that my ways may be established To keep Your statutes!</verse>
<verse>Then I shall not be ashamed When I look upon all Your commandments.</verse>
<verse>I shall give thanks to You with uprightness of heart, When I learn Your righteous judgments.</verse>
<verse>I shall keep Your statutes; Do not forsake me utterly!</verse>
<verse>How can a young man keep his way pure? By keeping it according to Your word.</verse>
<verse>With all my heart I have sought You; Do not let me wander from Your commandments.</verse>
<verse>Your word I have treasured in my heart, That I may not sin against You.</verse>
<verse>Blessed are You, O LORD; Teach me Your statutes.</verse>
<verse>With my lips I have told of All the ordinances of Your mouth.</verse>
<verse>I have rejoiced in the way of Your testimonies, As much as in all riches.</verse>
<verse>I will meditate on Your precepts And regard Your ways.</verse>
<verse>I shall delight in Your statutes; I shall not forget Your word.</verse>
<verse>Deal bountifully with Your servant, That I may live and keep Your word.</verse>
<verse>Open my eyes, that I may behold Wonderful things from Your law.</verse>
<verse>I am a stranger in the earth; Do not hide Your commandments from me.</verse>
<verse>My soul is crushed with longing After Your ordinances at all times.</verse>
<verse>You rebuke the arrogant, the cursed, Who wander from Your commandments.</verse>
<verse>Take away reproach and contempt from me, For I observe Your testimonies.</verse>
<verse>Even though princes sit and talk against me, Your servant meditates on Your statutes.</verse>
<verse>Your testimonies also are my delight; They are my counselors.</verse>
<verse>My soul cleaves to the dust; Revive me according to Your word.</verse>
<verse>I have told of my ways, and You have answered me; Teach me Your statutes.</verse>
<verse>Make me understand the way of Your precepts, So I will meditate on Your wonders.</verse>
<verse>My soul weeps because of grief; Strengthen me according to Your word.</verse>
<verse>Remove the false way from me, And graciously grant me Your law.</verse>
<verse>I have chosen the faithful way; I have placed Your ordinances before me.</verse>
<verse>I cling to Your testimonies; O LORD, do not put me to shame!</verse>
<verse>I shall run the way of Your commandments, For You will enlarge my heart.</verse>
<verse>Teach me, O LORD, the way of Your statutes, And I shall observe it to the end.</verse>
<verse>Give me understanding, that I may observe Your law And keep it with all my heart.</verse>
<verse>Make me walk in the path of Your commandments, For I delight in it.</verse>
<verse>Incline my heart to Your testimonies And not to dishonest gain.</verse>
<verse>Turn away my eyes from looking at vanity, And revive me in Your ways.</verse>
<verse>Establish Your word to Your servant, As that which produces reverence for You.</verse>
<verse>Turn away my reproach which I dread, For Your ordinances are good.</verse>
<verse>Behold, I long for Your precepts; Revive me through Your righteousness.</verse>
<verse>May Your lovingkindnesses also come to me, O LORD, Your salvation according to Your word;</verse>
<verse>So I will have an answer for him who reproaches me, For I trust in Your word.</verse>
<verse>And do not take the word of truth utterly out of my mouth, For I wait for Your ordinances.</verse>
<verse>So I will keep Your law continually, Forever and ever.</verse>
<verse>And I will walk at liberty, For I seek Your precepts.</verse>
<verse>I will also speak of Your testimonies before kings And shall not be ashamed.</verse>
<verse>I shall delight in Your commandments, Which I love.</verse>
<verse>And I shall lift up my hands to Your commandments, Which I love; And I will meditate on Your statutes.</verse>
<verse>Remember the word to Your servant, In which You have made me hope.</verse>
<verse>This is my comfort in my affliction, That Your word has revived me.</verse>
<verse>The arrogant utterly deride me, Yet I do not turn aside from Your law.</verse>
<verse>I have remembered Your ordinances from of old, O LORD, And comfort myself.</verse>
<verse>Burning indignation has seized me because of the wicked, Who forsake Your law.</verse>
<verse>Your statutes are my songs In the house of my pilgrimage.</verse>
<verse>O LORD, I remember Your name in the night, And keep Your law.</verse>
<verse>This has become mine, That I observe Your precepts.</verse>
<verse>The LORD is my portion; I have promised to keep Your words.</verse>
<verse>I sought Your favor with all my heart; Be gracious to me according to Your word.</verse>
<verse>I considered my ways And turned my feet to Your testimonies.</verse>
<verse>I hastened and did not delay To keep Your commandments.</verse>
<verse>The cords of the wicked have encircled me, But I have not forgotten Your law.</verse>
<verse>At midnight I shall rise to give thanks to You Because of Your righteous ordinances.</verse>
<verse>I am a companion of all those who fear You, And of those who keep Your precepts.</verse>
<verse>The earth is full of Your lovingkindness, O LORD; Teach me Your statutes.</verse>
<verse>You have dealt well with Your servant, O LORD, according to Your word.</verse>
<verse>Teach me good discernment and knowledge, For I believe in Your commandments.</verse>
<verse>Before I was afflicted I went astray, But now I keep Your word.</verse>
<verse>You are good and do good; Teach me Your statutes.</verse>
<verse>The arrogant have forged a lie against me; With all my heart I will observe Your precepts.</verse>
<verse>Their heart is covered with fat, But I delight in Your law.</verse>
<verse>It is good for me that I was afflicted, That I may learn Your statutes.</verse>
<verse>The law of Your mouth is better to me Than thousands of gold and silver pieces.</verse>
<verse>Your hands made me and fashioned me; Give me understanding, that I may learn Your commandments.</verse>
<verse>May those who fear You see me and be glad, Because I wait for Your word.</verse>
<verse>I know, O LORD, that Your judgments are righteous, And that in faithfulness You have afflicted me.</verse>
<verse>O may Your lovingkindness comfort me, According to Your word to Your servant.</verse>
<verse>May Your compassion come to me that I may live, For Your law is my delight.</verse>
<verse>May the arrogant be ashamed, for they subvert me with a lie; But I shall meditate on Your precepts.</verse>
<verse>May those who fear You turn to me, Even those who know Your testimonies.</verse>
<verse>May my heart be blameless in Your statutes, So that I will not be ashamed.</verse>
<verse>My soul languishes for Your salvation; I wait for Your word.</verse>
<verse>My eyes fail with longing for Your word, While I say, "When will You comfort me?"</verse>
<verse>Though I have become like a wineskin in the smoke, I do not forget Your statutes.</verse>
<verse>How many are the days of Your servant? When will You execute judgment on those who persecute me?</verse>
<verse>The arrogant have dug pits for me, Men who are not in accord with Your law.</verse>
<verse>All Your commandments are faithful; They have persecuted me with a lie; help me!</verse>
<verse>They almost destroyed me on earth, But as for me, I did not forsake Your precepts.</verse>
<verse>Revive me according to Your lovingkindness, So that I may keep the testimony of Your mouth.</verse>
<verse>Forever, O LORD, Your word is settled in heaven.</verse>
<verse>Your faithfulness continues throughout all generations; You established the earth, and it stands.</verse>
<verse>They stand this day according to Your ordinances, For all things are Your servants.</verse>
<verse>If Your law had not been my delight, Then I would have perished in my affliction.</verse>
<verse>I will never forget Your precepts, For by them You have revived me.</verse>
<verse>I am Yours, save me; For I have sought Your precepts.</verse>
<verse>The wicked wait for me to destroy me; I shall diligently consider Your testimonies.</verse>
<verse>I have seen a limit to all perfection; Your commandment is exceedingly broad.</verse>
<verse>O how I love Your law! It is my meditation all the day.</verse>
<verse>Your commandments make me wiser than my enemies, For they are ever mine.</verse>
<verse>I have more insight than all my teachers, For Your testimonies are my meditation.</verse>
<verse>I understand more than the aged, Because I have observed Your precepts.</verse>
<verse>I have restrained my feet from every evil way, That I may keep Your word.</verse>
<verse>I have not turned aside from Your ordinances, For You Yourself have taught me.</verse>
<verse>How sweet are Your words to my taste! Yes, sweeter than honey to my mouth!</verse>
<verse>From Your precepts I get understanding; Therefore I hate every false way.</verse>
<verse>Your word is a lamp to my feet And a light to my path.</verse>
<verse>I have sworn and I will confirm it, That I will keep Your righteous ordinances.</verse>
<verse>I am exceedingly afflicted; Revive me, O LORD, according to Your word.</verse>
<verse>O accept the freewill offerings of my mouth, O LORD, And teach me Your ordinances.</verse>
<verse>My life is continually in my hand, Yet I do not forget Your law.</verse>
<verse>The wicked have laid a snare for me, Yet I have not gone astray from Your precepts.</verse>
<verse>I have inherited Your testimonies forever, For they are the joy of my heart.</verse>
<verse>I have inclined my heart to perform Your statutes Forever, even to the end.</verse>
<verse>I hate those who are double-minded, But I love Your law.</verse>
<verse>You are my hiding place and my shield; I wait for Your word.</verse>
<verse>Depart from me, evildoers, That I may observe the commandments of my God.</verse>
<verse>Sustain me according to Your word, that I may live; And do not let me be ashamed of my hope.</verse>
<verse>Uphold me that I may be safe, That I may have regard for Your statutes continually.</verse>
<verse>You have rejected all those who wander from Your statutes, For their deceitfulness is useless.</verse>
<verse>You have removed all the wicked of the earth like dross; Therefore I love Your testimonies.</verse>
<verse>My flesh trembles for fear of You, And I am afraid of Your judgments.</verse>
<verse>I have done justice and righteousness; Do not leave me to my oppressors.</verse>
<verse>Be surety for Your servant for good; Do not let the arrogant oppress me.</verse>
<verse>My eyes fail with longing for Your salvation And for Your righteous word.</verse>
<verse>Deal with Your servant according to Your lovingkindness And teach me Your statutes.</verse>
<verse>I am Your servant; give me understanding, That I may know Your testimonies.</verse>
<verse>It is time for the LORD to act, For they have broken Your law.</verse>
<verse>Therefore I love Your commandments Above gold, yes, above fine gold.</verse>
<verse>Therefore I esteem right all Your precepts concerning everything, I hate every false way.</verse>
<verse>Your testimonies are wonderful; Therefore my soul observes them.</verse>
<verse>The unfolding of Your words gives light; It gives understanding to the simple.</verse>
<verse>I opened my mouth wide and panted, For I longed for Your commandments.</verse>
<verse>Turn to me and be gracious to me, After Your manner with those who love Your name.</verse>
<verse>Establish my footsteps in Your word, And do not let any iniquity have dominion over me.</verse>
<verse>Redeem me from the oppression of man, That I may keep Your precepts.</verse>
<verse>Make Your face shine upon Your servant, And teach me Your statutes.</verse>
<verse>My eyes shed streams of water, Because they do not keep Your law.</verse>
<verse>Righteous are You, O LORD, And upright are Your judgments.</verse>
<verse>You have commanded Your testimonies in righteousness And exceeding faithfulness.</verse>
<verse>My zeal has consumed me, Because my adversaries have forgotten Your words.</verse>
<verse>Your word is very pure, Therefore Your servant loves it.</verse>
<verse>I am small and despised, Yet I do not forget Your precepts.</verse>
<verse>Your righteousness is an everlasting righteousness, And Your law is truth.</verse>
<verse>Trouble and anguish have come upon me, Yet Your commandments are my delight.</verse>
<verse>Your testimonies are righteous forever; Give me understanding that I may live.</verse>
<verse>I cried with all my heart; answer me, O LORD! I will observe Your statutes.</verse>
<verse>I cried to You; save me And I shall keep Your testimonies.</verse>
<verse>I rise before dawn and cry for help; I wait for Your words.</verse>
<verse>My eyes anticipate the night watches, That I may meditate on Your word.</verse>
<verse>Hear my voice according to Your lovingkindness; Revive me, O LORD, according to Your ordinances.</verse>
<verse>Those who follow after wickedness draw near; They are far from Your law.</verse>
<verse>You are near, O LORD, And all Your commandments are truth.</verse>
<verse>Of old I have known from Your testimonies That You have founded them forever.</verse>
<verse>Look upon my affliction and rescue me, For I do not forget Your law.</verse>
<verse>Plead my cause and redeem me; Revive me according to Your word.</verse>
<verse>Salvation is far from the wicked, For they do not seek Your statutes.</verse>
<verse>Great are Your mercies, O LORD; Revive me according to Your ordinances.</verse>
<verse>Many are my persecutors and my adversaries, Yet I do not turn aside from Your testimonies.</verse>
<verse>I behold the treacherous and loathe them, Because they do not keep Your word.</verse>
<verse>Consider how I love Your precepts; Revive me, O LORD, according to Your lovingkindness.</verse>
<verse>The sum of Your word is truth, And every one of Your righteous ordinances is everlasting.</verse>
<verse>Princes persecute me without cause, But my heart stands in awe of Your words.</verse>
<verse>I rejoice at Your word, As one who finds great spoil.</verse>
<verse>I hate and despise falsehood, But I love Your law.</verse>
<verse>Seven times a day I praise You, Because of Your righteous ordinances.</verse>
<verse>Those who love Your law have great peace, And nothing causes them to stumble.</verse>
<verse>I hope for Your salvation, O LORD, And do Your commandments.</verse>
<verse>My soul keeps Your testimonies, And I love them exceedingly.</verse>
<verse>I keep Your precepts and Your testimonies, For all my ways are before You.</verse>
<verse>Let my cry come before You, O LORD; Give me understanding according to Your word.</verse>
<verse>Let my supplication come before You; Deliver me according to Your word.</verse>
<verse>Let my lips utter praise, For You teach me Your statutes.</verse>
<verse>Let my tongue sing of Your word, For all Your commandments are righteousness.</verse>
<verse>Let Your hand be ready to help me, For I have chosen Your precepts.</verse>
<verse>I long for Your salvation, O LORD, And Your law is my delight.</verse>
<verse>Let my soul live that it may praise You, And let Your ordinances help me.</verse>
<verse>I have gone astray like a lost sheep; seek Your servant, For I do not forget Your commandments.</verse>
</chapter>