<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Psalms" book_id="19" n="135">
<verse>Praise the LORD! Praise the name of the LORD; Praise Him, O servants of the LORD,</verse>
<verse>You who stand in the house of the LORD, In the courts of the house of our God!</verse>
<verse>Praise the LORD, for the LORD is good; Sing praises to His name, for it is lovely.</verse>
<verse>For the LORD has chosen Jacob for Himself, Israel for His own possession.</verse>
<verse>For I know that the LORD is great And that our Lord is above all gods.</verse>
<verse>Whatever the LORD pleases, He does, In heaven and in earth, in the seas and in all deeps.</verse>
<verse>He causes the vapors to ascend from the ends of the earth; Who makes lightnings for the rain, Who brings forth the wind from His treasuries.</verse>
<verse>He smote the firstborn of Egypt, Both of man and beast.</verse>
<verse>He sent signs and wonders into your midst, O Egypt, Upon Pharaoh and all his servants.</verse>
<verse>He smote many nations And slew mighty kings,</verse>
<verse>Sihon, king of the Amorites, And Og, king of Bashan, And all the kingdoms of Canaan;</verse>
<verse>And He gave their land as a heritage, A heritage to Israel His people.</verse>
<verse>Your name, O LORD, is everlasting, Your remembrance, O LORD, throughout all generations.</verse>
<verse>For the LORD will judge His people And will have compassion on His servants.</verse>
<verse>The idols of the nations are but silver and gold, The work of man's hands.</verse>
<verse>They have mouths, but they do not speak; They have eyes, but they do not see;</verse>
<verse>They have ears, but they do not hear, Nor is there any breath at all in their mouths.</verse>
<verse>Those who make them will be like them, Yes, everyone who trusts in them.</verse>
<verse>O house of Israel, bless the LORD; O house of Aaron, bless the LORD;</verse>
<verse>O house of Levi, bless the LORD; You who revere the LORD, bless the LORD.</verse>
<verse>Blessed be the LORD from Zion, Who dwells in Jerusalem. Praise the LORD!</verse>
</chapter>