<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Psalms" book_id="19" n="136">
<verse>Give thanks to the LORD, for He is good, For His lovingkindness is everlasting.</verse>
<verse>Give thanks to the God of gods, For His lovingkindness is everlasting.</verse>
<verse>Give thanks to the Lord of lords, For His lovingkindness is everlasting.</verse>
<verse>To Him who alone does great wonders, For His lovingkindness is everlasting;</verse>
<verse>To Him who made the heavens with skill, For His lovingkindness is everlasting;</verse>
<verse>To Him who spread out the earth above the waters, For His lovingkindness is everlasting;</verse>
<verse>To Him who made the great lights, For His lovingkindness is everlasting:</verse>
<verse>The sun to rule by day, For His lovingkindness is everlasting,</verse>
<verse>The moon and stars to rule by night, For His lovingkindness is everlasting.</verse>
<verse>To Him who smote the Egyptians in their firstborn, For His lovingkindness is everlasting,</verse>
<verse>And brought Israel out from their midst, For His lovingkindness is everlasting,</verse>
<verse>With a strong hand and an outstretched arm, For His lovingkindness is everlasting.</verse>
<verse>To Him who divided the Red Sea asunder, For His lovingkindness is everlasting,</verse>
<verse>And made Israel pass through the midst of it, For His lovingkindness is everlasting;</verse>
<verse>But He overthrew Pharaoh and his army in the Red Sea, For His lovingkindness is everlasting.</verse>
<verse>To Him who led His people through the wilderness, For His lovingkindness is everlasting;</verse>
<verse>To Him who smote great kings, For His lovingkindness is everlasting,</verse>
<verse>And slew mighty kings, For His lovingkindness is everlasting:</verse>
<verse>Sihon, king of the Amorites, For His lovingkindness is everlasting,</verse>
<verse>And Og, king of Bashan, For His lovingkindness is everlasting,</verse>
<verse>And gave their land as a heritage, For His lovingkindness is everlasting,</verse>
<verse>Even a heritage to Israel His servant, For His lovingkindness is everlasting.</verse>
<verse>Who remembered us in our low estate, For His lovingkindness is everlasting,</verse>
<verse>And has rescued us from our adversaries, For His lovingkindness is everlasting;</verse>
<verse>Who gives food to all flesh, For His lovingkindness is everlasting.</verse>
<verse>Give thanks to the God of heaven, For His lovingkindness is everlasting.</verse>
</chapter>