<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Psalms" book-id="19" n="139">
<verse>O LORD, You have searched me and known me.</verse>
<verse>You know when I sit down and when I rise up; You understand my thought from afar.</verse>
<verse>You scrutinize my path and my lying down, And are intimately acquainted with all my ways.</verse>
<verse>Even before there is a word on my tongue, Behold, O LORD, You know it all.</verse>
<verse>You have enclosed me behind and before, And laid Your hand upon me.</verse>
<verse>Such knowledge is too wonderful for me; It is too high, I cannot attain to it.</verse>
<verse>Where can I go from Your Spirit? Or where can I flee from Your presence?</verse>
<verse>If I ascend to heaven, You are there; If I make my bed in Sheol, behold, You are there.</verse>
<verse>If I take the wings of the dawn, If I dwell in the remotest part of the sea,</verse>
<verse>Even there Your hand will lead me, And Your right hand will lay hold of me.</verse>
<verse>If I say, "Surely the darkness will overwhelm me, And the light around me will be night,"</verse>
<verse>Even the darkness is not dark to You, And the night is as bright as the day. Darkness and light are alike to You.</verse>
<verse>For You formed my inward parts; You wove me in my mother's womb.</verse>
<verse>I will give thanks to You, for I am fearfully and wonderfully made; Wonderful are Your works, And my soul knows it very well.</verse>
<verse>My frame was not hidden from You, When I was made in secret, And skillfully wrought in the depths of the earth;</verse>
<verse>Your eyes have seen my unformed substance; And in Your book were all written The days that were ordained for me, When as yet there was not one of them.</verse>
<verse>How precious also are Your thoughts to me, O God! How vast is the sum of them!</verse>
<verse>If I should count them, they would outnumber the sand. When I awake, I am still with You.</verse>
<verse>O that You would slay the wicked, O God; Depart from me, therefore, men of bloodshed.</verse>
<verse>For they speak against You wickedly, And Your enemies take Your name in vain.</verse>
<verse>Do I not hate those who hate You, O LORD? And do I not loathe those who rise up against You?</verse>
<verse>I hate them with the utmost hatred; They have become my enemies.</verse>
<verse>Search me, O God, and know my heart; Try me and know my anxious thoughts;</verse>
<verse>And see if there be any hurtful way in me, And lead me in the everlasting way.</verse>
</chapter>