<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Psalms" book-id="19" n="145">
<verse>I will extol You, my God, O King, And I will bless Your name forever and ever.</verse>
<verse>Every day I will bless You, And I will praise Your name forever and ever.</verse>
<verse>Great is the LORD, and highly to be praised, And His greatness is unsearchable.</verse>
<verse>One generation shall praise Your works to another, And shall declare Your mighty acts.</verse>
<verse>On the glorious splendor of Your majesty And on Your wonderful works, I will meditate.</verse>
<verse>Men shall speak of the power of Your awesome acts, And I will tell of Your greatness.</verse>
<verse>They shall eagerly utter the memory of Your abundant goodness And will shout joyfully of Your righteousness.</verse>
<verse>The LORD is gracious and merciful; Slow to anger and great in lovingkindness.</verse>
<verse>The LORD is good to all, And His mercies are over all His works.</verse>
<verse>All Your works shall give thanks to You, O LORD, And Your godly ones shall bless You.</verse>
<verse>They shall speak of the glory of Your kingdom And talk of Your power;</verse>
<verse>To make known to the sons of men Your mighty acts And the glory of the majesty of Your kingdom.</verse>
<verse>Your kingdom is an everlasting kingdom, And Your dominion endures throughout all generations.</verse>
<verse>The LORD sustains all who fall And raises up all who are bowed down.</verse>
<verse>The eyes of all look to You, And You give them their food in due time.</verse>
<verse>You open Your hand And satisfy the desire of every living thing.</verse>
<verse>The LORD is righteous in all His ways And kind in all His deeds.</verse>
<verse>The LORD is near to all who call upon Him, To all who call upon Him in truth.</verse>
<verse>He will fulfill the desire of those who fear Him; He will also hear their cry and will save them.</verse>
<verse>The LORD keeps all who love Him, But all the wicked He will destroy.</verse>
<verse>My mouth will speak the praise of the LORD, And all flesh will bless His holy name forever and ever.</verse>
</chapter>