<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Psalms" book_id="19" n="18">
<verse>"I love You, O LORD, my strength."</verse>
<verse>The LORD is my rock and my fortress and my deliverer, My God, my rock, in whom I take refuge; My shield and the horn of my salvation, my stronghold.</verse>
<verse>I call upon the LORD, who is worthy to be praised, And I am saved from my enemies.</verse>
<verse>The cords of death encompassed me, And the torrents of ungodliness terrified me.</verse>
<verse>The cords of Sheol surrounded me; The snares of death confronted me.</verse>
<verse>In my distress I called upon the LORD, And cried to my God for help; He heard my voice out of His temple, And my cry for help before Him came into His ears.</verse>
<verse>Then the earth shook and quaked; And the foundations of the mountains were trembling And were shaken, because He was angry.</verse>
<verse>Smoke went up out of His nostrils, And fire from His mouth devoured; Coals were kindled by it.</verse>
<verse>He bowed the heavens also, and came down With thick darkness under His feet.</verse>
<verse>He rode upon a cherub and flew; And He sped upon the wings of the wind.</verse>
<verse>He made darkness His hiding place, His canopy around Him, Darkness of waters, thick clouds of the skies.</verse>
<verse>From the brightness before Him passed His thick clouds, Hailstones and coals of fire.</verse>
<verse>The LORD also thundered in the heavens, And the Most High uttered His voice, Hailstones and coals of fire.</verse>
<verse>He sent out His arrows, and scattered them, And lightning flashes in abundance, and routed them.</verse>
<verse>Then the channels of water appeared, And the foundations of the world were laid bare At Your rebuke, O LORD, At the blast of the breath of Your nostrils.</verse>
<verse>He sent from on high, He took me; He drew me out of many waters.</verse>
<verse>He delivered me from my strong enemy, And from those who hated me, for they were too mighty for me.</verse>
<verse>They confronted me in the day of my calamity, But the LORD was my stay.</verse>
<verse>He brought me forth also into a broad place; He rescued me, because He delighted in me.</verse>
<verse>The LORD has rewarded me according to my righteousness; According to the cleanness of my hands He has recompensed me.</verse>
<verse>For I have kept the ways of the LORD, And have not wickedly departed from my God.</verse>
<verse>For all His ordinances were before me, And I did not put away His statutes from me.</verse>
<verse>I was also blameless with Him, And I kept myself from my iniquity.</verse>
<verse>Therefore the LORD has recompensed me according to my righteousness, According to the cleanness of my hands in His eyes.</verse>
<verse>With the kind You show Yourself kind; With the blameless You show Yourself blameless;</verse>
<verse>With the pure You show Yourself pure, And with the crooked You show Yourself astute.</verse>
<verse>For You save an afflicted people, But haughty eyes You abase.</verse>
<verse>For You light my lamp; The LORD my God illumines my darkness.</verse>
<verse>For by You I can run upon a troop; And by my God I can leap over a wall.</verse>
<verse>As for God, His way is blameless; The word of the LORD is tried; He is a shield to all who take refuge in Him.</verse>
<verse>For who is God, but the LORD? And who is a rock, except our God,</verse>
<verse>The God who girds me with strength And makes my way blameless?</verse>
<verse>He makes my feet like hinds' feet, And sets me upon my high places.</verse>
<verse>He trains my hands for battle, So that my arms can bend a bow of bronze.</verse>
<verse>You have also given me the shield of Your salvation, And Your right hand upholds me; And Your gentleness makes me great.</verse>
<verse>You enlarge my steps under me, And my feet have not slipped.</verse>
<verse>I pursued my enemies and overtook them, And I did not turn back until they were consumed.</verse>
<verse>I shattered them, so that they were not able to rise; They fell under my feet.</verse>
<verse>For You have girded me with strength for battle; You have subdued under me those who rose up against me.</verse>
<verse>You have also made my enemies turn their backs to me, And I destroyed those who hated me.</verse>
<verse>They cried for help, but there was none to save, Even to the LORD, but He did not answer them.</verse>
<verse>Then I beat them fine as the dust before the wind; I emptied them out as the mire of the streets.</verse>
<verse>You have delivered me from the contentions of the people; You have placed me as head of the nations; A people whom I have not known serve me.</verse>
<verse>As soon as they hear, they obey me; Foreigners submit to me.</verse>
<verse>Foreigners fade away, And come trembling out of their fortresses.</verse>
<verse>The LORD lives, and blessed be my rock; And exalted be the God of my salvation,</verse>
<verse>The God who executes vengeance for me, And subdues peoples under me.</verse>
<verse>He delivers me from my enemies; Surely You lift me above those who rise up against me; You rescue me from the violent man.</verse>
<verse>Therefore I will give thanks to You among the nations, O LORD, And I will sing praises to Your name.</verse>
<verse>He gives great deliverance to His king, And shows lovingkindness to His anointed, To David and his descendants forever.</verse>
</chapter>