<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Psalms" book_id="19" n="22">
<verse>My God, my God, why have You forsaken me? Far from my deliverance are the words of my groaning.</verse>
<verse>O my God, I cry by day, but You do not answer; And by night, but I have no rest.</verse>
<verse>Yet You are holy, O You who are enthroned upon the praises of Israel.</verse>
<verse>In You our fathers trusted; They trusted and You delivered them.</verse>
<verse>To You they cried out and were delivered; In You they trusted and were not disappointed.</verse>
<verse>But I am a worm and not a man, A reproach of men and despised by the people.</verse>
<verse>All who see me sneer at me; They separate with the lip, they wag the head, saying,</verse>
<verse>"Commit yourself to the LORD; let Him deliver him; Let Him rescue him, because He delights in him."</verse>
<verse>Yet You are He who brought me forth from the womb; You made me trust when upon my mother's breasts.</verse>
<verse>Upon You I was cast from birth; You have been my God from my mother's womb.</verse>
<verse>Be not far from me, for trouble is near; For there is none to help.</verse>
<verse>Many bulls have surrounded me; Strong bulls of Bashan have encircled me.</verse>
<verse>They open wide their mouth at me, As a ravening and a roaring lion.</verse>
<verse>I am poured out like water, And all my bones are out of joint; My heart is like wax; It is melted within me.</verse>
<verse>My strength is dried up like a potsherd, And my tongue cleaves to my jaws; And You lay me in the dust of death.</verse>
<verse>For dogs have surrounded me; A band of evildoers has encompassed me; They pierced my hands and my feet.</verse>
<verse>I can count all my bones. They look, they stare at me;</verse>
<verse>They divide my garments among them, And for my clothing they cast lots.</verse>
<verse>But You, O LORD, be not far off; O You my help, hasten to my assistance.</verse>
<verse>Deliver my soul from the sword, My only life from the power of the dog.</verse>
<verse>Save me from the lion's mouth; From the horns of the wild oxen You answer me.</verse>
<verse>I will tell of Your name to my brethren; In the midst of the assembly I will praise You.</verse>
<verse>You who fear the LORD, praise Him; All you descendants of Jacob, glorify Him, And stand in awe of Him, all you descendants of Israel.</verse>
<verse>For He has not despised nor abhorred the affliction of the afflicted; Nor has He hidden His face from him; But when he cried to Him for help, He heard.</verse>
<verse>From You comes my praise in the great assembly; I shall pay my vows before those who fear Him.</verse>
<verse>The afflicted will eat and be satisfied; Those who seek Him will praise the LORD. Let your heart live forever!</verse>
<verse>All the ends of the earth will remember and turn to the LORD, And all the families of the nations will worship before You.</verse>
<verse>For the kingdom is the LORD'S And He rules over the nations.</verse>
<verse>All the prosperous of the earth will eat and worship, All those who go down to the dust will bow before Him, Even he who cannot keep his soul alive.</verse>
<verse>Posterity will serve Him; It will be told of the Lord to the coming generation.</verse>
<verse>They will come and will declare His righteousness To a people who will be born, that He has performed it.</verse>
</chapter>