<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Psalms" book-id="19" n="25">
<verse>To You, O LORD, I lift up my soul.</verse>
<verse>O my God, in You I trust, Do not let me be ashamed; Do not let my enemies exult over me.</verse>
<verse>Indeed, none of those who wait for You will be ashamed; Those who deal treacherously without cause will be ashamed.</verse>
<verse>Make me know Your ways, O LORD; Teach me Your paths.</verse>
<verse>Lead me in Your truth and teach me, For You are the God of my salvation; For You I wait all the day.</verse>
<verse>Remember, O LORD, Your compassion and Your lovingkindnesses, For they have been from of old.</verse>
<verse>Do not remember the sins of my youth or my transgressions; According to Your lovingkindness remember me, For Your goodness' sake, O LORD.</verse>
<verse>Good and upright is the LORD; Therefore He instructs sinners in the way.</verse>
<verse>He leads the humble in justice, And He teaches the humble His way.</verse>
<verse>All the paths of the LORD are lovingkindness and truth To those who keep His covenant and His testimonies.</verse>
<verse>For Your name's sake, O LORD, Pardon my iniquity, for it is great.</verse>
<verse>Who is the man who fears the LORD? He will instruct him in the way he should choose.</verse>
<verse>His soul will abide in prosperity, And his descendants will inherit the land.</verse>
<verse>The secret of the LORD is for those who fear Him, And He will make them know His covenant.</verse>
<verse>My eyes are continually toward the LORD, For He will pluck my feet out of the net.</verse>
<verse>Turn to me and be gracious to me, For I am lonely and afflicted.</verse>
<verse>The troubles of my heart are enlarged; Bring me out of my distresses.</verse>
<verse>Look upon my affliction and my trouble, And forgive all my sins.</verse>
<verse>Look upon my enemies, for they are many, And they hate me with violent hatred.</verse>
<verse>Guard my soul and deliver me; Do not let me be ashamed, for I take refuge in You.</verse>
<verse>Let integrity and uprightness preserve me, For I wait for You.</verse>
<verse>Redeem Israel, O God, Out of all his troubles.</verse>
</chapter>