<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Psalms" book-id="19" n="33">
<verse>Sing for joy in the LORD, O you righteous ones; Praise is becoming to the upright.</verse>
<verse>Give thanks to the LORD with the lyre; Sing praises to Him with a harp of ten strings.</verse>
<verse>Sing to Him a new song; Play skillfully with a shout of joy.</verse>
<verse>For the word of the LORD is upright, And all His work is done in faithfulness.</verse>
<verse>He loves righteousness and justice; The earth is full of the lovingkindness of the LORD.</verse>
<verse>By the word of the LORD the heavens were made, And by the breath of His mouth all their host.</verse>
<verse>He gathers the waters of the sea together as a heap; He lays up the deeps in storehouses.</verse>
<verse>Let all the earth fear the LORD; Let all the inhabitants of the world stand in awe of Him.</verse>
<verse>For He spoke, and it was done; He commanded, and it stood fast.</verse>
<verse>The LORD nullifies the counsel of the nations; He frustrates the plans of the peoples.</verse>
<verse>The counsel of the LORD stands forever, The plans of His heart from generation to generation.</verse>
<verse>Blessed is the nation whose God is the LORD, The people whom He has chosen for His own inheritance.</verse>
<verse>The LORD looks from heaven; He sees all the sons of men;</verse>
<verse>From His dwelling place He looks out On all the inhabitants of the earth,</verse>
<verse>He who fashions the hearts of them all, He who understands all their works.</verse>
<verse>The king is not saved by a mighty army; A warrior is not delivered by great strength.</verse>
<verse>A horse is a false hope for victory; Nor does it deliver anyone by its great strength.</verse>
<verse>Behold, the eye of the LORD is on those who fear Him, On those who hope for His lovingkindness,</verse>
<verse>To deliver their soul from death And to keep them alive in famine.</verse>
<verse>Our soul waits for the LORD; He is our help and our shield.</verse>
<verse>For our heart rejoices in Him, Because we trust in His holy name.</verse>
<verse>Let Your lovingkindness, O LORD, be upon us, According as we have hoped in You.</verse>
</chapter>