<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Psalms" book-id="19" n="34">
<verse>I will bless the LORD at all times; His praise shall continually be in my mouth.</verse>
<verse>My soul will make its boast in the LORD; The humble will hear it and rejoice.</verse>
<verse>O magnify the LORD with me, And let us exalt His name together.</verse>
<verse>I sought the LORD, and He answered me, And delivered me from all my fears.</verse>
<verse>They looked to Him and were radiant, And their faces will never be ashamed.</verse>
<verse>This poor man cried, and the LORD heard him And saved him out of all his troubles.</verse>
<verse>The angel of the LORD encamps around those who fear Him, And rescues them.</verse>
<verse>O taste and see that the LORD is good; How blessed is the man who takes refuge in Him!</verse>
<verse>O fear the LORD, you His saints; For to those who fear Him there is no want.</verse>
<verse>The young lions do lack and suffer hunger; But they who seek the LORD shall not be in want of any good thing.</verse>
<verse>Come, you children, listen to me; I will teach you the fear of the LORD.</verse>
<verse>Who is the man who desires life And loves length of days that he may see good?</verse>
<verse>Keep your tongue from evil And your lips from speaking deceit.</verse>
<verse>Depart from evil and do good; Seek peace and pursue it.</verse>
<verse>The eyes of the LORD are toward the righteous And His ears are open to their cry.</verse>
<verse>The face of the LORD is against evildoers, To cut off the memory of them from the earth.</verse>
<verse>The righteous cry, and the LORD hears And delivers them out of all their troubles.</verse>
<verse>The LORD is near to the brokenhearted And saves those who are crushed in spirit.</verse>
<verse>Many are the afflictions of the righteous, But the LORD delivers him out of them all.</verse>
<verse>He keeps all his bones, Not one of them is broken.</verse>
<verse>Evil shall slay the wicked, And those who hate the righteous will be condemned.</verse>
<verse>The LORD redeems the soul of His servants, And none of those who take refuge in Him will be condemned.</verse>
</chapter>