<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Psalms" book_id="19" n="37">
<verse>Do not fret because of evildoers, Be not envious toward wrongdoers.</verse>
<verse>For they will wither quickly like the grass And fade like the green herb.</verse>
<verse>Trust in the LORD and do good; Dwell in the land and cultivate faithfulness.</verse>
<verse>Delight yourself in the LORD; And He will give you the desires of your heart.</verse>
<verse>Commit your way to the LORD, Trust also in Him, and He will do it.</verse>
<verse>He will bring forth your righteousness as the light And your judgment as the noonday.</verse>
<verse>Rest in the LORD and wait patiently for Him; Do not fret because of him who prospers in his way, Because of the man who carries out wicked schemes.</verse>
<verse>Cease from anger and forsake wrath; Do not fret; it leads only to evildoing.</verse>
<verse>For evildoers will be cut off, But those who wait for the LORD, they will inherit the land.</verse>
<verse>Yet a little while and the wicked man will be no more; And you will look carefully for his place and he will not be there.</verse>
<verse>But the humble will inherit the land And will delight themselves in abundant prosperity.</verse>
<verse>The wicked plots against the righteous And gnashes at him with his teeth.</verse>
<verse>The Lord laughs at him, For He sees his day is coming.</verse>
<verse>The wicked have drawn the sword and bent their bow To cast down the afflicted and the needy, To slay those who are upright in conduct.</verse>
<verse>Their sword will enter their own heart, And their bows will be broken.</verse>
<verse>Better is the little of the righteous Than the abundance of many wicked.</verse>
<verse>For the arms of the wicked will be broken, But the LORD sustains the righteous.</verse>
<verse>The LORD knows the days of the blameless, And their inheritance will be forever.</verse>
<verse>They will not be ashamed in the time of evil, And in the days of famine they will have abundance.</verse>
<verse>But the wicked will perish; And the enemies of the LORD will be like the glory of the pastures, They vanish--like smoke they vanish away.</verse>
<verse>The wicked borrows and does not pay back, But the righteous is gracious and gives.</verse>
<verse>For those blessed by Him will inherit the land, But those cursed by Him will be cut off.</verse>
<verse>The steps of a man are established by the LORD, And He delights in his way.</verse>
<verse>When he falls, he will not be hurled headlong, Because the LORD is the One who holds his hand.</verse>
<verse>I have been young and now I am old, Yet I have not seen the righteous forsaken Or his descendants begging bread.</verse>
<verse>All day long he is gracious and lends, And his descendants are a blessing.</verse>
<verse>Depart from evil and do good, So you will abide forever.</verse>
<verse>For the LORD loves justice And does not forsake His godly ones; They are preserved forever, But the descendants of the wicked will be cut off.</verse>
<verse>The righteous will inherit the land And dwell in it forever.</verse>
<verse>The mouth of the righteous utters wisdom, And his tongue speaks justice.</verse>
<verse>The law of his God is in his heart; His steps do not slip.</verse>
<verse>The wicked spies upon the righteous And seeks to kill him.</verse>
<verse>The LORD will not leave him in his hand Or let him be condemned when he is judged.</verse>
<verse>Wait for the LORD and keep His way, And He will exalt you to inherit the land; When the wicked are cut off, you will see it.</verse>
<verse>I have seen a wicked, violent man Spreading himself like a luxuriant tree in its native soil.</verse>
<verse>Then he passed away, and lo, he was no more; I sought for him, but he could not be found.</verse>
<verse>Mark the blameless man, and behold the upright; For the man of peace will have a posterity.</verse>
<verse>But transgressors will be altogether destroyed; The posterity of the wicked will be cut off.</verse>
<verse>But the salvation of the righteous is from the LORD; He is their strength in time of trouble.</verse>
<verse>The LORD helps them and delivers them; He delivers them from the wicked and saves them, Because they take refuge in Him.</verse>
</chapter>