<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Psalms" book-id="19" n="38">
<verse>O LORD, rebuke me not in Your wrath, And chasten me not in Your burning anger.</verse>
<verse>For Your arrows have sunk deep into me, And Your hand has pressed down on me.</verse>
<verse>There is no soundness in my flesh because of Your indignation; There is no health in my bones because of my sin.</verse>
<verse>For my iniquities are gone over my head; As a heavy burden they weigh too much for me.</verse>
<verse>My wounds grow foul and fester Because of my folly.</verse>
<verse>I am bent over and greatly bowed down; I go mourning all day long.</verse>
<verse>For my loins are filled with burning, And there is no soundness in my flesh.</verse>
<verse>I am benumbed and badly crushed; I groan because of the agitation of my heart.</verse>
<verse>Lord, all my desire is before You; And my sighing is not hidden from You.</verse>
<verse>My heart throbs, my strength fails me; And the light of my eyes, even that has gone from me.</verse>
<verse>My loved ones and my friends stand aloof from my plague; And my kinsmen stand afar off.</verse>
<verse>Those who seek my life lay snares for me; And those who seek to injure me have threatened destruction, And they devise treachery all day long.</verse>
<verse>But I, like a deaf man, do not hear; And I am like a mute man who does not open his mouth.</verse>
<verse>Yes, I am like a man who does not hear, And in whose mouth are no arguments.</verse>
<verse>For I hope in You, O LORD; You will answer, O Lord my God.</verse>
<verse>For I said, "May they not rejoice over me, Who, when my foot slips, would magnify themselves against me."</verse>
<verse>For I am ready to fall, And my sorrow is continually before me.</verse>
<verse>For I confess my iniquity; I am full of anxiety because of my sin.</verse>
<verse>But my enemies are vigorous and strong, And many are those who hate me wrongfully.</verse>
<verse>And those who repay evil for good, They oppose me, because I follow what is good.</verse>
<verse>Do not forsake me, O LORD; O my God, do not be far from me!</verse>
<verse>Make haste to help me, O Lord, my salvation!</verse>
</chapter>