<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Psalms" book_id="19" n="40">
<verse>I waited patiently for the LORD; And He inclined to me and heard my cry.</verse>
<verse>He brought me up out of the pit of destruction, out of the miry clay, And He set my feet upon a rock making my footsteps firm.</verse>
<verse>He put a new song in my mouth, a song of praise to our God; Many will see and fear And will trust in the LORD.</verse>
<verse>How blessed is the man who has made the LORD his trust, And has not turned to the proud, nor to those who lapse into falsehood.</verse>
<verse>Many, O LORD my God, are the wonders which You have done, And Your thoughts toward us; There is none to compare with You. If I would declare and speak of them, They would be too numerous to count.</verse>
<verse>Sacrifice and meal offering You have not desired; My ears You have opened; Burnt offering and sin offering You have not required.</verse>
<verse>Then I said, "Behold, I come; In the scroll of the book it is written of me.</verse>
<verse>I delight to do Your will, O my God; Your Law is within my heart."</verse>
<verse>I have proclaimed glad tidings of righteousness in the great congregation; Behold, I will not restrain my lips, O LORD, You know.</verse>
<verse>I have not hidden Your righteousness within my heart; I have spoken of Your faithfulness and Your salvation; I have not concealed Your lovingkindness and Your truth from the great congregation.</verse>
<verse>You, O LORD, will not withhold Your compassion from me; Your lovingkindness and Your truth will continually preserve me.</verse>
<verse>For evils beyond number have surrounded me; My iniquities have overtaken me, so that I am not able to see; They are more numerous than the hairs of my head, And my heart has failed me.</verse>
<verse>Be pleased, O LORD, to deliver me; Make haste, O LORD, to help me.</verse>
<verse>Let those be ashamed and humiliated together Who seek my life to destroy it; Let those be turned back and dishonored Who delight in my hurt.</verse>
<verse>Let those be appalled because of their shame Who say to me, "Aha, aha!"</verse>
<verse>Let all who seek You rejoice and be glad in You; Let those who love Your salvation say continually, "The LORD be magnified!"</verse>
<verse>Since I am afflicted and needy, Let the Lord be mindful of me. You are my help and my deliverer; Do not delay, O my God.</verse>
</chapter>