<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Psalms" book_id="19" n="45">
<verse>My heart overflows with a good theme; I address my verses to the King; My tongue is the pen of a ready writer.</verse>
<verse>You are fairer than the sons of men; Grace is poured upon Your lips; Therefore God has blessed You forever.</verse>
<verse>Gird Your sword on Your thigh, O Mighty One, In Your splendor and Your majesty!</verse>
<verse>And in Your majesty ride on victoriously, For the cause of truth and meekness and righteousness; Let Your right hand teach You awesome things.</verse>
<verse>Your arrows are sharp; The peoples fall under You; Your arrows are in the heart of the King's enemies.</verse>
<verse>Your throne, O God, is forever and ever; A scepter of uprightness is the scepter of Your kingdom.</verse>
<verse>You have loved righteousness and hated wickedness; Therefore God, Your God, has anointed You With the oil of joy above Your fellows.</verse>
<verse>All Your garments are fragrant with myrrh and aloes and cassia; Out of ivory palaces stringed instruments have made You glad.</verse>
<verse>Kings' daughters are among Your noble ladies; At Your right hand stands the queen in gold from Ophir.</verse>
<verse>Listen, O daughter, give attention and incline your ear: Forget your people and your father's house;</verse>
<verse>Then the King will desire your beauty. Because He is your Lord, bow down to Him.</verse>
<verse>The daughter of Tyre will come with a gift; The rich among the people will seek your favor.</verse>
<verse>The King's daughter is all glorious within; Her clothing is interwoven with gold.</verse>
<verse>She will be led to the King in embroidered work; The virgins, her companions who follow her, Will be brought to You.</verse>
<verse>They will be led forth with gladness and rejoicing; They will enter into the King's palace.</verse>
<verse>In place of your fathers will be your sons; You shall make them princes in all the earth.</verse>
<verse>I will cause Your name to be remembered in all generations; Therefore the peoples will give You thanks forever and ever.</verse>
</chapter>