<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Psalms" book_id="19" n="49">
<verse>Hear this, all peoples; Give ear, all inhabitants of the world,</verse>
<verse>Both low and high, Rich and poor together.</verse>
<verse>My mouth will speak wisdom, And the meditation of my heart will be understanding.</verse>
<verse>I will incline my ear to a proverb; I will express my riddle on the harp.</verse>
<verse>Why should I fear in days of adversity, When the iniquity of my foes surrounds me,</verse>
<verse>Even those who trust in their wealth And boast in the abundance of their riches?</verse>
<verse>No man can by any means redeem his brother Or give to God a ransom for him--</verse>
<verse>For the redemption of his soul is costly, And he should cease trying forever--</verse>
<verse>That he should live on eternally, That he should not undergo decay.</verse>
<verse>For he sees that even wise men die; The stupid and the senseless alike perish And leave their wealth to others.</verse>
<verse>Their inner thought is that their houses are forever And their dwelling places to all generations; They have called their lands after their own names.</verse>
<verse>But man in his pomp will not endure; He is like the beasts that perish.</verse>
<verse>This is the way of those who are foolish, And of those after them who approve their words. Selah.</verse>
<verse>As sheep they are appointed for Sheol; Death shall be their shepherd; And the upright shall rule over them in the morning, And their form shall be for Sheol to consume So that they have no habitation.</verse>
<verse>But God will redeem my soul from the power of Sheol, For He will receive me. Selah.</verse>
<verse>Do not be afraid when a man becomes rich, When the glory of his house is increased;</verse>
<verse>For when he dies he will carry nothing away; His glory will not descend after him.</verse>
<verse>Though while he lives he congratulates himself--And though men praise you when you do well for yourself--</verse>
<verse>He shall go to the generation of his fathers; They will never see the light.</verse>
<verse>Man in his pomp, yet without understanding, Is like the beasts that perish.</verse>
</chapter>