<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Psalms" book_id="19" n="51">
<verse>Be gracious to me, O God, according to Your lovingkindness; According to the greatness of Your compassion blot out my transgressions.</verse>
<verse>Wash me thoroughly from my iniquity And cleanse me from my sin.</verse>
<verse>For I know my transgressions, And my sin is ever before me.</verse>
<verse>Against You, You only, I have sinned And done what is evil in Your sight, So that You are justified when You speak And blameless when You judge.</verse>
<verse>Behold, I was brought forth in iniquity, And in sin my mother conceived me.</verse>
<verse>Behold, You desire truth in the innermost being, And in the hidden part You will make me know wisdom.</verse>
<verse>Purify me with hyssop, and I shall be clean; Wash me, and I shall be whiter than snow.</verse>
<verse>Make me to hear joy and gladness, Let the bones which You have broken rejoice.</verse>
<verse>Hide Your face from my sins And blot out all my iniquities.</verse>
<verse>Create in me a clean heart, O God, And renew a steadfast spirit within me.</verse>
<verse>Do not cast me away from Your presence And do not take Your Holy Spirit from me.</verse>
<verse>Restore to me the joy of Your salvation And sustain me with a willing spirit.</verse>
<verse>Then I will teach transgressors Your ways, And sinners will be converted to You.</verse>
<verse>Deliver me from bloodguiltiness, O God, the God of my salvation; Then my tongue will joyfully sing of Your righteousness.</verse>
<verse>O Lord, open my lips, That my mouth may declare Your praise.</verse>
<verse>For You do not delight in sacrifice, otherwise I would give it; You are not pleased with burnt offering.</verse>
<verse>The sacrifices of God are a broken spirit; A broken and a contrite heart, O God, You will not despise.</verse>
<verse>By Your favor do good to Zion; Build the walls of Jerusalem.</verse>
<verse>Then You will delight in righteous sacrifices, In burnt offering and whole burnt offering; Then young bulls will be offered on Your altar.</verse>
</chapter>