<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Psalms" book-id="19" n="55">
<verse>Give ear to my prayer, O God; And do not hide Yourself from my supplication.</verse>
<verse>Give heed to me and answer me; I am restless in my complaint and am surely distracted,</verse>
<verse>Because of the voice of the enemy, Because of the pressure of the wicked; For they bring down trouble upon me And in anger they bear a grudge against me.</verse>
<verse>My heart is in anguish within me, And the terrors of death have fallen upon me.</verse>
<verse>Fear and trembling come upon me, And horror has overwhelmed me.</verse>
<verse>I said, "Oh, that I had wings like a dove! I would fly away and be at rest.</verse>
<verse>"Behold, I would wander far away, I would lodge in the wilderness. Selah.</verse>
<verse>"I would hasten to my place of refuge From the stormy wind and tempest."</verse>
<verse>Confuse, O Lord, divide their tongues, For I have seen violence and strife in the city.</verse>
<verse>Day and night they go around her upon her walls, And iniquity and mischief are in her midst.</verse>
<verse>Destruction is in her midst; Oppression and deceit do not depart from her streets.</verse>
<verse>For it is not an enemy who reproaches me, Then I could bear it; Nor is it one who hates me who has exalted himself against me, Then I could hide myself from him.</verse>
<verse>But it is you, a man my equal, My companion and my familiar friend;</verse>
<verse>We who had sweet fellowship together Walked in the house of God in the throng.</verse>
<verse>Let death come deceitfully upon them; Let them go down alive to Sheol, For evil is in their dwelling, in their midst.</verse>
<verse>As for me, I shall call upon God, And the LORD will save me.</verse>
<verse>Evening and morning and at noon, I will complain and murmur, And He will hear my voice.</verse>
<verse>He will redeem my soul in peace from the battle which is against me, For they are many who strive with me.</verse>
<verse>God will hear and answer them--Even the one who sits enthroned from of old--Selah. With whom there is no change, And who do not fear God.</verse>
<verse>He has put forth his hands against those who were at peace with him; He has violated his covenant.</verse>
<verse>His speech was smoother than butter, But his heart was war; His words were softer than oil, Yet they were drawn swords.</verse>
<verse>Cast your burden upon the LORD and He will sustain you; He will never allow the righteous to be shaken.</verse>
<verse>But You, O God, will bring them down to the pit of destruction; Men of bloodshed and deceit will not live out half their days. But I will trust in You.</verse>
</chapter>