<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Psalms" book-id="19" n="66">
<verse>Shout joyfully to God, all the earth;</verse>
<verse>Sing the glory of His name; Make His praise glorious.</verse>
<verse>Say to God, "How awesome are Your works! Because of the greatness of Your power Your enemies will give feigned obedience to You.</verse>
<verse>"All the earth will worship You, And will sing praises to You; They will sing praises to Your name." Selah.</verse>
<verse>Come and see the works of God, Who is awesome in His deeds toward the sons of men.</verse>
<verse>He turned the sea into dry land; They passed through the river on foot; There let us rejoice in Him!</verse>
<verse>He rules by His might forever; His eyes keep watch on the nations; Let not the rebellious exalt themselves. Selah.</verse>
<verse>Bless our God, O peoples, And sound His praise abroad,</verse>
<verse>Who keeps us in life And does not allow our feet to slip.</verse>
<verse>For You have tried us, O God; You have refined us as silver is refined.</verse>
<verse>You brought us into the net; You laid an oppressive burden upon our loins.</verse>
<verse>You made men ride over our heads; We went through fire and through water, Yet You brought us out into a place of abundance.</verse>
<verse>I shall come into Your house with burnt offerings; I shall pay You my vows,</verse>
<verse>Which my lips uttered And my mouth spoke when I was in distress.</verse>
<verse>I shall offer to You burnt offerings of fat beasts, With the smoke of rams; I shall make an offering of bulls with male goats. Selah.</verse>
<verse>Come and hear, all who fear God, And I will tell of what He has done for my soul.</verse>
<verse>I cried to Him with my mouth, And He was extolled with my tongue.</verse>
<verse>If I regard wickedness in my heart, The Lord will not hear;</verse>
<verse>But certainly God has heard; He has given heed to the voice of my prayer.</verse>
<verse>Blessed be God, Who has not turned away my prayer Nor His lovingkindness from me.</verse>
</chapter>