<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Psalms" book-id="19" n="68">
<verse>Let God arise, let His enemies be scattered, And let those who hate Him flee before Him.</verse>
<verse>As smoke is driven away, so drive them away; As wax melts before the fire, So let the wicked perish before God.</verse>
<verse>But let the righteous be glad; let them exult before God; Yes, let them rejoice with gladness.</verse>
<verse>Sing to God, sing praises to His name; Lift up a song for Him who rides through the deserts, Whose name is the LORD, and exult before Him.</verse>
<verse>A father of the fatherless and a judge for the widows, Is God in His holy habitation.</verse>
<verse>God makes a home for the lonely; He leads out the prisoners into prosperity, Only the rebellious dwell in a parched land.</verse>
<verse>O God, when You went forth before Your people, When You marched through the wilderness, Selah.</verse>
<verse>The earth quaked; The heavens also dropped rain at the presence of God; Sinai itself quaked at the presence of God, the God of Israel.</verse>
<verse>You shed abroad a plentiful rain, O God; You confirmed Your inheritance when it was parched.</verse>
<verse>Your creatures settled in it; You provided in Your goodness for the poor, O God.</verse>
<verse>The Lord gives the command; The women who proclaim the good tidings are a great host:</verse>
<verse>"Kings of armies flee, they flee, And she who remains at home will divide the spoil!"</verse>
<verse>When you lie down among the sheepfolds, You are like the wings of a dove covered with silver, And its pinions with glistening gold.</verse>
<verse>When the Almighty scattered the kings there, It was snowing in Zalmon.</verse>
<verse>A mountain of God is the mountain of Bashan; A mountain of many peaks is the mountain of Bashan.</verse>
<verse>Why do you look with envy, O mountains with many peaks, At the mountain which God has desired for His abode? Surely the LORD will dwell there forever.</verse>
<verse>The chariots of God are myriads, thousands upon thousands; The Lord is among them as at Sinai, in holiness.</verse>
<verse>You have ascended on high, You have led captive Your captives; You have received gifts among men, Even among the rebellious also, that the LORD God may dwell there.</verse>
<verse>Blessed be the Lord, who daily bears our burden, The God who is our salvation. Selah.</verse>
<verse>God is to us a God of deliverances; And to GOD the Lord belong escapes from death.</verse>
<verse>Surely God will shatter the head of His enemies, The hairy crown of him who goes on in his guilty deeds.</verse>
<verse>The Lord said, "I will bring them back from Bashan. I will bring them back from the depths of the sea;</verse>
<verse>That your foot may shatter them in blood, The tongue of your dogs may have its portion from your enemies."</verse>
<verse>They have seen Your procession, O God, The procession of my God, my King, into the sanctuary.</verse>
<verse>The singers went on, the musicians after them, In the midst of the maidens beating tambourines.</verse>
<verse>Bless God in the congregations, Even the LORD, you who are of the fountain of Israel.</verse>
<verse>There is Benjamin, the youngest, ruling them, The princes of Judah in their throng, The princes of Zebulun, the princes of Naphtali.</verse>
<verse>Your God has commanded your strength; Show Yourself strong, O God, who have acted on our behalf.</verse>
<verse>Because of Your temple at Jerusalem Kings will bring gifts to You.</verse>
<verse>Rebuke the beasts in the reeds, The herd of bulls with the calves of the peoples, Trampling under foot the pieces of silver; He has scattered the peoples who delight in war.</verse>
<verse>Envoys will come out of Egypt; Ethiopia will quickly stretch out her hands to God.</verse>
<verse>Sing to God, O kingdoms of the earth, Sing praises to the Lord, Selah.</verse>
<verse>To Him who rides upon the highest heavens, which are from ancient times; Behold, He speaks forth with His voice, a mighty voice.</verse>
<verse>Ascribe strength to God; His majesty is over Israel And His strength is in the skies.</verse>
<verse>O God, You are awesome from Your sanctuary. The God of Israel Himself gives strength and power to the people. Blessed be God!</verse>
</chapter>