<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Psalms" book-id="19" n="69">
<verse>Save me, O God, For the waters have threatened my life.</verse>
<verse>I have sunk in deep mire, and there is no foothold; I have come into deep waters, and a flood overflows me.</verse>
<verse>I am weary with my crying; my throat is parched; My eyes fail while I wait for my God.</verse>
<verse>Those who hate me without a cause are more than the hairs of my head; Those who would destroy me are powerful, being wrongfully my enemies; What I did not steal, I then have to restore.</verse>
<verse>O God, it is You who knows my folly, And my wrongs are not hidden from You.</verse>
<verse>May those who wait for You not be ashamed through me, O Lord GOD of hosts; May those who seek You not be dishonored through me, O God of Israel,</verse>
<verse>Because for Your sake I have borne reproach; Dishonor has covered my face.</verse>
<verse>I have become estranged from my brothers And an alien to my mother's sons.</verse>
<verse>For zeal for Your house has consumed me, And the reproaches of those who reproach You have fallen on me.</verse>
<verse>When I wept in my soul with fasting, It became my reproach.</verse>
<verse>When I made sackcloth my clothing, I became a byword to them.</verse>
<verse>Those who sit in the gate talk about me, And I am the song of the drunkards.</verse>
<verse>But as for me, my prayer is to You, O LORD, at an acceptable time; O God, in the greatness of Your lovingkindness, Answer me with Your saving truth.</verse>
<verse>Deliver me from the mire and do not let me sink; May I be delivered from my foes and from the deep waters.</verse>
<verse>May the flood of water not overflow me Nor the deep swallow me up, Nor the pit shut its mouth on me.</verse>
<verse>Answer me, O LORD, for Your lovingkindness is good; According to the greatness of Your compassion, turn to me,</verse>
<verse>And do not hide Your face from Your servant, For I am in distress; answer me quickly.</verse>
<verse>Oh draw near to my soul and redeem it; Ransom me because of my enemies!</verse>
<verse>You know my reproach and my shame and my dishonor; All my adversaries are before You.</verse>
<verse>Reproach has broken my heart and I am so sick. And I looked for sympathy, but there was none, And for comforters, but I found none.</verse>
<verse>They also gave me gall for my food And for my thirst they gave me vinegar to drink.</verse>
<verse>May their table before them become a snare; And when they are in peace, may it become a trap.</verse>
<verse>May their eyes grow dim so that they cannot see, And make their loins shake continually.</verse>
<verse>Pour out Your indignation on them, And may Your burning anger overtake them.</verse>
<verse>May their camp be desolate; May none dwell in their tents.</verse>
<verse>For they have persecuted him whom You Yourself have smitten, And they tell of the pain of those whom You have wounded.</verse>
<verse>Add iniquity to their iniquity, And may they not come into Your righteousness.</verse>
<verse>May they be blotted out of the book of life And may they not be recorded with the righteous.</verse>
<verse>But I am afflicted and in pain; May Your salvation, O God, set me securely on high.</verse>
<verse>I will praise the name of God with song And magnify Him with thanksgiving.</verse>
<verse>And it will please the LORD better than an ox Or a young bull with horns and hoofs.</verse>
<verse>The humble have seen it and are glad; You who seek God, let your heart revive.</verse>
<verse>For the LORD hears the needy And does not despise His who are prisoners.</verse>
<verse>Let heaven and earth praise Him, The seas and everything that moves in them.</verse>
<verse>For God will save Zion and build the cities of Judah, That they may dwell there and possess it.</verse>
<verse>The descendants of His servants will inherit it, And those who love His name will dwell in it.</verse>
</chapter>