<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Psalms" book-id="19" n="71">
<verse>In You, O LORD, I have taken refuge; Let me never be ashamed.</verse>
<verse>In Your righteousness deliver me and rescue me; Incline Your ear to me and save me.</verse>
<verse>Be to me a rock of habitation to which I may continually come; You have given commandment to save me, For You are my rock and my fortress.</verse>
<verse>Rescue me, O my God, out of the hand of the wicked, Out of the grasp of the wrongdoer and ruthless man,</verse>
<verse>For You are my hope; O Lord GOD, You are my confidence from my youth.</verse>
<verse>By You I have been sustained from my birth; You are He who took me from my mother's womb; My praise is continually of You.</verse>
<verse>I have become a marvel to many, For You are my strong refuge.</verse>
<verse>My mouth is filled with Your praise And with Your glory all day long.</verse>
<verse>Do not cast me off in the time of old age; Do not forsake me when my strength fails.</verse>
<verse>For my enemies have spoken against me; And those who watch for my life have consulted together,</verse>
<verse>Saying, "God has forsaken him; Pursue and seize him, for there is no one to deliver."</verse>
<verse>O God, do not be far from me; O my God, hasten to my help!</verse>
<verse>Let those who are adversaries of my soul be ashamed and consumed; Let them be covered with reproach and dishonor, who seek to injure me.</verse>
<verse>But as for me, I will hope continually, And will praise You yet more and more.</verse>
<verse>My mouth shall tell of Your righteousness And of Your salvation all day long; For I do not know the sum of them.</verse>
<verse>I will come with the mighty deeds of the Lord GOD; I will make mention of Your righteousness, Yours alone.</verse>
<verse>O God, You have taught me from my youth, And I still declare Your wondrous deeds.</verse>
<verse>And even when I am old and gray, O God, do not forsake me, Until I declare Your strength to this generation, Your power to all who are to come.</verse>
<verse>For Your righteousness, O God, reaches to the heavens, You who have done great things; O God, who is like You?</verse>
<verse>You who have shown me many troubles and distresses Will revive me again, And will bring me up again from the depths of the earth.</verse>
<verse>May You increase my greatness And turn to comfort me.</verse>
<verse>I will also praise You with a harp, Even Your truth, O my God; To You I will sing praises with the lyre, O Holy One of Israel.</verse>
<verse>My lips will shout for joy when I sing praises to You; And my soul, which You have redeemed.</verse>
<verse>My tongue also will utter Your righteousness all day long; For they are ashamed, for they are humiliated who seek my hurt.</verse>
</chapter>