<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Psalms" book_id="19" n="72">
<verse>Give the king Your judgments, O God, And Your righteousness to the king's son.</verse>
<verse>May he judge Your people with righteousness And Your afflicted with justice.</verse>
<verse>Let the mountains bring peace to the people, And the hills, in righteousness.</verse>
<verse>May he vindicate the afflicted of the people, Save the children of the needy And crush the oppressor.</verse>
<verse>Let them fear You while the sun endures, And as long as the moon, throughout all generations.</verse>
<verse>May he come down like rain upon the mown grass, Like showers that water the earth.</verse>
<verse>In his days may the righteous flourish, And abundance of peace till the moon is no more.</verse>
<verse>May he also rule from sea to sea And from the River to the ends of the earth.</verse>
<verse>Let the nomads of the desert bow before him, And his enemies lick the dust.</verse>
<verse>Let the kings of Tarshish and of the islands bring presents; The kings of Sheba and Seba offer gifts.</verse>
<verse>And let all kings bow down before him, All nations serve him.</verse>
<verse>For he will deliver the needy when he cries for help, The afflicted also, and him who has no helper.</verse>
<verse>He will have compassion on the poor and needy, And the lives of the needy he will save.</verse>
<verse>He will rescue their life from oppression and violence, And their blood will be precious in his sight;</verse>
<verse>So may he live, and may the gold of Sheba be given to him; And let them pray for him continually; Let them bless him all day long.</verse>
<verse>May there be abundance of grain in the earth on top of the mountains; Its fruit will wave like the cedars of Lebanon; And may those from the city flourish like vegetation of the earth.</verse>
<verse>May his name endure forever; May his name increase as long as the sun shines; And let men bless themselves by him; Let all nations call him blessed.</verse>
<verse>Blessed be the LORD God, the God of Israel, Who alone works wonders.</verse>
<verse>And blessed be His glorious name forever; And may the whole earth be filled with His glory. Amen, and Amen.</verse>
<verse>The prayers of David the son of Jesse are ended.</verse>
</chapter>