<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Psalms" book_id="19" n="73">
<verse>Surely God is good to Israel, To those who are pure in heart!</verse>
<verse>But as for me, my feet came close to stumbling, My steps had almost slipped.</verse>
<verse>For I was envious of the arrogant As I saw the prosperity of the wicked.</verse>
<verse>For there are no pains in their death, And their body is fat.</verse>
<verse>They are not in trouble as other men, Nor are they plagued like mankind.</verse>
<verse>Therefore pride is their necklace; The garment of violence covers them.</verse>
<verse>Their eye bulges from fatness; The imaginations of their heart run riot.</verse>
<verse>They mock and wickedly speak of oppression; They speak from on high.</verse>
<verse>They have set their mouth against the heavens, And their tongue parades through the earth.</verse>
<verse>Therefore his people return to this place, And waters of abundance are drunk by them.</verse>
<verse>They say, "How does God know? And is there knowledge with the Most High?"</verse>
<verse>Behold, these are the wicked; And always at ease, they have increased in wealth.</verse>
<verse>Surely in vain I have kept my heart pure And washed my hands in innocence;</verse>
<verse>For I have been stricken all day long And chastened every morning.</verse>
<verse>If I had said, "I will speak thus," Behold, I would have betrayed the generation of Your children.</verse>
<verse>When I pondered to understand this, It was troublesome in my sight</verse>
<verse>Until I came into the sanctuary of God; Then I perceived their end.</verse>
<verse>Surely You set them in slippery places; You cast them down to destruction.</verse>
<verse>How they are destroyed in a moment! They are utterly swept away by sudden terrors!</verse>
<verse>Like a dream when one awakes, O Lord, when aroused, You will despise their form.</verse>
<verse>When my heart was embittered And I was pierced within,</verse>
<verse>Then I was senseless and ignorant; I was like a beast before You.</verse>
<verse>Nevertheless I am continually with You; You have taken hold of my right hand.</verse>
<verse>With Your counsel You will guide me, And afterward receive me to glory.</verse>
<verse>Whom have I in heaven but You? And besides You, I desire nothing on earth.</verse>
<verse>My flesh and my heart may fail, But God is the strength of my heart and my portion forever.</verse>
<verse>For, behold, those who are far from You will perish; You have destroyed all those who are unfaithful to You.</verse>
<verse>But as for me, the nearness of God is my good; I have made the Lord GOD my refuge, That I may tell of all Your works.</verse>
</chapter>