<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Psalms" book-id="19" n="74">
<verse>O God, why have You rejected us forever? Why does Your anger smoke against the sheep of Your pasture?</verse>
<verse>Remember Your congregation, which You have purchased of old, Which You have redeemed to be the tribe of Your inheritance; And this Mount Zion, where You have dwelt.</verse>
<verse>Turn Your footsteps toward the perpetual ruins; The enemy has damaged everything within the sanctuary.</verse>
<verse>Your adversaries have roared in the midst of Your meeting place; They have set up their own standards for signs.</verse>
<verse>It seems as if one had lifted up His axe in a forest of trees.</verse>
<verse>And now all its carved work They smash with hatchet and hammers.</verse>
<verse>They have burned Your sanctuary to the ground; They have defiled the dwelling place of Your name.</verse>
<verse>They said in their heart, "Let us completely subdue them." They have burned all the meeting places of God in the land.</verse>
<verse>We do not see our signs; There is no longer any prophet, Nor is there any among us who knows how long.</verse>
<verse>How long, O God, will the adversary revile, And the enemy spurn Your name forever?</verse>
<verse>Why do You withdraw Your hand, even Your right hand? From within Your bosom, destroy them!</verse>
<verse>Yet God is my king from of old, Who works deeds of deliverance in the midst of the earth.</verse>
<verse>You divided the sea by Your strength; You broke the heads of the sea monsters in the waters.</verse>
<verse>You crushed the heads of Leviathan; You gave him as food for the creatures of the wilderness.</verse>
<verse>You broke open springs and torrents; You dried up ever-flowing streams.</verse>
<verse>Yours is the day, Yours also is the night; You have prepared the light and the sun.</verse>
<verse>You have established all the boundaries of the earth; You have made summer and winter.</verse>
<verse>Remember this, O LORD, that the enemy has reviled, And a foolish people has spurned Your name.</verse>
<verse>Do not deliver the soul of Your turtledove to the wild beast; Do not forget the life of Your afflicted forever.</verse>
<verse>Consider the covenant; For the dark places of the land are full of the habitations of violence.</verse>
<verse>Let not the oppressed return dishonored; Let the afflicted and needy praise Your name.</verse>
<verse>Arise, O God, and plead Your own cause; Remember how the foolish man reproaches You all day long.</verse>
<verse>Do not forget the voice of Your adversaries, The uproar of those who rise against You which ascends continually.</verse>
</chapter>