<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Psalms" book-id="19" n="77">
<verse>My voice rises to God, and I will cry aloud; My voice rises to God, and He will hear me.</verse>
<verse>In the day of my trouble I sought the Lord; In the night my hand was stretched out without weariness; My soul refused to be comforted.</verse>
<verse>When I remember God, then I am disturbed; When I sigh, then my spirit grows faint. Selah.</verse>
<verse>You have held my eyelids open; I am so troubled that I cannot speak.</verse>
<verse>I have considered the days of old, The years of long ago.</verse>
<verse>I will remember my song in the night; I will meditate with my heart, And my spirit ponders:</verse>
<verse>Will the Lord reject forever? And will He never be favorable again?</verse>
<verse>Has His lovingkindness ceased forever? Has His promise come to an end forever?</verse>
<verse>Has God forgotten to be gracious, Or has He in anger withdrawn His compassion? Selah.</verse>
<verse>Then I said, "It is my grief, That the right hand of the Most High has changed."</verse>
<verse>I shall remember the deeds of the LORD; Surely I will remember Your wonders of old.</verse>
<verse>I will meditate on all Your work And muse on Your deeds.</verse>
<verse>Your way, O God, is holy; What god is great like our God?</verse>
<verse>You are the God who works wonders; You have made known Your strength among the peoples.</verse>
<verse>You have by Your power redeemed Your people, The sons of Jacob and Joseph. Selah.</verse>
<verse>The waters saw You, O God; The waters saw You, they were in anguish; The deeps also trembled.</verse>
<verse>The clouds poured out water; The skies gave forth a sound; Your arrows flashed here and there.</verse>
<verse>The sound of Your thunder was in the whirlwind; The lightnings lit up the world; The earth trembled and shook.</verse>
<verse>Your way was in the sea And Your paths in the mighty waters, And Your footprints may not be known.</verse>
<verse>You led Your people like a flock By the hand of Moses and Aaron.</verse>
</chapter>