<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Psalms" book-id="19" n="78">
<verse>Listen, O my people, to my instruction; Incline your ears to the words of my mouth.</verse>
<verse>I will open my mouth in a parable; I will utter dark sayings of old,</verse>
<verse>Which we have heard and known, And our fathers have told us.</verse>
<verse>We will not conceal them from their children, But tell to the generation to come the praises of the LORD, And His strength and His wondrous works that He has done.</verse>
<verse>For He established a testimony in Jacob And appointed a law in Israel, Which He commanded our fathers That they should teach them to their children,</verse>
<verse>That the generation to come might know, even the children yet to be born, That they may arise and tell them to their children,</verse>
<verse>That they should put their confidence in God And not forget the works of God, But keep His commandments,</verse>
<verse>And not be like their fathers, A stubborn and rebellious generation, A generation that did not prepare its heart And whose spirit was not faithful to God.</verse>
<verse>The sons of Ephraim were archers equipped with bows, Yet they turned back in the day of battle.</verse>
<verse>They did not keep the covenant of God And refused to walk in His law;</verse>
<verse>They forgot His deeds And His miracles that He had shown them.</verse>
<verse>He wrought wonders before their fathers In the land of Egypt, in the field of Zoan.</verse>
<verse>He divided the sea and caused them to pass through, And He made the waters stand up like a heap.</verse>
<verse>Then He led them with the cloud by day And all the night with a light of fire.</verse>
<verse>He split the rocks in the wilderness And gave them abundant drink like the ocean depths.</verse>
<verse>He brought forth streams also from the rock And caused waters to run down like rivers.</verse>
<verse>Yet they still continued to sin against Him, To rebel against the Most High in the desert.</verse>
<verse>And in their heart they put God to the test By asking food according to their desire.</verse>
<verse>Then they spoke against God; They said, "Can God prepare a table in the wilderness?</verse>
<verse>"Behold, He struck the rock so that waters gushed out, And streams were overflowing; Can He give bread also? Will He provide meat for His people?"</verse>
<verse>Therefore the LORD heard and was full of wrath; And a fire was kindled against Jacob And anger also mounted against Israel,</verse>
<verse>Because they did not believe in God And did not trust in His salvation.</verse>
<verse>Yet He commanded the clouds above And opened the doors of heaven;</verse>
<verse>He rained down manna upon them to eat And gave them food from heaven.</verse>
<verse>Man did eat the bread of angels; He sent them food in abundance.</verse>
<verse>He caused the east wind to blow in the heavens And by His power He directed the south wind.</verse>
<verse>When He rained meat upon them like the dust, Even winged fowl like the sand of the seas,</verse>
<verse>Then He let them fall in the midst of their camp, Round about their dwellings.</verse>
<verse>So they ate and were well filled, And their desire He gave to them.</verse>
<verse>Before they had satisfied their desire, While their food was in their mouths,</verse>
<verse>The anger of God rose against them And killed some of their stoutest ones, And subdued the choice men of Israel.</verse>
<verse>In spite of all this they still sinned And did not believe in His wonderful works.</verse>
<verse>So He brought their days to an end in futility And their years in sudden terror.</verse>
<verse>When He killed them, then they sought Him, And returned and searched diligently for God;</verse>
<verse>And they remembered that God was their rock, And the Most High God their Redeemer.</verse>
<verse>But they deceived Him with their mouth And lied to Him with their tongue.</verse>
<verse>For their heart was not steadfast toward Him, Nor were they faithful in His covenant.</verse>
<verse>But He, being compassionate, forgave their iniquity and did not destroy them; And often He restrained His anger And did not arouse all His wrath.</verse>
<verse>Thus He remembered that they were but flesh, A wind that passes and does not return.</verse>
<verse>How often they rebelled against Him in the wilderness And grieved Him in the desert!</verse>
<verse>Again and again they tempted God, And pained the Holy One of Israel.</verse>
<verse>They did not remember His power, The day when He redeemed them from the adversary,</verse>
<verse>When He performed His signs in Egypt And His marvels in the field of Zoan,</verse>
<verse>And turned their rivers to blood, And their streams, they could not drink.</verse>
<verse>He sent among them swarms of flies which devoured them, And frogs which destroyed them.</verse>
<verse>He gave also their crops to the grasshopper And the product of their labor to the locust.</verse>
<verse>He destroyed their vines with hailstones And their sycamore trees with frost.</verse>
<verse>He gave over their cattle also to the hailstones And their herds to bolts of lightning.</verse>
<verse>He sent upon them His burning anger, Fury and indignation and trouble, A band of destroying angels.</verse>
<verse>He leveled a path for His anger; He did not spare their soul from death, But gave over their life to the plague,</verse>
<verse>And smote all the firstborn in Egypt, The first issue of their virility in the tents of Ham.</verse>
<verse>But He led forth His own people like sheep And guided them in the wilderness like a flock;</verse>
<verse>He led them safely, so that they did not fear; But the sea engulfed their enemies.</verse>
<verse>So He brought them to His holy land, To this hill country which His right hand had gained.</verse>
<verse>He also drove out the nations before them And apportioned them for an inheritance by measurement, And made the tribes of Israel dwell in their tents.</verse>
<verse>Yet they tempted and rebelled against the Most High God And did not keep His testimonies,</verse>
<verse>But turned back and acted treacherously like their fathers; They turned aside like a treacherous bow.</verse>
<verse>For they provoked Him with their high places And aroused His jealousy with their graven images.</verse>
<verse>When God heard, He was filled with wrath And greatly abhorred Israel;</verse>
<verse>So that He abandoned the dwelling place at Shiloh, The tent which He had pitched among men,</verse>
<verse>And gave up His strength to captivity And His glory into the hand of the adversary.</verse>
<verse>He also delivered His people to the sword, And was filled with wrath at His inheritance.</verse>
<verse>Fire devoured His young men, And His virgins had no wedding songs.</verse>
<verse>His priests fell by the sword, And His widows could not weep.</verse>
<verse>Then the Lord awoke as if from sleep, Like a warrior overcome by wine.</verse>
<verse>He drove His adversaries backward; He put on them an everlasting reproach.</verse>
<verse>He also rejected the tent of Joseph, And did not choose the tribe of Ephraim,</verse>
<verse>But chose the tribe of Judah, Mount Zion which He loved.</verse>
<verse>And He built His sanctuary like the heights, Like the earth which He has founded forever.</verse>
<verse>He also chose David His servant And took him from the sheepfolds;</verse>
<verse>From the care of the ewes with suckling lambs He brought him To shepherd Jacob His people, And Israel His inheritance.</verse>
<verse>So he shepherded them according to the integrity of his heart, And guided them with his skillful hands.</verse>
</chapter>