<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Psalms" book_id="19" n="80">
<verse>Oh, give ear, Shepherd of Israel, You who lead Joseph like a flock; You who are enthroned above the cherubim, shine forth!</verse>
<verse>Before Ephraim and Benjamin and Manasseh, stir up Your power And come to save us!</verse>
<verse>O God, restore us And cause Your face to shine upon us, and we will be saved.</verse>
<verse>O LORD God of hosts, How long will You be angry with the prayer of Your people?</verse>
<verse>You have fed them with the bread of tears, And You have made them to drink tears in large measure.</verse>
<verse>You make us an object of contention to our neighbors, And our enemies laugh among themselves.</verse>
<verse>O God of hosts, restore us And cause Your face to shine upon us, and we will be saved.</verse>
<verse>You removed a vine from Egypt; You drove out the nations and planted it.</verse>
<verse>You cleared the ground before it, And it took deep root and filled the land.</verse>
<verse>The mountains were covered with its shadow, And the cedars of God with its boughs.</verse>
<verse>It was sending out its branches to the sea And its shoots to the River.</verse>
<verse>Why have You broken down its hedges, So that all who pass that way pick its fruit?</verse>
<verse>A boar from the forest eats it away And whatever moves in the field feeds on it.</verse>
<verse>O God of hosts, turn again now, we beseech You; Look down from heaven and see, and take care of this vine,</verse>
<verse>Even the shoot which Your right hand has planted, And on the son whom You have strengthened for Yourself.</verse>
<verse>It is burned with fire, it is cut down; They perish at the rebuke of Your countenance.</verse>
<verse>Let Your hand be upon the man of Your right hand, Upon the son of man whom You made strong for Yourself.</verse>
<verse>Then we shall not turn back from You; Revive us, and we will call upon Your name.</verse>
<verse>O LORD God of hosts, restore us; Cause Your face to shine upon us, and we will be saved.</verse>
</chapter>