<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Psalms" book-id="19" n="89">
<verse>I will sing of the lovingkindness of the LORD forever; To all generations I will make known Your faithfulness with my mouth.</verse>
<verse>For I have said, "Lovingkindness will be built up forever; In the heavens You will establish Your faithfulness."</verse>
<verse>"I have made a covenant with My chosen; I have sworn to David My servant,</verse>
<verse>I will establish your seed forever And build up your throne to all generations." Selah.</verse>
<verse>The heavens will praise Your wonders, O LORD; Your faithfulness also in the assembly of the holy ones.</verse>
<verse>For who in the skies is comparable to the LORD? Who among the sons of the mighty is like the LORD,</verse>
<verse>A God greatly feared in the council of the holy ones, And awesome above all those who are around Him?</verse>
<verse>O LORD God of hosts, who is like You, O mighty LORD? Your faithfulness also surrounds You.</verse>
<verse>You rule the swelling of the sea; When its waves rise, You still them.</verse>
<verse>You Yourself crushed Rahab like one who is slain; You scattered Your enemies with Your mighty arm.</verse>
<verse>The heavens are Yours, the earth also is Yours; The world and all it contains, You have founded them.</verse>
<verse>The north and the south, You have created them; Tabor and Hermon shout for joy at Your name.</verse>
<verse>You have a strong arm; Your hand is mighty, Your right hand is exalted.</verse>
<verse>Righteousness and justice are the foundation of Your throne; Lovingkindness and truth go before You.</verse>
<verse>How blessed are the people who know the joyful sound! O LORD, they walk in the light of Your countenance.</verse>
<verse>In Your name they rejoice all the day, And by Your righteousness they are exalted.</verse>
<verse>For You are the glory of their strength, And by Your favor our horn is exalted.</verse>
<verse>For our shield belongs to the LORD, And our king to the Holy One of Israel.</verse>
<verse>Once You spoke in vision to Your godly ones, And said, "I have given help to one who is mighty; I have exalted one chosen from the people.</verse>
<verse>"I have found David My servant; With My holy oil I have anointed him,</verse>
<verse>With whom My hand will be established; My arm also will strengthen him.</verse>
<verse>"The enemy will not deceive him, Nor the son of wickedness afflict him.</verse>
<verse>"But I shall crush his adversaries before him, And strike those who hate him.</verse>
<verse>"My faithfulness and My lovingkindness will be with him, And in My name his horn will be exalted.</verse>
<verse>"I shall also set his hand on the sea And his right hand on the rivers.</verse>
<verse>"He will cry to Me, 'You are my Father, My God, and the rock of my salvation.'</verse>
<verse>"I also shall make him My firstborn, The highest of the kings of the earth.</verse>
<verse>"My lovingkindness I will keep for him forever, And My covenant shall be confirmed to him.</verse>
<verse>"So I will establish his descendants forever And his throne as the days of heaven.</verse>
<verse>"If his sons forsake My law And do not walk in My judgments,</verse>
<verse>If they violate My statutes And do not keep My commandments,</verse>
<verse>Then I will punish their transgression with the rod And their iniquity with stripes.</verse>
<verse>"But I will not break off My lovingkindness from him, Nor deal falsely in My faithfulness.</verse>
<verse>"My covenant I will not violate, Nor will I alter the utterance of My lips.</verse>
<verse>"Once I have sworn by My holiness; I will not lie to David.</verse>
<verse>"His descendants shall endure forever And his throne as the sun before Me.</verse>
<verse>"It shall be established forever like the moon, And the witness in the sky is faithful." Selah.</verse>
<verse>But You have cast off and rejected, You have been full of wrath against Your anointed.</verse>
<verse>You have spurned the covenant of Your servant; You have profaned his crown in the dust.</verse>
<verse>You have broken down all his walls; You have brought his strongholds to ruin.</verse>
<verse>All who pass along the way plunder him; He has become a reproach to his neighbors.</verse>
<verse>You have exalted the right hand of his adversaries; You have made all his enemies rejoice.</verse>
<verse>You also turn back the edge of his sword And have not made him stand in battle.</verse>
<verse>You have made his splendor to cease And cast his throne to the ground.</verse>
<verse>You have shortened the days of his youth; You have covered him with shame. Selah.</verse>
<verse>How long, O LORD? Will You hide Yourself forever? Will Your wrath burn like fire?</verse>
<verse>Remember what my span of life is; For what vanity You have created all the sons of men!</verse>
<verse>What man can live and not see death? Can he deliver his soul from the power of Sheol? Selah.</verse>
<verse>Where are Your former lovingkindnesses, O Lord, Which You swore to David in Your faithfulness?</verse>
<verse>Remember, O Lord, the reproach of Your servants; How I bear in my bosom the reproach of all the many peoples,</verse>
<verse>With which Your enemies have reproached, O LORD, With which they have reproached the footsteps of Your anointed.</verse>
<verse>Blessed be the LORD forever! Amen and Amen.</verse>
</chapter>