<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Psalms" book_id="19" n="9">
<verse>I will give thanks to the LORD with all my heart; I will tell of all Your wonders.</verse>
<verse>I will be glad and exult in You; I will sing praise to Your name, O Most High.</verse>
<verse>When my enemies turn back, They stumble and perish before You.</verse>
<verse>For You have maintained my just cause; You have sat on the throne judging righteously.</verse>
<verse>You have rebuked the nations, You have destroyed the wicked; You have blotted out their name forever and ever.</verse>
<verse>The enemy has come to an end in perpetual ruins, And You have uprooted the cities; The very memory of them has perished.</verse>
<verse>But the LORD abides forever; He has established His throne for judgment,</verse>
<verse>And He will judge the world in righteousness; He will execute judgment for the peoples with equity.</verse>
<verse>The LORD also will be a stronghold for the oppressed, A stronghold in times of trouble;</verse>
<verse>And those who know Your name will put their trust in You, For You, O LORD, have not forsaken those who seek You.</verse>
<verse>Sing praises to the LORD, who dwells in Zion; Declare among the peoples His deeds.</verse>
<verse>For He who requires blood remembers them; He does not forget the cry of the afflicted.</verse>
<verse>Be gracious to me, O LORD; See my affliction from those who hate me, You who lift me up from the gates of death,</verse>
<verse>That I may tell of all Your praises, That in the gates of the daughter of Zion I may rejoice in Your salvation.</verse>
<verse>The nations have sunk down in the pit which they have made; In the net which they hid, their own foot has been caught.</verse>
<verse>The LORD has made Himself known; He has executed judgment. In the work of his own hands the wicked is snared. Higgaion Selah.</verse>
<verse>The wicked will return to Sheol, Even all the nations who forget God.</verse>
<verse>For the needy will not always be forgotten, Nor the hope of the afflicted perish forever.</verse>
<verse>Arise, O LORD, do not let man prevail; Let the nations be judged before You.</verse>
<verse>Put them in fear, O LORD; Let the nations know that they are but men. Selah.</verse>
</chapter>