<chapter translation="NASB" testament="Old" book="Psalms" book-id="19" n="94">
<verse>O LORD, God of vengeance, God of vengeance, shine forth!</verse>
<verse>Rise up, O Judge of the earth, Render recompense to the proud.</verse>
<verse>How long shall the wicked, O LORD, How long shall the wicked exult?</verse>
<verse>They pour forth words, they speak arrogantly; All who do wickedness vaunt themselves.</verse>
<verse>They crush Your people, O LORD, And afflict Your heritage.</verse>
<verse>They slay the widow and the stranger And murder the orphans.</verse>
<verse>They have said, "The LORD does not see, Nor does the God of Jacob pay heed."</verse>
<verse>Pay heed, you senseless among the people; And when will you understand, stupid ones?</verse>
<verse>He who planted the ear, does He not hear? He who formed the eye, does He not see?</verse>
<verse>He who chastens the nations, will He not rebuke, Even He who teaches man knowledge?</verse>
<verse>The LORD knows the thoughts of man, That they are a mere breath.</verse>
<verse>Blessed is the man whom You chasten, O LORD, And whom You teach out of Your law;</verse>
<verse>That You may grant him relief from the days of adversity, Until a pit is dug for the wicked.</verse>
<verse>For the LORD will not abandon His people, Nor will He forsake His inheritance.</verse>
<verse>For judgment will again be righteous, And all the upright in heart will follow it.</verse>
<verse>Who will stand up for me against evildoers? Who will take his stand for me against those who do wickedness?</verse>
<verse>If the LORD had not been my help, My soul would soon have dwelt in the abode of silence.</verse>
<verse>If I should say, "My foot has slipped," Your lovingkindness, O LORD, will hold me up.</verse>
<verse>When my anxious thoughts multiply within me, Your consolations delight my soul.</verse>
<verse>Can a throne of destruction be allied with You, One which devises mischief by decree?</verse>
<verse>They band themselves together against the life of the righteous And condemn the innocent to death.</verse>
<verse>But the LORD has been my stronghold, And my God the rock of my refuge.</verse>
<verse>He has brought back their wickedness upon them And will destroy them in their evil; The LORD our God will destroy them.</verse>
</chapter>